Anton Osika (00:00:00):
... Lovable is your personal
AI software engineer. You describe an idea and
then you get a fully working product. The reason
is to enable those who have had such a hard time
finding people who are good at creating software
that's been their absolute bottleneck and let them
take their ideas and their dreams into reality.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:00:19):
You guys hit 4 million ARR in the
first four weeks. You hit 10 million ARR in the
first two months with just 15 people. You're the
fastest growing startup in all of Europe. How did
you decide on Lovable is the name. It's so sweet.
Anton Osika (00:00:31):
The best word for a great
product is that it's lovable. A lot of jargon
that I like to use to emphasize what we should
be striving for is building a minimum lovable
product and then building a lovable product and
then building an absolutely lovable product. So
I took that jargon with me in the company name.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:00:47):
People would wonder just what
jobs will be more important, what
skills will be less important?
Anton Osika (00:00:51):
Doing a bit of everything. Being a generalist,
I think much more important than it used to be.
If I'm putting together a product team today,
I would really obsess about getting as many
skill sets as possible for each person I hire.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:01:03):
What have you done that has
allowed you to grow this fast with so few people?
Anton Osika (00:01:07):
People love the product.
That's the driver of the growth.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:01:15):
Today, my guest is Anton O-C-K.
Anton is co-founder and CEO of Lovable, which is
essentially an AI engineer that takes an English
prompt and codes a product for you in minutes.
You can then talk to it, iterate on the product,
and then launch it to the world. It's one of the
fastest growing products in history. The fastest
growing startup in Europe ever, and as Anton
describes, their goal for Lovable is for it to
be the last piece of software that anybody has to
write because it'll be able to create all future
products for us. They launched just a few months
ago in the first four weeks, hit 4 million ARR in
the first two months across 10 million ARR, all
with just 15 people. Absurd. In our conversation,
we covered a lot of ground, including a live
demo of Lovable, how their team operates,
how they hire, what has most enabled their
team to scale this quickly with so few people,
pro tips for using Lovable, how it all started,
how he recommends you build product teams going
forward with tools like this existing, what
skills will matter more and less going forward?
(00:02:17):
Plus how to
think about Lovable versus competitors and so
much more. If you're trying to wrap your head
around how product building will change
with the rise of AI tools, this episode
is a must watch. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if
you become a yearly subscriber of my newsletter,
you now get a year free of Perplexity and
Notion and Superhuman and Linear and Granola.
Check it out at Lenny'snewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Anton, O-C-K.
(00:02:49):
This episode is brought to you
by Cinch the customer Communications Cloud. Here's
the thing about digital customer communications.
Whether you're sending marketing campaigns,
verification codes or account alerts, you need
them to reach users reliably. That's where Cinch
comes in. Over 150,000 businesses, including eight
of the top 10 largest tech companies globally use
Cinch's API to build messaging, email and calling
into their products. And there's something big
happening in messaging that product teams need
to know about. Rich Communication Services or RCS,
think of RCS as SMS 2.0. Instead of getting texts
from a random number, your users will see your
verified company name and logo without needing
to download anything new. It's a more secure and
branded experience, plus you get features like
interactive carousels and suggested replies,
and here's why this matters. US carriers are
starting to adopt RCS. Cinch is already helping
Nature Brands send RCS messages around the world
and they're helping Lenny's podcast listeners
get registered first before the rush hits the
US market. Learn more at get started at Cinch.com
slash Lenny. That's S-I-N-C-H dot com slash Lenny.
(00:04:02):
This episode is brought
to you by Persona, the adaptable identity platform
that helps businesses fight fraud, meet compliance
requirements, and build trust. While you're
listening to this right now, how do you know that
you're really listening to me, Lenny? These days,
it's easier than ever for fraudsters to steal PII,
faces and identities. That's where Persona comes
in. Persona helps leading companies like LinkedIn,
Etsy, and Twilio securely verify individuals and
businesses across the world. What sets Persona
apart is its configurability. Every company
has different needs depending on its industry,
use cases, risk tolerance and user demographics.
That's why Persona offers flexible building blocks
that allow you to build tailored collection and
verification flows that maximize conversion while
minimizing risks. Plus Persona's orchestration
tools, automate your identity process so that
you can fight rapidly shifting fraud and meet
new waves of regulation. Whether you're a
startup or an enterprise business,
Persona has a plan for you. Learn more
at withpersona.com slash Lenny. Again, that's
with P-E-R-S-O-N-A dot com slash Lenny. Anton,
thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Anton Osika (00:05:19):
It's a pleasure to talk to you,
Lenny, great to be here.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:05:22):
I don't know how you have time
to do this podcast. Your life must be insane these
days with the pace at which you guys are scaling,
just how much is changing in AI every day.
So I just extra appreciate you making time
for this. I think you said it's 10:30,
your time, is when we're doing this.
Anton Osika (00:05:39):
I'm a bit tired,
yes. Mostly from the crazy
pace of everything, but yes.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:05:45):
This is going to be an invigorating conversation
and you're not going to be able to sleep.
Anton Osika (00:05:50):
Yes. I'm sure. I'm sure.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:05:51):
Okay, so for folks that are
maybe a little bit familiar with
Lovable or not at all familiar,
what is Lovable? What's the
simplest way to understand it?
Anton Osika (00:06:00):
I'd say Lovable is your personal AI
software engineer. You describe an idea and then
you get a fully working product from the AI. And
what this means is that entrepreneurs actually
today, they turn their ideas into real businesses.
We have a lot of designers and product managers
that create the first version of their product
ideas to show to the teams, and some of them
become founders because of the empowerment from
this, but also developers themselves, they
actually writing code or creating products
much faster. The reason, it's pretty obvious
for me, but I'll spell it out, the reason why
we're doing Lovable is that I don't know about
your mom, but my mom doesn't write code and-
Lenny Rachitsky (00:06:52):
Same.
Anton Osika (00:06:55):
... almost all my friends
throughout my life reached out for help.
Like, "Anton, I need to build something.
How do I find a great software engineer?" And we
are building for this 99% of the population who
don't write code. Currently, if you're technically
inclined, you get much further, but over time,
naturally the way to build software is by just
talking to an AI. And that's how we see it.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:07:21):
I love the way that you guys
describe it and you didn't mention it, but I
think it's building the last piece of
software ever. How do you phrase that?
Anton Osika (00:07:28):
Yeah, we say we're
building the last piece of software.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:07:31):
The last piece of software. Okay,
we're going to do a live demo, but
first of all, can you just share
some stats on the scale of this business
at this point because it's quite absurd.
Anton Osika (00:07:42):
Yeah. So we launched Lovable less than
three months ago, and now we have 300,000 monthly
active users and 30,000 of those are actually
paying and it is growing at the same rates,
just almost only through organic word of mouth.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:08:02):
Okay. And I'll share a couple stats
in terms of revenue, just so folks know this, and
we'll have this in the intro too. I think you guys
hit 4 million ARR in the first four weeks. You hit
10 million ARR in the first two months with just
15 people. You're the fastest growing startup
in all of Europe, and you guys had to rewrite
your entire code base recently and you couldn't
ship any new features for a while. Is that right?
Anton Osika (00:08:26):
That's right, yeah. People were
saying like, "Oh, you're shipping so fast."
And we were all quite frustrated because we
wrote our service in this kind of scripting
language and then as we started scaling,
we were just, no, we have to throw everything
away and rewrite it in a more performant way.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:08:43):
Okay, before we get to the demo,
last question, you shared there's some
companies that have started based on
Lovable. I didn't even know that. So what are
some examples of companies slash businesses
that have launched off of Lovable
and now are actually companies?
Anton Osika (00:08:56):
I mentioned designers using
Lovable and one of our early users, Harry, he
started shipping real web apps to his clients
instead of just shipping designs. And then he went
on to say, okay, wait, I'm going to start an AI
startup. And his company, he launched on Product
Hunt and everything and making money is just like,
let's anyone upload their photo library and
then the AI parses and categorizes it. And
if you go to launched.lovable.app, this
is an app built with Lovable is again a
product Hunt version where you can see a lot
of businesses or small SaaS featured there.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:09:38):
Okay, cool. So we're going to
come back to some of this stuff, but let's get
into demo. I rarely do demos on this podcast,
but I'm finding that I think it's really important
for people to see these products in action because
in a large part, this is the future of product
building and a lot of people hear about, "Oh yeah,
AI's coming," and I don't think a lot of
people actually see what the latest tools
are capable of. And so I love showing
these sorts of things on this podcast.
Anton Osika (00:10:05):
So Lenny, I was thinking,
did you ever consider making a
copy and build your own Airbnb?
Lenny Rachitsky (00:10:14):
I haven't, but go on.
Anton Osika (00:10:17):
How about you do that?
Lenny Rachitsky (00:10:18):
Let's do it. Let's do it. Okay,
so we're going to make our own Airbnb.
Anton Osika (00:10:18):
Okay.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:10:21):
Okay, cool.
Anton Osika (00:10:22):
So I just put in the
first prompt for an Airbnb clone.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:10:27):
Okay. And what is the prompt, just
for folks that aren't watching?
Anton Osika (00:10:31):
Two words, Airbnb clones. That's the prompt.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:10:33):
Okay.
Anton Osika (00:10:34):
Just start simple and then what you
get is that the AI says, okay, I can go through
what does a beautiful Airbnb clone look like and
it goes through a bit of design decisions and then
I'll zoom out to see more of it. We have this just
UI that is... I mean it has all the nice things
you would expect from Airbnb clone where you see
different categories and you can see two listings
from Airbnb with login buttons and everything.
So far it doesn't have the functionality of
Airbnb, it just has the UI. I would now ask for
an improvement on some of the functionality. Like
if I'm switching category, I want to see different
listings, let's say. But if you have any thoughts
on what we should build next, let me know.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:11:25):
Okay, and so you had this preloaded,
so you didn't see how long it would
take, but how long would this normally
take for it to just write all
this code and have it for you?
Anton Osika (00:11:32):
The first prompt takes 30 seconds.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:11:34):
30 seconds? Okay. And it's
like a very good copy of Airbnb. I love
that you didn't have to show it a design,
you just tell it Airbnb and it knows. Okay, so
your question is would I want to add to my own
version of Airbnb? I've always wanted to explore
buying the place that I look at just like, Is
this for sale? So what if we see what that would
feel like if you're just a way to buy a listing.
Anton Osika (00:11:59):
Okay. Okay. So how about we add,
I mean prompting is important here, so
let's be specific, but we would ask,
add a button on the listing which has
purchased this Airbnb home. Is that it?
Lenny Rachitsky (00:12:16):
Perfect.
Anton Osika (00:12:19):
Okay, so, add, and [inaudible 00:12:19]. I'll
be even more specific. It will pop
up a model to purchase the listing.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:12:32):
Perfect. And I love... So I
think something as you're typing, I'm just going
to share thoughts as you're doing this. So the
site that you asked this AI engineer to build,
it's actually a functioning website that you
can browse around. It's not just a design,
obviously there's no actual listings here,
there's no actual houses here. Say you were
trying to actually build Airbnb and you
wanted to start adding actual homes that plug
into this, how does that sort of step work?
Anton Osika (00:13:02):
So as you say, this is just kind of the mockup UI,
but it's also interactive. If I want to add login
and add listing management, then we will connect
something called the backend. So where data is
stored, where user's log information is stored,
and I can show you how to do that. First let's
just try out where we got with this short prompt.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:13:29):
Let's do it.
Anton Osika (00:13:31):
Adding the purchase listing
and it didn't do exactly what I wanted.
I said, add a button... Or I didn't say
what a button should say, but it says book
now, and if I click book now I get a booking
confirmation. So the AI was like, okay, it
didn't... It was probably surprised by you
wanting to buy the listing since it's Airbnb.
So it still says book the listing, but it
shows a pretty model where I can click confirm
and pay. And then it's says booking confirmed.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:14:05):
I'll just say real quick,
I love that this is actually a really good
example of why being a good product manager
is important. A lot of wasted time happens when
you're not clear about the problem you're trying
to solve and why you're trying to solve it
and all that kind of stuff. So it's really
cool that this is a use case where you have
to be really good at explaining what it is
you want. And it's interesting, you don't have
to tell this AI-why. Humans want to understand,
"Why is this important." Mostly you need to be
very clear about what it is you're doing and I
love that's a really strong PM skill. Your
PM's really good at that. So we have to...
Anton Osika (00:14:39):
Hey. Explaining exactly
what you expect and what you're not
getting is even more important with
AI than with the humans. So I'm going into
hooking up more of the actual functionality,
but first I'll actually show you something.
What's the fastest way to change what
went wrong, it's created buttons that say book
now and I want them to say, "Buy now." And what
I could do is select this item and say change
it to buy now. But what we just realized is
that you can actually edit this, this is a fully
functioning product, but you can edit it visually
like you do in Squarespace and Wix and so on. So
I'll just change the text to buy now and then it
instantly changes. It actually changes deep down
in the code base, but it's very fast to do that.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:15:35):
So I think people listening to
this and seeing this, if you're not aware this
is the cutting edge of tools like this, no other
tool out there lets you generate code from an AI
engineer and then actually just change a small
element of it of every other tool that I'm aware
of. You have to ask the agent, do this for me,
and then you hope that it does the right thing. So
this is a huge deal which you just showed. Right?
Anton Osika (00:16:00):
Yeah. Now it says buy now.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:16:01):
Okay. Like that's amazing. Okay, and
that's something you just launched?
Anton Osika (00:16:04):
Yeah. Great. We just launched this
a few days ago, but I won't go into for building
the full functionality, but what it looks like
is that you connect an open source backend as a
service and that's called SuperBase. And I have
this instance to connect to that's completely
empty, just like one click to set that up and
now it's connected to the backend. It's just
automatically generating some code and explaining
what I can do next. And what I would do now is,
say, let's add login, let's say let's add login.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:16:41):
And where is it actually
hosted on the backend and everything in general?
Anton Osika (00:16:45):
So everything can be one click
deployed and then it's running.
It's hosted by a cloud vendor,
which is hosting, I think a huge chunk
of the internet, it's called Cloudflare,
and the backend is hosted by also good
cloud writer, which is called SuperBase.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:17:07):
Amazing. Okay, let's wrap up the demo, that was...
Unless there's anything else, was there anything
else really important that you wanted to show?
Anton Osika (00:17:14):
No I'll just explain what
I would do next. I would say, okay, let's
add login. Let's make the listings editable
by the users so users can upload listings and
then this is going to take a bit more time,
but with patience and good prompting skills,
you're going to get to a full working Airbnb.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:17:33):
That was a really good piece to add.
So basically this is getting to a place where it
actually is not so different from actual Airbnb.
People can log in, they can add their home, you
can add internal tools to add listings for your,
say, sales team, ops team. Basically it just will
allow you to build a marketplace that looks a lot
like Airbnb. Amazing. Okay, thank you for the
demo. I think for a lot of people they're like,
"Yeah, yeah, I've seen this kind of stuff,"
for most people, like, "Holy shit." It's
unreal what... It's almost like we're taking
for granted now. You can ask an app to build
you a whole website and that costs probably like
a few pennies. It took like five minutes versus
it would've been tens of thousands and weeks and
weeks and months to even build just a prototype.
Anton Osika (00:18:23):
I mean, these tools as we see here,
they're already very good, it looks really good
as well, but mainly I would say they're getting
better very, very fast. And I'd say one of the
bigger bottlenecks is now they're not integrated
into the current way that you have your existing
products and so on. But since they're getting
better so fast, I think the best thing for people
who are interested in this or interested in just
being a part of the future economies, get your
hands very dirty with these tools because being in
the top 10% in using them is going to absolutely
set you apart in the coming months and years.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:19:05):
So let me follow that thread. So say
you are magically able to sit next to everybody
that is using Lovable for the first time and
you could just whisper a tip in their ear to be
successful with Lovable, what would that tip be?
Anton Osika (00:19:20):
It takes a lot to master using tools like
Lovable and being very curious and patient and
we have something called chat mode where you can
just ask to understand like, "How does this work?
I'm not getting what I want here, am I missing
something? What should I do?" Is the best way to
be productive is also one of the best ways to just
learn about how software engineering works, which
is you don't have to write the code anymore, but
it is useful to understand how software engin- or
how building products works. So I think that's the
patience and curiosity is super useful. The second
part that we spoke about is that being, if I would
sit next to you, I would probably say like, "Hey,
you are not being super clear here." For example,
don't say it doesn't work. Just explain exactly
what you're expecting and which parts are working
and which parts are not working. And that's
something that a lot of people don't do naturally.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:20:25):
I love that when you have an engineer you're
working with that does a very expensive mistake to
miscommunicate something, to just forget about a
feature, to forget a better requirement, and
here it's... You do that and then 30 seconds
later you're like, "Oh okay, sorry, that was
wrong." And then you could just try again.
Anton Osika (00:20:41):
That's true. It might be more costly with humans.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:20:45):
Okay, and so the first step
is chat mode. So your advice is chat
with the... What do you call it? Do you
call it an agent? What's the term for
the thing that you were talking with?
Anton Osika (00:20:57):
Yeah, Lovable is an agent.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:20:59):
Just Lovable?
Anton Osika (00:20:59):
Yeah.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:21:00):
Okay. So you're talking about
Lovable by the way. How decide on
Lovable as the name? It's so sweet.
Anton Osika (00:21:06):
I think it's all about building
a great product. That's what I want more people
to be able to do and the best word for a great
product is that it's Lovable. A lot of jargon
that I like to use to emphasize what we should
be striving for is building a minimum Lovable
product and then building a Lovable product and
then building an absolutely Lovable product. So
I took that jargon with me in the company name.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:21:36):
That is great. Absolute Lovable product. ALP
is the new MVP. Okay, so we talked about this, the
scale you guys have hit at this point, I imagine
it's far beyond 10 million ARR. Do you share that
at this point or are you keeping that private?
Anton Osika (00:21:51):
We don't anchor on the numbers,
but I could probably do a two X
tweet about this quite soon. Yes.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:21:57):
Okay, so it's far beyond 10
million ARR at this point. It's one of
the fastest growing startups in history,
the fastest growing startup in Europe.
I want to zoom us back to the beginning.
What is the origin story of Lovable? How did
it all begin? What was the journey to today?
Anton Osika (00:22:14):
I think I was not impressed
by what people were doing with the large
language models [inaudible 00:22:21],
especially after I was using them way back. But
when ChatGPT came out, they were starting to get
really good at taking a human instruction and
spitting out code and then people in my team,
I was the CTO at a YC startup, they felt like,
"Oh, Anton, you're exaggerating. This is not
going to change anything in the coming years."
So I wanted to prove a point and I created an
open source tool called GPT Engineer where you
write something like create a snake game and
then it spits out a lot of code, a little of
different files and then opens the snake game.
And then I tweeted a video about that and
GPT Engineer is to date the most popular open
source tool to showcase the ability for large
language models to create applications and it's
at like 50 something thousand GitHub
stars and dozens of academic references.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:23:21):
And I know that I'll just
add that it GitHub shut you down because
they thought it was some kind of attack,
like how many stars you're getting,
how many people were using it,
Anton Osika (00:23:29):
Right. Yeah. So that came later.
That's with Lovable. So this is Lovable. Lovable,
earlier was always creating new projects on GitHub
when someone used Lovable and we asked them, "Is
it fine? How was the limits here?" They said,
"Oh, there are no limits." But once we started
creating 15,000 projects per day, so there were a
lot of usage. Then some engineer when was on call,
maybe they woke up in the night and they saw their
servers were taking too much load because of us.
So then they shut off down completely and we got
this email that said, "Oh, you broke some kind
of rules and we didn't know what was going on."
Lenny Rachitsky (00:24:13):
That's similar to a story I
heard when ChatGPT was originally being trained,
Microsoft servers blocked it because they
thought it was some crawler and it was
just actually the very first version ChatGPT
being trained on data. Anyway, keep going.
Anton Osika (00:24:29):
So I built this tool called GPT
Engineer and I was thinking about we're seeing
the biggest change humanity will ever see,
I think, where before you had the manual
labor being taken over by machines,
but now it's actually cognitive labor being
done better than humans by machines and what's
the best way to have some kind of positive impact
here? It's not to make engineers more productive,
which there's a lot of companies using
AI to make engineers more productive,
Microsoft did with co-pilot and so on. But it is
to enable those who have such a hard time finding
people who are good at creating software that's
been their absolute bottleneck and let them take
their ideas and their beliefs into reality. So
enabling more entrepreneurship and innovation
by building the AI software engineer for anyone.
And then I grabbed a previous colleague of mine
who has also been a founder, Fabian, and
I said we should build something like GPT
Engineer but it has to be for the people
who don't write code and that's the story.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:25:43):
Okay. And then that became
lovable? There's the shift from open source
into a product that anyone can use but also
pay for. Makes sense. Okay, so from that
point I saw a stat that you started making
a million dollars in ARR per week and
once you launched lovable, is that true?
Anton Osika (00:26:00):
Yeah, so launched, we actually called the first
version of the product like GPT Engineer app and
it was very different in some ways and we launched
that under a waitlist and said like, Oh yeah, we
have this waitlist and we got a lot of feedback
and iterated. Finally, when we thought the product
was really good we said okay, now we have a
Lovable product. And it was mainly on the AI that
we did a lot of improvements, once we launched
that, that was 21st of November, so that's almost
three months ago. We just hit 1 million ARR in a
week and then it kept growing at that pace. It
still growing at even faster than that pace.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:26:43):
Faster than 1 million ARR per week. Holy shit.
Anton Osika (00:26:48):
Yeah.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:26:48):
Okay, that sounds like product
market fit to me. You said that you did
a lot of work on the backend. I saw you
tweet about this that you guys figured
out some kind of unlock on scalability,
like a new scaling law that allowed you to
build something like this. What can you talk
about there that on the technical element allowed
you to build something new and the successful?
Anton Osika (00:27:08):
There are many scaling laws I would
say when you build AI systems and this one in
particular is about when you put in more work, the
product reliably gets better and better. And what
you've seen generally when you have AI building
something is that it can get stuck in some place.
It is super good in the beginning and then it gets
stuck. What we did was to painstakingly identify
places where it got stuck and there is different
approaches but address different ways how we do
it but address the places where it gets stuck,
tune the entire system quantitatively and having
a very fast feedback loop to improve it in the
areas where it got stuck. The most important
areas, it still does get stuck sometimes,
but that's the scaling law and we're still
early in that scaling law, I would say.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:28:04):
And so when you talk about
things getting stuck, it's like the AI agent
just saying, I don't know what to do from
this point or they introduce some kind of
bug. Is that an example of getting stuck?
Anton Osika (00:28:13):
Yeah. It introduces some
kind of bug and then it's not smart enough
to figure out how to get out of that bug.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:28:20):
I see. And this is a common
problem people have with tools like this is
they get to a certain point and then it's like,
"Well I don't know what to do. I'm not an
engineer, here's a bug it's running into or
the infrastructure's built the wrong way."
And so it sounds like one of the paths to
solving that is what you're describing is you
make the AI smarter to avoid more and more of
these places they get stuck. Another is people
just learning how to get AI unstuck. This is
something when we had Amjad on the podcast
from Replit, he said that this is the main
skill that he thinks people need to learn is
how to unstuck AI when it runs into a problem.
Just thoughts there, I don't know anything
along those lines come up as I say that.
Anton Osika (00:29:04):
This is something that is
a problem today and the frontier of where
this is a problem is very rapidly receding
back. So what we did was we identified the most
important areas, so specifically adding login,
creating data persistence, adding payment with
Stripe. Those are the things that we made sure
it doesn't get stuck on, for example.
And the places where it gets stuck today
is currently something that you can use being
very good at understanding and getting unstuck,
but in the future it won't be so important.
This experience just going to not get stuck.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:29:48):
And I know you're not talking
super in-depth about this because
this is one of your unfair advantages,
this kind of stuff you figured out. So I'm
not going to push too far. I know you want not
everyone's into exactly the same stuff. So I want
to zoom back to the pace of growth that you guys
have seen. One of the big stories, everyone's
always looking at you guys of like 15 people,
10 million ARR in two months. That's absurd. I
don't know if it's ever been done in history.
If so, it's maybe a couple other AI startups
recently. How have you been able to do this?
What have you done that has allowed you
to grow this fast with so few people?
Anton Osika (00:30:24):
I'd like to take credit of
having done everything end to end in the product,
but we are building on top of taking the oil here,
which we have discovered oil, which is are the
foundation models and then what we've done is
that we're obsessed about what's the right way to
present this to a user. What's the interface for
the human to get as much out of this as possible?
Packaging together, I showed you in the demo how
you can add authentication and making this work
seamlessly together as a whole. That's what we've
done. And then people love the product. That's
the driver of the growth. For getting awareness,
we've mainly been posting what we've shipped on
social media, that's how people know about us.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:31:17):
So building in public is how
people usually describe that. So I think
it's like you guys have the advantage of
the demos are just like, "Holy shit, you
can do that." And then you guys share the
numbers that you guys are growing at. So
it's innately interesting and shareable,
but I imagine most people have something
interesting to share. I guess is there anything
that you think you did that other companies maybe
haven't done that make the product so lovable?
Anton Osika (00:31:43):
I mean the team is everything
in building a great product, so I just give a big
shout-out to the team that has written the code. I
haven't written much of the code recently, I would
say. You want people who can ship really fast and
have good taste for what this simple, what's
the right abstractions and I think that's what
we've done differently and have this obsession
for us making it better and better and better.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:32:17):
This episode is brought to you by
the Fundrise Flagship Fund. Full disclosure,
real estate investing is boring. Prediction
markets are exciting. Meme coins are a
thrill ride. Even the stock market can
swing wildly on a headline. Hello Deepseek.
But with real estate and investing there's
no drama or adrenaline or excuses to refresh
your portfolio every few minutes. Just bland
and boring stuff like diversification and
dividends. So you won't be surprised to
learn that the Fundrise Flagship real
estate fund is a complete snoozefest.
The fund holds 1.1 billion dollars worth of
institutional caliber real estate managed by
team of pros focused on steadily growing your
net worth for decades to come, see? Boring.
(00:32:59):
That's the point.
You can start investing in minutes
and with as little as $10 by visiting
Fundrise.com slash Lenny. Carefully
consider the investment objectives,
risks, charges and expenses of the Fundrise
Flagship fund before investing. Find this
information and more in the fund's prospectus at
fundrise.com slash flagship. This is a paid ad.
(00:33:22):
Okay, I want to come back to
the team. I know you have a lot of thoughts
there in terms of writing code, how much do
you guys actually use AI to write the code that is
building Lovable? How does that work on your team?
Anton Osika (00:33:32):
We have set up lovable so
that we can change lovable with itself.
We have done that. There is a lot of
hyper-specific things in terms of running a
separate... We spin up a dedicated computer
for each user. It doesn't do everything.
Lovable doesn't do everything. So we use
the tools that are for developers, not for
the 99%, most of the time. And everyone
uses AI all the time in writing code. It's
also in great course for experimentations.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:34:10):
And are there tools like
Cursor and stuff like that? Like
any tools you can share right now?
Anton Osika (00:34:14):
Yeah. I think Cursor is
the one that almost everyone uses in the team.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:34:19):
Yeah. Okay, cool. I did a survey recently on
tools that my listeners and readers use in cursor.
17% of all people that read my newsletter use
Cursor already, which is absurd and you guys are
in there, too. Okay, so kind of along these lines,
there's obviously other competitors and companies
in this space, so everyone's always wondering,
you, Bolt, Replit, Cursor is a different kind of
thing. What's the simplest way to understand maybe
how Lovable might be different from say Bolt and
Replit, which I think are probably the closest.
Anton Osika (00:34:49):
The packaging for non-technical
people is what we aim for and I showed you
in the demo that you can edit the text,
you can change the colors and so on instantly
without having to go into the code editor and
without having to wait about 30 seconds for the AI
do the full change. So that's the big way that we
think about packaging it. And then for making sure
that this can be used as productively as possible
in a larger team. Something that's different
from I think all the other tools is that it is
synchronized with GitHub and that means that you
can use Cursor, or the people in your team that
want to be more low-level, they can use Cursor
and while the people who don't want to mess
and set up their local file system and commit
to GitHub and so on, they can use Lovable's.
(00:35:48):
Not getting stuck is
I think the most important thing for people.
And that's why we entered this space late,
we haven't done the same type of
marketing as many others and we still,
from the people that I talked to, ranked
as the one that works most reliably.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:36:06):
I love it. Okay. So this point
about how you can just use Lovable to
build a lot of it for you and then get
into Cursor to edit and tweak is a
really big point. And you're saying
other companies aren't as good at that.
I don't know if any other does that.
Anton Osika (00:36:06):
Yeah.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:36:23):
I don't think they let you do
that. Amazing. Okay. And then what's the
vision for Lovable? What's the end state
of this? Is this everybody can build anything
they want sort of thing? What's the simplest
way to understand where you're going in
the next, I don't know, five, 10 years.
Anton Osika (00:36:37):
I have to say. So we're building the
last piece of software and it is inherently very
hard to predict how the world looks like in five
years. These days it's very hard. But the last
piece of software, how I see that is that it's
almost instant to go from what you want to change
in the product or what product you want to build
to having it fully working end-to-end, integrated
with any of your existing systems or integrated
with the very powerful third-party providers.
Already today you can just ask, add and chat
with OpenAI and then you get the chat with OpenAI
in your product. But that's just working perfectly
is something that's coming in the coming
two years, I would say. And then after that
there is a lot of things in building a
product that is not just the engineering side,
right? And I think an AI can be very useful
in aggregating and understanding your users.
(00:37:42):
So, if you use the analytics tools,
you know that there is something quite common
which is to see how users have interacted with the
product. AIs can do that on an absolutely massive
scale and propose changes to a human to say, "Oh,
yeah, that sounds like a good change
to make it a bit more intuitive." And
it can also automatically run A-B
tests so that you can see the data,
all these improvements to the product. I
think that's on the horizon as well, quite.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:38:15):
What's interesting about this in one
way is people wonder just what jobs will be more
important, what skills will be less important? Let
me share a thought I have and then I want to get
your take and see where you go with this. It feels
like what is getting more valuable is being
good at figuring out what to build and then
knowing if the thing you had built is correct
and good and ready. So it's like discovery,
ideation, idea, part of the step of launching
a product and then it's like taste and craft.
Just like is this the thing? Is this going to
solve people's problems because the building
now is being done more and more and it's
interesting, it used to be the reverse
engineering was the hardest, most valuable
skill and now it's figuring out what to build.
(00:38:59):
You could sit there and you could
just tell it what to build and a lot of people
get to your screen I'm sure and they're like,
"I don't know what to build, I don't know what
people want." And it's like that's the thing
now. So just reactions to that and thoughts
on what's skills will matter more and less.
Anton Osika (00:39:13):
I mean if you're a founder
or you want to build something. Yeah, I totally
agree that figuring out what are pain points and
seeing there are often currently solutions, some
kind of solution to everything. How can you make
this 10X better somehow figuring that out is super
important when you have an existing product. Then
I think taste and tasting what is good is even
more of the important part. The engineer skill set
is still going to be important because that helps
you understand what are the constraints, so what
you can build and I just think a lot of software
engineers are probably a bit scared now like,
"Okay, am I out of a job? What's going to happen?"
But they should see themselves as the people who
translate the problems that are stated a human,
probably, to technical solutions, but they do
have to abstract themselves up a few steps, not
just looking at in their tech stack like oh I
can just do the front end changes. Engineers or
technical people are very good at understanding
what are the constraints technically and they
should see themselves as that translators.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:40:30):
Is it almost like you want
to learn the eng manager skill of overseeing
engineers versus the actual engineering skill or
you think it's still going to be really important
to learn how to code and be really good at that?
Anton Osika (00:40:44):
I mean doing a bit of
everything. Being a generalist is I think
much more important than it used to be. And
if I'm putting together a product team
today, I would re-obsess about getting
as many skill sets as possible for each person I
hire. They should know how architecting a system
works, preferably they should know the sign,
they should have product taste, they should
know how to talk to users. I think everyone
should know a bit of all of that, preferably.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:41:17):
Easier said than done. It's
hard to find people that know all these
things. So let's segue to hiring and how
you hire. How many people do you have at
this point? Is that something you share?
Anton Osika (00:41:27):
Yeah, now we're at 18.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:41:29):
18. Okay. Wow. I love that you...
It sounded like you're about to say, "Oh, we have
a hundred people now." No, 18. Okay, so you went
from 15 to 18. Okay, great. So what do you look
for when you're hiring people? The way I saw you
describe it on Twitter is you look for cracked
engineers, the best crack team in Europe,
things like that. I guess just specifically
what are you looking for when you're hiring?
Anton Osika (00:41:52):
I think the most important
thing is that people care a lot and they're not
just like, "Oh, I'm here for a job. I'm here for
being just a passenger on this journey," but
everyone should really care about the product,
the users and care a ton about the team,
how the team works together and that you're
always contributing to making the team work more
productively together and that care or preferably
obsession gets you a very long way and then
you do often want to have absolute superpower
in some dimension to be able to understand
and do as many possible things as possible,
have this generalist brain that quickly learns any
skill but be super, super good in one dimension.
And for us that's mostly cramming as much out
of AI, out of the large language models and
understanding the entire parameter space of what
you can change to make our product perform better.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:42:58):
So, how do you actually test for these
things? Some of these things describe, I think
everyone's looking for, they care about the user,
they want to collaborate well. Because you have
18 people building in a company that's growing
more than a million ARR every week. That's an
absurd scale and the people you have found are
clearly world-class and I think a lot of
people are going to want to hire the type
of people you're hiring. So when you're actually
interviewing, how do you suss out some of these
things like their AI cramming skills, their team
building collaboration, what do you actually do?
Anton Osika (00:43:32):
I ask people what they've
done before and these people that I'm describing,
they have often done something where they care
a lot about what they've done before and dig
into details about the technical things that
they did. And then we do the normal thing
of showing a very hard problem that is a bit
unorthodox that someone hasn't seen before
preferably and see how they think through
thinking research through that. Then something
that I think is more uncommon is that we do,
I pretty much always have people join the work
simulation for at least a day, often a full week.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:44:13):
Awesome. Okay, so work trial. That's
awesome. So basically they work with the team
for at least a day. You said sometimes a week,
and I love this point you made about
they care deeply about something
they previously worked on and you look
for just obsession with the thing that
they built last or something they worked on.
What percentage are engineers of these 18?
Anton Osika (00:44:39):
So 12 at least write code at least part-time.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:44:44):
12 out of 18. Okay, cool. When
we were setting up, you're like, "Oh, our
engineer's creating content now." I think
that's a cool example of how people do
a lot of different things. Also. Okay,
so I have your job posting that you shared
once of the actual job description. I'm
going to read a few lines from it. It's
very inspired by Shackleton, right?
Anton Osika (00:45:07):
Yeah.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:45:07):
Would you agree? Cool. I love it.
By the way, did you write this or did you have
AI write this job description where you create
an engineering job description? In fact,
let me read it to you. I don't even know,
you may not know what M you're referring to. I'll
read a few lines here. "Long hours, high pace,
candidates must thrive under a high urgency
under AGI timelines approaching, difficult
mission ahead, honor and recognition in case of
success, those seeking comfortable work need not
apply." And then there's a few other things,
"Collaboration with other exceptional minds,
purpose larger than any normal engineering role,
generous share in the venture success." Amazing.
Anton Osika (00:45:44):
Thank you.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:45:44):
Thoughts?
Anton Osika (00:45:45):
Yeah, so I did get some help with the formatting
of this, but then it was mostly me doing the
exact phrasing of the different sentences.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:45:56):
So good. And I love that to
some people it's going to be like, "Holy shit, I'm
not signing up for this." But to a lot of people,
the people you want is like, "Yes, this
is exactly what I want to be doing."
Anton Osika (00:46:07):
Great.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:46:07):
Amazing.
Anton Osika (00:46:08):
Yeah.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:46:08):
Okay, cool. So it feels like
one of the elements of hiring here is,
create a really good filter to be clear
about just how intense this is so that the
people that want that are the ones drawn to
you. Okay. And then you're also, you're in
Sweden, fastest growing startup in Europe
ever thoughts on building in Europe slash
Sweden versus the US slash San Francisco?
Anton Osika (00:46:34):
Yeah, so this ambition level that you're talking
about in the job ad is more uncommon in Sweden and
I think that is the biggest unlock that someone
like me, sees that this is the time in human
history when you have the most impact for a worked
hour and that's why we have to be super ambitious,
just up the ambition level and then we can maybe
retire and have AI take care of most things in
society and inspiring people to be this ambitious
in a place where the average ambition is lower but
the talent, the raw talent is much more available,
is a great recipe. I think that's a great recipe.
And that's, I think it's some kind of advantage
there. It is a bit of a double-edged
sword but it's some kind of advantage.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:47:34):
So what I'm hearing is there's
incredible people in Europe, they're just
not, they're harder to find and what I'm
hearing is the key is how do you suss them
out and get them to want to talk to you?
Anton Osika (00:47:49):
Most people in Europe,
they haven't thought that, "Oh, going
on an extremely ambitious mission is
what I want to do." So that's figuring
out who those are is a big part of it.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:48:01):
Awesome. Okay. I want to
talk about prioritization. I imagine all
these things that I just shared about just
how ambitious this mission is, how much
you're doing the last piece of software,
you must have a bazillion things that
people ask you to build that you want to
build. What's your approach to deciding
what to prioritize and actually build?
Anton Osika (00:48:21):
Just top line? I think identifying what is
the biggest bottleneck, what's the biggest problem
and iterating fast on saying, "Okay, this is the
biggest problem, let's really, really solve that
problem." And then picking in the next one and not
overthinking, not dreaming out the long roadmap,
that's my [inaudible 00:48:41]. There's a very,
very simple algorithm. Understanding what is the,
mostly the biggest problem is not always a simple
problem I think. Yeah, so we spend time as one
should on talking to users, reading up on what
people are writing. We have the feature board for
where people do a lot of requests, as you say. And
then when we pick one of the problems, we are
quite engineering-led. For a product like ours,
it's hard to be have product managers that are not
engineers say, oh, this is what we should do now
because the right solution to the problem might
be entangled in things that are technical details.
(00:49:32):
They might be
entangled in technical details of like,
"Okay, yes, this is the biggest problem,
but we should have this larger technical
initiative that's going to solve all of
these problems." So it's quite engineering-led
compared to many other product companies.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:49:48):
As it should. I'd be worried
if you guys had a product manager at this point,
that wouldn't make no sense right now. I imagine
the answer is it's chaos and there's no actual
defined process, but just what does it look like
generally? What's kind of the cadence you guys
operate on? How do you take an idea to build it,
spec it, launch it? Just what does
that look like if you have something?
Anton Osika (00:50:10):
If you look back three months, we mainly said,
"Okay, let's do this weekly planning." We do
have a big jam board where we have all the
main problems and then we have kind of ranked
them which else do we focus or when we focus
on next or this week? And then we have a demo
where we say, "Okay, these are things we ship
this week." So to get everyone on the same
page, we do have a bit more of a roadmap now,
where we say we are going to make so sure you can
support custom domains. Next, they're going to add
collaboration after that. And the biggest problem
now or the biggest initiative now that solves
the biggest problem is making the system more
agentic and that has a bit of a longer roadmap,
but we still do the cadence of weekly planning.
These are the things we're focusing on. This week,
it's mostly... There's a good word for
this that I would want your help with,
but polish, we were fixing the bugs and polish
this week and that was the planning on Monday.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:51:21):
That was actually this week was polish,
polish week. I love that. How far is
this roadmap that you are now having?
Anton Osika (00:51:28):
I mean it's clear over the coming month,
but it stretches out three months, but in one
month it's probably going to look a bit different.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:51:39):
Okay. And then what are the
tools you use just for folks that want
to understand the latest tools? So you
said FigJam, what else is in that stack of tools?
Anton Osika (00:51:46):
I mean we do so many things in our company
in Linear because it's just amazing product. So we
do talent application tracking in Linear and after
going through and this thing, lot of the other
custom-made tools for that Linear and then FigJam.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:52:06):
So simple. How soon until one
of your engineers is an agent engineer,
an AI Engineer, do you have a sense?
Anton Osika (00:52:15):
I love to dig into what does
that question actually mean? I think we've been
talking about, Oh, AI that would require something
playing chess, that's AI. If a computer can play
chess, that's AI and now that's like, Oh no,
that's a chess program and which always shifting
this forward and forward. I think anything that a
human doesn't do is just a smart computer system,
right? When is an software engineer and agent,
I think it's always going to be just we're
building in... Lovable is just an interface
that humans interact with to create the software
that they want and then how we solve that, we said
going to be an agent under some definition. Yeah,
sure. I think so, but that's less important to me.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:53:15):
Okay, I like that. Let me ask this,
you guys are moving super fast,
scaling like crazy. You described
a little bit about your process,
weekly planning, FigJam board of
ideas and now there's a roadmap that you're
kind of thinking out in the future. Is there
anything else that you found helps you move
this fast that gives you a lot of leverage
over the small team you have to ship quickly and
move fast that you haven't already mentioned?
Anton Osika (00:53:40):
We work from the office most
of the time. I think it's pretty nice. Then you
can say like, "Hey, I think we're thinking wrong
about this thing," or, "Shouldn't we actually do
this other thing?" And especially I think lunch,
eating lunch together is a pretty productive hour
where you're cross pollinating. I mean people are
constantly thinking subconsciously as well about
how to solve these different problems and which
the most important ones are. And then being in
office has this focus or most of the time usually
focus, but you also have this high bandwidth where
everyone has to be down structured communication.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:54:18):
I love that. The answer to
the CEO of a company that's one of the
most advanced AI tools in the world is
one of your answers to how to move fast is
lunch together. I love that. That's so human
and so it makes all the sense in the world,
but I love that that's still a part of this.
Anton Osika (00:54:34):
Yeah.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:54:36):
Okay. You talked about this kind of
on the same thread you talked about if you were
to start a team, like a new product team today,
say you were head of product somewhere or head
of RPM, VP of product somewhere building a new
product team, scaling a product team, what
would you do going forward that's different
from what people have done in the past in terms
of who you're hiring, how you're structuring them,
that kind of thing? Just what do you think
people should be thinking as they build product
teams going forward? Knowing tools like Lovable
exist and all the other stuff that's going on.
Anton Osika (00:55:13):
I mean everyone should be excited
about using AI. I think that's a pretty big ones.
And then the team working really well together is,
like the lunch, you have to sit down and
solve problems together. The bottleneck
for most products these days is not going to be
as much on engineering, but having good taste,
good intuition about your users. And that,
engineers and everyone preferably in the team
should have that willingness at least to want to
go through that motion and listen to the users and
truly understand what they care about.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:55:59):
Well it's kind of like the
background of most of the engineers and people
you've hired. Is there anything in common? Are
they just super impressive humans generally,
like champions of programming contests,
stuff like that? I don't know. What are some
attributes of the folks you've hired so far?
Anton Osika (00:56:19):
I think raw cognitive capability is the strongest,
the strongest correlate of being at Lovable.
But there is this startup mindset that I think
is also very strong. Being much more interested in
moving very fast and iterating fast, then having
a lot of structure, a lot of process and thinking
about the business as a whole. More than thinking
about my specific profession, my specific craft
that I'm seeing myself wanting to dig into on me.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:56:58):
Amazing. Okay. So smart,
very smart entrepreneurial, acts like an owner,
isn't just like, this isn't just a job. But they
feel like they actually have agency. Okay, this
is great. There's something you said kind of along
these lines that I think is important that one
of the things that gets you excited about what
you're building is giving people super powers
and especially people that don't add a code,
basically 99% of people. Is there anything along
those lines that you think is important to share?
Anton Osika (00:57:27):
It's very clear to most people who have
been engineers or been founders, that there's so
many that have failed in their endeavors because
they didn't have someone that know how to solve
the technical parts. And now that we're close
to having people know that this exists and they
solve everything, it's going to be an Cambrian
explosion of entrepreneurship and better software
product. We're not going to settle for all the
annoying bad technology that we use today.
And everyone who has an idea is going to say,
"Okay, I'm going to build this thing and show you
that this is the best version of the product or
what our company should be doing," instead of
having long meetings or writing up documents.
So it's going to be empowering across a lot of
different professions and places in the world.
Lenny Rachitsky (00:58:33):
What's next for Lovable? What's
the next few things they might
launch as this episode comes out?
Anton Osika (00:58:38):
As I mentioned this agentic behavior,
and when I say agentic, what it means is that
you give more freedom to the system to decide
what happens next. It might want to write
a test, run those tests and say like, "Oh,
the test failed, let's fix those." So that's
one of the big unlocks for getting further
faster. And then there's some more obvious
things that you want to do to go all the way
to easily go all the way to making money with
Lovable. And that's like how do you set up so
that it's hosted on your specific domain? How
do you collaborate there seamlessly with your
team and making that is here so that those are
just obvious things and something we're thinking
about is to help founders succeed after they
built their first version. And how do they get
more users? How do they get feedback? How do they
get the word out if they build something useful?
Lenny Rachitsky (00:59:42):
I was just going to say that
and that's exactly where my mind went is
everyone's going to be building all these
things. No one's ever going to get any traction
with these tools. No one knows how to find users,
get anyone to basically go to market. And growth
is a whole different skill. So that is so cool
that you're thinking about that. How do we run
some paid ads for you? How do we think about
SEO? How do we think about word of mouth,
reality referrals? That is very cool. Okay.
Anton Osika (01:00:06):
Yeah, we already have playbooks
that we help the people building with how do you
do those things that you can find up on our blog?
Lenny Rachitsky (01:00:15):
Interestingly, this makes me want to buy some
meta stock because all these apps that everyone's
building, they're going to be running paid ads
on Facebook and Google. Oh my god, what a good
business those other guys get. I want to come back
to, you said that you can work on your existing
code base. This is actually a big question for a
lot of people. They see all these tools, they're
all amazing for prototypes and concepting. You
talked about how you can actually do this
within your existing code base, use Lovable.
Anton Osika (01:00:41):
Let me correct you there.
You cannot use it on any existing code base.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:00:46):
Got it.
Anton Osika (01:00:47):
We kind of have a research
preview of importing your code base, but
what you can do is if you start in Lovable,
then you can have engineers editing it in
whatever tool they want to use for editing it.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:00:59):
Okay, cool. That's great clarification.
So I guess just for people, because most
listeners here are not building something
brand new, they're working within an existing
product. So you're saying that that is coming,
you can use Lovable in the future in some
form with your existing app and product?
Anton Osika (01:01:15):
Correct.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:01:16):
Wow, that's huge. Okay. Because
basically most people, so that's going
to be a big deal. Okay. Final question.
We have the segment on this podcast called Failure
Corner, where most people come to this podcast,
they show all these stories of success and
everything's going great, and here's all
the things always winning. You guys, this
is a good example, just up into the right,
the fastest growing product ever. What's
an example when something totally failed
in the course of your career and
what did you learn from that?
Anton Osika (01:01:49):
I am a bit hard-pressed
to find something that totally failed, but I
think there's a bit of a product lesson where
I was the first employee at an AI startup
here in Stockholm called Summer Labs,
and the premise was just, okay, so humans
learn in different ways. If you personalize,
then you get two standard deviations more
effective learning. So there are a lot of
products like education software that helps
you learn that is not personalized. And we
were building an API to personalize learning
and the AI and so on, it was pretty good.
(01:02:34):
But the thing
that we were doing in the end was to say like,
Okay, here's this product. Someone has to build
a product or some way to learn or be it like
English thing Duolingo, and then the people
that have that product have to use this advanced
AI API to start making it personalized. And it
is very hard retrofitting like, oh, you have
to switch out the engine and put in this AI.
And the big learning here is that it didn't work
very well for the company. I mean, the company
wasn't super successful in this. The big learning
is that you have to start with how is this product
working end-to-end and then add AI or think where
should we add AI? So that was a big learning for
me that you really want to see what does the big
picture of the user, what's the big picture of
how do you think the user experience should be?
And then add something with AI to solve specific
problems. And now Summer Labs is doing great,
but it's not on top of that product specifically.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:03:49):
I think it's a lot of people hear
this and they're like, of course, but I think
it's so hard to actually remember this point
when you have some cool tech and you're like,
"Holy shit, everyone needs to try this. They're
going to love it." And then you don't realize no
one actually cares if it's not solving a problem
for them. There's a lot of novelty products
that everyone want to use for a little bit and
then forget instant, I don't actually need this
often. And so what this makes me think about is,
there's all these product lessons for what is
likely to help your product be successful. And
an app like a tool like Lovable can help you do
this because if someone is building something,
you can guide them, Okay, what's the
problem you're solving for somebody?
How many people have this problem?
How much does this matter to them?
Anton Osika (01:04:38):
Maybe we should add
the Lenny mode. It activates in
Lovable, it activates this product
coach. That would be infinite questions, like,
"No, no, wait, hold on, why are you doing this?"
Lenny Rachitsky (01:04:50):
Absolutely. Let's take a
step back. Everyone's going to be like,
"[inaudible 01:04:55], get out of my way."
Anton Osika (01:04:57):
[inaudible 01:04:57].
Lenny Rachitsky (01:04:56):
Yeah, exactly. What's your experiment
plan? I think there's actually a big opportunity
there to save people. There's a play around with
this thing and then there's like, okay, but
really is this anything people actually want?
Anton Osika (01:05:09):
I love it. Can we call it
Lenny mode? Is that fine with you?
Lenny Rachitsky (01:05:12):
100%.
Anton Osika (01:05:13):
Awesome.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:05:14):
Let's do it. I'll license you no cost.
Anton Osika (01:05:16):
Sure.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:05:17):
Okay. Okay. We made a deal
here. Let's do it. Okay, Anton, is there
anything else that you wanted to share?
Anything you want to leave listeners
with before I let you go and go to sleep?
Anton Osika (01:05:28):
I think, again, the world is changing
quickly and it's very fun. You should see that's
like have fun in all of this change, and the best
thing you can do for your current profession or if
you want to have a new job is to be in the top 1%
in knowing how to use AI tools. So go out there,
use Loveable, use other AI tools, and become...
Make sure to understand or try to understand as
much as possible in how to use them productively.
That's something I tell all my friends generally,
and I love the audience to know as well.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:06:06):
Okay. Well, I got to try to make this even more
specific for people. How do you know if you're
in the top 1%? What's a heuristic almost slash
how do you get there? Is it just use it a hundred
times a day? What else? What can you recommend?
Anton Osika (01:06:19):
Yeah. I think if you spend a
full week on trying to reach an outcome, the
best way to learn is I want to do this thing
and then I want to use AI to do that
thing. And you've spent a full week,
you are in the top 1% in the global population.
And if you surround yourself with friends who have
this obsession or they also care a lot about
this, then you'd be quickly in the top 0.1%.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:06:47):
So what I'm hearing is find a
problem that can be solved, find a problem,
a pain point for yourself or someone,
and then end-to-end fully solve
that problem. Spend a week getting
from idea to a thing that somebody's
actually using and you're in the top 1%.
Anton Osika (01:07:03):
Yeah. I think... At the top,
yeah, the top 1% by just spending a full week and
asking AI if you don't understand.
So making sure that you understand.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:07:15):
Yeah, that's the thing people
forget. You just ask. Would you ask
the chat feature of Lovable in this
case or would you go to Cloud
or ChatGPT to ask for advice?
Anton Osika (01:07:24):
I mean, my recommendation
here, if you're in product is to use Lovable to
build software and learn that AI tool and then
you should use ChatMode and ChatMode, I have
to add, is something you activate in your user
profile. It's not launched in the main product,
so it's in labs, but if you add that flag,
then you can use ChatMode. If you want to
learn some other AI tool, then you should
ask that tool or ask Cloud, ChatGPT
about how that topic, that domain works.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:08:02):
Okay, amazing. Where can people
find you? Where can they find Lovable
and how can listeners be useful to you?
Anton Osika (01:08:09):
Lovable posts updates,
and memes on Lovable underscore dev on
Twitter, we post things on LinkedIn as well,
and there are a lot of things coming out
and changing in how we build software,
so you can follow Lovable underscore dev and you
can follow me at AntonOsika at Twitter. I'd love
more feedback on where people see this is a huge
change for them. There are a lot of people posting
about that on Twitter, but we have a Discord
where you can share like, "Oh, this is how I
use Lovable. It was super useful to me." And
feedback.lovable.dev can ask for new features.
There's a lot of people asking and uploading what
features you want next. And that's super useful.
That's the most important thing for us.
We just want to solve people's problems.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:09:04):
Amazing. Anton, you're doing incredible
work. What a journey. I'm excited to have you back
someday when we see more chapters of this journey.
Anton Osika (01:09:12):
I have a lot more to learn.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:09:13):
As do we all. That's why people
listen to this podcast. Anton,
thank you so much for being here.
Anton Osika (01:09:18):
Thank you so much, Lenny.
Lenny Rachitsky (01:09:19):
Bye everyone. Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lenny'sPodcast.com. See you in the next episode.