The worst thing that you do as a leader is you hesitate on the next decision.
The thing that causes you to hesitate is both decisions are horrible.
Probably one of my bigger ones on that was we went public with $2 million in trailing 12 months revenue at 18 months old.
That's obviously a bad idea.
But the truth of it was the alternative was going bankrupt.
And that's a worse idea.
>> It's very difficult and painful to be a CEO, to be a founder.
In spite of that, so many people want to start companies.
The psychological muscle you have to build to be a great leader is to be able to click in the abyss and go,
"Okay, that way is slightly better.
We're going to go that way."
If everybody agrees with the decision, then you didn't add any value cuz they would have done that without you.
So, the only value you ever add is when you make a decision that most people don't like.
You are famous for writing one of the most popular pieces of literature for product managers.
What I was trying to get out in good product manager, bad product manager was the job is fundamentally a leadership job and it's a tricky
leadership job because nobody is actually reporting to you.
>> There's always this kind of sense that the PM is not the mini CEO.
How dare you call yourself that?
I actually think that's exactly what the PM is.
>> It doesn't matter if you write a good spec or you have a good interview or you do this or do that.
What matters is that the product wins.
Today my guest is Ben Horowitz.
Ben is the Z in A16Z, the world's largest venture capital firm with over $46 billion in committed capital.
They're investors in OpenAI, Cursor Andreal, Data Bricks, Figma, basically every generational tech company.
He's also the author of two New York Times bestselling books.
The hard thing about hard things and what you do is who you are.
Ben is endlessly fascinating.
He started a rap group when he was younger.
He started his career as a product manager and wrote the now famous good product manager bad product manager piece.
In our wide-ranging conversation, we cover a ton of ground and Ben shares stories and insights that he's never shared anywhere else.
A huge thank you to Shaka Sangor, Ali Goatsy, and Adam Newman for suggesting topics for this conversation.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It helps tremendously.
And if you become an annual subscriber of my newsletter, you get a year free of 15 incredible products,
including a year free of Lovable, Replet, Bolt, NAN, Linear, Superhum, Dscript, Whisper Flow,
Gamma, Perplexity, Warp, Granola, Magic Patterns, Raycast, Chapd, and Mobin.
Check it out at lennisnewsletter.com and click product pass.
With that, I bring you Ben Horowitz.
Today's episode is brought to you by DX, the developer intelligence platform designed by leading researchers.
To thrive in the AI era, organizations need to adapt quickly.
But many organization leaders struggle to answer pressing questions like which tools are working?
How are they being used?
What's actually driving value?
DX provides the data and insights that leaders need to navigate this shift.
With DX, companies like Dropbox, Booking.com, Adion, and Intercom get a deep understanding of how AI is providing value to their developers and what impact AI is having
on engineering productivity.
To learn more, visit DX's website at getdx.com/lenny.
That's getdx.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Basecamp.
Basecamp is the famously straightforward project management system from 37 Signals.
Most project management systems are either inadequate or frustratingly complex.
But Base Camp is refreshingly clear.
It's simple to get started, easy to organize, and Base Camp's visual tools help you see exactly what everyone is working on and how all work is progressing.
Keep all your files and conversations about projects directly connected to the projects themselves so that you always know where stuff is and you're not constantly switching contexts.
Running a business is hard.
Managing your projects should be easy.
I've been a longtime fan of what 37 Signals has been up to and I'm really excited to be sharing this with you.
Sign up for a free account at basscamp.com/lenny.
Get somewhere with Basecamp.
Ben, thank you so much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
>> All right.
Thank you, Lenny.
Excited to be here.
I'm even more excited to have you here.
I want to start with a question that a close friend of yours suggested I ask you, uh,
Shaka Singh So Shock uh he's like we could do an hour just on how interesting this guy is and the things he's done.
>> Three hours on Joe Rogan that he's very >> So we're not gonna do that just to give a glimpse.
He uh he was in prison for 19 years.
He was in solitary for seven years.
He uh led a huge prison gang.
You wrote you wrote uh about him in your book uh as a great exemplar of great culture in the prison gang that he ran.
Uh so interesting.
But uh something that he learned from you that he told me I need to ask you about is about success.
and how to be successful and how it's not what people think.
And he said that you learned this lesson from a pilot.
What is that story?
What is that lesson?
>> Well, it's kind of I mean I would say it's a long life lesson, but that the pilot story is um I actually you know I ask people like silly questions
sometimes when I meet them.
And so I, you know, I met this gentleman who was a pilot and, you know, it was right around the time uh JFK Jr.
crashed his airplane uh and and ultimately died.
And I asked him, I was like, you know, like what happened?
Because there's always, you know, the story in the press, and I know this from them writing about me or anything,
is it's always what's the best narrative, not what's true.
So you can never kind of actually find out what happened.
you just find like the best story version of what happened.
Uh and you know the story in the press was all about oh he wasn't trained on instruments instrumentation was flying that night and I wanted to know was that right?
And the pilot said well he said really it's like all plane crashes are a series of bad decisions and none of the decisions by themselves is that bad but
when you add them up it's bad.
So the first decision was he needed to get wherever he was going and that was the priority and in flying
that can't ever be the priority.
Uh you know because there are conditions there are things that happen.
And then the second one was well like his timing of when the sun would go down was wrong.
So he thought he'd be flying in sunlight and he wasn't.
And then, you know, once he got up there, it was, you know, when the plane was, uh, you know,
going down, kind of making it go up, uh, was a bad decision because he was upside down and like,
you know, so so then I can't remember all the things, but this guy had like 17 steps,
you know, 17 bad decisions in a row.
And the big thing for me that that I felt was really true is it's you know one decision leads to
another.
Uh and so you know if you can break you know if psychologically you can take the sunk cost um then that
gets you out of a lot of bad paths and then you know a little good decision may be difficult but you have to believe it's going to lead to the next one.
And you know a lot of success is about that.
You know it's a it's a small thing a small thing that's hard to do that doesn't seem to have a high impact.
Um but it leads to the next small hard to do thing and then eventually uh you get an outcome.
So so that was kind of the concept.
But >> so the lesson there is just success is just a bunch of little things.
It's not this like well I got here and a big thing.
somebody were to write a story about me, they would be like, "Then Ben did this really smart thing and blah blah blah."
You know, happy ending.
But, you know, it really wasn't like that.
I don't think it's like that for you or anybody.
Um, and it, you know, I spent a lot of time with Shaka on, you know, how because because it's always your own psychology that,
you know, gets you.
And one of the kind of most insightful things he said to me is, you know, because he was in most people who are in solitary for seven years,
that's it.
you're insane, like you're never coming back from that.
It's just an impossible thing.
But if you like study his story, he actually kind of really was massively self-improved coming out of solitary,
which is, you know, like, and he wouldn't recommend that for anybody, just to be clear,
it wasn't solitary, but what it was, you know, is he changed in solitary, he was able to change a big
set of beliefs that he had about himself that kind of got him out of that.
And the thing that his conclusion from it, which I thought was really interesting, he's like,
"Look, I was in prison for 19 years.
I was in solitary for seven.
I come out.
I can't rent an apartment.
I can't vote.
You know, I can't get a gun.
I can't do like like no rights."
None of that was anything compared to what I did to myself.
And I think that's very true for CEOs in general and people in general is that like all the things that you perceive that are happening to you that are bad,
you know, be it like the systems against you or somebody undercut you or racism or sexism or this or that or the other is very small compared to like it means a lot if you believe it.
You know, if you believe what people say about you, if you believe what they did to you,
um then then that destroys you.
But if you if you go like that's not me.
Um you can overcome almost anything.
And that's you know he's got a new book out on that anyway that that I think is very good because that's the you know I say more than anything that's the key to success.
>> Something you it's like if you look at all the writing you've done it's essentially about the struggle and pain and suffering of being a C.
You're hard.
You know your first book to hard thing about hard things.
>> There's a lot of talk these days about just how important struggle is and how valuable it is to go through struggle.
Jensen's big on this, you know, he talks a lot about just you have to go through pain and suffering to be a great leader.
>> Yeah.
You don't really have a choice, you know, like that.
That's true.
>> There's something that I saw you share that I love, which is running towards fear versus running away from fear.
Something that you tell all your leaders to to work on.
Uh easy to hear, uh hard to do.
We don't like doing things that are scary.
Running towards things that are scary.
Why is this so important?
Why is this something people need to learn to do?
Well, so the biggest mistake that you made there the the worst thing that you do as a leader like there's things in your control and there's things like
out of your control and hesitation is uh you know that that's generally the most destructive and and I can go through all
the ways that it's destructive but it's extremely bad and the thing that causes you to hesitate is
you know both decisions are horrible right like There is like it it's not business school where like you're going through a case study and if you had done that then the company would have gone
this way but if you had done that it's a great success like that's not actually you know what happens to you as CEO what happens to you as CEO it's like okay if
we rearch you know like this product is the architecture is not actually get us to where we need to go.
I kind of know that, but if we rearchitect it like we're gonna probably miss all the features,
miss the quarter, have trouble raising money, you know, etc., etc.
So, like that's really bad.
And then not rearchitecting is really bad.
And so, I'm just going to try and avoid this subject because I don't I don't even want to deal with either of those.
And that's that that's the worst thing because if rearch, you know, if action is the better choice,
then, you know, that's good.
And then if you don't make an explicit decision, then the whole company's going to get nervous because they know that the architecture is whack and you got to fix it.
And you know, like probably one of my bigger ones on that was, you know, we went public with $2 million in trailing 12 months revenue at 18
months old, right?
Like in the p like that's obviously a bad idea.
I mean, like there's no question that wasn't a bad idea.
But the truth of it was the alternative uh because of where the private markets were was going bankrupt and that's a worse idea.
And if you look at that time, you know, March of 2001 when we went public, you just look at the number of CEOs that hesitated on that and didn't do it and went bankrupt.
It's a lot.
And so that's, you know, that getting good at making a decision that everybody's going to go,
"Wow, that was insane."
Ben, like you went like the Wall Street Journal wrote a whole like long story about how stupid I was.
And then Business Week wrote a story called the IPO from Hell.
That was the name of like our idea, the IGO from hell, which like was accurate in a sense,
but so like that's really bad, but it it wasn't as bad.
And this is why it's so scary to make that decision because you know that's going to happen.
I knew those stories would get written.
Like there was no question.
Uh and uh yeah, and that's that's the kind of muscle.
So, like if you think about like the psychological muscle you have to build to be a great leader is to be able to like look in the abyss and go,
"Okay, we're going that that way is slightly better.
We're going to go that way."
Uh, and it's very hard to do.
I would say it's it's a thing people struggle with.
And it began something should I fire the head of sales?
So, I don't want to have that conversation.
Like, and then I'll have to replace him.
And then like there's going to be a bad PR story and then and and and and and you can kind of quickly calculate all the bad stuff that's going to happen if you do it.
But if you don't do it, uh that's probably going to be much worse and you know, kind of that's why you have to run towards a pain and darkness.
>> What is the advice you share with founders?
Because as you said, it's very hard to do this.
Just like how what helps them actually get better at this?
Is it just Ben being by their side telling them this is how it is?
Is there anything else you could >> No, no, no, no, no, no.
Like I would say this is one where you know I can't really coach you to be good at this.
Like I can point it out and like so that you recognize that you were slow or whatever.
But it's kind of like I always liken it when I talk to them.
It's like football.
Like, you know, you have a really fast great athlete, but if they don't trust their eyes,
if they don't run to the ball when they see it, if they think, "Oh, maybe that was a fake," then they're that step slower and then they're not um they'll never be as good.
And CEOs are like that.
You know, if you don't trust what you see and you don't run at it, then like you're just not going to be good.
And it it's hard to get CEOs not to hesitate.
But look one thing the thing that does help is you know they look at it and I look at it and you know and I kind of confirm no that that is as it
appears.
Uh and you know sometimes they're afraid of the conversation.
So that one I can help with.
So you know a CEO might be afraid like they want to do something but they they don't know how to say it.
They don't know how to have the conversation with the employee.
So I can walk them through that.
Um, you know, I I had an instance where the CEO said,"Hey, you know, like um I need your help,
Ben.
My CTO, he's an asshole."
And I was like, "Okay, you know, like great."
I said, "But you're not going to fire him because I know he's a good CTO or are you asking me should you fire him?"
He said, "No, no, I don't want to fire him."
And I was like, "So, you're asking me what to do because you don't know how to have that conversation with him about being an without him quitting?
Like, that's what you're saying."
And he goes, "Yeah, that's the problem."
And so I go, "Well, like why is he an asshole?"
And he says, "Well, he's an because you know, the other day he made like a very junior young woman in our finance organization cry."
And I was like, "Oh, that that's kind of Yeah, I got you."
I said, "Look, this is what I would say to him.
I'd say I just sit him down and I would say look you're a really good director of engineering um because you do a great job of managing the team get the products out all that but like you're
not really a CTO because to be a CTO you have to be effective with other parts of the organization um you can't just be like effective only with engineering and
so you know and making like somebody cry like she's never going to do anything you want you you lost all effectiveness with all of finance by doing
And so if you want to get good at that, I'll help you.
I'll work with you on it.
But if you don't, I'm going to have to hire a CTO at some point because like obviously I need that.
And you know, and and then he's like, "Oh, okay.
I can have that conversation."
You know, I can't have the conversation that, hey, you're an because I don't want them to quit.
But I can have the conversation that's more specific.
And a lot of kind of getting people not to hesitate is just getting them over that.
And so so often like and I would say, you know, early in a CEO's career, a lot of it is just not knowing how to have the conversation.
>> There's also I imagine an element of I just want to be liked.
I don't want people to hate me.
You have this great line that you want to be liked and respected in the long run, not the short run.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
That's that's tricky because it's so by the way, I have to deal with this in the in the firm too and you know like you know people want to be entrepreneur friendly.
I'm like no it's not friendly.
you know, respectful, but you got to be able to tell them the truth in a way that you probably don't tell most of your friends the truth because your friend,
you know, like look, anthropologically we want people to like us.
Like it's just so that, you know, they don't throw us to the lion or whatever like that.
That's just kind of a thing.
So you say tell people what they want to hear.
But in dealing, you know, in a in a company level and a, you know, in a context of you're on the board of somebody's company,
you got to be able to tell them what they don't want to hear.
That's the most important thing you're going to say.
And yes, they're not going to like it when you say it.
There's no question.
But over time, like it could save the company.
And uh and m you know all the most important things I said are things that I've said to CEOs that they did not want to hear you know and look that's what
leadership is about.
It's making if everybody agrees with the decision then you didn't add any value because they would have done that without you.
So the only value you ever add is when you make a decision that most people don't like.
Um and that's where leadership comes in because you know that's where it's got to get to.
Uh, and you know that's that's a thing that takes practice.
I think you know when Jensen talks about like you got to get to near death to get yourself to do that.
That's true.
You know it's hard it's hard to build that if everything's going great and and I would say like the CEOs who kind of had an easy run of it for their like let's
say they just launch a product that's an instant hit.
It's very hard for them to develop that muscle compared to the ones that built a company like Jensen where he like you know gutted it out for multiple decades before they had big success.
>> Clearly it's very uh difficult and painful to be a CEO to be a founder.
Uh in spite of that so many people want to start companies so many people like dream of having their own company.
What do you who who is not right to start a company?
like what advice do you share with folks that are thinking about starting a company that may not understand just what they're about to get into?
>> Yeah.
So, it it's funny.
So, there's a couple things.
You know, John Reed, who was the CEO of Cityroup when I when I started as CEO, said to me something I never forget.
He said, "Ben, the only reason to start a company is because you have an irrational desire to do so because it's not worth the money."
And you know, I was like, "Wow, he doesn't he didn't even quantify how much money."
And this guy's running cities, so he's a very numbers banking guy.
And he didn't quantify it.
And um I remember when we sold Loudcloud for $1.6 billion, I remember thinking, "Wow,
that wasn't worth the money."
So So I think if you're doing it for the money, h that's a very bad reason and it'll be extremely difficult to get to an outcome.
you really have to have an irrational desire to do something larger than yourself to kind of improve the world in some way.
Um that you know somehow like that is your purpose and if if you don't feel that uh then you'll never get through it.
It just is too many too many bad things happen along the way.
So then how do you think of founders that are kind of looking around for ideas that kind of brainstorm that look for you know market opportunities versus come from I have this mission I got to do this thing in the world.
>> If you have a you know and my uh business partner Mark always talks about that.
So like if you have a product that forces you to build a company um that is a great case of it right like okay you build something and the world wants it and you need a company to deliver it
that's going to you know you already have the right product and so that's very helpful I think there are cases of people I think Hulip Packard was kind of built that way that they're like okay
like we got to build technology you know was that abstract we got to build some technology for the world you and then they started with well like what do you need you know to they called it the next
bench thing what does the uh engineer sitting next to me need the next engineer on the bench was so the kind of how they define the first set of problems so it can work the other way but like I think the thing that is in
common is like it's just a very abstract idea that like you have to build something that's going to be important that like is going
to you know people are going to like working there people are going to benefit benefit from the products.
Like you have to have some like weird concept other than oh this is going to be successful and I'm make a lot of money.
I think that's I think you're way better off taking sucks offer at Meta and just doing that like that's a way better deal.
Along these lines, something else Shaka suggested to ask you about.
Apparently, there's a story where the CEO of data bricks asked you for $200,000 in the early days and you said no.
And it's not because you didn't want to, you know, invest in and it was more about helping him think bigger.
Uh how what happened there?
>> Uh so there were six six of them.
there are six PhD students and uh well and Yan Stoker who is their professor um and Yan
is a super genius uh but you know they you know when I when I met with them they were like you know we need to raise $200,000
uh and I knew you like I knew at the time that uh what they had was this thing called Spark and they had you know the competitor
uh was something called Hadoop and Hadoop you know had very wellunded companies already running towards it and Spark was open source so like the clock
was ticking uh and you know and I think they didn't quite know what they had but I and then there's also a thing always although I I wouldn't say Jan has
this mentality but professors in general like it's a pretty big win if you start a company and you make $50 million like you're a hero on campus.
Like that's a that's a pretty cool thing to have done.
And so I'm always a little nervous about uh kind of a company that comes out of academia thinking too small anyway.
And uh so I said, "Look, I'm not going to write you a check for $200,000.
I'll write you a check for $10 million."
Um because like this company, you need to build a company.
You need to really go for it if you're going to do this.
other rice like you guys should stay in school and and they were all graduating right right then.
So that was kind of that.
And Ali Ali actually was VP of engineering at the time.
And it was a while, you know, before uh I made him CEO.
And that that was very good luck on my part because I had no idea that they had a guy that good inside the company who could become CEO when I invested.
Like that that was just, you know, God smiled on me and gave me that one.
Um, so speaking of Ali, I actually asked him what to ask you about.
And he immediately shared this story.
I don't know if you remember this in your first one-on-one with him after you made him a CEO.
He was struggling with a bunch of low performers because he was coming in to lead the company.
And he was trying to turn things around, trying to coach them, trying to level them up.
And your advice to him was, quote, "You don't make people great.
You find people that make you great, that make the company great, that you learn from,
not the other way around."
And there's something that he called managerial leverage.
What is that all about?
What's the lesson there?
>> Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So like understand he had just become CEO.
So I was teaching him he had been VP of engineering and CEO is different and and I'll get into why and what I mean by leverage.
So, I actually wrote a post about this with a little wang quote where I think the quote was,
"The truth is hard to swallow and hard to say to, but I graduated from that Now I hate school."
And and that that was always my feeling about this particular idea was look, if you're VP of engineering,
you can develop people.
You can teach them to be better engineers.
You can teach them to be better engineering managers.
Like that's very like doable.
But if you're a CEO, like what do you know about being CFO?
Like what do you know about being, you know, VP of HR?
What do you know about any of these jobs?
You know, except maybe VP of engineering, right?
Like, and so the idea that you're going to take somebody who doesn't who isn't world class at marketing and make them world class and you don't know anything about marketing is a dumb idea.
It just doesn't work.
Um, and then the company can't afford for you to be spending time on that because they need you to make very high quality,
fast decisions.
They need you to set the direction for the company and they need you to have a world-class team.
And so like that and it's a very hard lesson if you've been VP of engineering because if you're a good VP of engineering,
you do develop your people.
But as a CEO like it's not like you don't do any of it.
um but it is very very small you know compared to so I like to make things just very stark so you you get what I'm saying I don't like to hedge it and then managerial
leverage means this it's very simple it's okay if I have the ideas about what your department should do next if I you
know am kind of pushing you to kind of move your organization forward then that's no leverage what's leverage is if you're telling me what you should do and
how you can push the company forward.
That's leverage.
Then I'm getting kind of more than I'd have if you weren't there.
Otherwise, I could just manage a team.
And that's the point when you feel like you're not getting leverage, when you got to go say,
"Hey, why aren't we doing this?
Why aren't we doing that?"
That's when you got to make the change.
And by the way, he's unbelievable at that.
Um, as good as anybody I've seen as as a guy who's not callous as a CEO.
He really cares about the people who work for him.
He really wants him to have great careers and all that, but he does not hesitate like if he's losing leverage,
he'll make a move.
Kind of going back to the origin story of A16Z, something you guys were really big on was helping founders stay CEOs,
become great CEOs, not replace them with professional CEOs.
I wanna I want to flip this question on you.
When does it actually make sense to replace a CEO?
When are people not going to make great cos?
it really the the there's a very consistent thing that happens which is um you know then somebody doesn't make it and it kind of starts with confidence
is the way I would put it.
So when you you're you invent a product, you kind of recruit a team so forth, all of a sudden you're CEO,
but you got to run a big organization.
You don't know how to do that.
Like most founders are like that.
Um and so if you don't know what you're doing, you're going to make mistakes.
And they all make a lot of mistakes.
And then when you make those mistakes, they're very expensive.
you know, like they could cost you to do a down round or they could cost you to lose a company or they could cost you a customer or,
you know, you screw up a product.
Like they're very high impact and not just on you but everybody who you talked into joining you.
And so that kind of motion can really cause you to lose confidence.
Uh and then if you lose confidence, what happens is you hesitate on the next decision.
And you know, as we talked about, like hesitation is very dangerous because one, like it it locks up the company,
but even worse, what happens is if you have senior people working for you, they get very nervous and they feel like they need to
jump into that void and make the decision for you.
And that's when it gets political, like very political, because people are like vying for power inside your little,
you know, screwed up company.
And so now you've got a political dysfunctional organization.
And that um, you know, like that's that's generally where like, okay, the founder probably can't run this thing anymore is,
you know, that's how it happens.
So, you know, most of what we do as a firm is to try to help people with that confidence problem.
And there's like a whole series of ideas that we have around that.
But that's, you know, you kind of have to somehow climb the confidence and the competency curve together.
It's very hard to do.
Uh, and you particularly like if you're an engineer and you're used to getting things right or if you've been a straight A student or something like that,
it's very disconcerting.
Most is better to have like CEOs who are like C minus students, you know.
>> Why is that?
>> Yeah.
a little physicious like well like it's just good to be used to filling.
So I I think I I wrote this but like the the the median on the CEO kind of test is like 18.
It's not like 90.
And so you got to be comfortable getting a lot of D minuses because the D minus is fine,
you know, as long as you don't get the F.
as long as you don't run out of cash, as long as you don't lose the whole thing, you know,
okay, like you got through it.
Keep going, you know.
And that's that's a lot of the the thing that we try to do as CEOs.
>> Yeah.
It comes back to the your core, I don't know, message through your first book is just how much you will fail and how much you will struggle and how much pain you'll go through as CEO.
Yeah.
And you know, like I mean, a lot of why I wrote that book was just to normalize that.
I think what happens is, you know, particularly, you know, when I wrote it and I think it's come back and been true now is like the way the narrative gets written on all these successes is like,
oh, they came up with a genius idea and then they built this company and they hired all these smart people and it was all great,
but like that's not all how it happens.
Um, and you know, I've spent enough time with like everybody from like Mark Zuckerberg to Sam Aldman and so forth that like they all go through that same thing that
you who has, you know, your struggling company go through like you screw a lot of things up and they have massive consequences.
Uh, but you you you have to kind of maintain your confidence.
Actually, I was at a storytelling event last night and I we were chat I was chatting with someone that I ran into there and told her I was chatting with you today and she said how meaningful uh your first book was to her as a founder
exactly as you said normalizing that it's very hard and painful and this is just the way it is.
>> Yeah.
And the feeling look I mean you know like if you think about organizational design or you know goals and objectives or OKRs or what whatever management technique like you need like
a you know a basic like eighth grade education to like do any of that stuff.
It's it's not that complicated.
The difficult part is the the feeling that you have when you have to do it uh is very like the hard thing about a reorg is you're redistributing power.
So, you're going to have people really freaking mad at you because somebody's losing power if you do it correctly.
And that person may be like a really good employee.
Dealing with that is the hard thing.
Like knowing how the organization should work to make communication better.
It's not that complex.
>> Yeah.
I think about I was at Airbnb for a long time and just thinking of Brian who I don't know even know if he had a job before Airbnb.
>> Oh yeah.
I don't know.
I spent a lot of time with Brian and he uh after COVID he it all kind of clicked for him.
Um and then he did that you that good talk on founder mode and so forth.
But the reason that was so articulate is because he had screwed every one of those things up.
um you know he hired LT and you know all this stuff and you know these are very senior people and you know he didn't he wanted to defer to them but you can't defer as a CEO you know
because you know what Airbnb should be doing he may know what finance should do but you know what Airbnb should do and this kind of thing and and
then then it gets really wild uh when you like you can't defer decisions as a CEO you got to like understand what people are saying and go now we're going to do this
>> and this again comes back to the point of you have to go through the struggle and pain and failure to learn those lessons.
>> Yeah.
No, like I mean it's they're really hard to learn without kind of doing and without often like without paying the consequence and I you know like even I like I make mistakes.
I I was having conversation with Ali the other day and I was like he's like how's it going Ben?
And I was like, "Well, you know, like I'm finally dealing with something that I had put off for,
you know, a very long time."
And he said,"Why'd you put it off?"
I said, "Cuz things were going too good.
I didn't have to deal with it."
And he was like,"Yeah."
He said, "I know that like and I say Alli is, you know, one of the if not the kind of best private company CEO out there."
And he's making a mistake and I'm making a mistake.
So like it's just tough.
You said that one of the maybe the main reason founders fail SEOs is they lose confidence and you had some ideas that you guys have to help founders work through that.
Are there a couple you can share how you help?
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
So we do we do a lot of things on that.
So the kind of design of the firm is about confidence.
So the first thing is well what would give you well like if you can get stuff done.
So, what if I could give you a network that's as good as Bob Iger's network day one,
like the day you step into the job.
And so, you know, we have 600 people at the firm.
And why is that?
Well, most of them are building that network for you.
So, you can call any CEO or anybody in Washington or, you know, kind of any executive or that kind of thing and get them on the phone and they'll talk to
you and you can kind of deal with that thing.
Uh and then that just makes you feel like a CEO and then you know we have a lot of people in the firm like myself who you can talk to on like a CEO to CEO
basis as opposed to an investor to CEO and just kind of feel that early in the firm's days we used to do this thing I think I'm going to bring back in some
form this thing called the CEO barbecue and it was like you know a lot of people have these events where like you know they bring in speakers and this and that and the other and I always felt like
those were one they were too many days and then sometimes you know the what they said wasn't really applicable and that kind of thing and so what I said well why don't we
just have a barbecue and like I would barbecue we get everybody in my backyard was 500 people at the peak which is why the kind of stuff because I couldn't
cook that much food after that and then uh you know we'd have Larry Page and Mark Zuckerberg in Pa West.
And so you're a CEO in there with Cor.
You're like, "Wow, like I must be important.
I'm here with all these guys and we're just hanging out having a drink, eating barbecue."
Um, and so then when I go back to my company, like I feel like I am somebody and like,
okay, I might not be like perfect at all this, but I am really a CEO.
I was at the CEO barbecues were crying out loud and that kind of thing.
And so yeah that that's but it's all the whole idea was always like okay do you feel like you can do it because
that's yeah that's about it.
Uh and look having been in and you know every CEO has been in a position where they feel like well maybe I shouldn't be the one running this thing.
Maybe it's just too big for me.
And that's a bad you don't you don't want to go there.
uh and because as as we've said founders can get to the next product and that's something that you know almost no professional CEO is able to do like
there have been rare cases but very rare so clearly you've worked with a lot of companies a lot of founders let me kind of zoom out a little bit and ask you this question what's the most counterintuitive lesson you've learned
about building companies that goes against common startup wisdom >> well you know the common startup wisdom keeps changing change it,
you know, uh, like one of the early ones that, um, you know, was wrong and kind of Brian articulated it and then now I think a little bit of what people have gone to
is also wrong.
So the the first idea that was wrong was like, okay, build a team of like senior executives,
you know, as soon as you get product market fit as fast as possible and they can scale the thing.
And I think that you got to build that team slowly and deliberately kind of paced to your ability to man integrate and then manage them.
Because if you bring in a bunch of senior people and you don't know really how they map to your company or how that function works or so forth,
then you're going to start deferring.
And once you start deferring, it's going to get out of control very fast because they're going to build empires.
they're going to get political, they're going to do all that kind of thing.
So, that was bad advice.
You kind of have to do it in a measured way.
I think that founder mode I think a lot of people have taken to never hire anybody with experience and that's also bad advice uh in that look
somebody who knows how to do something can really accelerate your thing.
So very early on um one of the founders, great founder, uh Arcelon at data bricks was running sales and I'm like Olli like
you're going to have to hire like somebody who knows sales.
Um because Arselon's PhD in computer science like I like that but um that that's probably not where you're going to have to start if you're going to catch these guys before they take Spark and like use it
against you.
And you know and I sat down with Arcelon and I explained why I said look you know a lot of what sales there's a lot of knowledge in how to build a worldwide sales representation you need knowledge
of customers territories territory splitting rep profiles like there's just like a litany of stuff that you really can only learn by doing trial and error
and you don't know any.
So like you're phenomenal.
Like let's get you, you know, and he's still he's a very senior executive in the company now,
but we need somebody who knows that.
And the idea that there are companies that go, okay, we're just not going to hire that because we're in founder mode.
That's also a mistake.
So then there's a lot of it's more subtle than you think.
Uh and it's more complex than you think.
And so you kind of have to get all the way to the truth.
And these little snippets of advice that VCs give because they watch some podcast are all stupid.
Like it's just there's a lot of depth to these things.
You have to know the answer to the next question, the next question, and the next question.
And it does drive me crazy.
Like one of the funnier things that happened um along these lines just to show you how little you know as an investor about what it means to be CEO uh one of the we were at a board dinner
one of the CEOs uh says to me he goes or one of my you know one of our CEOs says hey you know Ben like that thing you told me a while ago about don't be CEO
at home he said like I I I was doing that and I stopped and it really helped me and then the other kind of VC said,
"Yeah, you know, you got to unplug sometime."
And I said, I was like, "What the are you talking about?
He's CEO.
He's not unplugging.
Like, he's getting all the time.
Like, he's got to deal with that."
Like, that was not what I meant.
I was like, "You can't go home and boss your family around."
That's what I meant, you know?
Like, so so it's the the you hear something from like somebody who But if you haven't done it,
you don't even know what that means.
And so then you kind of then trying to transfer the advice to the next guy.
That's not going to work.
So anyway, so but it's, you know, like he was very innocent.
I just don't want to kind of uh speak bad of him, but like it that's how it sounds, right?
But that's not what it is.
>> That's an amazing story.
>> So the advice partly here is just don't believe everything you see on Twitter and little sound bites of advice.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, I mean like I and I think actual CEOs know it and that's kind of how like people in my profession kind of get a bad wreck because like giving advice that that's not something that you know
but something that you heard is very dangerous I think.
So speaking of advice that uh you've shared that might be out of date now you are famous for writing uh one of the most popular pieces of literature for product managers.
There's a lot of PMs that listen to this podcast called good product manager bad product manager.
And if you actually go to that post today at the top you say this document was written 15 years ago and it's probably not relevant today for PMs.
I present this merely as an example of a useful training document.
Still people link to it.
I actually just link to it as an as is just like this is something every PM needs to read.
What is it that you think people should maybe not take away from it and what do you think people still should take away from that piece?
>> Yeah.
So the reason I wrote it when I wrote it was um that I had a lot of product managers and one thing about product management is um it's a job that's completely different
at every company like and there is no training for it.
So like everybody kind of figures it out how as they go and depending on like what's being emphasized like they'll get wrapped around the axle on you know like if it's enterprise
company okay well like you know pitching to customers or like I need to be like really good with the press or I need to be really good at writing you know the
product requirements document or that kind of thing and none of the those are all like these tasks Um but none of those were the job.
Uh and what I was trying to get out and good product manager, bad product manager was the job is fundamentally a leadership
job and it's a tricky leadership job because nobody is actually reporting to you.
So it's like this influence.
How do I get people to do what I want?
you know, even though I'm not paying them, I can't fire them, I can't promote them, and so forth.
And which is kind of the essence of like real leadership because if you start to rely on promotion and firing and so forth for authority,
then you you're never going to be good at being CEO or anything.
So I wanted them to get into the mindset of okay your actual job
is to get a product into market that customers love that's better than anything that anybody else in the world puts in market.
Like that's your job.
And so to accomplish that job you need engineering to understand you with clarity.
You need to understand engineering with clarity.
You need to have a really good view of the market and the competitors and the technology and so forth.
And you need to kind of put that all together and deliver the thing.
And all the other things are tasks that may or you may or may not need to do.
I don't know if you need to do them, but like the thing is, you know, you have to be the leader.
You've got to get the thing done.
And and so what I think it's still good on is that like the the mindset like you know be the leader.
Uh I think the details of it um you know of any kind of thing that was kind of task specific was
like really for my group at Netscape in like 1996 whenever the hell I wrote it.
So it's you know it's a kind of document I read out of frustration.
Uh but I'm I am glad that that the people still like it.
Uh and I think leadership in general is under undervalued underestimated um it's
it's the most powerful thing.
uh and and most of the great you know great companies Jensen is a great example like what a phenomenal leader he is not just of Nvidia but of the whole industry and he doesn't have authority over the
industry but like he drives it forward and that's and and that's why the good product manager bad product manager is so important because that thing if you
learn how to do it that's the thing uh I didn't realize you wrote that initially as just an internal document and then you made it public >> it was it was kind of before um blog bugging took off.
So, it's just an internal thing.
Uh, and I published it later.
>> It was I was just getting so mad, you know, and by the way, my product management team >> at the time was like very good uh very talented people.
They just didn't they they just were not getting that concept.
So, you know, like David Widens at Coastal Ventures, Ragu Raguram who was went on to be CEO of VMware.
I mean, like the team was like that team.
Uh, but they were driving me crazy.
And so I I just I was like I can't yell at people anymore.
I have to like explain to myself.
And so it's a good thing if you find yourself yelling at people like you probably haven't explained what you want is was the other big take away from that.
>> Do you ever think that piece would be so long lasting and so I don't know.
>> No, I thought I didn't even know like I thought it was kind of like aggressive when I wrote it.
Like you could tell I was mad because I called it good product manager bad product manager.
It's like bad dog, you know, bad pride, bad bad product manager.
That's that was kind of the emotion I had.
So, you know, it's it's kind of shocking.
Some of the things that you write, I I I would say that that's, you know, and kind of creative and you probably know this,
like the ideas that you have um the things that you write in five minutes end up being much better than things you write in five weeks,
you know.
And uh I I find in talking to you know uh musicians or writers or anybody everybody has that same experience like the thing that you've already
synthesized so much that you just have to write it out is uh that's the best stuff.
There's something that you mentioned there in your answer about the PM being the leader.
There's always this kind of sense that the PM is not the mini CEO.
How dare you call yourself that?
I actually think that's exactly what the PM is.
They're basically the closest to the CO.
their kind of job is to think like the CEO within the team.
>> Yeah.
People get mad, you know, like because everybody, you know, like this is the whole challenge of management in general,
like people get jealous over stewardship.
But look, from from the perspective of the PM, like it doesn't matter if you write a good spec or you have a good interview or you do this or do that.
like what matters is that the product wrench and you have to get all the way to there and kind of work backwards from that and
you can't do that without leadership because it is about okay we want to build that and and you're not necessarily the person comes up with every idea or this or that or you're
just the keeper of the vision you know and that's true for CEOs too like you don't want every idea in a company coming from the CEO like that's I think it's misunderstanding what a CEO is is
why people don't like that.
They don't know what a CEO is.
But a CEO isn't the one who has every idea, gives every order, does every That's not the way it works.
The way it works is there's somebody who's got to consolidate, you know, get all the good ideas,
prioritize them, decide which good ideas we're going to do, and then get everybody on the same page so that they have very high fidelity understanding of what that is.
And if you you know so that it is a CEO kind of function.
Now it doesn't mean like I'm better than you.
It just means that like that's what I'm doing.
>> This episode is brought to you by Miro.
Every day new headlines are scaring us about all the ways that AI is coming for our jobs,
creating a lot of anxiety and fear.
But a recent survey from Miro tells a different story.
76% of people believe that AI can benefit their role.
But over 50% of people struggle to know when to use it.
Enter Miro's innovation workspace, an intelligent platform that brings people and AI together in a shared space to get great work done.
Miro has been empowering teams to transform bold ideas into the next big thing for over a decade.
Today, they're at the forefront of bringing products to market even faster by unleashing the combined power of AI and human potential.
Guests of this podcast often share Miro templates.
I use it all the time to brainstorm ideas with my team.
Teams especially can work with Miro AI to turn unstructured data like sticky notes or screenshots into usable diagrams,
product briefs, data tables, and prototypes in minutes.
You don't have to be an AI master or to toggle yet another tool.
The work you're already doing in Miro's Canvas is the prompt.
Help your teams get great work done with Miro.
Check it out at miro.com/lenny.
That's mirro.com/lenny.
Let's talk about AI.
I'm very proud of us.
It's been almost an hour.
We haven't even mentioned AI.
I think that's a record.
>> Uh, okay.
So, I asked Adam Newman, uh, WeWork founder, now Flow founder, someone you work closely with now,
what to ask you about, and he said he has some really interesting insights about how AI is impacting hiring.
You know, Adam is probably the single most controversial investment that we ever made.
like we got called everything from stupid to sexist to racist to this and that for like like literally just funding that.
Um and I think it's going to end up being one of the best investments we ever made.
Um he's doing a phenomenal job there.
But it's there's an important principle in in that which kind of we do as a firm which I think is
um not widely done but I would love it if people copied it which is and I something I learned um
you know somewhat from Shaka which is you you don't judge a person by the worst thing that ever happened to them.
Like we've all had bad things happen to us.
We've all made bad decisions.
Most of them they don't make a miniseries about, right?
And so like to judge them on that, you want to judge people on what they do well, not what they screwed up.
And you know, because that's where you see the talent.
If you look at what Adam did well, it's truly spectacular.
Uh you know, like we work, everybody knows how we work.
It's like it's the name a more important commercial real estate brand than we work like you can't uh and so like what an accomplishment and then you know and there were so many things that
went into that and and yeah so many things he did right and then if you kind of look at really unravel the things that went wrong most of it was like a
combination of inexperience and nobody around him that would tell him the truth and so like that and you know maybe he wasn't good at listening to the truth
either at the time.
Um, but to throw away a guy on that, which is, by the way, the world was so mad at us for not throwing him away for for
believing in him.
Um, is just a it's a big mistake.
And uh, you know, I credit Mark because Mark is the one who called him up originally and just said,
"Hey, Adam, what are you doing?"
uh because like you know we watched what you did at Weiwork and we thought it was pretty impressive and so I think that uh you know that that's
probably the biggest secret there.
It's not really about AI but I think that um look looking you know you judge Al Davis once said you know coach players on what they can do and I think that's very true
you know judge people on what they can do um you know coach people on what they can do like help them take their strengths and use them as
opposed to overfocus on their weaknesses and just, you know, hand ring about the one thing they don't know how to do.
Because look, everybody's uneven.
>> What it's like what you're describing essentially this is the job of an investor is to find an underappreciated asset and invest or before something people don't see.
>> Yeah.
And I mean I think that it's you know like venture capital is really about investing in people,
right?
like you know that you have ideas as an investor but like what you really are ultimately betting on is the entrepreneur and the
entrepreneurs's idea because the initial idea isn't where they end up usually it changes a lot um with with everybody we invest in so you know you kind of have
to make the judgment on the person and you know how you do that is uh is really really important one of the things we emphasize inside the firm this look like
we're investing in strength, not lack of weakness.
Like I want to know like how good like are they world class?
Do they have a world class strength and you know can that beat anybody and look everybody's flawed and so like let's help them deal with the flaws and you
know surround them with people who can handle that and put the right person on the board who can talk to him.
I go to all Adam's board meeting.
Even though Mark's on the board, I go to all his board meetings because I'm the one who's good at like killing a guy who's that confident.
Um when he's like, "Okay, that's not your best idea."
Like that's a good world for me.
But that's how you deal with that.
You don't, you know, throw them away and go,"Okay, like we don't want to be called names,
so we're not going to invest in Adam Newman after he built Rework."
That's crazy.
>> That's also why you guys invested in Cluey, I imagine.
Similar.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
No, that's right.
Like I mean like if you look at what those guys did, that was like some like highlevel marketing genius too.
And you know that's really something.
Plus the product is awesome.
>> I'm going to bring us back to AI.
Something that a lot of people are talking about right now while we're recording this is this potential huge bubble we're in with AI.
Sam Alman said we're in a big bubble which is you know that's saying a lot.
I'm curious just how you think >> what what is it saying?
So you gota like first of all I should qualify this by saying I'm an investor um and Sam's a CEO.
So CEOs have to have much more purpose when they talk.
Investors just have to be entertained.
Um, so you got to give Sam credit for like what is it in his interest to say it?
Well, like if it's a bubble, then the one thing you should invest in is him and not all these guys chasing after him.
Um, so that I I would say like that's very smart.
And then the other thing that's smart about it is there's nothing that you can say to the press that will make them love you more than saying all investors and like entrepreneurs chasing this are idiots.
Like they love them because you know the press are generally haters.
And so it's just like red meat for the haters which is also super clever.
So I think whether even he believes that or not that was a super smart thing to say.
So I'll just put it there.
Whereas what I'm going to say um won't be as smart, but it will I I don't really have a an axe to grind here.
I mean, I could have an axe to grind and say, okay, like let's get all the other investors out.
I'll say it's a massive bubble.
But what I would say about that is um so the first thing the one thing about bubbles is anytime
everybody thinks it's a bubble, it's not a bubble because in order for it to bubble,
you need capitulation and that you need kind of everybody to believe it's not a bubble because then the prices really go out of control.
But as long as there's people who think it's a bubble, then it's hard for that to happen.
And it's funny, I had this debate um in in the economist I think with Steve
Blank in like 2011 or 12 when everybody thought it was a tech bubble if you can imagine that which it absolutely was not but because
there were like 1,400 articles saying that we were in a tech bubble and yeah I mean you know where prices were then compared to where they are now.
Um, but I knew because everybody was saying it was a bubble when a bubble like I knew that the prices were higher,
but the reason the prices were higher was we're getting to a global market.
AI prices are higher than prior prices, but if you look at the revenue growth and memories,
we've not seen anything like it.
The products are work.
Chachi Sam's product works so amazingly.
We never seen that before.
Like not even Google, not not anybody.
And so like that's real and you know we have companies that you know went from 0 to 800 million in a year and that kind of thing and so
it's not a I would say there's a basis for the prices going up first of all now will the the I think the thing that's
right about kind of what Sam is saying is the landscape is early really early the technology techology is very immature as amazingly as it works.
You know, there's a long way to go to improve it.
So, it's very possible, you know, when you have that much technological change that the positions that these companies have achieved with
their high revenue isn't sustainable and that, you know, there will be a competitive uh change that either kind of lowers prices or a new number one
emerges or that kind of thing.
And so that yeah that's possible but I would characterize that as being like a financial bubble uh in that like like if
you go back to the great.com bubble that everybody's always waiting for it to happen again which I was CEO during the thing that happened there was very
different which is it was the internet and every smart investor knew that the internet was a big deal like how could you not know that the internet was of course it's a big
But like if you go back to 1996 at Netscape, we had 90% browser share and we had 50 million users.
So there were 55 million people on the internet in total and half of those were on dialogue.
So and then to build a product like Evite, the greeting card company had 300 engineers.
That's how hard it was to build this stuff.
And so the math didn't work.
And the math didn't work on any of those ideas.
And but the investors kept pouring money in.
And then eventually, you know, um, everybody went bankrupt because there was no revenue coming in.
And like when they figured that out, then nobody would invest in anything.
And of course, then everybody realized, well, the internet was actually real.
And Paul Krugman didn't know what he's talking about.
And like it was going to be a big thing.
And then Facebook and Google and all these things emerged.
But the thing that made it a bubble was like the unit economics didn't work, the businesses didn't work.
Like these businesses are all working and they're being priced appropriately for how they're growing.
So that's not in effect.
So the the thing that you could say is they're not going to keep growing like that or like and so forth.
And I'm not sure about that.
Like like the products, like I said, are working so much better than any technology product that we've ever built has worked.
like it's just mind-blowing how good this stuff is.
And so I don't know.
I I if I had to bet I would bet not a bubble.
Uh you know there I think there will be some dislocation.
I think companies that I think always in venture capital if you've got like a run like this then the great company and the crap company both
get funded.
But you know that's just that's just venture capital.
uh sound a bubble >> for founders starting companies these days when you look into the future of the AI industry say in 5 10 years how do you how do you think things will play out slash where do you think the biggest
opportunities remain where are you guys looking to invest most >> in infrastructure um I I think that like there is obviously
like a real estate power cooling play um >> yeah I I think that's a little outside of you know kind of hardcore technology technology investing that we do.
But there's another layer which is like who can run you know you take a given open source model who can run it the cheapest
um with the kind of lowest latency and that's going to be extremely valuable like whoever has that uh and you know Google has been historically very good
at that and so forth and I Sam is really trying to build that um now a Stargate and so I think that's going to be a very important layer of value.
I think that you know on the foundation model side you have to be very selective as an investor.
So in order to compete in foundational model world our basic rule of thumb is you have to be able to you know without much product pro progress
raise at least $2 billion because that's basically what it's going to cost you to train something that gets you competitive enough to make money.
Um and there are just very few founders like that.
Uh so Ilia is one of those you know mirror is one of those fee is one of those but like that's the kind of class of person you need and there's you
know whatever there's certainly less than 10 of those in the world and so that that's kind of like an important area but a small area uh and then I
think the application layer is going to be very very interesting and I think that you know if you look that Sam like he's making most of his money
off chat GPT almost all his money off chat GPT now and Chat GPT is like you know I it looks like it's got a real like it or not it's got a real moat it's
very hard to knock it off its perch there's a you know everybody's taking a shot at people with great distribution like Google and you know Elon and and Zuckerberg and everybody and like that
thing just keeps going like it is so I think the applications are both more complex and uh kind of stickier
than people thought they were originally.
Like so the the thing that people got very wrong is this whole thin wrapper around GPG.
Like that's really wrong.
In fact, here's how wrong it is.
back in the 80s there that same phrase was used but it was thin wrapper around an RDBMS uh which >> database.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
So it meant companies like Salesforce were basically just a thin wrapper and I think that that's kind of the mistake people made.
So like we're at this company Curser and if you look under the covers in Curser they've built like 14 different models
to really understand um how a developer works like a high-end like a a real developer and they have that those
models have tons and tons of interactions with how people talk to their friend cursor about how they should design their programming so forth.
And that's like real that's not that's not just a thin layer on a foundation model.
And I think there are many many applications like that.
Uh and and so I I think there's going to be a lot of opportunity at the application layer.
There's going to be some opportunity at the foundation model and of course you can invest in SAM,
you can invest in Anthropic and so forth and as well.
Um but there will probably be like a very small number of companies at that set and then a almost unlimited number of companies at the application layer and
then you know as the technology advances we'll of course see more things with embodied AI.
I mean already, you know, autonomous cars are working like really well now after a long long long long time since like I think Sebastian won
the uh the challenge in 2006 when he drove the self-driving car across the country.
Um and here we are 20 years later and now they're deployed.
So that was a long time.
Robots I think is a harder problem than self-driving cars.
So, we'll see how that goes.
Um, but uh yeah, there there's certainly a lot in that world as well.
>> Wow.
Okay.
There's a lot to this answer.
Something that >> no ex exactly what I was looking for.
the cursor example.
It's something that comes up a lot on this podcast in the application layer specifically the uh thought that the way to win in this space and to build a moat is as you said
build your own model slash have proprietary data that you build through people using your product thoughts on that >> yeah I mean I think that's ends up just being what's required so it turns out
that um the universe is longtailed is is as fat tailed and humans are very fat tailed in terms of human behavior,
human conversation and so forth.
So to get to the real meaning of it and to get to the kind of essence of the problem,
you know, in any domain uh turns out to be I think more complex than we thought.
And so like like the early things and you know people were running around uh saying okay there's going to be one big brain to rule them all and these kinds
of things.
uh that's kind of not played out yet.
uh and and in fact like if you look underneath the covers you have LLMs which have generalized pretty you know like in fascinating ways
but they've kind of also asintoted in that um you know we we have run out of data for the most part and so if you look at the GPT5
LLM compared to the GPT4 one and how much more it costs to train and so forth like it's you It's definitely not going linear anymore.
On the other hand, the reinforcement learning side has been linear, but it doesn't generalize.
So, if you build a great uh programming model, it may be an idiot at math.
And so, that I think is just very different than what people would have said three years ago.
And I think that's kind of, you know, that there's not something that's both scaling and generalizing yet.
And you know, maybe we'll get there, but that certainly opens the door to something that's more user friendly,
that's more effective in any number of domains than just the basic foundation model infrastructure.
Now, those models are incredibly important and they're and I think open AI is probably 80% of the revenue in AI or something like that now.
Like it's massive.
So that foundation model is really really important.
Um, and then like the the the the basic consumer app is really really important.
Um, that just answers whatever the hell you want to know.
Like th those things are like very very real.
But I do think you know particularly and then if you get into like enterprise stuff and then it's no longer internet data it's their data that becomes very
different like data bricks is having a lot of success there because okay well once you're inside a company guess what like you care about access control and
that's hard with an AI world you know it gets trained on some stuff how does it know who has access to that information who present and so forth.
Um you have semantic issues.
So if you look at an enterprise, find 10 enterprises, they all have a different definition of what a customer means.
Like you would think customer is a basic thing.
Well, is it a department at AT&T?
Is it AT&T?
Is it like a person at AT&T?
Is like what the hell is a customer?
It turns out to be very very very meaningful.
uh particularly if you're trying to um figure out like important things like churn and this and that and third.
So like that kind of stuff matters.
So so it I I would just say like the the problem space is a lot bigger than you can just attack with a basic foundation model.
um at you know currently you know maybe that will change and like if that changes then certain prices will have in retrospect looked way inflated and others will look
you know too low but you know that that is TBD >> so a big takeaway from this is that there's still tons of opportunity for
founders to start companies building AI products >> I think so I mean you can solve so many everything that we couldn't solve with software we can solve now almost so it's
It's a really big world.
And it's funny, you know, like because we're investors in in Whimo and uh one of the things when you get into like what took so long to make Whimos this so
safe like they are now, it wasn't the things that everybody reported on the podcast.
It wasn't sle and, you know, heavy rain and it was people.
It was like the human who was driving 75 in the 25 zone.
was very hard for the AI to anticipate because it was rare but important and the number of rare important crazy that humans do is
very high.
Uh and I think that that goes for all of AI.
Um so to make things work really well, you have to understand this this very kind of fat tale of human behavior.
along this AI thread, something that is really important to you clearly, something you talk a lot about is is the US being successful in AI and be in leading the world in AI.
Why is it so important?
Why is something you spent a lot of time on?
>> It starts with uh I think my view of the US uh and its role in the world.
So it's my personal view is like it's very very very important
not for society to be completely fair because it's not going to be completely fair or completely equal because we've never had one that's been completely equal.
But it's important that everybody have a chance um at life you know and particularly uh you know kind of both culturally but
also just like you can't advance the world if you know you can't tap into all of your resources.
And so if you kind of take away motivation and and these kinds of things, you get into trouble.
And if you look at the kind of every country today and and this is by the way um so you want like the right amount of
decentralized power.
Um you know you don't want it to be completely concentrated.
Concentrated power makes it very very difficult for everybody to have a chance.
This is the big kind of lesson of communism over the last hundred years is it turned out right and and you know we still have politicians selling it this way today.
It's like oh it's power to the people.
No no no it's power to you because you're removing all power from the private sector and installing it into the government and then you're putting yourself in charge of the government.
And so I become extremely powerful.
And this is why it didn't matter if it was Mao or Pulpot or Chescu or Stalin, everybody died because when you give
anybody that much power, nobody has a chance.
There's no incentive.
Uh there's no carrot.
There's only stick.
And so use that stick.
And that's just the nature.
It's a systems problem.
It's not a person problem.
It's not Stalin was evil.
Joesco is evil.
It was like that system is evil.
Uh and that's a saying with fascism, right?
Be it Hitler or Mousolini, it doesn't matter.
Like that level of power is evil.
Um and the US does the best job systematically.
It's the best system.
It's got all kinds of issues.
It's got problems.
People always trying to defeat it.
But you know one of the things that um you know if you look at kind of the declaration of independence or the constitution like the language is very
important you know it's we hold these truths to be self-evident.
What does that mean?
It means there it's not my rule.
It's not the president's rule.
It's God's rule.
And so those rules are bug the president.
And then you work in that context and that that distributes power because you're under the law not under the
person.
And we see that you know now even with Europe where Europe is kind of the leaders are going well I have a rule it's you can't say certain things or
I'll throw you in jail.
And the kind of shield they hide behind is well like we have to keep the kids safe.
But if you say something that I don't agree with and the kids hear it, they're not safe,
right?
Like so the the the kind of um transitive property of like is going to override.
And so it's really important that we have at least like one society and as flawed as we are,
as flawed as the US is, it's still the best.
And you can see it by the number of new company creations, the number of new ideas that come out of here.
and so forth.
Um it's really really important that the US kind of stays important and powerful in the world.
And we know from the last century, if you look at the last century, who were the countries that had economic power,
military power, cultural power, they were the ones that industrialized.
Yeah.
And the ones that industrialized first and best and the ones that didn't became communists,
right?
like you know Russia, China like they they were slow on industrialization and they fell into this very dangerous uh system.
Looking forward that's going to happen again but it's going to be AI.
And so it is kind of fundamentally important not just to like America but to humanity that America succeed at that.
you know, like we don't have to be the one winner or this or that, but we do have to be like in that tier.
Uh, and you know, as I go around the world and travel, I can't tell you everybody and and everybody was getting,
by the way, very very worried about us uh earlier um and they say, "Look, we need you to succeed.
You know, don't destroy the dollar.
Don't like fall behind AI.
Don't overregulate it too early.
Don't do do these things, please."
because we need you to win like because we're all like counting on that.
Uh and and I think it's um it's the most important work that we do.
It's why we're so involved in policy and and and so forth.
Um I think this is also, you know, very going to be very very true with crypto which ends up being an incredibly important networking technology that complements
AI.
Uh and uh and so that's I Yeah.
And that you know that work is I would say beyond for the money like that's although like we will end up making a lot of money with the right policies like so I don't want to like seem
totally philanthropic on this but but it's more important than that it's it's certainly more important than us succeeding or anything like that that the country succeed.
Speaking of philanthropic and other passions of yours, something that I don't think most people know about you and I think will give them another insight into how interesting you are.
You uh run an organization called Paid in Full, which uh is incredibly cool.
Talk about what that's about, why this is so important to you.
We kind of our our ethos as a firm is um kind of uh what I'd say is something from nothing.
Um you know like that this is the greatness of entrepreneurship.
you start with nothing and then you you make something really important.
And um you know that that kind of that that is also how hip-hop started where you had like a bunch of kids who didn't even have instruments um and they kind of
created something out of nothing and and the people in that world always talk about that and you know one of the really unfortunate things that happens is the people kind of who invent the art form and certainly in the case of
hip-hop don't get anywhere near the kind of proportional benefit of their invention.
And a lot of the guys uh you know people have forgotten about or you know are kind of struggling to make ends meet and so forth.
So what we created was this thing called the paid and full foundation named after uh the Rock Kim Eric B song which I did call Rock Kim and ask him for permission to use the
name.
So read it taken.
And what we do is we give essentially pensions to the old rappers um that enable them to kind of continue their work.
Uh and then we have a big event.
Go to paidenfoldfoundation.org for tickets which is amazing.
Um where they kind of get the award and uh you know and they're celebrated by all their peers and so forth and it's really phenomenal.
But you know, so some of the award ease have been uh Raken um Scarface uh from the ghetto boys um Roxan Shante Grandmaster Cass Kul Modi.
This year we're honoring George Clinton for being sampled uh Kool Gap and Graham Puba and also uh Jalil
from Houdini.
Um and it's just it's very I I can't even describe how high impact it is on these guys.
I mean, I think Rock Kim was touring close to 200 nights a year and he got his award and came out with his first album in 15 years and is doing amazingly well and all of a sudden,
you know, everybody's going,"Oh, yeah, that's the greatest rapper of all times."
Like, they're finally going back and remembering all the things he did.
Uh, Roxan Shante, I mean, nobody had mentioned her in years and years and years.
And I think six months after we gave her the award, the Grammys gave her a lifetime achievement award,
which is amazing.
So, it's a it's super high impact.
It's a great thing.
You know, as a hip-hop fan, I say dream come true.
So, it's not only built.
>> What is what's the origin story of you and hip-hop?
I imagine many people look at you and wouldn't imagine you you these records behind you.
Nas gifted you.
You uh you're so deep into the community.
Just how did this all begin?
>> Well, so there's I actually wrote a blog post on it called The Legend of the Blind MC.
uh which I think would be uh if you're really interested, it's worth reading, but it is kind of a story of me uh becoming a rapper and um and like how
that occurred and how it went and so forth.
But uh you know like I always say the very short story is you know I was in New York when it at the birth of hip-hop and we're at the birth when it
really became big kind of 84th radi8 and yeah it's just the most exciting thing yeah to see a new art form kind of pop out and the creativity and
everything you know once music kind of becomes mainstream I would say it gets very shaped by business and like in the early days
there's no yeah everybody's just coming out with whatever idea they have and so forth then so there's the early days of rock and roll were like that the early days of jazz were like that so
>> I see now even more why you guys uh brought on Eric Tornberg uh beyond his many talents he's also really big into rap himself >> yeah yeah I need to that that's a good reminder I need to make sure he gets the
paid fall >> Ben this was incredible >> is there anything else that you want to leave listeners with or share before we get to our very exciting quick lightning
round?
>> Yeah, I mean I would just say um you know like if you're a CEO listening to this then know that like
how you feel about yourself is going to end up meaning as much as anything.
And so like take your time on that.
Don't don't uh you know like self-evaluation is the one of my favorite quotes is um that one of my old managers told me as like there's
no uh there no from this day on no credit will be given for predicting rain only credit for building an arc and I think that's more true for CEOs than
anybody you know you have to build arc like it doesn't matter like if you predict you're going to fail you still failed it doesn't it gets you nothing um so what you have to do is figure your
way out of it and spend all your time on that.
>> Well, with that, we've reached our very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you.
Are you ready?
>> Yes, sir.
>> First question, what are two or three books that you find yourself recommending most to other people,
not including your own books?
>> Yeah.
So two that um I learned a lot from are one is the weirdest people in the world uh which um it's a kind of big history book but
through an anthropological kind of cultural lens and it's really fascinating explains an awful lot about like how society works and how little
changes in the rules completely change the culture.
Um, you know, one of the things that he he basically endeavors to explain, okay, why did the West get ahead of the rest of the world?
Um, and it kind of comes down to like a weird anomaly with the Catholic Church where they've kind of enforced um monogamous
marriage.
And it turns out that the natural state of humans is polygamy.
Um, but the problem with polygamy is there's no cooperation among men.
um which is a problem.
Uh and as a result uh and then everything is secret.
So there's no shared there's no sharing of knowledge because it's all kept in the family in what he calls kinbased culture.
It leads to something called kinbased culture and like even recipes won't be shared if you're in a kinbased culture because it's a secret.
Um so you can't build science, you can't build cities, you can't build big companies.
Um and you know so because the west kind of enforced broad monogous marriage early it was able to kind of evolve into all these things.
And he kind of shows why and how he does these psychological tests today with people from kind of monogous cult marriage culture kind of like western culture and kinbased
culture and the psychology is completely different.
And he gives examples like um you know if a person murders another person is that still murder if that person who did the murder is your brother?
And in western society yeah that's a murder in kinbased culture it's not a murder it's just not
and so like that's really different and so like morality is different like everything kind of comes off of that.
So it's just a fascinating fascinating book.
Uh so that's That's one.
Um I I tell you know another book that I recommend a lot is Shaka's book uh his first book writing my rhymes.
He has a new book that I think is better which is called How to be free.
Uh so I'm going to start it's not quite out I or maybe it's releasing it's releasing like next month.
So I recommend it.
So what it does is it goes through like how did he work his way out of prison and solitary confinement to his current psychology
and what are the techniques he used and it's um they're very powerful very powerful ideas so I think that like you know CEOs always ask me like how do you deal with
it like how do you deal with it you know they'll ask in like work life balance or like and it's like what are you talking about no work life balance for seats Um but or particularly like entrepreneur
CEOs like come on but like what do you do?
Do you meditate?
Do you do this or that?
But he kind of goes through the things that you really ought to do.
So that that's what I would recommend if somebody's wondering like how do you deal with all this pressure?
>> I love this uh just the whole idea of Shaka being this uh help for cos someone that killed someone went to prison led a prison gang.
I just love that how >> valable turn out to be really complicated things to ma manage enough.
Sorry for getting into this, but the problem with running a prison gang is you're just dealing with people who all come from broken culture,
right?
Like so in any organization like the fundamental thing is trust.
And so you're you you're bringing in a bunch of no trust people.
And so you can't and like and it's kind of like a military organization.
It's a gang.
And if you think about a military operation, if you don't have trust, people don't trust the order,
then you're completely dysfunctional.
So, how do you build trust from zero is a very interesting problem.
And he's a genius at that, by the way.
Uh, and you know, I learned a lot uh from kind of talking to him about it.
So like that from a management standpoint it's a I would just say it's an important kind of boundary case of how you build culture
and uh so I he is very very smart at that.
I mean you kind of have to like I said you have to look at people >> about you know their greatness not not the worst thing they ever did.
I I know this is the lighting ramp, but uh can you just share one example of something he did that was like wow that's a really good lesson someone trying to create a good culture that worked for him.
>> Yeah.
So like one of the things that he did that that I thought was um really smart is well he did a couple things.
One is just like a simple thing was he just made everybody eat lunch together in the game just to kind of build rapport,
relationship, trust like it's all one thing.
We're all together on that.
And I think you know like particularly in like remote world and so forth.
People really underestimate how powerful like just that idea can be.
And then you know another thing he did is he he made kind of like morality.
You know he he had kind of very specific things about you know if you you had to be good to your word
internally and externally.
Um, and so normally a gang you went like, you know, like I said, it's kind of a kinbased culture thing,
but it made it much more powerful when he said, "Look, like you you can't do devious like outside
the gang either."
Um, and he had a bunch of examples of that that I went through in the book, but it's a very um like like I said,
because you're building it from zero, you really have to take a hard line on things that I think people in companies don't even take a hard line on.
Like, you know, is it okay to lie internally?
Probably not.
Is it okay to lie to a customer?
Well, in some organizations it is.
Um, but like in Shaka's organization, like that's as big a cuty as I'm internally and and and these things I think end up being really important.
>> We're going to link to this book.
This is uh what you do is who you are.
This is your second book that fewer people know about and this is one of the stories you tell and just what the lessons are.
>> It's kind of a more advanced book, you know, like I think people don't >> you kind of have to survive to want to care about dealing with the cultural issues and
>> the survival book has a bigger audience.
Amazing.
Okay, we're going to keep going with Lightning Round.
Is there a favorite recent movie or TV show you have really enjoyed?
>> Yeah.
So, well on TV I really like Slow Horses, which is like uh the show about the MI6 kind of cast offs um guys and then I you know I haven't seen a lot of
movies lately but I watched Centers.
I went to the uh theater centers and it's I mean just the cinematography is unbelievable and the story is really original and the acting is incredible
and the costumes are amazing.
So it's it's just like a great kind of comprehensive piece of work like people have the craftsmanship on that thing is
just a lot beyond what most people making movies are doing these days.
So I I I really enjoyed that.
>> Mhm.
Yeah, I hate scary movies, but I I watched it and loved it.
>> Yeah, it wasn't that scary.
>> It wasn't that scary, but still, you know, zombies popping out of corners.
>> Yeah, not not my jam usually.
>> Yeah.
>> Is there a product you recently discovered that you really love?
It could be a gadget, could be clothes, could be something else.
>> I bought a coffee machine called the Technov Mocha Master, which is freaking incredible.
In fact, uh, a friend of mine saw it.
I was like, what is that?
And I just bought it for him, too, because it's so awesome.
Like, this thing makes coffee that it's just like perfect.
Like, there's no bitterness.
It's completely clean.
It's amazing.
Like, the only problem with it is I can't drink coffee that it doesn't make anymore,
which >> I don't know if that's a good thing or a bad thing, but >> that might be that might come out someday in the AI future.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Uh, two more questions.
one, do you have a is there a life motto that you often come back to find really useful in work or in life?
>> The thing that I would say has had the biggest effect on me is something my father said to me years ago um which is life isn't fair.
And that that seems like really really simple, but I think that um the thing that defeats people more than any other thing that I've seen
just in life is the expectation of some fairness.
Uh you know, like it's just not fair.
And there are like all kinds of stuff that are going to happen to you that you know and happen to everybody um that
don't happen to other people that are completely unfair but it doesn't matter because that's the way it is and as soon as you get that idea out of your mind um then you can just deal with it like oh
yeah of course it's unfair but I'm going to what should I do now which is the real question not how do I go back and get people to be fair because nobody's gonna be fair.
It's not fair.
It's the nature of it.
If you think about it for more than five seconds, you'll realize that.
And I think a lot of uh you know, and it's as an individual like if you want to make the world a better place,
whatever.
But for as an individual, do not expect anything to be fair.
It'll only defeat.
>> Final question.
This comes from Shaka actually.
Uh he gave me so many great suggestions.
I had to save this one for last.
Okay.
So, the question is, if you had to build a business curriculum from two hip-hop albums and one funk album,
what would they be and why?
>> I think probably Follow the Leader um by Rakim.
I thought that was so and and and the reason is kind of uh what we had kind of gotten into earlier
which is um leadership.
So when he came out with that song, which was like, you know, maybe the greatest hip-hop song ever written,
you know, he's telling people to like follow him.
Um, you know, follow the leader.
Uh, and just to have the idea that he was the leader of the entire art form, not just,
you know, his band, it isn't like amazing idea.
Um and and then the way he expressed it was incredible.
And then he's got uh he's got other great concepts in there.
Um that would give you like it's hard to listen to that record and have confidence.
I think from a like competitive purely competitive standpoint stillmatic um from Nas I mean that's one with ether.
That's the one with uh get yourself a gun.
That's the one with you man.
It's kind of like all of like the idea of competition is kind of encapsulated in that in that album.
So that that would be the other one.
Uh and then funk for one nation under a group for sure.
one nation under group because it's kind of like this is uh how do you initiate people into like a concept or
an idea and and right how do you infuse them like one nation under a groove is all about joining the nation um and like
it's so musically interesting and and kind of getting people to be part of that that is probably I If you asked me tomorrow,
I probably have three other ones.
>> Incredible.
I'm going to go listen to these.
Ben, final question.
How can listeners be useful to you?
>> If you get something that makes you better, please take it.
If you need kind of more advice on it, let me know.
But, um, look, my job is to help everybody build something great.
So, if you're if you're an entrepreneur, um, thank you for that.
>> Uh, also check out Payeyton Full Payeytonfoundation.org if you want to learn more about Yes.
that >> nonprofit.
Yeah, definitely.
We would love to have you.
>> Amazing, Ben.
Thank you so much for being here.
>> All right.
Awesome.
Thank you, Lenny.
>> Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much for listening.
If you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating or leaving a review as that really helps other listeners find the podcast.
You can find all past episodes or learn more about the show at lennispodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.