Who lead work on Codex?
Codex is OpenAI's coding agent.
We think of Codex as just the beginning [music] of a software engineering teammate.
It's a bit like this really smart intern that refuses to read Slack, doesn't check DataDog [music] unless you ask it to.
I remember Karpathy >> gnarliest bugs that he runs into that he just spends hours trying to figure out nothing else is solved.
He gives it to Codex, lets it run for an hour and it solves it.
>> Starting to see glimpses of the future where we're actually starting to have Codex be on call for its own training.
Codex writes a lot of the code that helps like manage its training run, the game infrastructure.
And [music] so we have a Codex code review is like catching a lot of mistakes.
It's actually caught some like pretty interesting configuration mistakes.
One of the most mind-blowing examples of acceleration the Sora Android app, like a fully new app.
We built it in 18 days and then 10 days later, so 28 days total we went to the public.
How do you think you win [music] in this space?
>> One of our major goals with Codex is to get to productivity.
>> If we're going to build a super assistant, it has to be able to [music] do things.
One of the learnings over the past year is that for models to do stuff, they're much more effective when they can use a computer.
It turns out the best way for models to use computers [music] is simply to write code.
And so we're kind of getting to this idea where if you want to build any agent, maybe you should be building a coding agent.
>> When you think about progress on Codex, I imagine you have a bunch of evals and there's all these public benchmarks.
>> A few of us are like constantly on Reddit.
You know, there's a there's praise up there and there's a lot of complaints.
What we can do as we as a product team is just try [music] to always think about how are we building a tool so that it feels like we're maximally accelerating people rather than building a tool that makes it more unclear what you should do as the human.
>> Being at OpenAI, I can't not ask about how far you think we are from AGI.
The current under appreciated limiting [music] factor is literally human typing speed or human multitasking speed.
Today my guest is Alexander Imbiricos, product lead for Codex, OpenAI's incredibly popular and powerful coding agent.
In the words of Nick Turley, head of ChatGPT and former podcast guest, Alex is one of my all-time favorite humans I've ever worked with and bringing him and his company into OpenAI ended up being one of the best decisions
we've ever made.
Similarly, Kevin Weil, OpenAI CPO, said Alex is simply the best.
In our conversation, we chat about what it's truly like to build product at OpenAI, how Codex allowed the Sora team to ship the Sora app,
which became the number one app in the App Store in under 1 month.
Also, the 20x growth Codex is seeing right now and what they did to make it so good at coding,
why his team is now focused on making it easier to review code, not just write code,
his AGI timelines, his thoughts on when AI agents will actually be really useful, and so much more.
A huge thank you to Ed Bay, Nick Turley, and Dennis Yang for suggesting topics for this conversation.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
And if you become an annual subscriber of my newsletter, you get a year free of 19 incredible products,
including a year free of Devin, Lovable, Replit, Bolt, Linear, Superhuman, Descript,
Warp, Granola, Magic Patterns, Raycast, Jasper, D Mob, and Posthog, and Stripe Atlas.
Head on over to Lenny's Newsletter.com and click product pass.
With that, I bring you Alexander Imbiricos after a short word from our sponsors.
Here's a puzzle for you.
What do OpenAI, Cursor, Perplexity, Vercel, Plaid, and hundreds of other winning companies have in common?
The answer is they're all powered by today's sponsor, WorkOS.
If you're building software for enterprises, you've probably felt the pain of integrating single sign-on,
SCIM, RBAC, audit logs, and other features required by big customers.
WorkOS turns those deal blockers into drop-in APIs with a modern developer platform built specifically for B2B SaaS.
Whether you're seed stage startup trying to land your first enterprise customer or a unicorn expanding globally,
WorkOS is the fastest [music] path to becoming enterprise ready and unlocking growth.
They're essentially Stripe for enterprise features.
Visit workos.com to get started or just hit up their Slack support where they have real engineers in there who answer your questions super fast.
WorkOS allows you to build like the best with delightful APIs, comprehensive docs, and a smooth developer experience.
Go to workos.com to make your app enterprise ready today.
This episode is brought to you by Finn, the number one AI agent for customer service.
If your customer support tickets are piling up, then you need Finn.
Finn is the highest performing AI agent on the market with a 65% average resolution rate.
Finn resolves even the most complex customer queries.
No other AI agent performs better.
In head-to-head bake-offs with competitors, Finn wins every time.
Yes, switching to a new tool can be scary, but Finn works on any help desk with no migration needed,
which means you don't have to overhaul your current system or deal with delays in service for your customers.
>> [music] >> And Finn is trusted by over 6,000 customer service leaders and top companies like Anthropic,
Shutterstock, Synthesia, Clay, Vanta, Lovable, monday.com, and more.
And because Finn is powered by the Finn AI engine, which is a continuously improving system that allows you to analyze,
train, test, and deploy with ease, Finn can continuously improve your results, too.
So if you're ready to transform your customer service and scale your support, give Finn a try for only 99 cents per resolution.
Plus, Finn comes with a 90-day money-back guarantee.
Find out how Finn can work for your team at fin.ai/lenny.
That's fin.ai/lenny.
Alexander, thank you so much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much.
I've been following for ages and I'm excited to be here.
I'm even more excited.
I really appreciate that.
I'm going to start with your time at OpenAI.
So you joined OpenAI about a year ago.
Before that, you had your own startup for about 5 years.
Before that, you were a product manager at Dropbox.
I imagine OpenAI is very different from every other place you've worked.
Let me just ask you this.
What is most different about how OpenAI operates and what's something that you've learned there that you think you're going to take with you wherever you go,
assuming you ever leave?
By far, I would say the speed and ambition of working at OpenAI are just like dramatically more than what I can imagine.
And you know, I guess it's kind of an embarrassing thing to say because you you know,
everyone who's a startup founder thinks like, "Oh yeah, my startup moves super fast and the talent bar is super high and we're super ambitious."
But I have to say like working at OpenAI just kind of like made me reimagine what it what that even means.
We hear this a lot about, you know, feels like every AI company is just like, "Oh my god,
I can't believe how fast they're moving."
Is there an example of just like, "Wow, that wouldn't have happened this quickly anywhere else?"
The most obvious thing that comes to mind is just like the the explosive growth of Codex itself.
I think it's wild since we bumped our thermal number of it, like you know, it's like the the 10x thing of Codex's scale was just like super fast in a matter of months.
And it's like well more since then.
And you know, like once you've lived through that or at least in speaking for myself,
like having lived through that now, I feel like anytime I'm going to spend my time on like,
you know, building tech product, there's that kind of that speed and scale that I now need to to to meet.
If I think of like what I was doing at my startup, it moved like way slower.
And I you know, there's always this balance with startups of like how much do you commit to an idea that you have versus like find out that it's not working uh and then pivot.
But I think one thing I've realized at OpenAI is like the the amount of impact that we can have and in fact need to have to do a good job is so high that it is a I have to be like way more ruthless with how I spend my time now.
Before we get to Codex, is there a way that they've structured the org or I don't know,
the way that OpenAI operates that allows the team to move this quickly?
Because everyone everyone wants to move super fast.
I imagine there's a structural approach to allowing this to happen.
I mean, so one thing is just the technology that we're building with has like just transformed so many things,
you know, from like both how we build, but also like what kinds of things we can enable for users.
And you know, we spend most of our time talking about like the sort of improvements in the foundation models,
but I I believe that even if we had no more progress today with models, which is absolutely not the case,
but if even if we had no more progress, we are way behind on product.
There's so much more product to build.
So I think like just like the moment is right, if that makes sense.
Mhm.
But I think there's a lot of sort of counterintuitive things that surprised me when I arrived as far as like how things are structured.
One example that comes to mind is like when I was working at my startup and and before that when I was at Dropbox,
it was like very important, you know, especially as a PM to like always kind of rally the ship and it was kind of like make sure you're pointed in the right direction and then you can like accelerate in that direction.
But here, I think because we don't exactly know like what capabilities will even come up soon and we don't know what's going to work uh technically and then we also don't know what's going to land even if it
works technically, it's much more important for us to be very like humble and learn a lot more empirically and just try things quickly.
And like the org is is set up in that way to to be incredibly bottoms up.
You know, this is again one of those things that like as you were saying, everyone wants to move fast.
I think everyone likes to say that they're bottoms up or at least a lot of people do,
but OpenAI is like truly truly bottoms up and that's like been a learning experience for me.
That now like it it'll be interesting if I ever work at I don't think that it'll ever it'll even make sense to work at a non-AI company in the future.
I don't even know what that means.
But if I were to imagine it or go back in time, I think I would like run things totally different.
What I'm hearing is kind of this ready fire aim is the approach more than ready aim fire.
And there's something and as you process that cuz that may not come across well, but I actually have heard this a lot at AI companies is because you don't know and Nick Turley shared I think the same sentiment.
Because you don't know how people will use it, it doesn't make sense to spend a lot of time making it perfect.
It's better to just get it out there in a primordial way, see how people use it, and then go big on that use case.
Yeah.
It's like to to okay, to use this analogy a little bit, I feel like there there is an aim component,
but the aim component is much fuzzier.
You know, it's kind of like roughly what do we think can happen?
Like someone um I've learned a ton from working here is a is a research lead and he likes to say that like at OpenAI,
we can you can have really good conversations about something that's like a year plus from now.
And you know, there's a lot of ambiguity in what will happen, but but like that's a right sort of timeline.
And then we can have really good conversations about what's happening like in like low months or low or weeks.
But there's kind of this like awkward middle ground, which is like as you start approaching a year,
but you're not at a year where it's like very difficult to reason about, right?
And so as far as like aiming, I think we want to know like, okay, what are some of the futures that we're trying to build towards?
And like a lot of the problems we're dealing with in AI like such as alignment or problems you need to be thinking out like really far out into the future.
So we're kind of aiming fuzzily there.
But when it comes down to the more tactically like, oh yeah, like what product will we build and therefore how will people use that product?
That's the place where we're much more like, let's find out empirically.
That's a good way of putting it.
Something else that when people hear this, they people sometimes hear companies like yours saying,
okay, we're going to be bottoms-up, we're going to try a bunch of stuff, we're not going to have exactly a plan of where it's going in the next few months.
The key is you'll hire the best people in the world.
And so that feels like a really key ingredient in order to be this successful at bottoms-up work.
And just supervising basically.
Um I was just like, again, surprised or even shocked when I arrived at like the level of like individual like drive and like autonomy that everyone here has.
So I think like the way that Open AI runs like many you can't like read this or be on the listen to a podcast and go like,
I am I'm just going to deploy this to my company.
Um you know, maybe this is a harsh thing to say, but I think like yeah, very few companies have the talent caliber to be able to do that.
So it might need to be like adjusted if you were going to implement this.
Okay, so let's talk Codex.
You lead work on Codex.
How's Codex going?
What numbers can you share?
Is there anything you can share there?
Also just not everyone knows exactly what Codex is.
Explain what Codex is.
Totally, yeah.
So I had the very lucky job of of living in the future and leading products on Codex.
Um and Codex is Open AI's coding agent.
So super concretely that means it's an IDE extension, like a VS Code extension, uh that you can install or terminal tool that you can install.
And when you do so, you can then basically pair with Codex to answer questions about code,
write code, uh you know, run tests, execute code, and do a bunch of the work in sort of that like thick middle section of the software development life cycle,
which is all about uh you know, writing code that you're going to get into production.
Uh more broadly, we think of Codex as like it's the what it currently is is just the beginning of a software engineering teammate.
And so, you know, when we when you when we use a big word like teammate, like some of the things we're imagining are that it's not only able to to write code,
but actually it participates like early on in like the ideation and planning phases of writing software,
and then further downstream in terms of like validation, deploying, and like maintaining code.
To make that a little more fun, like one thing I like to imagine is like if you think of what Codex is today,
it's a bit like this like really smart intern that like refuses to read Slack, and like doesn't check DataDog or like Sentry unless you ask it to.
And so like no matter how smart it is, like how much you're going to trust it to write code without you also working with it,
right?
So that's how people use it mostly today is they pair with it.
But we want to get to the point where, you know, it can work like just like a new intern that you hire,
and you don't only ask them to write code, but you ask them to participate across the cycle.
And so you know that like even if they don't get something right the first try, they're eventually going to be able to iterate their way there.
I thought the way I thought the point about not reading Slack and DataDog was it's just not distracted,
it's just constantly focused, and is always in flow.
But I get what you're saying there is it doesn't have all the context on everything that's going on.
And like that's not only true when it's performing a task, but again, if you think of like the best human teammates,
like you don't tell them what to do.
Right?
Like maybe when you first hire them, you have like a couple meetings and you're like,
hey, like you kind of learn like, okay, this is this these prompts work for this teammate,
these prompts don't, right?
This is how to communicate with this person.
Then eventually you give them some starter tasks, you delegate a few tasks.
But then eventually you just say like, hey, great, okay, you're working with this set of people in this area of the code base.
You know, feel free to work with other people in other parts of the code base too, even.
And uh yeah, you tell me what you think makes sense to be done.
Right?
And so, you know, we think of this is like proactivity, and like one of our major goals with Codex is to like get to proactivity.
I think this is this is like critically important to like achieve the mission of Open AI,
which is to deliver the benefits of AGI to all humanity.
You know, I like to joke today that like AI products, and it's it's a half joke, they're actually like really hard to use,
because you have to like be very thoughtful about when it could help you.
And if you're not prompting a model to help you, it's probably not helping you at that time.
And if you think of how many times like the average user is prompting AI today, it's probably like tens of times.
But if you think of how many times people could actually get benefit from a really intelligent entity,
it's thousands of times per day.
And so a large a large part of our our goal with Codex is to figure out like, what is the shape of an actual teammate agent that is sort of helpful by default?
When people think about Cursor and even Cloud Code, it's like IDE that helps you code and kind of auto-completes code and maybe does some agentic work.
What I'm hearing here is the vision is is different, which is it's a teammate.
It's like a remote teammate building code for you that you talk to and ask to do things.
And it also does a IDE auto-complete and things like that.
Is that is that a kind of a differentiator in the way you think about Codex?
It's basically this idea that like we want the way like if you're a developer and you're trying to get something done,
we want you to just feel like you have superpowers and you're able to move much, much faster.
But we don't think that in order for you to reap those benefits, you need to be sitting there constantly thinking about like,
how can I invoke AI at this point to do this thing?
We want you to be able to sort of like plug it in to the way that you work and have it just start to do stuff without you having to think about it.
Okay, I have a lot of questions on these lines, but just how's it going?
Is there any stats, any numbers you can share about how Codex is doing?
Yeah, it's been Codex has been growing like absolutely explosively since the launch of GPT-5 back in August.
Um listen, definitely some interesting like product insights to talk about as to like how we unlocked that growth if you're interested.
But again, the last the last thought we shared there was like we were like well over 10x since August.
In fact, it's been like 20x since then.
Um also, the Codex models are serving many many trillions of tokens a week now, and it's basically like our most served coding model.
Um one of the really cool things that we've seen is that the way that we decided to set up the Codex team uh was to build a you know,
a really tightly integrated product and research team that are iterating on the model and the harness together.
And it turns out that lets you just do a lot more and try many more experiments as to how these things will work together.
And so, we were just training these models for use in our first-party harness that we were very opinionated about.
And then what we've started to see more recently actually is that other major sort of API coding customers are now starting to adopt these models as well.
And so we've reached a point where actually the Codex model is the most served coding model in the API as well.
You uh hinted at this what unlocked this growth.
I am extremely interested in hearing that.
It felt like before, I don't know, maybe this was before you joined the team.
It just felt like Cloud Code was killing it.
Just everyone was sitting on top of Cloud Code.
It was by far the best way to code.
And then all of a sudden Codex comes around.
I remember Karpathy tweeted that he just like has never seen a model like this.
I think the tweet was the gnarlies bugs that he runs into that he just spends hours trying to figure out,
nothing else has solved.
He gives it to Codex, lets it run for an hour, and it solves it.
What did what did you guys do?
We have the strong sort of mission here at Open AI to, you know, basically to build AGI.
Um and so we we think a lot about what how can we shape the product so that it can scale?
Right?
You know, earlier I was mentioning like, hey, like if you're an engineer, you should be getting help from an from AI like thousands of times per day,
right?
And so we thought a lot about the primitives for that when we launched our first version of Codex,
uh which was Codex Cloud.
And that was basically a product that had its own computer, lived in the cloud, you could delegate to it.
And you know, the sort of the coolest part about that was you could run many, many tasks in parallel.
But some of the challenges that we saw are that it's a little bit harder to set that up both in terms of like environment configuration,
like giving the model the tools it needs to validate its changes, and to learn how to prompt in that way.
And sort of my my analogy for this is going back to this teammate analogy.
It's like if you hired a teammate, but you're never allowed to get on a call with them,
and you can only go back and forth, you know, asynchronously over time.
Like that works for some teammates.
And eventually that's actually how you want to spend most of your time, so that's still the future.
But it's hard to initially adopt.
And so we still have that vision of like that's what we're trying to get you to, a teammate that you delegate to and then is proactive.
And we're seeing that growing, but the key unlock is actually first you need to land with users in a way that's like much more intuitive and like trivial to get value from.
So the way that most people discover like the vast majority of users discover Codex today is either they download an IDE extension,
or they run it in their CLI, and the agent works there with you on your computer interactively.
And uh it works within a sandbox, which is actually like a really cool piece of tech to to help that be safe and secure.
But it has access to all those dependencies.
So if the agent needs to do something, like it needs to run a command, it can do so within the sandbox,
we don't have to set up any environment.
And if it's a command that doesn't work in the sandbox, it can just ask you.
And so you can get into this like really strong feedback loop using the model.
And then over time like our team's job is to like help turn that feedback loop into you sort of as a byproduct of using the product configuring it so that you can then be delegating to it down the line.
And again, analogy, you know, keep going back to it, but like if you hire a teammate and you ask them to do work,
but they you just give them like a fresh computer from the store, it's going to be hard for them to do their job,
right?
But if as you work with them side by side, you could be like, oh, you don't have a password for this service we use.
Here's the password for this service.
You know, yeah, don't worry.
Feel free to run this command."
Then it's like much easier for them to then go off and do work for hours without you.
So, what I'm hearing is the initial version of Codex was almost too far in the future.
It's like a remote in the cloud uh agent that's coding for you asynchronously.
And what you did is, okay, let's actually come back a little bit.
Let's integrate into the way engineers already integrate into IDEs and locally and help them kind of on-ramp to this new world.
Totally.
And this is it was quite interesting because we we dogfood product a ton at OpenAI.
So, you know, dogfood we as in we use our own product.
And so, Codex has been accelerating OpenAI over the course of the entire year and the cloud product was a massive accelerator to the company as well.
Um it just turns out that this is one of those places where the signal we got from dogfooding is a little bit different from the signal you get from like the general market because at OpenAI,
you know, we train reasoning models all day and so, we're very used to this kind of prompting and like,
you know, think up front, run things massively in parallel.
And uh you know, it will take some time and then come back to it later asynchronously.
And so, you know, now when we build, we still get a a ton of signal from dogfooding internally,
but uh you know, we're also very cognizant of like the different ways that different audiences use the product.
>> That's really funny.
It's like live in the future, but maybe not too far in the future.
And I could see how everyone at OpenAI is living very far in the future and sometimes that won't that won't work for everyone.
Yeah.
What about just like uh intelligence, training data?
I don't know.
Is there something else that helped Codex accelerate its ability to actually code?
Is it like better, cleaner data?
Is it more just models advancing?
Is there anything else that really helped it accelerate?
Yeah, so there's like a few components here.
Um I guess, you know, you were mentioning models and the models have improved a ton.
In fact, um just last Wednesday, we shipped GPT-5.1 Codex Max.
A very, you know, accurately named model.
Uh that is that is awesome.
It is awesome both because it is um for any given task that you were using GPT-5.1 Codex for,
it's like, you know, roughly uh 30% faster at accomplishing that task.
But also, it unlocks a ton of intelligence.
So, if you use it at our higher reasoning levels, it's just like even smarter.
Um and you know, that that feedback that or that tweet you were saying like Karpathy made about like,
"Hey, give this your gnarly bugs."
like, you know, obviously there's a a ton going on in the market right now, but like Codex Max is definitely like carrying that mantle of uh you know,
tackling the hardest bugs.
Um so, that is that is super cool.
But, I will say it's like some of what how we're thinking about this is evolving a little bit from being like,
"Yeah, we're just going to think about the model and like let's just like train the best model."
to really thinking about like what is an agent actually overall.
Right?
And you know, I'm not going to try to define agent exactly, but at least the stack that we think of it as having is just like you have this model,
really smart reasoning model, that knows how to do a specific kind of task really well,
so we can talk about how we make that possible.
But then actually, we need to serve that model through an API into a harness and both of those things also have a really big role here.
So, for instance, one of the things that we're really proud of is you can have GPT-5.1 Codex Max work for really long periods of time.
That's not like normal, but you can set it up to do that or that might happen.
But now routinely we'll hear about people saying like,"Yeah, it ran like overnight."
or it ran for 24 hours.
And so, you know, for a model to work continuously for that amount of time, it's going to exceed its context window.
And so, we have a solution for that which we call compaction.
Um that compaction is actually a feature that uses like all three layers of that stack.
So, you need to have a model that has a concept of compaction and knows like,"Okay, as I start to approach its context window,
I might be asked to like prepare to be run in a new context window."
And then at the API layer, you need an API that like understands this concept and like has an endpoint that you can hit to do this change.
And at the harness layer, you need a harness that can like prepare the payload for this to be done.
And so, like shipping this compaction feature that now just like made this behavior possible to like anyone using Codex,
actually meant working across all three things and I think that's like increasingly going to be true.
Another maybe like under-appreciated version of this is is if you think about all the different coding products out there,
they all have like very different tool harnesses with like very different opinions on how the model should work.
And so, if you want to train a model to be good at like all the different ways uh it could work,
like, you know, maybe you have a strong opinion that it should work using semantic search.
Right?
Maybe you have a strong opinion that it should like call the spoke tools.
Or maybe you have like in our case a strong opinion that it should just use like the shell,
work in the terminal.
You know, you can be much you can move much faster if you're just optimizing for one of those worlds.
Right?
And so, the way that we built Codex is that it just uses the shell, but in order to make that like safer and secure,
we have a sandbox that the model is used to operating in.
So, I think one of the biggest accelerators to go all the way back to your to your answer question is just like we're building all three things in parallel and like kind of tuning each one and um you know,
constantly experimenting with how those things work with like a tightly integrated product and research team.
How do you think you win in this space?
Do you think it it'll even it'll always be this kind of like race with other models constantly kind of leapfrogging each other?
Do you think there's a world where someone just runs away with it and no one else can ever catch up?
Is there like a path to just we win?
Again, comes back to this idea of like building a teammate.
And not just a teammate that, you know, uh participates in team planning and prioritization.
Not just a teammate that, you know, really tests its code and like helps you maintain and deploy it.
But even a teammate, you know, like if you think again, an engineering teammate, they can also like schedule a calendar invite,
right?
Or move standup.
Or do whatever, right?
And so, in my mind, if we just imagine that every day or every week some like crazy new capability is just going to be deployed by a research lab,
it's just impossible for us like, you know, as humans to keep up and like use all this technology.
And so, I think we need to get to this world where you kind of just have like an AI teammate or a super assistant that you just talk to and it just knows how
to be helpful like on its own.
Right?
And so, you don't you don't have to be like reading the latest tips for how to use it and you just like you plug it in and it just provides help.
And so, that's kind of the shape of what I think we're building and I think that will be like a very sticky like winning product if we can do so.
So, the shape that I'm in my head at least I have is that we build, you know, maybe a fun topic is like is chat the right interface for AI?
I think chat is a very good interface when you don't know what you're supposed to use it for.
Uh in the same way that if I think of like I'm like on a Teams or in Slack with a teammate,
chat is pretty good.
I can ask for whatever I want, right?
It's like kind of the common denominator for everything.
So, you can chat with a super assistant about whatever topic you want, whether it be coding or not.
And then if you are like a functional expert in a specific domain such as coding, there's like a GUI that you can pull up to go really deep and like look at the code and like work
with the code.
So, I think like what we need to build as OpenAI is basically this idea of like you have chat,
ChatGPT, and that is a tool that's like ubiquitously available to like everyone.
You start using it even like outside of work, right?
To just help you.
You become very comfortable with the idea of being accelerated with AI.
And so, then you get to work and you just can naturally just, yeah, I'm just going to ask it for this and I don't need to know about all the connectors or like all the different features.
I'm just going to ask it for help and it'll surface to me the the best way that it can help at this point in time.
And maybe even chime in when I didn't ask it for help.
Um so, in my mind if we can get to that, I think that's, you know, that's how we we really build like the winning product.
This is so interesting because at with the my chat with Nick Charney, the head of ChatGPT,
I think he shared that the original name for ChatGPT was super assistant or something like that.
Yeah.
And it's interesting that there's like that approach to the super assistant and then there's this Codex approach.
It's almost like the B2C version and the B2B version.
And what I'm hearing is the idea here is, okay, you start with coding and building and then it's doing all this other stuff for you,
scheduling meetings, I don't know, probably posting in Slack.
Uh I don't know, shipping designs.
I don't know.
Is that Is the idea there this is like the the business version of ChatGPT in a sense or is there or or is there something else there?
Yeah, so you know, so we're getting to the like the like one-year time horizon conversation.
A lot of this might happen sooner, but in terms of fuzziness, I think we're at the one-year.
So, I'll give you like a contention and like a plausible way to get there, but as for how it happens,
who knows.
So, basically, if we're going to build a super assistant, it has to be able to do things,
right?
So, like we're going to have a model and it's going to be able to do stuff affecting your world.
And one of the learnings I think we've seen over the past year or so is that for models to do stuff,
they're much more effective when they can use a computer.
Right?
Okay.
So, now we're like, "Okay, we need the super assistant that can use a computer."
Right?
Or many computers.
And now the question is, okay, well, how should it use the computer?
Right?
And there's lots of ways to use a computer.
Uh you know, you could try to hack the OS and like use accessibility APIs.
Maybe a bit easier is you could point and click.
That's a little slow, you know, and unpredictable sometimes.
Um and another way, it turns out the best way for models to use computers is simply to write code.
Right?
And so, we're kind of getting to this idea where like, "Well, if you want to build any agent,
maybe you should be building a coding agent."
And maybe to the user, a non-technical user, they won't even know they're using a coding agent the same way that no one thinks about are they using the internet or not.
It's just they're more just like,"Is Wi-Fi on?"
Right?
So, I think that what we're doing with Codex is we're building a software engineering teammate and as part of that,
we're kind of building an agent that can use uh a computer by writing code.
And so, we're already seeing like some pull for this.
It's like quite early, but we're starting to see people like who are using Codex for like coding-adjacent product purposes.
And so, as that develops, I think we'll just naturally see that like, "Oh, it turns out like we should just always have the agent write code if there is a coding way to solve a problem instead of you know,
even if you're doing in financial analysis, right?
Like maybe write some code for that.
So basically like you know, you were like, hey, is this like the two ends of of of this product for the super assistant,
right?
Of ChatGPT.
In my mind like just coding is a core competency of any agent including ChatGPT.
And so like what really what we think we're building is like that competency.
But so here's here's like the really cool thing about agents writing code is that you can import code.
Right?
Code is like composable.
Interoperable.
Right?
Cuz if if we you know, one very reductive view we could have for an agent is it's just going to be given a computer and it's just going to like point and click and and you know,
go around.
But you know, that is the future and then how we get there is difficult to sort of chart a path because a lot of the questions around building agents aren't like can the agent do it,
but it's more about well, how can we help the agent understand the context that it's working in and like the team that's using it,
you know, probably has a way that they like to do things.
They have guidelines.
They probably want certain deterministic guarantees about what the agent can or cannot do.
Or they want to know that the agent understands sort of this detail.
Like an example would be, you know, if we're looking at a crash reporting tool hitting a connector for it,
every sub-team is probably has a different meta prompt for like how they want the crashes to be analyzed.
Right?
And so we start to get to this thing where like, yeah, we have this agent sitting in front of a computer,
but we need to make that configurable for the team or for the user, right?
And let them like stuff that the agent does often, we probably just want to like build in as a competency that this agent has that it can do.
So I think we end up with this generalizable thing that you were saying of like an agent that can just write its own scripts for whatever it wants to do.
But I think that the the really key part here is can we make it so that everything that the agent has to do often or that it does well,
we can just like remember and store so that the agent doesn't have to write a script for that again,
right?
Or maybe like if I just joined a team and you are already on the same team as me, I can just like use all those scripts that the agents have written already.
Yeah, it's like if this is our teammate, we can they can share things that it's learned from working with other people at the company.
Just makes sense as a metaphor.
Yeah.
It feels like you're in the Karpathy camp of agents today are not that great and mostly slop and maybe in the future they'll be awesome.
Does that resonate?
I think so I think coding agents are pretty great.
I think Uh that's right.
Yeah.
>> Yep.
And then I think like agent side outside of coding, it's still like very early.
And you know, this is just my opinion, but I think they're going to get a whole lot better once they can use coding to and like in a composable way.
Mhm.
This is it's kind of the fun part of like when you're building for software engineers.
Like I in my setup we were building for software engineers too for a lot of that journey and they're just such a fun audience to build for because you know,
they also like building for themselves and are often like even more creative than we are in thinking about how to use the technology.
Um and so like by building for software engineers, you get to just observe a ton of emergent behaviors and like things that you should do and build into the product.
I love how you you say that cuz a lot of people building for engineers get really annoyed cuz the engineers are so they're just always complaining about stuff.
They're like, ah, this sucks.
Why did you build it this way?
I love that you enjoy it, but I think it's probably because you're building such an amazing tool for engineers that can actually solve problems and just you know,
code for them.
Um kind of along those lines, you know, there's always this talk of what will happen to jobs,
coding, do you have to learn coding, all these things?
Clearly the way you're describing it is it's a teammate.
It's going to work with you making more superhuman.
It's not going to replace you.
What's the way you just think about the impact on the field of engineering having this super intelligent engineering teammate?
I think there's there's two sides to it, but the one we were just talking about is this idea that maybe every agent should actually use code and be a coding agent.
And in my mind that's just like a small part of this like broader idea that like, hey,
as we make code even more ubiquitous.
I mean, you could probably claim it's ubiquitous today even pre-AI, right?
And as you make code even more ubiquitous, it's actually just going to be used for many more purposes.
And so there's just going to be a ton more need for people with this like humans with this competency.
So that's my view.
I think this is like quite a complex topic.
So you know, you know, it's something we talk about a lot and we have to kind of see how it pans out,
but I think what we can do what we can do basically as a product team building in the space is just try to always think about how are we building a tool so that it feels like we're like maximally accelerating uh people.
You know, rather than building a tool that makes it like more unclear what you should do as the human.
Right?
Like I think like to to you know, give an example right now like nowadays when you work with a coding agent,
um it writes a ton of code, but it turns out writing code is actually one of the most fun parts of software engineering for many software engineers.
And so then you end up reviewing AI code.
Right?
And that's often a less fun part of the job for many software engineers, right?
And so I actually think like we see that like this this comes out plays out all the time in like a ton of micro decisions and so we as a product team are always thinking about like,
okay, how do we make this more fun?
How do we make you feel more empowered?
Where is this not working?
And I would argue that like reviewing agent written code is like a place that today is like less fun and so you know,
then I think, okay, what can we do about that?
Well, we can ship a code review feature that like helps you both confidence the AI written code.
Okay, cool.
You know, another thing we could do is we can make it so that the agent's like better able to validate its work.
And you know, it it gets all the way down into like micro decisions.
Like if you're going to have the an agent capability to validate work and let's say you have like I'm thinking of Codex web right now.
Like you have a a pane that sort of reflects the work the agent did.
What do you see first?
Do you see the diff or do you see the image preview of the code it wrote?
Right?
And you know, I think if you're thinking about this from perspective like, how do I empower the human?
How do I make them feel like as as accelerated as possible?
Like you obviously see the image first, right?
You shouldn't be reviewing the code unless first you know, you've seen the image unless it's maybe it's been like reviewed by an AI and now it's time for you to take a look.
When I had Michael Turalda, CEO of Cursor on the podcast, he had this kind of vision of us moving to something beyond code.
And I've seen this rise of something called spec driven development where you kind of just write the spec and then the code,
you know, the AI writes the code for you and so you kind of start working at this higher abstraction level.
Is that something you see where we're going?
Just like engineers not having to actually write code or look at code and there's going to be this higher level of abstraction that we focus on.
Yeah, I mean, I think I think there's like constantly these levels of abstraction and they're actually already played out today.
Right?
Like today like coding agents mostly it's like prompt to patch.
We're starting to see people doing like spec driven development or like plan driven development.
That's actually one of the ways people ask like, hey, how do you run Codex on a really long task?
Well, it's like often collaborate with it first to write like a plan.md like a markdown file that's your plan.
And once you're happy with that, then you ask it to to go off and do work and if that plan has verifiable steps,
it'll like work for much longer.
Um so we're totally seeing that.
I think spec driven development is like an interesting idea.
It's not clear to me that it'll work out that way cuz a lot of people don't write like don't like writing specs either.
But it it seems plausible that some some people will work that way.
You know, like uh a bit of a joke idea though is like if you think of like um the way that many teams work today,
they're they often like don't necessarily have specs, but the team is just really self-driven and so stuff just gets done and so almost that is like I'm coming up with this on the spot.
So it's you know, not a good name, but like chatter driven development.
Where it's just like stuff is happening, you know, on social media and like in your team communications tools and then as a result like code gets written and deployed.
Right?
So yeah, I think I'm a little bit more oriented in that way of you know, I don't even necessarily want to have to write a spec.
Like sometimes I want to only if I like writing specs.
Right?
Other times I might just want to say like, hey, here's like the customer, you know, service channel and like tell me what's interesting to know,
but if it's a small bug, just fix it.
I don't want to have to write a spec for that, I have this sort of uh hypothetical future uh that I like to share with sometimes with people as a provocation which is like in a world where we have like truly
amazing agents, like what does it look like to be a solopreneur?
Um and uh you know, one terrible idea for how it could look is that it's actually is a mobile app.
And um every idea that it the agent has to do is just like vertical video on your phone.
And then you can like swipe left if you think it's a bad idea and you can like swipe right if it's a good idea and like you can press and hold and like speak to your phone if you want to give feedback on the idea before you swipe.
You know, and in this world like basically what your job is just like plug in this app into like every single like signal system,
you know, system of record and then you just sort of sit back and like swipe.
I don't know.
I love this.
So this is like Tinder meets TikTok meets Codex.
It's pretty terrible.
No, this is great.
So the idea here is this thing is this agent is watching and right listening to you,
paying attention to the market, your users and it's like, well, I hear something I should do.
It's like a proactive engineer.
Just like, here, we should build this feature or fix this thing.
Exactly.
I think it's a really good idea.
Communicating with you in like the lowest like effort way.
>> the gyms, like the the modern way we communicate.
Yeah, swipe left or right and in vertical feed.
And then the Sora video.
Okay, I see how this all connects now.
I see.
>> Yeah, to be clear, we're not building that, but like, you know, it's a fun idea.
I mean, you can see now like in this example though, like one of the things that it's doing is it's consuming external signals,
right?
I think the other really interesting thing is like if we think about like what is the most successful like AI product to date?
Um I would argue um funny actually not to confuse things at all, but like with the first time we used in the the brand Codex at OpenAI was actually the model powering GitHub Copilot.
This is like way back in the day years ago.
Uh so we decided to reuse that that brand recently um cuz it's just so good.
You know, Codex, code execution.
But I think actually like auto completion in IDEs is like one of the most successful AI products today.
And part of what's so magical about it is that when the it can surface like ideas for helping you really rapidly.
When it's right, you're accelerated.
When it's wrong, it's not like that annoying.
It can be annoying, but it's not that annoying.
Right?
And so you can create this like mixed initiative system that's like contextually responding to like what you're attempting to do.
And so in my mind, this is like a really interesting thing for us as OpenAI as we're building.
So for instance, you know, when I think about launching a browser, which we did with Atlas,
right?
Like in my mind, one of the really interesting things we can then do is we can then like contextually surface like ways that we can help you as you're going about your day.
Right?
And so we break out of this like you know, we're just looking at code or we're just in your terminal um into this idea that like,
"Hey, like a real teammate is dealing with a lot more than just code, right?
They're dealing with a lot of things that are web content."
So like, you know, how can we help you with that?
Man, there's so much there.
I love this.
Okay, so auto complete on web with the browser, that's so interesting.
Just like here's all the things that we can help you with as you're browsing and going about your day.
I want to talk about Atlas.
I'll come back to that.
Uh Codex, code execution, did not know that.
That's really clever.
I I get it now.
Okay, and then this chatter.
What is a chatter driven development?
Uh I had a No, this is a really good idea.
But it reminds me I had John G Donji on the podcast, CTO of Block, and they they have this product called Goose,
which is their own internal agent thing.
And he talked about an engineer at Block just uh has Goose watch him with like his screen and listens to
every meeting and proactively does work that he should probably want to do.
So ships a PR, sends an email, drafts a Slack message.
So he's doing exactly what you're describing in in kind of a very early way.
Yeah, that's super interesting.
And you know, I bet you the so if we go if we went and asked them what the bottleneck to that productivity is,
did did they share what it is?
Uh probably looking at it and just making sure this is the right the right thing to do.
Yeah.
Yeah, so like we see this now.
Like we have a Slack integration for Codex.
People love, you know, if there's like something that you need to do quickly, people will just like at mention Codex.
Like, "Why do you think this bug is happening?"
Right?
Doesn't have to be an engineer.
Even like maybe, you know, data scientists often in here are using Codex a ton to just like answer questions.
Like, "Why do you think this metric moved?
What happened?"
So questions, you know, you get the answer right back in Slack, it's amazing, super useful.
But when it's as for when it's writing code, then you have to go back and look at the code.
Right?
And so the real like I think bottleneck right now is like validating that the code worked and like writing code review.
So in my mind, if we wanted to get to something like you know, the friend you were talking about's world,
I think we we really need to figure out how to get people to configure their coding agents to be much more autonomous on those later stages of the work.
It makes sense.
Like you said, writing code I used to be an engineer, I was an engineer for 10 years.
Really fun to write code, really fun to just get in the flow, build, architect, test.
Not so fun to look at everyone else's code and just have to go through and be on the hook if it is doing something dumb that's going to take down production.
And now that building has become easier, what I've always heard from companies that are really at the cutting edge of this is the bottleneck is now like figuring out what to build and then it's at the end of like a Okay,
we have all this all 100 PRs to review.
Who's going to go through all that?
Right.
Yeah.
This episode is brought to you by Jira Product Discovery.
The hardest part of building products isn't actually building products.
It's everything else.
It's proving that the work matters, managing stakeholders, trying to plan ahead.
Most teams spend more time reacting than learning, chasing updates, justifying roadmaps,
and constantly unblocking work to keep things moving.
Jira Product Discovery puts you back in control.
With Jira Product Discovery, you can capture insights and prioritize high impact ideas.
It's flexible, so it adapts to the way your team works and helps you build a roadmap that drives alignment,
not questions.
And because it's built on Jira, you can track ideas from strategy to delivery, all in one place.
Less chasing, more time to think, learn, and build the right thing.
Get Jira Product Discovery for free at atlassian.com/lenny.
That's atlassian.com/lenny.
What is the impact of Codex been on the way you operate as a product person as a PM?
It's clear how engineering is impacted.
Uh code is written for you.
What has it done to the way you operate in the way PMs operate at at OpenAI?
Yeah, I mean I think mostly I just feel like much more empowered.
Um I've always been sort of more technical leaning PM.
And especially when I'm working on products for engineers, I feel like it's necessary to like,
you know, dogfood the product.
But even beyond that, I I I just feel like I can do much much more as a PM.
And uh you know, Scott Belsky talks about this idea of like compressing the talent stack.
I'm not sure if I'm phrased that right.
But it's basically this idea that like maybe the boundaries between these roles are a little bit like less needed than before because people can just do much more.
And every time you someone can do more, you can like skip one communication boundary and make the team like that much more efficient.
Right?
So I think I think we see it you know, in a bunch of functions now, but I guess since you asked about like product specifically,
uh you know, now like answering questions much much easier.
You you know, just ask Codex for thoughts on that.
Uh a lot of like PM type work, understanding what's changing, again, just ask Codex for help with that.
Um prototyping is often faster than writing specs.
This is something that a lot of people have talked about.
I think something that I don't think it's super surprising, but something that's slightly surprising is like we see like we're mostly building Codex for to write code that's going to be deployed to production.
But actually we see a lot of throwaway code written with Codex now.
It's kind of going back to this idea of like, you know, ubiquitous code.
So you'll see uh you know, someone wants to do an analysis.
Like if I want to understand something, it's like, "Okay, just give Codex a bunch of data,
but then ask it to build like an interactive like data viewer for this data."
Right?
You would That's just like too annoying to do in the past, but now it's just like totally worth the time of just getting an agent to go do something.
Um similarly, I've seen like some pretty cool prototypes on our design team about like if you want to well,
like a designer basically wanted to build an animation.
And this is the coin animation in Codex.
And it was like normally it'd be too annoying to program this animation, so they just vibe coded a animation editor.
And then they use the animation editor to build the animation, which they then checked into the repo.
Actually, our designers are there's a ton of acceleration there and like speaking of compressing the talent stack,
I think our designers are very PM-y.
So, you know, they they do a ton of product work and like they actually have like an entire like vibe coded sort of side prototype of the Codex app.
And so a lot of how we talk about things is like we'll have like a really quick jam cuz there's like 10,000 things going on.
And then the designer will like go think about how this should work, but instead of like talking about it again,
they'll just like vibe code a prototype of that in their like standalone prototype.
We'll play with it.
If we like it, they'll vibe code that prototype into or vibe engineer that prototype into an actual PR to land.
And then depending on their comfort with the code base, like Codex UI is in Rust, that's a little harder.
Maybe they'll like land it themselves or they'll like get close and then an engineer can help them like land the PR.
Um you know, we recently shipped the Sora Android app.
Um and uh that was one of the most sort of mind-blowing examples of acceleration actually cuz the usage of Codex internally at OpenAI is obviously really
really high, but it's been growing uh over the course of the year both in terms of like now it's basically like all technical staff use it.
Uh but even like the intensity and know-how of how to make the most of coding agents has gone up by a ton.
And so the Sora Android app, right?
Like a fully new app, we built it in 18 days.
It went from like zero to launch to employees.
And then 10 days later, so 28 days total, we went to just like GA to the public.
And that was done just like with the help of Codex.
So pretty insane velocity.
I would say it was like a little bit I don't want to say easy mode, but there is one thing that Codex is really good at if you're a company that's like building software on multiple platforms.
So you've already figured out like some of the underlying like APIs or systems.
Asking Codex to sit like to port things over is really effective cuz it has like something it can go look at.
And so the engineers on that team uh were basically having Codex go look at the iOS app,
produce plans of work that needed to be done, and then go implement those.
And it was kind of looking at iOS and Android at the same time.
And so, you know, basically it was like 2 weeks to launch to employees, 4 weeks total.
Insanely fast.
What makes that even more insane is it was the it became the number one app in the App Store.
I don't this just boggles the mind.
Okay, so Yeah, so imagine there's the number one app in the App Store with like a handful of engineers.
Uh I think it was like two or three possibly uh in a handful of weeks.
Yeah.
This is absurd.
So yeah, so that's a really fun um example of acceleration and then like Atlas is the other one that I think Ben did a podcast the the the
engine on Atlas uh sharing a little bit about how we built there.
You know, many Atlas is is actually I mean it's a it's a browser, right?
And building a browser is really hard.
Um and so we uh had to build a lot of difficult systems in order to do that.
And basically we got to the point where that team has a ton of power users of Codex right now.
And you know, got to the point where they they were basically we you know, we were talking to them about it cuz a lot of those engineers are people I I to work with uh before at my startup.
And so they'd say, you know, before this would have taken us like 2 to 3 weeks for two to three engineers.
And now it's like one engineer, one week.
Um so, massive acceleration there as well.
And what's quite cool is that uh you know, we we shipped Atlas on on Mac first, but now we're working on the Windows version.
You know, that So, the team now is like ramping up on Windows, and they're helping us make Codex better on Windows,
too.
Which is admittedly earlier.
Like, just the model we we shipped last week is the first model that natively understands PowerShell.
So, you know, PowerShell being uh the native like shell language on Windows.
So, yeah, it's been it's been really awesome to see like the whole company getting accelerated by Codex like from And you know,
most obviously also research and like improving how quickly we train models and how well we do it,
and then even like uh design as we talked about and and marketing.
Like, actually we're at this point now where uh my product marketer is often also making string changes just directly from Slack.
Or like updating docs directly from Slack.
These are amazing examples.
You guys are living at the bleeding edge of what is possible, and this is how other companies are going to work.
Uh just shipping again, what became the number one app in the App Store and just beloved all over the It just like took over the I don't know,
the world for at least a week.
Uh built, you said in 28 days and like I don't know, 10 days, 18 days just to get like the core of it working.
>> Yeah, so it's like 18 days we had a thing that employees were playing with, and then 10 days later we were out.
And you said just a couple engineers.
Yeah.
Two or three.
Okay.
And then Atlas, you said it was took a week to build.
>> No, no, no.
So, Atlas is not the whole week, but Atlas was like a really meaty project.
Yeah.
Um and so I was talking to one of the engineers on Atlas um about like, you know, just how what they use Codex for.
And it's basically like, we use Codex for absolutely everything.
I was like, okay.
Well, like you know, how would you how would you measure the acceleration?
And so, basically the the answer I got back was previously would have taken two to three weeks for two to three engineers,
and now it's like one engineer, one week.
Do you think this eventually moves to non-engineers doing this sort of thing?
Like, does it have to be an engineer building this thing?
Could sort of built been built by a I don't know, a PM or a designer?
I think we will very much get to the point where Well, basically where the boundaries are a little bit blurred.
Right?
Like I think we you're going to want someone who's like understands the details of what they're building,
but what details those are will evolve.
Kind of like how now like, if you're writing Swift, you don't have to speak assembly.
You know, there's a handful of people in the world, and it's really important that they exist and like speak assembly.
Uh maybe more than a handful, right?
But that's like a specialized function that like most companies don't need to have.
So, I think we're just going to naturally see like an increase in layers of abstraction.
And then the cool thing is now we're we're entering like the language layer of abstraction,
like natural language.
And then natural language itself is really flexible.
Right?
Like, you could have engineers talking about like a plan, and then you could have engineers talking about a spec,
and then you could have engineers talking about just you know, a product or an idea.
So, I think we can also like start moving up those layers of of abstraction as well.
But you know, I I do think this is going to be gradual.
I don't think it's going to go up to like all of a sudden like nobody ever writes anything and like,
you know, any code and it's just specs.
I think it's going to be much more like, okay, we've set up our coding agent to be really good at like previewing the build or like at running tests.
Maybe that's the first part, right?
That most people have set up.
And it's like, okay, now we've set it up so that it can like execute the build and it can like see the results of its own changes,
but you know, we haven't yet built a good integration harness so that it can like in the case of Atlas,
like By the way, I don't know if they've done any of this or not.
I think they've done a lot of this, but you know, maybe the next stage is like enable it to like load a few sample pages to see how well those work,
right?
So, then okay, now we're going to like set up set up through that.
And I think for some time at least we're going to have humans kind of curating like which of these connectors or systems or components that it the agent needs to be good at talking to.
And then, you know, in the future there will be an even greater unlock where Codex tells you how to set it up or maybe sets itself up in a repo.
What a wild time to be alive.
Wow.
I'm curious just the second-order effects of this sort of thing, just how quickly it is to build stuff.
What does that do?
Does that mean distribution becomes much, much more important?
Does it mean uh ideas are just worth a lot more?
It's interesting to think about how quick how that changes.
I I'm curious what you think.
I still don't think ideas are worth as much as maybe some a lot of people think.
I think still think execution is really hard, right?
Like, you can build something fast, but you still need to execute well on it.
Still needs to make sense and be a coherent thing overall.
Um yeah, and distribution is massive.
Yeah.
Just feels like everything else is now more important.
Everything that isn't the building piece, which is coming up with the idea, getting to market,
profit, all that kind of stuff.
>> Yeah.
I I think we might have been in this weird temporary phase where you know, for a while like you could you could just it was so hard to build product that
you mostly just had to be really good at building product, and it maybe didn't matter if you like had a intimate understanding of a specific customer.
Um but now I think we're getting to this point where actually like, if I could only choose like one thing to understand,
it would be like really meaningful understanding of like the problems that a certain customer has.
Right?
If I could only if I could only go in with one like core competency.
So, I think that that's that's ultimately still what's going to matter most, right?
Like, if you're starting a new company today and you have like a really good understanding and like network of customers that are currently underserved by AI tools,
I think you're like you're set.
Right?
Whereas if you're like good [clears throat] at building like, you know, websites, but you don't have any specific customer to build for,
I think you're in in for a much harder time.
Bullish on vertical AI startups is what I'm hearing.
Yeah, I completely agree.
There's like, you know, there's like the general thing that can solve a lot of problems,
and then there's like, we're going to solve presentations incredibly well, and we're going to understand the presentation problem uh better than anyone,
and we're going to uh plug into your workflows and and all these other things that matter for a very specific problem.
Okay.
Incredible.
When you think about progress on Codex, I imagine you have a bunch of evals, and there's all these public benchmarks.
What's something you look at to tell you, okay, we're making really good progress?
I imagine it's not going to be the one thing, but what do you focus on?
What's like something you're trying to push?
What's like a KPI or two?
One of the things that I'm constantly reminding myself of is that a tool like Codex sort of naturally is a tool that you would you know,
become a power user of.
Right?
And so, we can accidentally spend a lot of our time thinking about features that are like very deep in the user adoption journey.
Um and so, we can kind of end up over-solving for that.
And so, I think it's like just critically important to like go look at like your like D7 retention.
Right?
Just go try the product.
Like, sign up from scratch again.
Um I have a few too many like ChatGPT Pro accounts that I've just like in order to maximally correctly dog food like sign up for on my Gmail,
and they charge me like 200 bucks a month.
I need to expense those.
But uh uh you know, like I think just like the feeling of being a user and the early retention stats are still like super important for us because you you know,
as much as this category is is taking off, I think we're still in the very early days of like people using them.
Um another thing that we do that that may might be I think we might be the most like user feedback  social media pilled team out there in this space
is like a few of us are like constantly on Reddit and Twitter.
And you know, there's uh there's praise up there, and there's a lot of complaints, but we take the complaints like very seriously and look at them.
And I think that again, because you can use a coding agent for so many different things,
um it often is like kind of broken in many sort of ways for like specific behaviors.
Um and so, we we actually monitor a lot just like what the vibes are on social media pretty often.
Especially I think for for Twitter X, um it's a little bit more hypey.
And then Reddit is a little more negative, but real actually.
Um so, I've started increasingly paying attention to like how people are talking about using Codex on Reddit actually.
This is uh important for people to know.
Which subreddits do you check most?
Is there like an r/Codex or I mean, the algorithm's pretty good at surfacing stuff, but like r/Codex is is there.
Okay.
I'll take.
Very interesting.
And then uh if people tag you on Twitter, you still see that, but maybe not as powerful as seeing it on Reddit.
Well, yeah, the interesting Well, the thing with Twitter is it's a little bit more one-to-one even if it's like in public.
Whereas like with Reddit, there's a like really good upvoting mechanics, and like maybe most people are still not bots.
Unclear.
Um so, you get you get like good signal on what matters and what other people think.
So, interestingly Atlas, I want to talk about that briefly.
You guys launched Atlas.
I tweeted actually that I tried Atlas, and then I I don't love the AI-only search experience.
I just like I just want to Google sometimes or whatever.
Like, just waiting for the AI to give me an answer.
I'm like, I don't want to And there was no way to switch, so I just tweeted, "Hey, I'm I'm switching back.
I don't It's not a great."
And I feel like I made some PMs at OpenAI sad.
And I saw someone tweet, "Okay, we have this now."
Which I imagine was always part of the plan.
It's probably an example of we just ship We got to ship stuff.
See how people use it, and then we figure it out.
Uh so, I guess one is that I don't know, is there anything there?
And two, I'm just curious, why are you guys building a web browser?
So, I I worked on Atlas for a bit.
Um I don't work on it now.
Um but you know, like the a bit of the narrative here for for me to tell my story a bit was like,
I was working on this like screen sharing like pair programming startup.
Right?
And then we joined OpenAI.
And so, the idea was really to build a contextual desktop assistant.
And the reason I believe that's so important is because I think that it's really annoying to have to give all your context to an assistant and then to figure out how it can help you.
Right?
And so, if it could just like understand what you were trying to do, then it could maximally accelerate you.
Um and so, I I I would you know, I still think of Codex actually as like a contextual assistant.
Um from a little bit of a different angle, like starting with coding tasks.
But um the some of the some of the thinking at least for me personally, I can't speak for the whole product,
but it was that a lot of work is done in the web, and if we could build a browser, then we could be contextual for you,
but in a much more first-class way.
We weren't hacking like other desktop software which have like very varied support for for like what content they're rendering to the accessibility tree.
Uh, we wouldn't be relying on screenshots, which are a little bit slower and unreliable.
Instead, we we we could like be in the rendering engine, right?
And like extract whatever we needed to to help you.
Um, and also, I like to think of like, you know, in video games, like, I don't know if you've played like,
I don't know, say Halo, right?
Like, you walk up to an object.
I mean, this is true for many games.
You press Now, it's been a long time.
This is embarrassing.
Press X and it just does the right thing, right?
And I was one of those guys who always read the instruction manual for every video game that I bought.
And I remember the first time I read about a contextual action and I just thought it was like this really cool idea.
And, uh, you know, the the thing about a contextual action is we need to know what you are attempting to do.
We have a little bit of context, and then we can and then we can help.
Uh, and I think this is critically important because, you know, imagine this world that we reach,
right?
Where where we have agents that are helping you thousands of times per day.
Um, imagine if the only way we could tell you that we helped you is if we could like push notify you.
So, you get a thousand push notifications a day of an AI saying like, "Hey, I did this thing.
Do you like it?"
It gets super annoying, right?
Whereas, imagine going back to software engineering, like, I was looking at a dashboard and I noticed some like key metric had like gone down.
And, you know, at that point in time, an AI could like maybe go take a look and then surface the fact that it has an opinion on why this metric went down and maybe a fix right there right when I'm looking at the dashboard.
Right?
That would be like that would much more keep me in flow and enable the agents to take action on like many more things.
So, in my mind, like, part of why I'm excited for us to have a browser is that I think we have then like much more context around like what we should help with.
Users have much more control over what they want us to look at.
It's like, "Hey, if you want to open If you want us to like take action on something,
you can open it in your AI browser.
If you don't, then you can open it in your other browser."
Right?
So, like really clear control and boundaries.
And then, we have the ability to build UX that's like mixed initiative so that we can surface contextual actions to you like at the time that they're helpful,
as opposed to just like randomly notifying you.
Hearing the vision for Codex being the super assistant.
It's not just there to code for you.
It's trying to do a lot for you as a teammate and as this kind of super teammate that makes you awesome at work.
So, I get this.
Speaking of that, are there other non-engineering common use cases for Codex?
Just ways that non-engineers We talked about it, you know, designers prototyping, building stuff.
Are there any kind of other unexpected ways people are using Codex that aren't engineers?
I mean, there's a load of a load of unexpected ways, but I think like most of what we're seeing like real traction with people using things are still for now like very like
I would say coding adjacent or like sort of tech-oriented places where there's like a mature ecosystem.
Um, or, you know, maybe you're doing data data analysis or something like that.
I personally am expecting that we're going to see a lot more of that over time.
Um, but for now, like, we're keeping the team like very focused on just coding for now cuz there's so much more work to do.
For people that are thinking about trying out Codex, is there like a Does it work for all kinds of code bases?
Uh, what what code does it support?
If you're like, I don't know, SAP, can you add Codex and start building things?
What's kind of like the sweet spot?
Where does it start to not be amazing yet?
This I'm really glad you asked this question, actually, because the best way to try Codex is to give it your hardest tasks,
which is a little different than some of the other coding agents.
Like, you know, some tools you might think, "Okay, let me like start easy or just like,
you know, like vibe code something random and decide if I like the tool."
Whereas, like, we're really building Codex to be the like professional tool that you can give your like hardest problems to.
Um, and you know, that writes like high-quality code in your like enormous code base that is in fact not perfect right now.
So, yeah, I think if you're going to try Codex, you want to try it on like a real task that you have,
and not necessarily like dumb that task down to something that's like trivial, but actually like,
you know, like, a good one would be like you have a hard bug and you don't know what what's causing that bug and you ask Codex to like help figure that out.
Or like to implement that, you know, the fix.
I love that answer.
Just give it your hardest problem.
I will say like, you know, if you if you're like, "Hey, okay, but well, the hardest problem I have is that I need to build like a new unicorn business."
Like, obviously, that, you know, it's not going to work.
Uh, not yet.
So, I think it's like give it like the hardest problem, but something that is still like one like question,
right?
Or one task, um, to start.
That's if you're testing, and then over time, you can learn how to use it for like bigger things.
Yeah, what languages does does it support?
Basically, the way we've trained Codex is like there's a distribution of languages that we support,
and it's like fairly aligned with like the frequency of these languages in the world.
So, unless you're writing some like very esoteric language or like some private language,
it should do fine in your language.
If someone was just getting started, is there a tip you could share to help them be successful?
Like, if you could just whisper a little tip into someone just setting up Codex for the first time to help them have a really good time.
What's something you'd whisper?
I might say try a few things in parallel.
Right?
So, you could try giving it a hard task.
Um, maybe ask it to understand the code base.
Uh, formulate a plan with it around an idea that you have, and kind of build your way up from there.
And like, sort of the meta idea here is it's again, it's like you're building trust with a new teammate.
Right?
And so, like, you wouldn't go to a new teammate and just give them like,"Hey, do this thing.
Here's zero context."
You would start by like first making sure they understand the code base, and then you would like maybe align on a plan and approach,
and then you would have them go off and do it bit by bit.
Right?
And I think if you use Codex in that way, you'll just sort of naturally start to understand like the different ways of prompting it because it is it's a super powerful like agent and model,
but it is it is a little bit different to prompt Codex than other models.
Just a couple more questions.
One, we touched on this a little bit.
As AI does more and more coding, there's always this question of should I learn to code?
And what do I should I spend time doing this sort of thing?
For people that are trying to figure out what to do with their career, especially if they're into software engineering,
computer science, do you think there are specific elements of computer science that are more and more important to lean into?
Maybe things they don't need to worry about.
Like, what do you think people should be leaning into skill-wise in as this becomes more and more of a thing in our workplace?
I think there's like a couple angles you could go at this from.
Um, I think the Well, the easiest one to think of at least is just like be a doer of things.
Um, I think that, you know, with coding agents um, getting better and better over time,
it's just what you can do as even like someone in college or a new grad is just like so much more than what that was before.
And so, I think you just want to be taking advantage of that.
And definitely when I'm looking at like hiring folks who are earlier career, it's like definitely something that I think about is how how productive are they using the latest tools?
Right?
They should be like super productive.
And if you think of it in that way, they actually have like less of a handicap than before versus a a more senior career person because,
you know, the divide is actually getting smaller because they've got these amazing coding agents now.
Um, so, that's one thing, which is just like, I guess the thing the advice is just like learn about whatever you want,
but just make sure you spend time doing things, not just like fulfilling homework assignments,
I guess.
I think the other side of it, though, is that it's still deeply worth understanding like what makes a good like overall software system.
So, I still think that like skills like really strong systems engineering skills or even like really effective like communication and collaboration with your team.
Skills like that, I think, are are important.
They're going to continue to matter for for quite some time.
Like, I don't think it's going to be like all of a sudden, uh, the AI coding agents are just able to build like perfect systems without your help.
I think it's going to look much more gradual, where it's like,"Okay, we have these AI coding agents.
They're able to validate their work."
It's still important and like that for example, like, thinking of an engineer who was working on Atlas since we were talking about it,
he set up Codex so that it can like verify its own work, which is a little bit non-trivial because of the the nature of the Atlas product.
So, the way that he did that was he actually prompted Codex like,"Hey, why can't you verify your work?
Fix it."
And like did that on a loop.
Right?
And so, you still like at various phases are going to want a human in the loop to like help configure the coding agent to be effective.
And so, I think like you still want to be able to reason about that.
So, maybe it's like less important that you can like type really fast and like you understand exactly how to write Not that anyone writes a,
you know, for each loop or something, right?
But, it is or, you know, you don't need to know how to implement like a specific algorithm.
But, I think you need to be able to reason about the different systems and like what makes like effective a software engineering team effective.
So, I think that's uh the other really important thing.
And then like maybe the last angle that you could take is I think if you're on the frontier of knowledge for a given thing,
I still think that's like deeply interesting to go down.
Partially because that knowledge is still going to be like uh, you know, agents aren't going to be as good at that,
but also partially because I think that like by trying to advance the frontier of a specific thing,
you'll actually like end up like being forced to take advantage of coding agents and like using them to accelerate your own workflows as you go.
What's an example that when you when you talk about being at the frontier of something?
Codex writes a lot of the code that helps like manage its training runs, the key infrastructure.
Uh, you know, we move pretty fast, and so we have a Codex code review is like catching a lot of mistakes.
It's actually caught some like pretty interesting configuration mistakes.
And, uh, you know, we're starting to see glimpses of the future where we're actually starting to have Codex even like be on call for its own training,
which is pretty interesting.
Um so, there's lots there.
Uh wait, what does that mean to be on call for its own training?
So, it's running, it's training, and it's like,"Oh, something broke.
Someone needs" And it it does it like alert people or it's like, "Here, I'm going to fix the problem and re- Yeah,
this is an early idea that we're like figuring out.
But the basic idea is that, you know, during a training run, there's like a bunch of graphs that like today like humans are looking at and it's like really important to like look at those.
Um we call this babysitting.
Because it's very expensive to train, I imagine, and very important to move fast and Exactly.
And there's a lot of there's a lot of systems underlying uh the training run.
And so, like a system could go down or there could be an error somewhere that gets introduced.
And so, we might need to like fix it or pause things or I don't know, there's lots of actions we might need to take.
And so, basically having Codex like run on a loop to like evaluate how those charts are moving over time,
um this sort of this idea that we have to like how to enable us to like train like way more efficiently.
I love that.
This is very much along the lines of this is the future of agents.
It's Codex isn't just for building code, right?
It's it's a lot more than that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Last question.
Uh being at OpenAI, uh I can't not ask about your AGI timeline and how far you think we are from AGI.
I know this isn't what you work on, but there's a lot of opinions, a lot of I don't know,
timelines.
How far do you think that we are from a uh humanly human version of AI, whatever that means to you?
For me, I think that it's a little bit about like when do we see the acceleration curves kind of go like this or I don't know which way I'm mirrored here.
Right?
When do we see the hockey stick?
And I think that the current limiting factor, I mean, there's many, but I think a current underappreciated limiting factor is like literally human typing speed or human multitasking speed
on like writing prompts.
Right?
And like, you know, you were talking about it's like you can have an agent like watch all the work you're doing,
but if you don't have the agent uh also validating its work, then you're still bottlenecked on like,
can you go review all that code, right?
So, my view is that we need to um unblock those productivity loops from like humans having to prompt and humans having to like about manually evaluate all the work.
And so, if we can like rebuild systems to let the agent like be default useful, we'll start unlocking hockey sticks.
Unfortunately, I don't think that's going to be binary.
I think it's going to be very dependent on what you're building, right?
So, like I would imagine that like next year, if you're a startup, and you're building a new new pieces like,
you know, some new app or something, it'll be possible for you to set it up on a stack where agents are like much more self-sufficient than not,
right?
But now, let's say I I don't know, you mentioned SAP, right?
Let's say you work in SAP.
Like they have many like complex systems and they're not going to be able to just like get the agent to be self-sufficient overnight in those systems.
So, they're going to have to slowly like maybe replace systems or update systems to allow the agent to like handle more of the work end to end.
And so, basically my sort of long answer to your question, maybe boring answer, is that I think starting next year,
we're going to see like early adopters like starting to like hockey stick their productivity.
Um and then over the years that follow, we're going to see larger and larger companies like hockey stick their productivity.
And then somewhere in that fuzzy middle is like when that hockey sticking will be like flowing back into the AI labs and that's when we'll we'll basically be at the AGI tier.
I love this answer.
It's very practical and it's something that comes up a lot on this podcast, just like the time to review all the things AI is doing is really annoying and a big bottleneck.
I love that you're working on this because it's one thing to just make coding much more efficient and do that for people,
it's another to take care of that final step of, okay, is this actually great?
And that's so interesting that your sense is that's the limiting factor.
It comes back to your earlier point of even if AI did not advance anymore, we have so much more potential to unlock if we uh as we learn to use it more effectively.
Uh so, that is a really unique answer.
I've never heard that perspective on what is the big unlock.
Human typing speed to review basically what AI is doing for us.
Mhm.
So good.
Okay.
Uh Alexander, we covered a lot of ground.
Is there anything that we haven't covered?
Is there anything you wanted to share, maybe double down on before we get to our very exciting lightning round?
I think one thing is that the Codex team is growing.
And uh as I was just saying, we're still somewhat limited by human thinking speed and human typing speed.
We're working on it.
So, um if you're an engineer um or a salesperson or I'm hiring for product product person,
uh please hit us up.
I'm not sure the best way to give contact info, but I guess you can go to a jobs page or do they have contact for you?
Actually, do you do listeners have contact for you?
Before they send me like, "Hey, I want to apply to Codex."
Uh I do have a contact form at lennyrachitsky.com.
I'm afraid of all the amazing people that are here >> Okay.
ping me, but there you go, we could try that.
Let's see how that goes.
>> yeah, or another maybe an easier way we can edit all that out.
Or if it's up to you.
But uh yeah, or I would just say you can drop us a DM.
Uh for example, I'm amber rico on Twitter and hit me up if you're interested in joining the team.
What a dream job for so many people.
What's a sign they will I don't know, what's like a way to filter people a little bit so they're not flooding your inbox?
So, specifically if you want to join the Codex team, then you need to be a technical person who uses these tools.
And I think I would just ask yourself the question, uh hey, let's say, you know, I were to join OpenAI and work on Codex over the next 6 months,
you know, and crush it, what does the life of a software engineer look like then?
And I think if you have an opinion on that, you should apply.
And if you don't have an opinion on that and have to think about it first, you know,
depending on how long you have to think about it, I guess that would be the filter, right?
Like I think there's a lot of people thinking about the space and so, we're we're very interested in folks who sort of have already been thinking about like what the future should look like
with agents.
And like we don't have to agree on where where we're going.
But I think we want people who like are very passionate about the topic, I guess.
It's very rare to be working on a product that has this much impact and is at such a bleeding edge of what's possible.
It's a what a cool role for the right person.
So, I'm it's awesome that you have an opening and this audience is a really good fit potentially for for that role.
So, I hope we find someone, that would be incredible.
With that, we've reached our very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you, Alexander.
Are you ready?
I don't know what these are, but I'm excited.
Let's do it.
Uh they're uh the same questions asked everyone except for the last one.
So, uh probably not a surprise.
I should probably make them more more often a surprise.
Okay, first question, what are a couple books that you recommend most to other people?
Two or three books that come to mind.
I have been reading a lot of science fiction recently.
And I'm sure this has been recommended before, but the Culture.
I think it's Ian Banks is the name of the author.
Part of why I love it is because it's like basically relatively recent writing about a future with AI,
but it's an optimistic future with AI.
Um and I think, you know, a lot of sci-fi is like fairly dystopian.
Um but this is like people uh sort of the joke at least on the Culture subreddit is that let me let me see if I can get this right.
It is a like space communist utopia.
Or or like I think it's a gay space communist utopia.
Um and uh I just think it's like really fun to think about um like to use the Culture as a way to think about like what kind of world can we usher in and like what decisions can we make today to help usher in that world.
Well, I've not I I don't think anyone's recommended that.
I know you're reading, you mentioned before we started recording, Lord of the Rings right now.
Uh if you want another AI-ish sci-fi book, uh have you read Fire Upon the Deep?
No, I haven't.
>> Okay.
It's uh incredibly good.
It's like uh a sci-fi space opera sort of epic tale with uh super intelligence.
Cool.
Yeah, somewhat mostly not optimistic, but somewhat optimistic.
Okay, next question.
Is there a favorite recent movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
Yeah, there's an anime called Jujutsu Kaisen, which I really like.
Um again, it's got a kind of a slightly dark topic of like demons.
Um but what I love about it is that the hero is really nice.
And I think there's this new wave of like anime and cartoons where the protagonists are really friendly and like people who care about the world rather than being like
sort of like if you look at like some older anime like that started the genre like, you know,
there was there was like Evangelion uh or Akira.
And like those characters, the protagonists are like deeply flawed, like quite unhappy.
Um they they didn't start the genre, but it was like a trend for a while to sort of poke fun at the idea that in these in these cartoons,
the protagonist was very young but being given a ridiculous amount of responsibility to like save the world.
And so, there was kind of a a wave of like uh content that was like critiquing this by making the character like basically go through like serious like mental issues in the middle of the show.
Um and I'm not saying this is better, but at least it's quite fun to have like these like really positive protagonists or just trying to help everyone around them.
I love how much we're learning about your personality hearing these recommendations.
Yeah.
Nice protagonists, optimistic futures.
I think you know, if you don't believe it, you can't will it into existence.
Mhm.
You need a balance.
This is your training data.
Is there a product you recently discovered that you really love?
Could be an app, could be some clothing, could be some kitchen gadget, tech gadget, a hat.
Yeah, so I have been like quite into uh you know, combustion engines um and cars.
Actually, the reason I came to America initially was cuz I wanted to work on like US aircraft.
Um but you know, now I work in software.
And so for the longest time I've basically only had like quite old sports cars.
Old just cuz they were more affordable.
And then recently We got a Tesla instead.
And I have to say that I find the Tesla software like quite inspiring.
In particular, it has like the self-driving feature and you know, I've mentioned a few times like today like I think it's really interesting to think about how to build like mixed initiative software that makes you feel maximally
empowered as a human.
Maximally in control, but yet you're getting a lot of help.
And I think they did a really good job.
With enabling sort of the car to drive itself, but All these different ways that you can adjust what it's doing without turning off the self-driving.
So like you can accelerate and you know, it'll like listen to that.
You can turn a knob to change its speed.
You can steer slightly.
Um I think it's a it's actually a master class in like building an agent.
That Still leaves the human in control.
This reminds me Nick Turley's whole mantra was are we maximally accelerated?
Yeah.
>> It was like it's completely infiltrated everything at OpenAI which makes sense.
That tracks.
Uh two more questions.
Do you have a life motto that you often think about come back to in work or in life that's been helpful?
I don't know if I have a life motto, but maybe I can tell you about the number one value Company value from my startup.
Love it.
Which is still something that sticks with me, which is to be kind and candid.
That tracks.
Kind and candid.
Wow.
Yeah, and we had to put them together because we As founders realized that we Often would be nice.
And it wasn't actually the right thing to do.
We would like delay the difficult conversations and we were not candid.
And so every time we would like remind ourselves of this motto and then we would become more candid and then 6 months later we would realize that we were in fact not candid 6 months ago.
And we needed to be even more candid.
So then the question is like okay, like How could how should we be candid?
It's like okay, well Let's let's think of being candid as an act of kindness, but also think of that both in terms of doing it and willing ourselves to do it,
but also in terms of how we frame it to people.
That is a beautiful way of summarizing how to how to lead well.
What's the The book about dare challenge directly but care deeply.
Radical candor.
Oh yeah, yeah, right.
Yeah.
Yeah, so it's like another way of thinking about radical candor.
Okay, last question.
I was looking up your last name just like hey, what's the what's the story here?
So your last name is Imbrios.
And I was talking to ChatGPT.
And it told me the most famous individuals with the surname are The influential Greek poet and psychoanalyst Andreas Imbrios.
And his relative the wealthy shipping magnate and art collector George Imbrios.
So the question is which of these two do you most identify with?
The Greek poet and psychoanalyst or the wealthy shipping magnate and art collector?
I think it's it's going to have to be the poet because Uh He He loved the island that our family's from.
Wait, you know these people?
Okay, this is not news to you.
Okay.
>> Well, I mean it's an enormous family, but it's like Greek.
So you know, these big families everyone like everyone's your uncle.
You know what I mean?
Like my mother's Malaysian and also like everyone is my uncle or aunt in Malaysia too if that makes sense.
Yeah.
But Yeah, he he loved this island that the family sort of like initiated from.
I believe I don't actually know where that shipping magnate I think it was New York or something,
but anyway, we all came from this island called Andros.
Which is a really beautiful place and it's like there's more like livestock there than than humans.
Not too many tourists go there.
But I think he like part of what I think is really cool is like he published a lot and a lot of his writing is about like the beauty of that island,
which I think is super cool.
Wow, that was an amazing answer.
Two more questions.
Where can folks find you if they want to follow you online and you know, maybe reach out and then how can listeners be useful to you?
I I'm one of those people who has social media only for the purposes of having work.
You know, my phone my phone turns black and white at like 9:00 p.m.
at night.
But yeah, so Twitter or X at nbrico.
And yeah, if you post in r/codex I'll probably see it.
So you know, you can go there.
How can listeners be useful?
I would say please try Codex.
Please share feedback.
Let us know what to improve.
We pay a ton of ton of attention to feedback.
I think it's like Honestly like the growth has been amazing, but it's still very early times.
So we still pay a lot of attention and hope to do so forever.
And also I would say if you're interested in in working On the future of coding agents and then agents generally,
then please Apply to our job site and or message me in those social media places.
Alexander, this was awesome.
I always love meeting people working on AI because it always feels like there's very I don't know Sterile,
scary, mysterious thing.
And then you meet the people building these tools and they're always just so awesome.
And you especially just so nice and uh As you like the examples you shared optimism and kindness,
you know, this is what we want to be.
This is these are the kinds of people we want to be building these tools that are going to drive the future.
So um I'm I'm really thankful that you did this.
Um Grateful to have met you and thank you so much for being here.
Yeah, thanks so much for having me.
This is fun.
Thank you so much for listening.
If you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the show on Apple podcast, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating or leaving a review as that really helps other listeners find the podcast.
You can find all past episodes or learn more about the show at lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.