Almost everyone living in a modern economy now
is going to have hundreds of interactions with a
phone or with a computer. And unfortunately, a lot
of those interactions are not going to be great.
We have an obligation as product people to put
that emotional energy back into people's lives.
You actually have a really unique
perspective on just what is design.
Design is trying to imagine the future you want to
live in and then take the steps to make it real.
Saying a company is design-led does not mean
it's designer-led. I've never seen somebody
graft it on after the fact. It's there at the
beginning in the root DNA or doesn't exist.
It wasn't a successful stint at Pinterest. I just
bounced off the culture. I came in thinking I
was supposed to behave the way I behaved at
Apple, which is very direct, fighting hard.
Why did you decide to join Apple?
I just seek out opportunities to witness
history. The whole company is constantly
asking how can the thing that I'm
working on be a little bit better?
Why do you Think that people that have left Apple,
a lot of amazing things haven't emerged? Today,
my guest is Bob Baxley. Bob is a designer,
executive and advisor who's built in led
design teams at Apple, Pinterest, Yahoo, and
most recently ThoughtSpot. Over the course of
his career that spanned over three decades,
Bob has played a pivotal role in the design
of the Apple online store, the Apple App Store,
Pinterest, and early in his career Yahoo Answers,
products that have been used by hundreds
of millions of people around the world.
Bob also mentors individuals and advises
organizations that are working to improve
the practice, craft and culture of digital
product design. There is something in this
conversation for everyone from why you should
consider having designed report engineering,
why it's your moral obligation to build great
products, why you should wait as long as possible
to draw a picture or create a prototype of your
idea to what the Moon Landing can teach us about
building better teams and products. I could
listen to Bob all day. I learned a ton from
this conversation, including a bunch of really
unique insights that I've never heard before.
A big thank you to Annie Warner, Andrew Hogan,
Irene A, and Joff Redfern for suggesting questions
for this conversation. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of a bunch of
incredible products including Linear,
Superhuman, Notion, Perplexity, Granola, and
more. Check it out lennysnewsletter.com and
click bundle. With that, I bring you Bob Baxley.
This entire episode is brought to you by Stripe.
There's a reason that I've had more guests on
this podcast from Stripe than any other company.
It's because they hire the best people and they
build incredible products. You probably know them
for their payments platform, which powers my
newsletter, and also companies like Nvidia and
Salesforce and Zoom and DoorDash. What you may not
know is that they have several other products that
can help accelerate your revenue, such as Stripe
Billing, which powers billing for companies that
you may have heard of, OpenAI, Anthropic, Figma,
Atlassian, and over 300,000 other companies.
Stripe Billing lets you bill and manage customers
however you want from simple recurring billing to
usage-based billing to sales negotiated contracts.
There's also Stripe's Optimized Checkout Suite
which is a plug and play super optimized
payments flow that natively supports over
100 global dynamic payment methods. There's also
a product called LINQ, which is an accelerated
checkout experience built specifically to increase
your checkout conversion. Every single one of the
Forbes top 50 AI companies that have a product
in the market today use Stripe to monetize it.
Half of Fortune 100 companies use Stripe. $1.4
trillion flows through Stripe annually, which is
equivalent to over 1% of global GDP. Use Stripe
to handle all of your payment related needs,
billing, manage revenue operations, and launch
or invent new business models. Learn more at
stripe.com. Bob, thank you so much for
being here and welcome to the podcast.
Lenny, thank you so much. Thanks for having
me, but also just thank you for what you do.
We are still in early days to try to figure
out how to make software together. I think of
it like where the film industry was in the
1920s. We've had our talkie moment. We're
on the cusp of having our shift to color
movement, but we're still trying to figure
out how to make movies and a podcast like
yours specifically yours I think is one of
the greatest resources we have for learning
from one another. I appreciate all you're
doing for the community and for helping
us as a community make better software.
Wow. Well, I really appreciate that. That means
a lot coming from you. There's so much I want
to talk about in our conversation. There's
a story that I hear that you often tell,
which is when somebody asked Steve
Jobs once, what is your favorite
product that you've built that you work
on? And his answer, what's that story?
So I actually can't remember where I heard
this, but I believe the story's true.
Steve at one point was recounting the products
that he had created that he was most proud of,
and if I recall the whole list, it was the
Apple II, the Mac, the iPod, the iPhone,
I think Apple retail was in the list and then he
said Apple itself. When I heard that and when I've
reflected on it, that is the longest lasting
thing. I remember there was also a story that
Steve was talking to, I think it was either Ed
Catmull or John Lasseter at Pixar, and he said,
"Everything we make is going to be a doorstop
in three years, but the stuff you guys make,
they're still going to be watching in
100 years." So I think Steve had some
concept of the longevity of these things.
They knew the products themselves were very
ephemeral, but there's something about the
culture of Apple that's lasted a very long
time and I personally believe will last for some
time yet to come. It's a way of making decisions,
it's a way of behaving, it's a way of seeing the
value of technology in the world and it infuses
everything in that company. I mean everything
from the checkout system when you go to the
receptionist to what it's like in the cafeteria.
At least when I was there, they had patented the
pizza box because they had reinvented the pizza
box that you would get at Cafe Max because the
whole company is constantly asking how can the
thing that I'm working on be a little bit better?
I think that was something Steve brought to them
and had them constantly asking that question.
One more Apple question then I'll move on to
other stuff. Why do you think that people that
have left Apple, a lot of amazing things haven't
emerged from people that have left? Humane was a
recent example. We're recording this the day after
Jony Ive Open AI emerged so we'll see what happens
there but just feels like there hasn't been a
ton of alumni that have built incredible things.
Obviously Tony Fadell would be one with Nest and
he'd be an outlier. I think the people that... I
went to Pinterest and did not have a successful
time in my year and a half at Pinterest. I think
my own particular mistake, and I've seen this
with some other Apple executives as well as we
went directly from Apple, I left Apple on a
Friday and I started Pinterest on a Monday.
I didn't give myself time to recalibrate to
the Pinterest culture. I think at some level,
a lot of the challenge is that
Apple, and it's not just Apple,
I think every major tech company,
they have really powerful cultures.
You get indoctrinated into all those standards
and it's really deep. It fuses all of your
behavior and how you conduct yourself in the
company, away from the company. I think it's
pretty hard to immigrate successfully from one
of those environments to another. Apple is one
of the strongest cultures and there's not many
other cultures that natively operate like that.
Airbnb is one exception. And so you have guys
like Hiroki Asai who leads all of marketing
and all of product and Hiroki is crushing at
Airbnb. He was incredibly successful at Apple.
It also should be noted that he had, it was a
multi-year gap between the time he left Apple
and the time he started Airbnb. He gave himself a
little bit of time to get through the... At Apple,
I think it was Tim or Steve used to talk about
the Apple car wash. Then when you started Apple,
they kind of had to take you through the
car wash and get off all that stuff that
you'd accumulated at other places. It turns out
there's a car wash you need to go through when
you leave Apple as well. And so I think Hiroki
gave himself time to do that and I think that's
probably a lot of why he's been so successful
at Airbnb. The thing I took away from Apple,
and I think this is true for anybody changing
from one major culture to another is most likely
the new place hires you because of the values of
the organization you left, but not the behaviors.
And so I think it's important to recalibrate and
say, well, I want to hold onto these values. So
at Apple, attention to detail, product excellence,
doing everything you can for the customer and the
user so try to hold onto those values but then
think, okay, how are those values best expressed
in this culture? I was more successful at
expressing those values in the culture of
ThoughtSpot, which was my last job than I was in
the culture of Pinterest. If I had to do it again,
I could probably do better at Pinterest. I
think that's useful for anybody leaving one
very specific culture and going someplace else,
try to hold onto the values but not the behaviors.
This is so interesting and I appreciate you
sharing that, the way you described it that
it wasn't a successful stint at Pinterest. A lot
of people don't share that sort of story and don't
put it that way. They see on their LinkedIn, oh,
a head of design at Pinterest. Oh, amazing so
cool. And then if you're like, oh, okay, but
it didn't work out that well, I think that's
really interesting. Is there anything more you
can share there about what you learned for other
people to maybe avoid that sort of situation?
Anything you took away from that experience?
One of my friends that was at Pinterest, I'm
still friends with, he said, "I just thought
of it as you bounced off the culture." I think
that's kind of the way to think of it. I came in
thinking I was supposed to behave the way
I behaved at Apple, which is very direct,
fighting hard. Everybody cares about each other.
It's never insulting, but it's intense. That's
not really where Pinterest was at the
time. Again, all this is a decade ago,
so I don't know what any of these companies
are like today, but at least when I was there,
Pinterest had posters in every conference room
that said, big poster that said, say the hard
thing. Well, that's where Pinterest was at the
time, and I can assure you nobody at Apple was
having to remind you to say the hard thing.
And so I probably could have picked up on that
better than I did. I'll say these careers
are really hard and the higher up you go,
people think of it like you're climbing a pyramid.
I think of it more like you're going out on a
branch on a tree and the branch gets a lot more
flimsy and can break and you can fall and you get
buffeted about by the wind. It's often at a time
in your life when there's a lot going on with your
family, there could be things going on with your
parents' health. I lost my mother when I was at
Pinterest. My kids were starting high school,
so we're struggling with the teenage years.
I had a long commute. It's a lot going
on and these jobs are super demanding.
Everything around you is changing really rapidly
and you're under tremendous pressure because the
financial and success stakes are super high.
I think the people falling off of these jobs
is the common use case. That is the common story.
We have a bias towards survivors and we all talk
about how it looks like they made it to the
top, but everybody that makes it to the top,
there's hundreds of people that don't. One of
the things I took away when I was at Pinterest
was I came to think that the job of a startup
was to grow the founder so they could continue
to lead the startup. I think what's true for
founders, also true for a lot of the other
folks in the executive staff, it's very hard
to grow emotionally and developmentally at
the rate that the company grows.
A lot of times I think people get
outgrown by the role, and I saw that across Apple.
I've experienced that myself at different times
in my career. I see that happening with my
friends and it feels like a failure. I mean,
that is the human experience, that's what happens.
It's very hard to grow as fast as some of these
companies are growing and we could debate the
merits of Mark Zuckerberg for example. But when
you think about the trajectory from being
a kid in a dorm room to within five years,
Facebook's a big thing. I mean, think of your own
life. Can you process that level of evolution and
change? I don't know, I think that's really
super hard to do that and stay balanced.
And also keep doing that for so long.
There'll be founders, I think it was
Brian's maybe first job or second job, and
he's doing that now for 15 years in a row.
Oh, founders, it's their life. It's very unusual
to see founders move out. I had this other theory
that a startup is still a startup until the
founder moves aside. By my definition of
even Meta is still a startup in a way that
Amazon's not, and Airbnb is still a startup
in a way that Pinterest is not because Ben's
moved on. You don't find out if the culture
can sustain itself until the founders are gone
and then you really see what's going to happen.
Just to close the loop here, one takeaway
here that I think is really interesting is
that you can fail in a job and things will be
okay. Clearly you're doing A okay and having a
place that doesn't work out, doesn't destroy your
career, which I think a lot of people feel like
if they're not doing well in their current job,
it's over. Things are all going to go downhill
Your career's not your life.
There's a lot more to it than that.
And then just to give someone something tactical
here, so you've realized the culture of Pinterest,
you bounced off of it. I love
that metaphor. If you were to,
when you're looking at new companies, what's
one thing you look at or a question you ask
or something you now look at to make sure you
avoid that in the future, that culture clash?
I'm fortunate at this stage of my career
that I usually get to interview with the
CEO or the founders or something like
that. What I'm usually looking for is
do they have a story as to why they believe
in design? Really in their heart and soul,
do they care about design? Because if I go
into a company that doesn't really value the
thing that I do, I'm just not going to have
a great time and I'm going to be constantly
buffeting up against all sorts of people. I
want to make sure I've got air cover from the
highest people in the company setting the culture.
In the case of, again, my most recent job was with
a company called ThoughtSpot. And ThoughtSpot
was founded by a gentleman named Ajeet Singh,
and Ajeet grew up in rural India, but
he tells this really great story about
he studied chemical engineering, he moves
to the United States. Early in his career,
he's working for Honeywell and they did a couple
of engagements with IDEO. As a very young person,
he got to see what IDEO did and he realized the
power of design and he's taken that to all of his
companies. He started Nutanix before he came to
ThoughtSpot, before he started ThoughtSpot. And
so when I heard that, I'm like, oh, this is a guy
that gets design right from the very beginning.
I've also come to believe that I actually
have never seen a company that grafted
design on after the founding. I could name lots
of companies that I think are kind of design led,
not always designer led, but design led or design
centric. But I've never seen somebody grafted on
after the fact. It's there at the beginning
in the root DNA or doesn't exist. And so the
thing that I'm looking for when I interview
is, is it there at the beginning? Can I get a
credible story that tracks it back to that?
And if that's the case, then I think I can
find a way to navigate in that culture. We have a
shared value system in a way that as an American,
I could immigrate to Australia and the culture
would be slightly different, but we'd have
a shared value system that I could relate to.
If I moved to, I don't know, Burma or China or
something, it would be wildly more challenging
because the base view of the world, the base
understanding of the world's just different and
it'd be much harder for me to adapt to that.
I think a way to extrapolate that insight
is just whatever function you're in,
get a sense of how important that function
is to that business. Do the founders value
engineering? Do they value product? Do they
value design? Depending on who you are.
Why would you want to work in a place that doesn't
value the thing that you do? God, that would suck.
You actually have a really unique
perspective on just what is design
that I haven't heard before. Let me ask
you that question is what is design?
Well, I'm going to go back to the Edward Tufte
quote that I use all the time, which is design is
clear thinking made visible. And so I think most
people when they talk about design, they think
of it as the visual expression of an idea. They
think of it as a team or a function or a group.
I think of it as a holistic mindset. When design
thinking became big, I was always really confused
because I didn't know how else you could think.
That was just how I naturally thought, which is
design is trying to imagine the future you want to
live in and then take the steps to make it real.
It's living with a certain type of
intentionality in almost a Buddhist type way,
which is different from science, which is
observational trying to understand. It's
a little bit different from engineering, which
is we kind of know where we want go at the end,
but we're trying to go one step at a time
versus design's trying to see some further
out future state and account for a larger or
a different set of constraints and issues than
engineering or some of the other problem solving
methodologies. Again, I look at it as a company,
does the company think in a design mindset and
Apple does, Airbnb does. I don't get the sense
that Google does and I don't get the sense
that Amazon does. That's not a critique on
them. I don't think that those organizations are
competing on design in the same way. But again,
I want to go work at a place that as an
organization thinks in a design type method.
Along those lines, a lot of people imagine
every founder, every product builder is just,
yes, I'd love amazing design. I'd love
our products to be incredibly beautiful,
intuitive, so easy for everyone to use and
understand, but they don't actually invest
in these areas and they don't put a lot
of resources into the designing process.
What's the best pitch you can make and
that you do make to companies to help
them see the strategic value of design
and the bottom of the value of design.
Let me back up and just dissect a little bit
the way you described design, you described it
in really tactical terms. You said beautiful,
intuitive products that make sense. I think it
was something like that. What you were describing
was you were describing the part of the iceberg
that sits above the water line, which is the
result. That's one of the outcomes of design,
but that's not the real heavy lifting of design.
Design is more like liberal arts or philosophy
or something. It's like what do we try to
achieve at a much lower level? And so what
I talk to founders and people about the value of
design, what I'm pushing them on is when we can
get organizational alignment around what we want
to do philosophically, why do we exist? What's
the vision for the company? How do all these
things ladder up through vision, through mission,
through specific tenets, design strategies.
And then into actual execution. How do we
ladder that whole thing up so it makes sense
as a whole? That's the magic of design. The
difference is when you design things, you end
up with a bunch of bricks that are piled into
a beautiful impenetrable wall. If you don't do
that, you end up with a bunch of bricks scattered
across the backyard and they don't really add up
to anything. I think that's one of the things,
if you look, again to go back to Apple, but
we could also talk about Lego Lyca, Porsche,
Airbnb, Patagonia, there's other companies that
make sense as a design centered organization.
If you think about everything they do, it all
ladders together into one cohesive sensical
thing. It's integrated. Makes sense as a unit.
I think that's a huge difference and an incredible
strategic advantage because the company can
operate with much greater efficiency. They
can onboard new people and get them in line.
Even Apple, for example, the team that designed
the online store, we had six designers for
a store that ran in 30 some odd countries,
12 and a half thousand instances of the store
doing billions of dollars of revenue. We had
six designers. Any other company would've
had 60 or more. Apple's able to operate with
much smaller staff because they have real
clarity of vision of what they're doing.
And the benefit of operating with a smaller
staff is not just that it saves money on payroll,
it's that you have... The way the minds
come together to create something that
feels like a single whole is a much higher
chance when you have fewer people involved.
I joke about The Beatles. You get The Beatles
with four people, you don't get The Beatles
with eight people and you certainly don't get
it with 24 people. The teams get too big and you
can't get that what Brian Eno calls scenius.
Brian Eno has this great word that he uses,
scenius is the genius that comes when you have
a group together. Scenius is the collective
idea of genius and I think that's something that's
really magical that I've experienced in my career,
but usually in smaller groups.
It's hard to do with a giant group.
I love this metaphor of The Beatles as
the way most people describe this is
designed by committee never works. I
love that the way you describe it is
the Beatles is like the ideal size
a small group versus a committee.
I just always have to point out to people
that there are 20 people that worked on
the original Mac. I mean it's 20 of them,
that's it, 20. Susan Kare was one of them,
Andy Hertzfeld, you go through the list, 20 of
them are on the patent. There's 24 that are on
the iPhone patent. Now there's other people
involved, but generally there's 24 people on
the iPhone patent. And that was the team. That
was Project Purple that was doing that stuff.
These are not massive massive groups doing
these things. If you had put a massive group,
I don't know man, maybe it'd end up with the Zune
or something completely different. Who knows?
They probably did have a
massive group on the Zune.
Yeah, so there's something, four is too
few for what we're trying to achieve at
scale. But even if you look at Pixar, any
good movie on the scripting and story side,
it's usually a fairly small team. Even
when you move into character development,
stuff like that, it's fairly small and then it
really scales when you move into production.
It's just hard to figure out something new to do
together when there's too many people involved.
I think that word new is really key here.
I think when people hear this advice,
they're thinking at their existing company,
should we just keep our company small? Should
we not scale this thing that we have? I think what
you're describing, which I completely agree with
is new stuff for sure you want to keep the team
small and tight, but as things grow and scale,
what's your take on just, okay, actually
it's okay to have a lot of people on this.
Well, you have to bring a lot of people
in once you figure out what you're doing.
And so to your point, once you realize you're
building Disneyland and you've got the whole
thing set and people know what it's about,
then they can come in and understand, oh,
I'm playing my piece over here. I'm supposed
to design the line experience for the new ride
sitting in Tomorrowland, but I know where that
fits into this larger thing. I think you can
scale once you have clarity of vision, but it's
very difficult to get vision with a lot of people.
Great. I think that's really powerful advice.
It's just when you're starting something new.
I actually had a CPA of N26 who was basically
leading Google Hangouts, the initial launch of
Google Hangouts, and he told the story of they
put so many resources on it. We got to win. We
got to do this. Larry Page or Sergey was sitting
next to him just like we got to make this work
and putting everything they could into it
and it didn't work out. And I think that's-
No, no, the more people you put in
it, the slower everything becomes.
I want to go back to something you said
about what design is. I think this is
really interesting. And so the way you
described design to a lot of people,
it sounds like that's like product management
also and product leadership, setting, strategy,
vision, figuring out how everything fits
together. I think your experience here,
I think Apple is a very different kind of company
where design actually leads a lot of this. At a
lot of other companies, it doesn't work that way.
Any thoughts? And just how you advise companies,
think about the split between design and
product management that aren't Apple.
One of the best lines I ever heard was from my
friend Joseph O'Sullivan at dinner one night. He
said saying a company is design led does not mean
it's designer led. And so what I try to hammer
home with people is that when I talk about design
as a mindset, I'm talking about it as a mindset.
Anybody could have that mindset functioning in any
role, any designer could have a product mindset.
In fact, I think that's a lot of what the design
community is trying to get at now when they say
designers should be speaking the language
of business. I think what they're saying is
designers need to inhabit the product mindset as
well. Maybe to some degree even the sales mindset.
Look, both functions matter. I look at my
counterparts in product and I assume that they're
much better connected to the customer, that they
understand much better the business realities,
and I expect them to drive the roadmap. I may
have some points of view on the roadmap. I may
offer some critique. I may have my own suggestions
and agenda in there. But once they say this is
the roadmap, I have to believe that they're right
and I don't try to bleed into their space. I very
much believe that once you get into a company,
your job is to figure out your role and respect
the boundaries between the different groups.
I'm like, you guys tell us what you need us to do,
what the features need to be, when they need
to be delivered, what the issues are, and
then give us the time and space to come up with a
solution to those problems. And then we can work
together to decide whether or not our solutions
actually solve the problem as you understand it,
but I'll stay out of your roadmap and you stay
out of my design stop and let's try to get to
the promised land together. I assume that the
product managers, particularly in enterprise
SaaS companies, like my team, ThoughtSpot did
data analytics. My team didn't know anything
about data analytics. We didn't have any of that
insight. We didn't have the bandwidth, the mental
horsepower to go out and do that stuff. We had
our hands full just trying to figure out the UI.
It's one of the points I try to make too, when
people are starting to theorize that gen AI can
remove teammates and oh, the designers don't need
engineers and the PMs don't need the designers
and everybody thinks they can throw engineering
overboard. And I'm like, stop it. We all need
each other and we need each other because we
need those different mindsets. One of those
mindsets inhabits somebody's head completely.
I just don't think you can simultaneously hold
multiple mindsets in your head. It's not that one
of my PM counterparts couldn't bring a lot to the
design table, it's just I need you to play
that position. Like in baseball, the second-
Like in baseball, the second baseman
doesn't cover first. That's not how it
works. Everybody's got to spread the field
and play their position so we can take care
of the whole thing and respect that together
we're going to come up with something better
than any one of us would've come up with
alone and embrace the creative tension,
welcome it. We still have to all go out to lunch
and love each other and have fun together and
keep in mind that we're having fun together, but I
like the rub. That's where all the magic happens.
That was a very illuminating clarification.
Something else that I heard you believe
that I haven't heard before is that
design share report to engineering.
So I'll say that every company culture is
different and different organizations work
in different ways. In my experience, I think that
design is most successful at impacting what ships
at the end if design is considered phase zero of
the engineering process, rather than a by product
or a part of the product process. What I've
seen happen over and over in my experience,
a ThoughtSpot, Pinterest, other places
when you're working directly with product,
it's easy to leave engineering out of the loop
and product and design can go cook up stuff that
doesn't quite make sense technically or is
really hard to implement or is just a bridge
too far. And I think that engineering
doesn't feel like they're a part of it,
so you bring them at the end and they haven't
really been brought along so they don't
quite understand how to extrapolate from the
specs you make into what should really ship.
Maybe they don't bring the same level of
enthusiasm to it, because they haven't been
brought along. So I think there's something
about having the design and engineering
team very tightly connected and kind of living
together. And it's not that you have to do that
structurally from an organization point of view,
but it's hard-pressed if you don't. I also think
you can just account for timelines and costs and
things better when design's part of engineering.
And many of my design friends will push back on
this and they'll say design should be its own
thing and it should be an independent group and we
should have three co-equal branches of government,
and that's a solid argument as well, and there's
some places where that works beautifully.
My experiences at design rarely has a budget
or an army, and so it's very hard for them to
really hold their own in that sort of a setting.
Also, although you'll see people argue with me on
LinkedIn about how design needs to be measured and
we need to have metrics and be held accountable
for a number, I don't really believe that in
my heart. I've just never seen a number that
you could apply to design that we could reliably
affect. So I think it's very hard to hold design
as an organization accountable for a particular
outcome the way that most of the other C-level
roles are held accountable. Sales has a number,
engineering has very specific expectations,
product has very specific expectations.
And although I know this will frustrate
some of my friends, I just haven't been able to
figure out how that works for design. And again,
it can vary from culture to culture. Certainly
there's very successful chief design officers
and we could go through the list. I just think
in many companies it's a stretch, it's just hard.
What I see work, and I'm curious to get
your take is just product, engineering,
design have exactly the same goal and the
more everyone... And their performance as
an employee is tied to the same thing
essentially because then everyone is
pushing in the same direction versus
like, oh, I have my engineering goal,
I have my design goal, I have my PM goal, and
just creates all kinds of weird incentives.
Yeah, look, I would kind of defer to you on
that, honestly. You've talked to a lot more
people across a lot more companies, so you have
a much broader set of information you're working
with. If you add my whole career together,
I've worked at maybe half a dozen places,
so a fairly limited sample set. And every
design team that I've ever been a part of,
I've been a part of. So I also
kind of have a biased view as to
what didn't work for me in those particular
organizations. I'll go back to what I said,
every company's different, every culture is
slightly different. It's not one size fits all.
I point out the idea of design reporting
to engineering just because I don't think
people consider the possibility often enough. So
there's three options, design is its own thing,
design is part of product, design is part of
engineering. And I think there's a moment when
you can back up and make an intelligent choice
about the pros and cons for each of those options
inside your org. And so I would encourage people
to just take a design mentality and put on that
designer mindset just for a moment and say, well,
what's the thing that we're trying to produce?
What's the incentives that we're trying to create?
What's the future state that we're trying to get
to? And which of these three options, permutations
is going to help us get there the best?
I love how radical this idea
is. I've not heard it. I think
designers will be like, " You stop it.
Just stop it." So have you operated
this way? Have you had design report to
engineering in companies you've worked at?
Sorry, but that's how it worked at Apple the
whole time under Steve. Design always reported
to engineering. Now I think it's structured a
little bit differently, but design has always
been part of engineering at Apple, so I saw
it work quite effectively there obviously.
It's so interesting. Okay, so say just to
give someone something very tactical to do
on their team, say they don't want to go
to this extreme and move the design org
under engineering, what's something
you've seen work that helps achieve
similar outcomes with having engineers
integrated early in the design process?
Yeah, look, I think you have to find some way
that you are able to identify a few people in
engineering that I refer to as creative
technologists. So these are people that
can come into what's ultimately kind of a fairly
airy-fairy philosophical discussion about what
we could do and what's right from a conceptual
model perspective. Ultimately, it's sort of a
philosophy issue. And there's not that many PMs
or engineers that can sit in that space and be
comfortable with the ambiguity of it all. A PM's
likely going to come in and they're going to say,
okay, well that was a great one hour. What's the
next step? And as a designer I'm always like,
well, the next step is we're going to have
another meeting and we're going to talk
again. And the engineers oftentimes when
they're starting to hear different ideas,
they're already cutting into the code and they're
trying to figure out what's hard and what's easy.
And so I think the trick is at the beginning,
can you find a small group of people from
the different functions that can sit with the
ambiguity of the space and talk through a broad
range of ideas to identify the direction we want
to go into? And then once everybody kind of falls
in love with the direction, then you can go into
the more tactical mindset of, okay, well, when we
can ship it and who can we show it to and how are
we going to code it and when's it going to go live
and all those sorts of things. But the trick is
to try to find a group that can sit, again, in the
ambiguous maybe space. I do think it's critical to
have everybody together at the beginning so they
all feel like they're part of it. And the worst
thing is when you bring something fully baked...
Well, the worst thing when you bring something
fully baked to anybody for their approval.
We could talk about this when you take a final
design to an exec and an exec sees it for the
first time in a high resolution state, I'll
get to that in a second. But when you go to
an engineering team says, "Hey, we've been working
in the lab for six months and we have this thing
that we love it and we just can't wait for you
guys to build it, and here it is," I don't know,
[inaudible 00:32:54] mention here. They're going
to be excited about. They're not order takers.
How do you make them part of the process? And
every product of consequence that I worked on,
there was some moment when we were showing it
to some critical person and you could see that
they fell in love with it. Sometimes they're
literally pointing at the comps on the board,
sometime you're in a meeting and they're
just like, "God, I just love this."
And for me, that was always the critical moment
because I knew that design can't bring you this
stuff into the world on its own. We can't raise
this baby, we need the village, and we need the
village to fall in love with the baby. And so
until that happens, you're not really quite sure
if this thing's going to take off or not. And so
it was always extremely important to me that you
had a few key engineers and some product people
fall in love with it so they could defend it and
embrace it and enhance it and add to it. And you
got to bring them along at the very beginning.
What I'm hearing there is there's
a big part of just buy-in and
then there's also just obviously
more good ideas early are great.
Yeah, sorry. Buy-in doesn't feel quite
right to me, because buy-in feels like, oh,
I've come to agree with you. And that's different
from it's a part of me. When I'm talking to teams,
the thing I try to tell them is, I walk into
the office every day with the idea that everyone
that I work with is fundamentally a
maker. Everybody in product design,
engineering, we've all chosen these
careers. Everybody's super smart,
everybody's super ambitious. Everybody
could have done a thousand other things,
but they're choosing to spend their precious
lifetime and creative energy creating software.
And so I believe in my heart that they're
all fundamentally makers. And the thing
that I know about makers is that they all want
to make something they're proud of so they can
take it home at the end of the day and show it
to their parents and say, "Look at what I made
at school with my friends today." That's the
fundamental thing, and they're all doing it
from their own different points of view and
their own different incentives and mindsets,
but they all at the end of the day want to make
something they're proud of. And so it's not a
matter of getting their buy-in, it's a matter
of them being a part of it. I don't know, it's
a part of their soul in a really deep, meaningful
way. And I'm not sure you can graph that onto
somebody after the fact. They kind of need to be
there at the moment of inception, if you will.
Wow, that's a really beautiful answer. I
imagine for a lot of people hearing this,
making every feature and product they
build a part of their soul feels like a
very high bar if they're building
some kind of B2B SaaS software.
So I guess just thoughts in just how much you
should spend, how much time, how many resources,
how deep you go on design for all these things
you're building. Say you're building some kind of,
I don't know, expense management system or
HRS thing, just like, what do you recommend
people do with, in terms of just how far to go
in design as a lever, as a differentiator maybe?
Well, inherent in your question is this assumption
that design takes more time. And so I'm going to
kind of reject that premise, because I don't think
design takes more time. I think design exists.
There is going to be a design. It's whether it's
going to be a good one or not. And I think there's
things that you can do so that you're able to
operate it at a quicker pace as design. Again, if
you get the... We haven't talked about tenets yet,
but we'll get to that in a moment. If you kind of
create a shared philosophical understanding
of the product and what you're trying to do,
you can go really fast because you're not asking
the question of what should you do, you're asking
the question of, what would this company with
what we stand for do for this thing? And that's
a much easier question that's much smaller.
So if you look at the companies that have the
largest design teams, they're often the companies
that have the most ambiguous cultures and the most
unclear design vision. When you go to companies
that really know what they're doing and they're
clear that this is who we are, this is what
we stand for, the design teams are super small
because they're not sitting there trying to do
all these permutations with color and typography
and ideas. They're operating in a really narrow
vein, because they know who they are. It's very
much like individuals. When you're a teenager
or a young adult, you can spend a lot of time
trying to figure out what to wear because
you haven't really sorted it out yet. But
by the time you get to be a little bit older,
you've kind of got your personal style, and so
dressing in the morning gets to be a lot easier.
Like at Pinterest. I was at Pinterest at a point
when Pinterest wasn't quite sure who it was. And
so when we were going to do an onboarding flow,
we had to look at a really broad sweep of things,
because we were trying to sort it out. But you
had other places that knew what they were about,
Apple's the key example there, we weren't trying
to figure out what it was about. We were trying
to figure out what was the apple way to do this
particular thing, and so that moves a lot faster.
And I agree, look, having your soul at every
little checkbox sounds like a high bar and in some
ways it is. I think you need to be able to back
up and look at the product, maybe not at every
state, but generally every six months or a year,
you need to back up and ask yourself, am I proud
of this? Is this something I am happy to be a part
of? Do I believe in this? Is it a representative
of my best work given the circumstances I was in,
which has limitations around time
and resources and everything else,
is this the best I could do or am I just sort of
trying to get through the day I have other goals?
So let's actually follow the thread
of design tenets and principles.
This is something I've heard about you,
that you're a big fan of design tenets
versus design principles. What is the
difference? Why is this so important?
Yeah, so look, there's whole websites dedicated to
design principles, and if you go and you read it,
you'll see a lot of principles like simple, clear,
beautiful, fast, secure. You'll hear these words
and all these words are great. I mean, obviously
I have nothing against any of these words,
but they're not useful as decision-making tools
because nobody would ever argue the opposite.
Nobody ever sat in a meeting and said, "Oh,
forget clear. Let's try to make it as confusing as
possible." So the idea of clear, it's nice to have
out there as, I don't know, sort of a platitude to
move towards, but I just don't think it helps
you make decisions. And so tenets are really
decision-making tools and it's sort of like... A
classic one is paper versus plastic. It's just too
complicated to reconsider that every time you're
at the grocery store. So you sort of make a rule
for yourself and you're just a paper person
or a plastic person, you move on from there.
And so it's sort of that at scale. And the story
comes from when they were starting to work on
Keynotes, apparently the guy who was responsible
for originating Keynote went to Steve and said,
"How should we think about Keynote?" And Steve
said, "I want you to keep three things in mind.
One is it should be difficult to make ugly
presentations. Two, you should focus on
cinematic quality transitions. And three, you
should optimize for innovation over PowerPoint
compatibility." And if you take that last one in
particular, if he hadn't kind of said, we're going
to go this way instead of that way, that team
would've spent the next 10 years gouging each
other's eyes out over whether they should try to
go for PowerPoint compatibility or innovation. And
so when I was at ThoughtSpot, I realized pretty
early on that I wasn't going to be able to have
any sort of command and control over everything
that was going to happen in the product.
There was too many people involved, too many
engineering teams, most of them were in India.
I needed to move from a mindset of control to
one of choreography. I needed to try to set
the culture and set certain design tenets
that everyone could internalize and follow
and hopefully then make the right decisions in
that groove, if you will. And so we had three,
I think you can't have more than three or four
because you need everybody to memorize them.
They can't be consulting a handbook. And so, one
of them was documentation is a failure state. In
enterprise companies, a lot of times people
think, "Oh, we'll just put it in the manual.
It'll be part of the training." And I would
constantly be coming back and go, "Stop it.
Nobody wants to learn our software. Nobody cares.
We are just one more browser tab in a world of
browser tabs. We are not this user's complete
world. They do not want to learn this stuff."
Documentation's a failure state. Maybe we can't
always avoid it, but we should do everything we
can to simplify things so you can figure it out
in the context of the product. That's number one.
Number two is every interaction should start
simple and the users should have to opt into
complexity. So our main competitor at the time was
Tableau. Tableau started with complexity. That was
their whole value prop is like, "We're a super
powerful tool. We can do all sorts of stuff."
So when you sit down at Tableau, it feels like
you're flying the space shuttle. And if you're a
professional data analyst, that's great. That's
the kind of tool you wanted. That wasn't what
ThoughtSpot was about. We were trying to take
data analytics into the hands of what I call
mere mortals, also known as business users, people
who didn't live in breathe this stuff every day.
So our goal with them was they could sit
down and it was an approachable piece of
software and they could turn on all the bells
and whistles and power if they wanted it,
so that was the second one. Start simple, let the
users opt into complexity. And the third one was
the entire product should look and feel like it
came from a single mind. And this was a tenet to
try to combat the natural tendency of enterprise
companies to really fragment because you have all
these different teams working on their incentive
to work just on their little piece. And so they
think about what's right for them and they
don't back up to look at the whole thing.
And so we had this tenet, the whole thing should
look and feel like it came from a single mind to
just try to remind people, how does this fit into
the whole system? And sometimes we need to go
along and do things that work for the product that
don't necessarily work quite the way we might want
them to for our feature. And so those tenets were
all... Again, they were all decision-making tools.
And when we would have design debates, we could
just come back to this, wait, are we actually
starting simple and forcing them to opt into
complexity or are we doing something else here?
So there's kind of this implication in
this discussion about tenets is that you
need to be very opinionated. There's a clear
here's what's in and here's what's out. Is
there anything more along those lines and
are there other tenet examples you could
share to give people some inspiration as
they think about their potential tenets?
It's very context specific, so it's a little bit
like what are your tenets for parenting? It's a
very specific personal type thing that's germane
to your particular context. So I'm not sure if I
have a lot of other examples, and I haven't
heard this used by a lot of other companies,
so I haven't been able to add a bunch of
stuff. We tried to come out with tenets
for individual features and we had trouble
with that. It felt like they operated at
sort of the design strategy level. And I
just think that varies dramatically from
company to company. What I would look for is
if you're a design leader or a product leader,
try to pay attention to what are the debates
that we keep having over and over where people
kind of seem to be digging in and things sort
of seem to be bifurcating into two camps.
And then is there something we can do where
we just have that debate once and for all,
we decide as an organization, we're going left
instead of right, and you're absolutely correct.
You have to be opinionated, but that's how
you're going to win. There's no unopinionated
software that's been successful. You have
to have a point of view. The question is,
what's it going to be? So I'd say practically
just try to look for places where it seems the
team's having the same debate over and over and
have it once, get it done, and put it behind you.
And make it a tenet. And why is the word
tenet versus principle so important?
I don't know. I settled on tenet. I'd have
to go look up the definition. I was trying to
differentiate it from principles because I think
principles are just... I describe principles as
sort of Applehood & Motherpie. Again, they're
just not something people are going to argue
over. And so I didn't think it was wise to try
to co-op that word and change how people think
about it so much as I might be more successful
just coming up with a different word altogether.
Makes sense. This entire episode is brought to
you by Stripe. Every single one of the Forbes
top 50 AI companies that has a product in the
market today uses Stripe to monetize it. $1.4
trillion flows through Stripe annually, which
is equivalent to over 1% of the entire global
GDP. And Stripe isn't just a payments platform,
they also have a product called Stripe Billing,
which powers billing for companies that you
may have heard of: OpenAI, Anthropic, Figma,
Atlassian, and over 300,000 other companies.
Stripe Billing lets you bill and manage
customers no matter your pricing
model, from simple recurring billing,
to usage based billing, to sales negotiated
contracts, collect and retain more revenue,
automate revenue management workflows, and
accept payments globally. Use Stripe to handle
all of your payment related needs, including
billing, revenue, operations, checkout flows,
or simply launching or inventing new business
models. Learn all the ways that Stripe can
grow revenue for your business at Stripe.com.
Okay. I want to zoom out a little bit and another
theme that came up a bunch when I ask people about
you and how you think is that you have a really
strong feeling that building great product
and building successful product is a moral
obligation of people that are in tech. Talk about
why you feel that way and what that even means.
Well, look, the example I use mostly is if you go
to an airport and you look around, you'll see a
lot of people using their phone to navigate that
system. They're trying to figure out where their
gate is, what time their flight's on, whether
or not... Can they pull up their boarding pass,
et cetera. And just watch people, watch
their faces, watch the level of confusion
and frustration. Some of them are tech superheroes
like you and me and most of your listeners, but a
lot of them are just mere mortals and they're not
living and breathing this stuff all the time. And
a lot of times they're super frustrated and then
take that and scale it out to their entire day.
And almost everyone living in a modern economy
now is going to have hundreds of interactions
with the phone or with a computer. And a lot of
those interactions are going to be consequential.
Unfortunately, a lot of those interactions
are not going to be great. They're going to
be confusing and frustrating. When I'm speaking
to live audiences, I often ask people, okay,
please raise your hand if you've had a frustrating
or confusing experience with software in the last
month? And obviously every hand goes up. Okay,
how about so far this week? Most all hands stay
up. I'm like, okay, how about so far today? And
most of the hands stay up, and it's often that I
speak in the morning, I'm like, okay, everybody's
had a frustrating experience with software and
it's 10 o'clock in the morning. That's a problem,
people, because each one of those interactions, it
takes a little bit of energy away from you and it
ramps your frustration just a little bit. And the
bummer about software, both for the audience and
for the creators is that it's an anonymous medium.
Nobody gets to see who's making these things.
You and I together, we might be able to name
six designers that have worked on products we
care about. And the only reason we could do
that is because a designer and I know a bunch of
them. By yourself, I'd be surprised if you could
name more than a handful. And again, we work
in tech. So if you think about the billions
of people out there that don't work in tech,
to them, these products are just these crazy
faceless things created by a bunch of people who
knows where, and these products are causing them
untold amounts of frustration and confusion, and
it just takes away from their life quality. And
I think we have an obligation as product people
to put that emotional energy back into people's
lives. They don't want to try to figure out how
to navigate our login screens or go through our
onboarding process, they just want to get
home and spend time with their families
and pet their dogs and have a nice dinner.
I just think every time we make a demand on
the audience, that's a failure on our part. And so
I do think it comes... I cast it in a moral way,
and I talk about it that way because I don't
think many people working in the industry
understand the scale of what they're doing,
again, because it's an anonymous field. We
never see anybody on the other side of the glass.
But I think with this podcast, it'll go out to,
I don't know, hundreds of thousands of people.
If you and I saw all the people that will
potentially listen to this in one place, we
would think to ourselves, oh my goodness,
that's like a lot of people. And we might think
of it differently. We might behave differently.
My team at Apple, but also my friends that
are working at Facebook or Google or wherever,
it's very hard to really understand that they're
creating something in Figma on their computer
that's going to be interacted with by billions
of people, thousands and thousands of times.
If you lose sight of that I think just, I don't
know, you get sloppy and disrespectful is the
wrong word, but I think you just lose sight of
how much impact you're having on other people.
Wow, that's really inspiring. That makes me
want to build products and make them awesome.
There's so much power to that. What this makes
me think about a little bit is kind of random,
but when I see someone click and watch
one of my podcast videos on YouTube,
I'm like, wow, that's one person that's going
to spend their time watching this thing. Wow,
I really want to make... It gives me more
motivation to make these even better and better.
Yeah, look, I think you have to find ways to
go... You have to find where you go out of your
way to see people using software in real time.
I've worked on products that have been used by
billions of people. I have friends who have
touched billions of people. None of us ever
get to see anybody use this stuff in the wild,
in their natural state. Maybe we see them in a
lab or something like that, but I've never seen
anybody just randomly using even Pinterest. But
there's ways that you can go and as a creator,
as a maker, you can go and watch people using
software in the wild. So just go observe
people going through self-checkout at Target,
which is the best self-checkout I've ever
seen. Go watch that, then go watch it at some
other grocery store where it's not as great
and really notice what happens with people.
Much to my kids' frustration when their friends
are over, I often grab their friend's phone
and just sort of flip through it to try to
understand how people are organizing their
home screens and which apps they use. And maybe
there's something in there that I haven't seen,
I'll ask them what that is and ask them to give
me a tour of it. I think we're living in a time
where people don't do so many usability
studies, so a lot of folks get pretty far
into their careers without ever having watched
mere mortals actually use software. Instead,
we're relying on metrics and stuff, which I sort
of joked that relying on metrics to understand
what's happening at the user level is like looking
at raw data from a radio telescope instead of just
going out inside and looking at the night sky.
You got to find a way to watch the audience.
Filmmakers can go to a theater, they can watch
people, understand stuff. Comedians can go
to a comedy club, they can start to develop an
intuition about why people laugh. None of us have
an obvious way to go watch people use software,
so we don't really understand how humans process
what's happening on the screen. And you have
to just find ways to do that. And fortunately,
software is everywhere. It's not just desktop or
mobile software. I mean, there's ATM machines,
there's ticketing kiosks, there's point of sale
systems everywhere. I mean, go watch somebody
over 70 fumble with a chip card insert or watch
somebody try to figure out Apple Pay. And these
are pretty seamless experiences and still
there's cognitive friction in all this stuff.
Just go rent a car and notice how long it takes
you to figure out what the heck is going on with
the dashboard. There's lots of opportunities
to try to develop that intuition of how people
navigate the human computer interaction,
and we need to find ways to do that.
An important element of what you're describing
here, which I think maybe people miss,
is that you're talking about just
any software, not your own product,
in order to start building your sense
of taste and gut feeling for what-
Building your sense of taste and gut feeling for
what works and doesn't work. And I had a guest on
recently, Guillermo Rauch from Vercel, founder
of Vercel, and he had a really great phrase of
something they do at their company. They have this
kind of mission of exposure hours. Increase your
exposure hours to people using our product. And
then you can extrapolate that to any product.
Yeah, well there's using your product,
but I always think when you're watching
somebody use your product, you come into it
with a psychological bias that makes it hard
for you to really see what's going
on. So there's something about just
understanding the audience and how they process
information on a screen, not your product.
At one point when I was redesigning a checkout
system, we did what I called a reality check,
which was we held a traditional usability style
exercise in a lab and all that sort of stuff,
but we had the subjects come through and
go through checkout in other products.
So we watched them go through eBay and
Williams-Sonoma and Amazon or something like
that. And we learned a ton about checkout, about
what was important to them, how it turns out ship
quote is almost as important as price. Things that
if we had been watching them use our own product,
I'm not sure we would've picked up on, because
we would've been sitting there yelling at them
to click on the button. Or we would've had a bias
and wanting to see the positive things. Whereas,
if you just watch people that are using
adjacent products could be super useful.
And again, we work in a medium, software
is a medium, and we need to understand our
medium in the same way. Again, musicians
go to concerts, filmmakers go to movies,
comedians go to comic clubs. When do people like
you and I go watch people just use software? Where
do we develop that intuition? And unfortunately
I think you have to go out of your way to do it.
Talk about more about this idea that software is
a medium. This is something that came up a bunch
also in conversations with folks that have worked
with you, that this is something that you believe.
Yeah, you're so good with the research, Lenny.
Yeah, look, so I left Pinterest in 2016, sorry,
2016. And I didn't have anything lined up so
I had some time to myself and I was driving
up and down the peninsula here in Silicon Valley
meeting with other design leaders and just sort of
commiserating with people. And you may remember
there was a very consequential presidential
election in the United States in 2016 and there
was some impression that social media had had a
significant impact on that election.
So I was kind of driving around Silicon
Valley and I was just sort of wondering what
the heck happened. I moved here in 1990 when
the hippie ethos that was really at the core of
Silicon Valley, and the hippie ethos was still
very visible, it was very much a part of what
was interesting to me about the valley when I
moved here. But 2016 is a long time later and
that hippie ethos had gotten pretty quiet.
And so I was listening to a podcast about
the history of Silicon Valley by a Stanford
group. The podcast was called Raw Data,
and it was season two. And it starts off
with an episode called A Monument to a Dead
Child, which is about Stanford University,
and it ends with Zuckerberg's testimony in
front of Congress. And in the middle of that,
they start talking about the counterculture
revolution in the late 1960s in San Francisco
and elsewhere. And they quote this book
by a guy named Fred Turner, I think it is,
the book's called From Counterculture to
Cyberculture. And he has this quote that is,
"you have to ask why it is personal computing
got started in Northern California in the late
1960s when at the time every major tech company
in the country was on the East Coast. And the
answer is because there was a very small
group of people in and around Stanford
University that saw software as a new form of
media on par with movies, music and books."
And when I heard that, all of a sudden I went,
wait a second, boom. That is why I do this. I
am fundamentally a maker. In high school I was
a photographer, in college I was going to be a
filmmaker, after college I went to music school.
After music school I started a graphic design
studio. I am a maker. And I realized looking back,
I was just hunting for my medium. And it took me
until I was 27 to find software as my medium.
It's like, oh, I'm a maker that designs software.
And then when I heard that software as a medium,
that whole concept of what I'd been doing with my
life and who I was about, it just sort of all
came together really quickly. And I realized,
oh, I am into software because software makes
me feel a certain way when it's working well.
And what I find so troubling now is that
a lot of time it's not working that way.
And I remember the first time I saw a computer,
probably a lot of people on listening to the
show can remember maybe the first time they saw
a desktop computer, probably the first time they
saw a pension zoom on a phone. You remember all
that stuff. It was just freaking magic man. It
was the future. It was so cool, and it just felt
like the most amazing aurora borealis, or sunrise,
or whatever. There was a sense of awe and wonder
that filled me and probably a lot of listeners,
that's probably the thing that
motivated you to be in the field.
And so I realized software is a medium because
there's an emotional component to it. Like a
hammer and saw, they're not really pulling
out an emotion for me. Maybe there's some,
if you're a carpenter, but I don't naturally have
an emotion with kitchen tools or things that I
think even more sophisticated tools like
calculators and pulleys, I still don't have
an emotional response to them. But every piece of
software I have an emotional response to. I either
feel confused or empowered. I feel like my world's
gotten bigger or my world's gotten smaller. They
all have an emotional component. And I think once
you realize and accept that, then you can say,
oh, there is an emotional component to what
we're doing with this product. I could just
leave that to chance, which is what most people
do, or I could try to be conscious of it and we
could try to bring that into our conception
of what the product's about and try to be
purposeful in the emotion we're trying to elicit
from the user. And I think that's where design and
particularly visual design can have a huge impact.
So again, in many conversations that I'd have in
design reviews, some executive would go,
"I don't know, ultimately this just kind
of comes down to a matter of opinion." And I was
always like, "no, it does not. Whether we choose
blue or red is going to elicit a certain emotional
response from the user. What is it we want them to
feel? And then let's make sure that we design
something visually that evokes that emotion."
So again, I think once you really get your head
around the fact that there are people on the other
side of the glass, real live human beings having
emotional moments with the thing that you're
putting in their hand and that they're focusing
their attention on. You are in those moments. And
are you going to own it and show up and be the
person you want to be in those moments or not?
A few months ago, I guess a little longer ago,
I was talking to the team at Toast who makes
the handheld point of sale stuff that they use
in restaurants. And the thing I was trying to
tell them, is whether or not you see it, tonight,
you're going to be at dinner with a few 100 000
people all across the country. And if we take
just one example, you're going to be at a very
nice diner with a grandmother and her two teenage
sons in Ohio, and the check's going to come and
the waiter, the waitress is going to hand over the
device to that grandmother, because she wants to
pick up the bill. And you have the opportunity
to either make her look like a superhero,
because she knows what she's doing, or to make her
look like a fool and one of her teenage grandsons
is going to grab the device and do it for her.
You're at the dinner table, what are you going
to do for grandma? You going to show up as well as
you can, or are you going to just let this whole
thing fall apart, because you didn't think hard
enough about grandma? And that's true for Toast,
that's true for every product any
of us are working on all the time.
This is so interesting and fascinating and
inspiring. I was going to ask how you use
this insight, that software is kind of the most
powerful medium media more than even than TV and
movies, and you shared it, which I think is really
important. So just to kind of double-down on this,
is the advice here is think about the emotion
you want the user of your software to have as
you're starting the design process,
not just what do you want them to do,
how fast do you want them to get to this flow,
it's what's the emotion you want them to have?
Yeah. I often don't think about what I
want them to do. I just think that's sort
of a selfish way to think about it. They
have something they want to do. I'm trying
to help them. I just don't ever approach these
things of the user's something for me to exploit
and take advantage of and manipulate. I know
there's people that do approach it that way,
which I think is a little unfortunate. But
as a designer, I guess I have my own set of
values and my own kind of compass on these
things that's pushed me in a certain way of
thinking about it. And so I'm kind of constantly
asking what's the right thing for the user?
And I believe in my heart that if we prioritize
that wonderful things will happen for all the
metrics, including the money metrics that matter.
I've never seen a product be successful that
used metrics as a driver for what they were
doing. I've seen a lot of companies be really
successfully seeing metrics as a consequence and
a way to evaluate the quality of their decisions,
and then using those to triangulate and make
better decisions moving forward. So they're
kind of a very useful feedback mechanism. But
I think there's definitely a risk to confusing,
doing something because it's a driver
versus something as a consequence.
There's a few more questions I would ask,
but I want to come back to something that
I asked earlier, that I think is on the minds
of a lot of say founders and product managers
listening to this. I'm just like, okay, this
all is sounds really great. I would love to
make these experiences so great. It's going
to take us a lot of time to do this really,
really well. You said that it doesn't
have to. What's a tactical tip or two
that you can suggest to a founder or
product manager to help them contain
the design process while also achieving
these outcomes that you're describing?
Well, I think if you can give... Maybe one
way to think about it is like a big giant
AI prompt. The more context you can give
it, the more specificity you can give it,
the more this is what I'm about and what we're
trying to get to, the more the designer's
going to be able to figure out which swim lane
they're supposed to be in to produce something.
So I think if you're going into it feeling like
the design process is going to take a lot of time,
it's because you haven't been clear in your
creative brief, so to speak, which often means
you're not really clear in your own head. And I
think... I have worked with a lot of founders,
and we could identify a bunch of big companies,
who I think got started that weren't clear in
their own head. I don't want to... Yahoo was an
amazing company, but if we just look at Yahoo for
a second, I worked there, it was never clear
to me what the founding vision of Yahoo was.
And I talk a lot about vision statements and
we could say the vision statement of Google is
organizing all the world's information. That's a
great vision. They'll never achieve that. That's
something that's always over the horizon. And
it's been a very useful organizing principle for
their acquisitions and how the company grows.
Amazon to be the Earth's most customer-centric
company. Okay, great. That's a vision, they will
never get there. It tells you how they're going
to expand. Apple doesn't have an explicit
vision, but I might describe it as personal
computing can have a transformative effect on
the lives of individuals. And I think that kind
of focuses a lot of what they're trying to do.
Disneyland, still the best vision statement of
all time, which is the happiest place on earth.
So once you tell an employee this is supposed
to be the happiest place on earth, then you're
signaling all sorts of things about how they need
to pick up the trash and how they need to show up
on time and how they need to wear their uniform.
You're just signaling a whole bunch of stuff.
So when I talked to founders, a lot of times
they just don't have that clarity of what's the
vision of the company. And to go back to Yahoo
for a second, I never heard of vision. And so I'm
not really sure what they were ever about. They
kind of stumbled into the directory and then
they added a bunch of stuff around the edges,
but it never seemed to make a lot of sense.
And so I think people operating inside Yahoo,
it ended up being inefficient, because they
were having to deal with all that ambiguity.
So I think that that can also be a
pretty big risk for founders. They
end up caught up with a product idea, and
they think that the company is the product,
the company is not the product. The product
is the product and the company's bigger than
the product. And you need to have some vision
that speaks beyond just this particular thing.
I think Slack, honestly, both Slack and
Pinterest I think are examples of products
that became companies, but neither one of those
places really knew what to do next, because they
didn't have a bigger vision of the change they
were trying to see in the world. So back to you,
you were asking a very pragmatic question. I
think you need to work on your prompt before
you go to your designers and try to give them
as much clarity about what you want to produce
as possible. And I think if you leave it open as
to the emotional response you want users to have,
you're inviting a lot of ambiguity, which
is going to invite a lot of inefficiency.
I love that answer. And it's so interesting that
AI can help us work better together as humans,
because when you find that the AI is
not achieving the outcome you want
as effectively as you want, that's a lesson.
This also translates the working with humans,
make the prompt more specific, add more context
in life, not just when you're talking to AI.
Yeah.
I love that. That's so interesting. So
the advice here is, if you're finding
design is taking too long or you want to just
level up your success with your design team,
give more context, spend more time on the
brief, on what you're actually trying to
achieve. And make sure there's a clear vision
or mission that everyone can row towards.
Yeah. Look, design is a problem solving
methodology. So the more variables you
can remove before they go into the process,
the more efficient it's going to be. And if
you give designers a lot of ambiguity, they're
going to spend a lot of time spinning around,
and honestly, that's your fault as the client.
As a design leader, I think one of my main
challenges is frankly trying to make the
PMs better clients, helping them get more
specific. It's very common for a design team to
get extremely ambiguous asks from a product team.
And the problem for designers, they have to take
all that ambiguity and they've got to wring it all
out. So when they give it to engineering,
engineering knows exactly what to code,
because computers don't tolerate ambiguity.
Engineers need to know what the thing's going
to be. And so design gets stuck with a really
ambiguous input, but they have to have a highly
specific output and then often timeboxed to do
that. And it's just not a recipe for success.
So you're much better off either kind of
compressing the PRD experience and bringing
the designers into that, kind of co-creating
with product and design really rapidly. But
you need to... You could think of it in some ways
as designers are going to draw the storyboards,
and if you don't give them a great script,
they're going to have a very hard time.
And then you can't give the shooting crew
ambiguous storyboards or you're just going
to waste untold amounts of money on set.
So if you think about those three steps
from script to storyboard to production,
it's all about getting rid of ambiguity.
And so the more ambiguity that can be removed
upstream, the faster design's going to go.
This begs the question then, you don't want to
give designers here exactly. Here's the thing
we're designing, make it really great and pretty.
There's always this balance of just give designers
space to think and be creative and explore.
Advice there of just how to navigate that.
Well, if you go back to my example of the script
and storyboard, scripts don't contain pictures,
there's still a lot of opportunity
to think differently and to come up
with original things and to have a lot
of creative input in the storyboarding
process. So the script is living mostly in
words, which is largely how PMs function.
The thing that I will say, to keep in mind
for PMs, there's always a tendency on PMs to
want to draw something and then try to give
a sketch to a designer. And I would caution
them against that. Sometimes they have to
draw themselves so they can think it out.
But if a PM came to me with something
that was drawn and kind of fully baked,
my response was like, thanks for giving me
that. Now I know exactly what we're not going
to do. Because as a point of pride, there's no
way I'm going to go execute that exact thing.
So you're right, PMs have to give you the
space to operate. And I think a lot of what
they're trying to achieve could be done in more
informal ways, conversationally and whiteboards,
things like that. But yet you need to narrow the
problem for the designers, they need constraints.
They don't need a tiny little box, but they need
constraints. Think in terms of, you don't give
them an airport tarmac and you don't even
give them a football field. You give them
something more like a basketball court, a sort
of scale at which they can do their design thing.
I want to talk about basketball later,
but not yet. You've shared a lot of
counterintuitive lessons on building
product, designing, building teams,
leadership. Is there another very counterintuitive
lesson you've learned about building products,
hiring leading teams that goes
against common startup wisdom?
The thing I would say is that you should
wait as long as possible to draw a picture.
I think that pushes against all the gen AI
tools that help you create prototypes. And
there's obviously a lot of excitement around
that. I can just give a prompt and the AI,
they're going to crank out of UI for me.
So I don't think I'm using the term right,
but I had this idea from art that I call the
primal mark, and that's the first mark that
you make on the canvas. And once you make
that mark on the canvas, everything you do
after that is in response to that mark. It
sort of sets your baseline. And so for me,
I always felt that as soon as we drew a
picture that looked even remotely real,
everybody gravitated towards that and said, oh,
that's the thing. And people were so uncomfortable
with ambiguity that they can't really deal with
the tension of, well, that might not be the thing.
And so as soon as you draw a picture that looks
even slightly realistic, much less something that
comes out of one of these gen AI tools, everybody
kind of goes, oh, that's the thing. You just keep
doubling down on that thing. And what's happened
is you've taken the possibilities from this big
broad thing down to this tiny little thing from
an AI system that's trained on existing solutions
and existing ideas and is maybe not even thinking
about it the right way, because all you've really
given it is your first-order of thinking.
I think there's a way you can stay in these
things conceptually and conversationally,
where you can get to your second, third,
fourth idea. And that's where stuff gets really
interesting. And again, I don't think that has to
take a lot of time. That can be over the course
of a single meeting, you could get to a second,
third, fourth idea. You just have to be willing
to not jump at the first thing that looks like a
possibility. You get that possibility,
you go, okay, well that's interesting,
let's table that. What else have we got?
There's one story that kind of related
that's useful. In one of my previous jobs, I was
responsible for the public website. I remember
coming across one of the product managers one day
and she's like, "Hey, this link on the home page,
we have to make it blue." I was like, "Well, we
don't use blue links anywhere." And she said,
"Yeah, yeah, but we just have to make it
blue." I was like, "Well, we're not making
it blue." And a couple of days go by and I saw
the home page and the link had been made blue,
because she had got around me and she'd
gone to engineering and just made it blue.
And I saw her in the hallway again. I was like,
"What the hell's up with that?" And she goes,
"Well, people couldn't see it." And
I'm like, "Oh, they couldn't see it,
so it wasn't prominent enough, right?" She's like,
"Yeah, it wasn't prominent enough." I'm like,
"Well, great. There's a 100 different things
we could do to make it more prominent, one of
which is making it blue, which is the thing that
came to you first because you're not a designer,
it's naturally... Because it's the most obvious
thing, but it actually doesn't fit in with
these larger things we're trying to do."
So I've often... I try to encourage the
product managers to what's the problem with the
thing? And then let us solve it. Don't jump to
it and tell us... Don't tell us this is just
exactly what we're supposed to do. And again,
I do the same thing on the roadmap. You decide
the roadmap, tell us what we're supposed to do,
I will ask you about it, and I may push back
and we may have some back and forth, but that's
your responsibility. I'm going to trust that you
are trained and you know what you're doing and
you're going to make the right call. And I just
want you to give me the same level of respect.
This advice about not drawing quickly and not
making that primal mark, which I love that term,
is, I'm curious your take on AI prototyping tools
these days. Because that's the extreme version of
that. Not only are you just creating a sketch,
it's like, oh, it's working, here it is. Here's
what it looks like. Thoughts on that, do you
discourage people from doing that, PMs especially?
Well, I think it's a production tool. Once
you know what you want and you can give it a
really robust prompt, then... I haven't played
with it a lot myself, because I'm not in an
operational role right now, but presumably it's
really useful at cranking out that actionable
prototype which you can click and experience.
And I've said for a long time that an interactive
idea needs to be expressed interactively, so
we're not talking with our hands and we can really
understand what's going to happen. So when the
idea is ready to be expressed, I think those tools
are probably fantastic. But ideas start off pretty
fragile, and the best ideas start off really
fragile. And I think when you push them to develop
too quickly and you put them out in the world and
expect them to be able to stand up to critique
too early, you're just going to squash them.
I often think about them like the little plant
in the Pixar movie, Wall-E, you've got to give
that little guy a little space, a little time,
some water and some nourishment, and you can't
really just suddenly put him out in the wind and
think he's going to make it. And so I think a lot
of... There's a lot of very fragile, interesting,
quiet ideas that I think you need to give some
space. And when you jump to the expression
of them, I think you're putting them at risk.
I'll also say that, everybody, when they look at a
prototype, what they're focusing on is the visual
and textual expression. And so as soon as you
produce something in high resolution the feedback
you're going to get is going to be about colors
and shapes and these presentation layer things,
which are very loosely related to usability
and value. It's like focusing on the special
effects of a movie that has a really bad story.
And so at ThoughtSpot, we used to use what we
call block brain diagrams, which were even
simplified versions of wire frames. It was
just big chunky blocks of here's how the screen
could be and where things might be located. And
because it was so low fidelity, people couldn't
get into commenting on what it looked like. We
had to talk about conceptually what it was.
And so we were trying to build up this firm
foundation where we could go from the block frames
to wire frames to kind of the final expression.
And I think it helped us clarify what we were
trying to do conceptually so that by the time
we got to the final visual presentation, that
stuff was actually really simple. And initially
it made the product team really nervous because
we would be sitting in these block frames and
wire frames for sometimes weeks, and they'd be
like, when are we finally going to see the comps?
And then what would happen, is because we had such
a robust design system, once we locked down on the
block frames, we could send it to an agency and
they could do the full high-res comps in a day,
because they knew exactly what they were
doing. And so the PMs were always like,
what the hell happened overnight? You're like,
well, it turns out that the high-res stuff,
that's not the hard thing. The hard thing is the
heavy lifting of thinking, what are we really
trying to do? That's the hard part.
And if you do the high-res stuff,
you really muddy the waters. And I think you
end up spending a lot more time churning,
if you didn't... Again, I'm going to go back
to the movie metaphor, because I studied
film. If you're trying to fix script issues
when you're in production or storyboarding,
you're going to churn and you're going to waste
a lot of effort. So you've got to figure out
what you're trying to do before you go draw the
high-res stuff. And I think a lot of the gen AI
tools, it's this seductive thing of, hey, let's
just go, let's go make the comp and see what we
think. I don't really know if you're going to
get anything great out of that process, maybe.
That's a really interesting counter-narrative
because it feels like every team now is just
straight to prototypes. I just had the C...
She's one of the CPOs at Microsoft. I realize
there's many CPOs, and she has this concept of
demos before memos and just prompt sets or
any PRDs, you should just be prototyping
all your ideas. And so it's interesting to
hear the perspective of maybe it's actually
hurting your ability to come up with a really
clever solution versus the obvious solution.
Yeah. Look, I think at some point, hopefully
people just back up and ask themselves,
are we actually producing better product
because of this process? And we're going faster,
but faster can't be the ultimate goal. You
need to be creating something great as well,
right? Something that's sustainable and frankly
that you're proud of and your users find value
in. And if you're just throwing so much spaghetti
at the wall, I don't know if having a spaghetti
throwing machine that goes faster is...
Look, there's a counter argument that's...
You can say, oh, it's like Darwinian evolution,
and we're just going to spin through a bunch of
random mutations and see what happens. And
I used to joke that it's true, that if you
take a bunch of hydrogen atoms and give them 14
billion years, you could end up with a tiger,
but you don't know you're going to get a tiger
and you could get a six headed shrimp instead,
and you don't really know when it's going
to shift. So I'm not exactly sure Darwinian
evolution is the way we create great product,
but a lot of companies are making a run at it.
I want to take us to a recurring segment on
the podcast called AI Corner. And in AI Corner,
I ask guests to share what's one
way that you've learned or figured
out to use AI in your job to help you do
better work, to help you do faster work?
Well, my job right now is trying to figure
out what my job is. And so the thing I've
been using AI for is I've very explicitly been
using it as a life coach. And so I had seen a
couple of prompts about asking it what a blind
spot was or what my strengths and weaknesses
were. I'd seen some prompts about that stuff.
And one of them was really fantastic. One of
them was, what's an outdated mindset that I'm
holding onto that's not still serving me? And
it came back with a very polite prompt or very
polite response about, well, given your age and
your profession, it's not surprising that
you're very wedded to the idea of control,
but that's not really the world we're living
in anymore. And that's not probably going to
suit the thing you're trying to do next, which is
writing and publishing and speaking and stuff. And
although it's statistically derived, it did come
back with a really nice phrase, which I view...
Although it's statistically derived, it
did come back with a really nice phrase
which I've used in your show, which was,
try to focus on choreography over control.
And so I thought that was really useful. I
asked for some of my blind spots, that was
also useful. I use it for a lot of exercise input,
that's useful. And the exercise that I've gone
through most recently was I realized that it was
inferring these things about me from the things
that I had asked it to help me with in the past.
So instead, I just switched. I just went to
ChatGPT, start a new project and said, I want
you to be my life coach. I want you to ask me
five questions a day for the next five days.
Let's go through those so you can explicitly
become better at helping me with this task.
And so we've just gone through that process
and it's been really useful for me. It's no
substitute for a therapist or a real coach or
anything like that. It's not a human being. It
doesn't care about me. I'm not saying that you
should use it instead of these other options.
You need a human being as well. But it's been
very good at reflecting back to me things that I
think have been floating around in my undermind.
So there's a wonderful book called Hair Brain
Tortoise Mind by a gentleman named Guy Claxton.
In that, he talks about the undermind. And
sometimes you might've heard this as your
unconscious or something like that. But I
think of your undermind as the part of your
brain that's processing information before
it gets to language. And then when you go to
consciousness, you've turned it into language.
And language isn't the full universe of things
you can think, language is what you can think in
English. And if you talk to multilingual speakers,
they'll tell you that they can think
things in other languages than what
they can think in English.
So if you only speak English,
you're only in one vein of what you could
think, but your undermind is operating through
all this other stuff. And for the computer
nerds out there, you could think about it
as a compiled code versus interpreted code.
So your undermind work in a compiled code and
it could do a lot of stuff that you
can't really do in the interpreted
code which moves slower and has different
orientations and we call that consciousness.
So I was feeding ChatGPT all this stuff over the
last year or so, and there are all these patterns
in my undermind that had been going into that I
wasn't able to express with conscious language.
And so when I started asking it questions, I
think what it was doing was it was statistically
reflecting patterns back to me that already
existed in my undermind, but because it was
putting them into language, my conscious mind
could now recognize them and respond to them.
And so again, as a life coach, I found it
very useful as a mirror back to things that
I was probably already thinking. And it
helped me clarify my thoughts. It's not
pushing me in new directions that a human
might do, but it's still been super useful.
That is extremely cool. That is a really cool
use case. I don't know if you've heard the Jerry
Colona episode that I did recently. Okay,
we'll link to it. He's got four questions
that he suggests people ask themselves.
The first is the title of the actual episode,
how are you complicit in creating the conditions
you say you don't want? And this often leads to a
lot of interesting insights about yourself,
and there's an important part of it,
complicit being like you're not responsible,
but you're actually helping achieve a thing.
It's a powerful word. Yeah.
And then also it's an important
element of say you don't want,
you say you don't want to be busy, but something
you just keep creating busyness for yourself,
maybe you do want this. So anyway, we'll link to
that episode. There's a lot of good stuff there.
Yeah, that's great.
Okay, one final question before we get to our
very exciting lightning round. This is one that
I don't think you have any idea I'm going to ask
you about. And so I'm curious where this goes.
This is a story that Joff Redfern suggested.
I ask you. He told me that you're obsessed
with space. You love researching
space, telling stories about space.
There's a story that you share about this
guy named John Hobolt. Does that ring a bell?
Oh yeah, totally.
Okay. Share that story because I think there's
something really powerful here
for people building products.
So I should clarify, I am a fan of astronomy
and space, but I'm a particular fan of the
Apollo program because I view the Apollo
program and the moon landings as the greatest
peacetime accomplishment of mankind ever.
And I think it's an incredible... There's
a profound number of leadership lessons and
individual lessons to be learned from that
program. And I've done multiple talks
about this. I could go on for hours.
Let's do it. Here we go.
The particular question you're
asking is John Hobolt. So, John was,
I can't remember exactly where he was at
the NASA hierarchy, but he was one of the
people that was tasked with figuring out
the question of how do you go to the moon?
So just to take yourself back in history a little
bit, John Kennedy, president Kennedy goes to Rice
University, I believe it's 19 September or
May 1962, he gives the famous moon speech,
we choose to go to the moon not because it's
easy, but because it is hard, that whole thing,
which I also have to say, and maybe a link to
this in the show notes as well, everyone should
go watch that talk. That is the perfect Ted talk.
It clocks in right at 18 minutes. It shows you how
to sell a big, giant, bold vision. The specifics
that Kennedy gets into the way he sets context at
the beginning, the technical problems are going
to happen, how much money it's going to cost,
the way he puts the passion, why we're
going to go to the moon, the whole thing.
It is an incredible talk. It's the only
moonshot talk ever because a moonshot has
to actually go to the moon. And so it is an
incredible talk. So go watch the talk. But he
steps off the stage and people at NASA are like,
we've only recently put Alan Shepard into space.
And he just went up and went down. That was
almost like it was a blue origins type thing
that was just up and down. We didn't even do a
lap around the earth like the Russians did with
Yuri Gagarin. And now we're talking about going
to the moon. Nobody knows how to go to the moon.
And there was three different options
for going to the moon, one at the time,
one was to build a big giant rocket and just
go straight to the moon. It's called direct
ascend. And the main advocate for that was Warner
von Braun, who was the main rocket guy in the
world. A little bit of a complicated past.
But nevertheless, Warner von Braun's a big
guy. He is, got the president's ear. He's like,
let's build a big giant rocket, go to the moon.
People are like, yeah, the problem is when you
get to the moon, the rocket's still super big.
So these guys are going to have to descend a big
ladder. That's a problem. So that was one idea.
There was another called Earth Orbit Rendezvous
where you spend two spacecraft into Earth and
then you link them up in Earth orbit and
then one of them goes off to the moon,
but you still got to land that thing on the moon.
And then there's a third idea called Lunar Orbit
Rendezvous, which is where you build a spacecraft
that includes a smaller spacecraft. So you send up
two spacecraft together, one of them's smaller,
much lighter, and you use that just as the ship
that goes down to the moon's surface and back up.
And that spacecraft is truly a spacecraft. It
only flies in space, which means the
engineering requirements around it are
profoundly different because it doesn't
have to survive re-entry into the earth.
And so as a result, it can be much lighter.
And it turns out that the whole problem of
landing on the moon is it's a weight problem.
You got to lift all the stuff off the earth,
which is incredibly expensive for fuel. You got
to land it on. There's just a lot goes on. And so
Hubert had come across this paper from a gentleman
named Yuri Kondrachev who was living in Ukraine
in the 1916, 1918 when he wrote this paper.
And he was the first guy to theorize Lunar
Orbit Rendezvous. And I try to take people back to
that. You and I can think about going to the moon,
but Yuri Kondrachev in 1918 is on the plains of
Ukraine looking at the moon, and he's actually
thinking about how to really go to the moon.
He's figuring it out. And so he writes this paper,
John discovers it years later, and John's trying
to sell Lunar Orbit Rendezvous. It's not going
over at NASA. And so eventually he decides to
go around all the hierarchy and he sends a very
famous memo to one of the top guys at NASA.
The memo starts somewhat as a voice in the
wilderness and then it goes on. And then there's
points in there where he's really emphatic,
do we want to go to the moon or not? And
then he goes through all the math of how
going to the moon is all about weight
and this was the only way to do it,
and there was no other option, stuff like that.
He just made the case and he risked his whole
career. The whole thing could have blown up.
He could have been fired for going around the
hierarchy and all that sort of stuff, but
of course, he's able to champion the idea.
And I think it was another year or so after
that famous memo, which you could read online,
it's nine pages long or something. After the memo,
it was still some time before they adopted Lunar
Orbit Rendezvous, but eventually they do.
And even with Don brought himself was very
complimentary to ALT for pushing that perspective.
So I tell the story, one, because it's just
amazing story and it does force you to
go back to the moment of like, wait,
they didn't actually know how to do it. We only
know how to do it now because they've done it.
But there's that moment of uncertainty and I
think you have to embrace and be amazed at that.
And it also shows you the power of these ideas.
A really great idea somehow finds a way to live
on somehow it just sits out there and it just
waits for its time. And Yuri had brought this
idea into the world and it just sat around
and then somebody it and dusted it off and
was able to push for it and it came through.
Then maybe the third lesson is ideas need
champions. They need champions willing
to put themselves on the line for them.
If you believe in something and you've made
your case and you can really make your case,
have the courage of your convictions and get
behind it and fight as hard as you can for it.
Such a great story. I love that you summarize the
takeaways too, by the way. So to me, the takeaways
and the lessons here is one is coming back to your
Pinterest board in the office, say the hard thing.
Two is be patient. It may take a little
bit of time for a radical idea, especially
to resonate and stick and get adoption. So
if you're pitching a big new product idea,
don't assume that they'll immediately agree. Also,
just this idea of if you really believe in it,
do go and champion it. There needs to be
someone passionately arguing for this.
Yeah, I'll just add to that one thing. I think
people need to understand that they're advocating
for ideas and not for themselves. And when I talk
to a lot of designers that may be true for PMS,
I hear a lot of people say that they're
reluctant to post on social media
or on LinkedIn or something because like,
"Well, I don't want to be self-promoting."
And I try to counsel them like, look, it's not
about self-promotion. There are ideas that you
care about that you want to see succeed in the
world. And so get out there as an advocate of the
idea. It's not about you, it's about the idea.
And don't be afraid to stand behind the idea.
We've spread a lot of good ideas in
this conversation, Bob. With that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
Yeah, let's go.
We added a ding to this. I like that drama you
added and there's a whole thing now. Okay, first
question, what are two or three books that you
find yourself recommending most to other people?
So the three books I'm going to recommend,
the first one's a beautiful poetic book about
typography called The Elements of Typographic
Style by Robert Bringhurst. Robert was the poet
laureate of Canada. And the first 80 pages
will change how you think about typography.
It will open you up to the wonderful world of
typography that we all live in. You'll think
differently about every sign you look
at, about every movie credit you see,
and it will give you an insight into the
designer mindset. When you understand typography,
I think you understand where designers
come from and the best designers I know
are just total type nerds. So highly
recommend Elements of Typographic Style.
Second book, Zen and the Motorcycle Maintenance.
Many people may know ultimately a philosophy book,
but it's about the concept of quality,
which I think is a very important topic.
So it talks about quality and the importance
of how things integrate into cohesive whole,
which I believe is the main challenge facing
most software teams. They create something
that's highly fragmented instead of a single
hole. So, Zen in the Motorcycle Maintenance.
And then the last one is a book called Time in
the Art of Living by Robert Gruden. It's just
a very interesting collection of impressionistic
views of time and how time passes and what time
means. So that's very different from the others
and it's not something probably gets recommended
on your show too often, but I think it'll
help people in their lives in a powerful way.
I think these are all brand new entries
in this question. Next question,
do you have a favorite recent movie
or TV show you've really enjoyed?
So I really enjoyed Severance. I enjoyed it
as a filmmaker. I was just blown away at the
filmmaking. I was intrigued with the story
and the characters. And I think as someone
who's worked in corporate America, when you
understand that it's basically critique and
commentary about the modern workplace.
There were times that I just thought
were unbelievably funny and insightful. It
was definitely interesting watching it with
my wife who was an attorney and hasn't worked
in those kinds of environments. So it was like
an episode where some people got disappeared and
the language that we're using was all around the
language you would hear around a layoff.
And so I was laughing myself to death,
but she was like, "What? What's going on?" So
that's super fascinating and then I'll throw
one other in there, which is not something I've
recently seen, but something I highly recommend
for everybody, which is Lords of Arabia. The
Lords of Arabia is I think one of the two or
three best expressions of the medium of film.
And so when you think about the ability to
hold moving pictures, characters, story,
music, photography, set design, costume,
the whole constellation of variables that come
to play into a movie, I think Lords of Arabia is
probably one of the two or three most complete
expressions of what the medium is capable of.
And I think it's useful to think about in
technology, all the different elements of
a product and all the different elements of a user
interface and how you can break those down the way
you can break down all these elements of a movie
and how many pieces of software do we use where
somebody is actually conducting that symphony
in a really coherent, powerful, full on way.
I love that movie. Next question,
do you have a favorite product that you have
recently discovered that you really love?
You're focused on recent and I'm just going to
push back. No, there's nothing terribly recent.
The stuff that I go back to, I'll give you a
couple of nerdy ones. I have a Leica M6 cam,
which is a film camera, and I recently started
shooting with film again, which I absolutely
love because it forces me to slow down.
I always talk about Leica cameras,
they're obscenely expensive, but the
thing about Leica cameras is you show up
different when you shoot with a Leica. So when
people think about cameras, they think about
the quality of the image, they don't think
about how the tool is going to change them.
When you show up with an iPhone, you're
thinking about sharing. When you show up
with a film camera, you're thinking about
saving film and you're spending more time
composing and thinking exactly about the
shot. When you show up with a digital SLR,
you just take a whole bunch of pictures
and hope something's going to turn out.
And so I think these cameras are very useful
metaphor for being conscious about how the
tools you pick are going to impact the thing that
you produce. So once you go into Figma, you've
made a decision about the thing you're going to
produce. If you stay in a sketchbook, you've made
a different decision. If you go into something
else, you've made a different kind of decision.
So I say the Leica M6 with film because of that.
And then the software product I would point out,
which is not terribly new, but I think it's
worth noting, is a tool called Habitica. And
Habitica is really fascinating. Ultimately,
it's a habit tracker and task management app,
but it's fundamentally a game.
It's a role playing game where you
create a character and your character revolves
and can buy armor and go on quests and things
as you check off your habits and stuff. And it
is the most interesting expression of shifting
conceptual models that I've ever seen.
So if you think about a conceptual model,
it's sort of the software equivalent of a genre
in a movie. And so once you say it's a project
management software, you're in a certain genre.
If you say it's a productivity tool, you're in a
certain genre. So if it's social media, you're in
a certain genre. So these are different genres.
And Habitica is really interesting because it
mixes genres, it mixes role playing game with to
do manager. And so I think it's a really powerful
example of how you can really shift the user's
thinking in the same way movies for example. Star
Wars is ultimately a cowboy movie set in space.
And when you come to those two genre mashups are
really interesting. When you come to a rom-com,
you have a certain expectation of what's going to
happen to a rom-com. If somebody suddenly got shot
in a rom-com, that would not make sense to you in
the same way that if somebody made a really funny
joke in a John Wick movie, it wouldn't make sense.
So I think Habitica is just the most interesting
example I've ever found is somebody really
doing a fascinating mashup of conceptual models,
which is... Sorry, I'll stop. It's an unexplored
and unexploited possibility of software ideas.
I love how profound this lightning
round already is. The point about
Leica changing the way you even think
about the photo is so interesting,
I've never thought of it that way. You mentioned
Star Wars. Have you seen Andor by the way?
No, but my wife, everybody's raving
about it. I've been watching basketball,
so I just haven't had the
spare time yet. But okay.
I have a basketball question, but
first of all, before we get to that,
do you have a favorite life motto that you
often come back to find useful and work in life?
Yeah, so there's three quotes that I come back to
all the time that I repeat in most of my talks.
First one I've already used, which is, design
is clear thinking made visible, by Edward Tufte.
Second one is from the American landscape
photographer, Ansel Adams. And I've also
alluded to this and the quote is, there's nothing
worse than a brilliant image of a fuzzy concept.
And then the last one is an African proverb
and it goes like this, if you want to go fast,
go alone. If you want to go far, go together.
And I think we've touched on all three of
those things today when we've talked about the
resolution of comps, we've talked about using
gen AI to try to go faster, things like that.
And those two ideas collide in interesting way.
People think if they cut their colleagues out
of the pie, they can go faster. And it's true,
they can go faster. You just can't go very
far. You need a group if you want to go far.
And just because you can create a brilliant
image doesn't mean you got a good concept.
Go look on Instagram, you'll find plenty
of photographs that tingle your senses
from a visual perspective and you will
forget them by the time you close the app
because they don't mean anything. And so
we live in a time when it's very easy to
produce things at incredibly high production
values, but they don't mean anything. And so
they're just like fancy potato chips.
There's no nourishment there, man.
I love that this connects back to the vibe
coding apps and prototypes that people build,
but you can do it really quickly,
but it won't go too far, potentially,
not to hit on those tools. They're amazing.
They are. All this AI stuff is profoundly amazing
and I will encourage people, one of the most
amazing things for me about this moment in AI
is that this, the kind of AI we're experiencing
has been theorized for well over 50 years.
So there is a vast warehouse of interesting,
amazing thoughts from philosophers
and engineers and social scientists
and people thinking about what is this
moment going to mean when we have this
sort of artificial intelligence that challenges
our conception of what it means to be human.
So there's so much stuff you could be reading
to help you process this moment in the very
intense and profound psychological
challenges it's bringing forth.
It definitely feels like we're
finally living in the future.
The future's actually happening.
It's going to be robots walking
around soon. We get self-driving cars all
over San Francisco and it's really stark.
It's a future. Yeah.
It's a future. Well, that's my concern
with a lot of the fiction of the future
is most of it is dystopian and here's all
the problems that we're going to run into,
which is going to be useful. Here's the
robot laws that we got to be thinking about.
Just to go back to this idea of how once
you create an expression of something,
people baseline off of it. I recently got to hear
Henry Modisett who's head of design at Perplexity,
give a talk. And one of the things he
said that just really struck me was
that people's conception of AI was founded,
was put out there by Hollywood years ago.
So this idea that AI is going to take stuff over
and is ultimately really dystopian and malevolent
towards humans and stuff like that, it's actually
something that's created by Hollywood and now
we're trying to outlive how and stuff like that.
And so it's just such a great example of
somebody put the concept out there and
planted that seed in people's heads and
now we're struggling to get people off that
baseline and to look at it with fresh eyes.
That's a really good point. It's
much more entertaining to watch
AI try to kill us all, not just, oh,
everything's amazing. Great job, AI.
Okay, final question. I know you're
a huge sports fan. In particular,
you're a big Warriors fan. So let me just ask you
this. Say you were running the Warriors, the owner
of the Golden State Warriors, what would you
change? What would you change to help them win?
A real team can't be dependent on a single
player. And I think there's such a dramatic
difference in the Warriors when Steph is on
the court and off the court. If you listen to
the local announcers, they're always like,
"These non-Steph minutes really matter."
I look at that, I'm like, that's not really a team
then, right? That's Steph in the band of Merriman.
And the Warriors are bigger than that and most
of these basketball teams are bigger than that
currently. I think across a lot of places in the
NBA, there's a single player that can go down that
makes a difference in the organization's success
and that just seems dangerous and not a team.
So I don't know what to say. I don't know how
you replace Steph Curry. He is a singular,
if you even call him a generational
player, it's a bit bigger than that.
He is unequivocally the greatest shooter
in the history of the game and he's one
of only two or three players has actually
fundamentally changed how the game's played.
But I just know for winning, the Warriors
are at risk because Steph is meaningfully
old for an NBA player and you can't have
the whole franchise built around just him.
I love this hot take. A great way to
end it, Bob. I can listen to you all
day. This is so fun and interesting
in so many ways on so many levels.
Two final questions. Where can folks find
you online if they want to reach out and
maybe learn more about what you're up to
and how can listeners be useful to you?
So, Bobbaxley.com is the easiest place right now.
It's just a bento site, but I'll get some more
stuff up there in the coming days, hopefully
before this episode goes out. We'll see.
But there's plenty of links there that'll
help you connect to me on LinkedIn and some
of my talks and a few Links to some other
things that I find useful. Just find me on
LinkedIn. I publish pretty much every day on
LinkedIn, so that's an easy way to find me.
I'm happy to be connected to whoever is interested
in being connected. And then in terms of how you
can help me, I'll go back to what I said earlier.
It's not really about me, Lenny, it's about these
ideas. It's about the idea that software matters,
that we're making something for people on the
other side of the glass and that it's a way that
we show that we care and that we should care.
So it's not about me, it's about us together
trying to create a digital world that we want
to live in. The digital world right now,
it's not something we really want to live
in. It's not a place any of us would turn our
kids loose in. You and I talked about this
earlier. The digital world's not safe for our
kids. Have we done something wrong? So I hope
people take that responsibility more seriously
and try to help clean things up a little bit.
I think we've made a dent in that.
Bob, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you so much, Lenny. It's been a real honor,
privilege, and just a ton of
fun. So thank you so much.
Same for me. Bye everyone. Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable,
you can subscribe to the show on Apple
Podcast, Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can
find all past episodes or learn more about
the show at Lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.