The way you described the early years of Notion,
you described the first three
to four years as the lost years.
We try many different versions. The first
version, okay, everybody can make and create
their software, so let's just build a developer
tool that's so easy that more people can do that.
We tried that a couple of years and learned
that actually most people just don't care. Our
realization is actually let's hide our vision,
which is everybody can create their software
in the form factor that people do care. So what
kind of tool do people use every day? Productivity
software. It took us two years to realize we
need to build a productivity tool. We called
it sugar-coated broccoli. People don't want
to eat the broccoli but people like sugar,
so it gave them the sugar then
hide your broccoli inside of it.
What other elements do you think are key to you
finding something that actually ended up working?
What is the building a product or business.
You want user. You want revenue. That's the
product business. And building for something
you want the world to have is building for
your value. You have some taste. You have
some aesthetic. There are different energy.
You need to create a balance. Too much of
yourself. Then there's no users. Then you're
just doing our project. And too much for
business, you're building a commodity.
The way you think about Notion, it's
almost like a philosophy of how to work
and be versus just a productivity
tool. And so I'm just curious how
you think about the relationship
between tools and human potential.
Tools are extensions of us. And once
they extend us, once we shape them,
once we bring them to world,
they can come back to shape us.
Today, my guest is Ivan Zhao. Ivan is the
co-founder and CEO of Notion. Ivan is a
really unique and also a deeply philosophical
founder who doesn't do a lot of podcasts,
so I'm really excited to share a glimpse into how
he built one of the most beloved and
most popular products in the world.
We talk about the first three to four years
of Notion that he describes as the lost years,
how he was able to get into a great school
in China by winning a programming contest,
the joy and suffering of building a successful
horizontal product, plus his approach to staying
lean and craft and making trade-offs and also
leadership. Also, a wild story about how Notion
almost died during COVID because the one database
that everything lived in almost ran out of space.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you become a
paid annual subscriber of my newsletter, you now
get a year free of Notion Pro and Perplexity
Pro and Superhuman and Linear and Granola.
Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Ivan Zhao.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo. Eppo is a
next generation A-B testing and feature management
platform built by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake
for modern growth teams, companies like Twitch,
Miro, ClickUp, and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation
is increasingly essential for driving growth and
for understanding the performance of new features,
and Eppo helps you increase experimentation
velocity while unlocking rigorous deep analysis
in a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform where
I could set up experiments easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my
own. Eppo does all that and more With advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time, and accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance, and out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying prolonged
analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A-B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Airtable
ProductCentral, the unified system that brings
your entire product org together in one place. No
more scattered tools. No more misaligned teams.
If you're like most product leaders, you're
tired of constant context switching between
tools. That's why Airtable built ProductCentral
after decades of working with world-class product
companies. Think of it as mission control for your
entire product organization. Unlike rigid point
solutions, ProductCentral powers everything, from
resourcing to voice of customer, to roadmapping,
to launch execution. And because it's built on
Airtable's no-code platform, you can customize
every workflow to match exactly how your team
works. No limitations, no compromises. Ready to
see it in action? Head to airtable.com/lenny
to book a demo. That's airtable.com/lenny.
Ivan, thank you so much for being
here, and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for having me.
I know you don't do a lot of podcasts, and so
I'm very honored that you're here. I want to
start with the story of Ivan. Your background
is quite unique for a founder of a $10 billion
plus tech company, and I don't think a lot of
people know it. For example, you grew up in a
small town in China. And the way you got out
of there, the way you got into tech is pretty
interesting. Can you just walk us through that
early years of Ivan and how you got out there?
Yeah. I think a small town in China, the
definition, it's actually 4 million people.
It is called Urumqi. It's in the northwest desert
part of China. So I grew up there and then I moved
into... My mom took me to Beijing, the capital
of China. And that's actually how I got into
programming, coding, because I'm from somewhere
else and in order to go into good school in the
capital, you need to win some kind of competition.
And there's different paths. You can get at math
or you can get at programming like Information
Olympiad. I was really into computer games at
the time so of course I picked the programming
one so I can play computers all day long. And
I win some competition and got me to a good
school. So that's how I got into programming.
Later then, I moved to Canada. When I moved to
Canada, got into college, did not study computer
science since I already knew how to code, but a
lot of video games. Did a lot of art actually, art
and science. By the time I graduated college, I
realized most of my friends are artists. They need
to make their websites, get web portfolio made.
And I'm the only nerd in my art friend circle so
I made three or four websites and realized, "Oh,
actually people don't know how to create with the
software media, computing media." So that got
me into want to create a product like Notion
today which it allow more people to create tools,
create software for their daily work and life.
Okay. So going back to get into a great
school and to leave the small town,
not so small, you had to enter
a programming contest. And you
placed first or second or how well
did you actually do in this one?
Second in Beijing.
In Beijing, okay.
Pretty big. Beijing is a big city.
Okay. Incredible. Another
stat or a story I heard is
that you learned English by watching
SpongeBob SquarePants. Is that real?
Yeah, it's real. I moved to Canada pretty late, 16
years old, and what I learned is in China you can
learn English but it's typically just grammar and
doing exams. What you're missing is the context,
the culture. So you have to watch SpongeBob or
Simpsons to get a sense of humor essentially.
You can understand jokes. Watching cartoons,
it's probably the easiest way to do that.
That's amazing. And there's another seminal moment
in your path. I don't know if it was this point or
later, but the Douglas Engelbart paper ended
up being a very meaningful moment for you.
So while I was in Canada in last year of school
working on trying to building website from our
friends and building a creative tool for them, and
then you just look into the history of a creative
tool for software, for computing. Eventually
arrived at 1960 and '70s. So you realize the
first generation of computing pioneers, which is
around San Francisco, Stanford areas, South Bay,
they actually had the best ideas. For them,
people like Douglas Engelbart, Alan Kay,
Ted Nelson, those first generation pioneers, for
them computing, there shouldn't be a separation
between builders and users. It's the same medium.
Engelbart's original paper called Augmenting Human
Intellect, when I read that paper, it's like holy
shit. If you are making software, if you know how
to code or design, this is the highest leverage
thing you can do for other people. So giving them
the ability to use computing to augment their
problem-solving ability or their intellect,
that just got me obsessed with this problem
and I want to start a company like Notion.
It makes me think of Steve Jobs's famous line
of how the computer is a bicycle for the mind.
You know what? Steve Jobs is actually at fault
of this in some strange ways. So the story is...
Actually, the fact. It's not a story. Xerox
PARC has working on the first-generation
personal computers called Xerox Alto. Alan
Kay was one of the main persons behind it.
Alto runs down the system called Smalltalk, which
is there's no separation between users and users'
app. There's no thing called application.
Everything is malleable. You can change the
tools. So when Steve Jobs, the famous story is
when he went to Xerox PARC to in demo with Alto,
he does not... It's the first time he see
graphic user interface, one of the first time,
and it's also they present them with this Alto
system that everything could change. But he did
not see the power of it. Even when people would
demonstrate like, "Hey," Steve Jobs say, "I don't
like this direction of scroll bar direction.
When you scroll up and down, it shouldn't scroll
the opposite reverse direction." Then people just
instantly change the scroll bar direction for him.
That's the power of the original Smalltalk
Alto system. He only saw the graphic user
interface. He did not see the underlying
object or the environment power. As the
generation of Steve Jobs and Bill Gates
made PC, personal computing, popular and
they stuck with this an application framework
rather than the Smalltalk object framework.
Then that has all the apps we have today
and has the SaaS route we have today.
That vision of how products should be sounds
very familiar and we'll talk about that
later of how you think about Notion, but
let's assume to the beginning of Notion,
when we were chatting earlier, the way
you described the early years of Notion,
you started Notion in 2013 and some
over 10 years ago at this point,
you described the first three to four years is the
lost years of Notion. And I think this is actually
a really big deal for founders to hear about
because there's all these companies these days,
you hear these stats, they had 100 million ARR
in two years, in under two years now. And you
don't hear a lot of stories of companies of your
scale and success that took three to four years
to find product market fit essentially. What went
on during these lost years as you described them
and just how did you stick with it? That's a long
time to stick with something that isn't working.
Because the goal is always building a computing
tool. It's like what product is this? It's really
hard to shape the product. The vision is, the
dream is there, but the product is very...
There's so many paths. We'll try many different
versions. The first version to take, okay,
everybody can make and create their software.
So let's just build a developer tool that's so
easy that more people can do that. We tried that
a couple of years and learned that actually most
people just don't care. The majority of people,
they wake up, they have report due, they need to
get their job done, they don't care creating
software to optimize whatever they're doing.
They don't care. So we give to our friends, give
to investors. It did not resonate with people.
But we really want to build
that tool so we just keep going
and our realization is actually, let's
hide our vision, which is everybody can
create their software, in the form factor that
people do care. So what kind of tool do people
use every day? Productivity software. So that's
why it came to Notion today. If you use Notion,
Notion are more understood as the productivity
suite, but our intent, and if you use Notion, more
you discover intent, which is that it has
a no-code developer power into it and you
can create almost any kind of productivity
software using Notion itself. That took us
two plus year to realize. So actually the world
is not like you. The world are not developer,
designer mind. That the world is they only care
what's in front of them and they're so noisy.
There's a quote that this makes
me think about where you said,
"The first version of Notion was more about
what I wanted than what people wanted."
It's very much so because sense of maturation
is you don't see the world just from your
perspective but from outside your perspective.
At tech, we were young. Took us multiple years.
It hit your head straight into the wall
to realize that. People just don't care.
I love the way you phrased that, that you
have to hide your vision behind something
that people understand and know how to use and...
We call it sugar-coated broccoli. People don't
want to eat the broccoli but people like sugar,
so give them the sugar then
hide the broccoli inside of it.
Wow. The other thing I've heard is that
you threw away your code every time,
so you rebuilt it many times. You
threw away the code each time.
That's true. Actually, it took us four year
to get somewhere. First two year is that you
build too much like developer product. Nobody
cares. It took us two year to realize we need
to build a productivity tool. Then it took
another year to realize to build this out,
but in the middle of that I realized we built
on the wrong technical foundation. So eight,
10 years ago, there's computing before. Right now,
all the web app runs on React. Before React wins,
there's a competing technology called Web
Component from Google. And it makes sense.
Web Component feels like a Lego-like, the building
block-like, and we're betting on that technology.
And then we realize because it's so new, it's
just so unstable. It don't know where the bug
come from. It's from your source code or from the
underlying libraries? Then we have to restart the
company, rebuild the whole thing. Otherwise,
we're going to run out of time. So we set a
code base. We set a company so we can build on
our own more orthodox technology foundation.
How did you actually stay solvent all this time?
A lot of people want to keep working at an idea.
Oftentimes they need to pay the bills. How
practically were you able to keep working
for three to four years? I know there's a story of
your mom loaning you some money during that time.
Well, Chinese mom always can help, and I'm
a single child. Yeah, actually my mom helped
me kickstart the company because I'm Canadian.
In order to move to US, you need to register a
company. So my mom helped me with the initial
and raised the money. I returned the money to
her. Then we run out of the money so, "Hey
mom, can I borrow that just to bridge us?"
Which she did. I'm really grateful for that. How
we bridged? How do you last here so long? Because
the thing you want to create does not exist,
which what is called Notions. It's a Lego for
software. It doesn't quite exist. There's a Lego
for Lego. You can see that in furniture exist,
but Lego for software at the usable mass market
adoption level doesn't quite exist. And you
just want that thing to exist. And I grew up with
Legos. It's the only toy I ever wanted, and I want
the same feeling of creativity and playfulness
to the toy that people can use every day. And
my co-founder, Simon, feels the same way. Lego
is the only thing he wanted for every Christmas.
Have you guys seen Magna-Tiles though? I have
a one-and-a-half-year-old and Magna-Tiles are
quite delightful. I think it's like a
pre-Lego. The children can play them.
Magna-Tile?
Yeah. It's like they're little magnetic
plastic planes and then you can build
much bigger things really quickly. It's
more for babies, but I'm having a blast.
Oh, I see it. It's like... Uh-huh.
It's a different version of Legos. I like that
you're in real-time looking it up. You're like,
"Okay, our new vision Magna-Tiles for software."
Now, most people know, "Oh, Magna-Tile."
Idea is the same. Modular, right?
Yeah, creativity. Okay, back to your story.
So there's also a moment where you moved
to Japan. Just what was that about?
Is that just escape and disconnect?
Yeah, that was during one of the rebuild phases.
During the... We know what the product should look
like. It should be a productivity software with
a Lego power hiding inside of it. We build on the
wrong technical foundation. And if we continue to
build on the wrong ones, we're going to run out of
money. Company won't exist. So we decided to lay
off everybody. At that time, the Notion was five
people. The layout I brought back to me and Simon,
two people. And morale obviously there was really
low. You have to say goodbye to your teammates.
And so we have the idea, "Let's just go somewhere
that we've never been to change the scenery a
little bit." And Japan is always top on our list.
So the funny thing is if we... And we subleased
our apartment and office. We're actually making
money living in Japan and then San Francisco.
So we did that for a while. We actually travel
around the world for a while just to
change it up, me and Sam just coding
every day and design every day. That's some
of the happiest moments. Birthday every day.
I saw a stat you're coding 18 hours a day.
Here's the quote I heard, :We just code,
code, code. Then hey, let's go for food. Then
we go eat, go back to work, and do it again."
Because me and him working so well now. Even
back then, it's like you know what each other
other people are thinking and you can just
cross through the problem space really
quickly. The technical product space, design
space, and just non-stop of shaping stuff.
So maybe just to close out this thread,
for people, for founders that are either
struggling and just can't find a thing
that's working, "I've been working on
something for a long time," I'm curious what
advice you'd share for sticking with it. And
I'll share things I've heard you say so far and
I'm curious if there's something you'd add. One
is you just believe this needs to exist in
the world and you need to really feel this,
"I need this to be a thing." I think
there's an element of staying lean,
like you've let everyone go and it's just you
and Simon again. There's also this element of
disconnecting almost and just going to a different
location and just like, "Let's just reset."
What other elements do you think are key to you
finding something that actually ended up working?
I'm lucky and Simon lucky that high is never too
high, low is never too low for us, so somehow it
wasn't feeling too down. Whenever I feel down, I
just go to sleep and next day I'm just reset. So
that's lucky for me. Definitely don't be afraid
to reset. I think courage is quite important
because oftentimes you're working on things don't
matter, but momentum just took you there. Your
first point of building something you want the
world to have. What is the building a product or
business? You want user. You want revenue. That's
a product business. It's almost like a sports. The
market is the arena. Then you'd want to optimize
the scorecard where it's building for winning.
And I grew up playing sports. I
like to compete so I like that.
And building for something you want the world
to have is building for your value. You have
some taste. You have some aesthetic. You have
some values. You want the world to have more
of that. They are different energy.
I realize actually fairly recently,
they're really different. Depends on which day I
wake up, I might be in different mood for things,
but building for value it's more lasting and more
fulfilling. Looking in the thing we're building
today and looking back, I find most proud of thing
I create something authentic to myself and happen
to be also useful for others, and that just keeps
you going. And that feels like a more durable
energy source for all those dark years, loss
years during Notion, and still every day for me.
It's interesting you say that because also
there's this aspect of it wasn't working
initially because you're building it for yourself
and not for people, but what I'm hearing is it's
still important to build a thing that you
are still excited about but also have you
go back and forth. Here's what the business
needs and here's the thing I'm excited about.
Yeah, really a cue. Almost like a therapist,
right? It's true. You're building too much
for your own self and value without
realizing at the end of the day,
if you're building a product and tool has
to be used by others, you need to create
a balance. Too much of yourself, then there's
no users. Then you're just doing our project.
You're just doing a research project. And
too much for a business, you're building
a commodity. So where's the spectrum? Yeah,
it's never ending spectrum. It's interesting.
Yeah, okay. So I'll summarize some of those
things you shared of just how to stick with
it and stay with an idea and not give up.
So I love that you said just get sleep,
very Brian Johnson of you, just like,
"Get some sleep when it's a real down
day. There'll be another day
tomorrow." Really simple but...
It's like a daily personal physical reset. You
can reset your code base. You
can reset your mental model.
Okay. And then there's also, I love
these points. Don't be afraid to reset,
as you just said. Tobi Lutke was on the podcast.
He said the same thing. "Just be comfortable with
some cost. I have done all this already and I will
throw it away and start again and that's okay."
Yeah. I think it's not just a self-help way
to say don't be afraid to reset. That's like,
that's okay, that's fine. I think the more
interesting point here, it's like you can
create progress through better abstractions.
And that thing compounds faster, can catch up
to all the things you build much quicker than
you ever thought. Or humans are not thinking,
not good at thinking in terms of abstraction
or exponentials. We're thinking in terms of
linearly. If you just reset it and you find a
better way to do it, you can get all the thing
you have to some cost recovered really quickly.
So actually going back to the computing pioneers
part, small talk, one of the first system
and a huge influence for Notion was really
tiny code base and inspired by Lisp, which is
another programming languages and probably a
hundred lines of code or something. The
kernel of things could be really small,
but just like math. It can compound. It can have
complex behavior that unlocks so much value and
things for you. But if you just find those right,
you can catch up to all the things you did. You
are free to lose really quickly. So I think
that's the kernel of why reset is so powerful.
And we're seeing exactly what you're
describing in LLM advancements these
days. All these companies have been working on
this for so long and then they've cracked an
abstraction of how to think about scaling
these systems. And now just people launch
them and are immediately where the companies
that have been working this for decades are
today because they are building off these
abstractions as you described in these.
Trying to caught up the US really quickly.
With DeepSeek, yeah. The point you also made
about momentum, be weary of momentum taking
you in direction and moving in a different...
not being stuck to that direction is exactly
the way I think the chain of thought models
network actually where generally LLMs are like,
next word, next word, next word, next
word. And if they ever make a wrong turn,
they're stuck. They keep going from that path.
And these chain of thought models are now good
at just like, wait, let me rethink. Is
this actually the right path or should
I start again? So I feel like AI has almost
figured out exactly what you're describing.
Interesting.
Oh, man. Okay, last question about the early
years. Everyone's always wondering what does
product market fit feel like? You worked on it
for three to four years. What was the moment?
What would it look like? What was different
when you're like, "Okay, this is going to work"?
I think going back to me and Simon, high is never
that high, low is never that low, it never hit us
as a binary state. Just like, "Oh, good. We have
people who care about this thing we make now. Oh,
good. People reach out to us who are paying us."
And it's a very gradual ramp. Maybe that's why
early days when it's really the lost eras, it
doesn't feel too low because it just... Even for
Notion today, it feels like it's so small in terms
of where it could be. It just they keep going,
right? It's a less of a milestone way to thinking
about things. It's more just like, "Can we do
the same that's in our head and better than we
did last week?" way of thinking about things.
So there's a such movement that product market,
boom, milestone achieved. Didn't feel that way.
I've heard that from a lot of founders actually.
Was there a moment in that point of just like,
"Oh, this is different," or, "Maybe
it's going to work this time"?
I think for a while, okay, once
we start revenue, product grows
faster now. Investors start knocking on the
door was like, I remember one day it's like
there's a dog food, dog treats sent to our
entire office. So first of all, office wasn't
public, the address. And the dog treats, why
do people want this so much? So that was a
moment I paused a little bit and I guess
there's enough attraction for investors.
And the dog treats were trying to...
It was like a gift to be like, "Hey,
you should talk to us. We're
sending this fun gift."
Yeah, because of the way how we just hire
someone in the office as a dog. Then I
think we post on Twitter or something. And I
said, "Why did this show up to our office?"
Someone really hustled into where we are in
our office address and follow us on Twitter.
Did you end up taking their money?
Not the first time, yeah.
Okay, later. Okay, it's long game.
No.
Awesome. So I've never heard that before.
Sign product market fit as VCs are starting
to... You start getting a lot more
messaging and cold outreach from VCs.
Actually, I had one of our investor, it's
really helpful because all those years you
just like there's no feedback loop. You just
go for it. Then the feedback loop gradually
show up. Then for a while it's, oh, VCs start
knocking on doors. So I should talk to those
people. The people like what we're doing. I did
some meetings, quite a few of meetings. Maybe it
doesn't... I realize and one of the members is
saying, "Ivan, what are you doing? You clearly
don't need money. You're just trying to feel good
to do external validation about this." And I said,
"Oh, that's so true." It doesn't help us make
a better product and the truth is with what
customer tell us. Then we just went back to
building. I went back to hardcore building,
no meeting modes. That's where the dog food story
came about and realized, "Oh." It's interesting.
You mentioned this investor, they said
it was really helpful. Is you want to
give them some credit or do you want to keep-
Oh, Shana Fisher. She's in New York.
Okay, cool.
Yeah, she's like another therapist, right?
This episode is brought to you by Sinch, the
customer communications cloud. Here's the
thing about digital customer communications.
Whether you're sending marketing campaigns,
verification codes or account alerts, you need
them to reach users reliably. That's where Sinch
comes in. Over 150,000 businesses, including eight
of the top 10 largest tech companies globally,
use Sinch's API to build messaging,
email, and calling into their products.
And there's something big happening in
messaging that product teams need to know about,
Rich Communication Services or RCS. Think
of RCS as SMS 2.0. Instead of getting texts
from a random number, your users will see your
verified company name and logo without needing
to download anything new. It's a more secure and
branded experience, plus you get features like
interactive carousels and suggested replies. And
here's why this matters. US carriers are starting
to adopt RCS. Sinch is already helping
major brands send RCS around the world,
and they're helping Lenny's podcast listeners
get registered first before the rush hits
the US market. Learn more and get started at
sinch.com/lenny. That's S-I-N-C-H.com/lenny.
I want to shift to talking about Notion today
and the way you've approached it and a good
segue is what you've been talking about right
now is how lean and efficient you've been and
how that's been a big priority for you. So
a few stats I've seen. One is that you guys
are profitable. You've been profitable for a
couple of years now. I don't know if you've
spent even the money you've raised.
I think most of it is still in the...
Yeah.
It's still in the bank. You're nodding,
if you're on YouTube. You didn't have a
salesperson until you hit over 10 million ARR.
You hired your first PM at 50 people. You've
always kept the team generally really small.
Why is that been important to you? It's very
cool now. Everyone's like, "Of course, that's
how it should be." But for the past decade,
that has not been the case. You've always
been that way. Why has that been so important?
I think going back to the abstraction system
way of problem solving, I think we're lucky
that me and Simon and Akshay, we have the
skillset you probably can run a whole company,
which is a couple of us, I can design, I can do
marketing, storytelling, close sales deals. So
you realize you don't need a lot. But when you
can do a lot at the same time or hire people
who can do that, naturally keep the company
small. And you all know you're doing product
management. The overhead is actually more from
internal communication. It's really hard to get
people's mind to be aligned on things, to
see the world in the same way. And the part
that you do need people, maybe you can solve
better through systems, through better tools.
Notion itself is a meta tool to build other tools.
So we pretty much run everything on Notion. We use
the same mindset to build our company. And
accidentally, that keep our headcount low,
keep our company profitable, which then puts
you on a positive treadmill of you don't have
to go for the next 18, 24 months to find
money. You can just focus on building.
And also because your team's small, we have this
internal Notion called talent density. We don't
try to track number of people but we try to
track how talent-dense, revenue per employee
we are. And people want to work with either more
talented people. So it's a positive company group.
I wonder how much of this is actually from being
around for so many years without success of,
"We just have to stay very lean and save our cash
because otherwise, we'll die." Do you think that
was a formative experience to inform how you
want to operate or is that always something?
No, I wouldn't say we're, Notion, is a cost
saving-first company. I like fancy chairs. I
like furniture. But we're not wasting money. I
think it's more just from a taste or approach
to problem solving. I just believe better system
is much better than brute force through people.
When people hear this idea of staying lean and
staying small, it sounds great or we're going to
be super efficient and lean and smart with our
money and down dense. It's very hard to do and
it's very hard not to hire more engineers,
more designers. What advice do you have for
folks that want to operate this way? What has
allowed you to actually be successful while
staying lean and not having as many engineers
as competitors, many designers as competitors?
I think just understand abstraction or
system is a better curve than pecan curve,
right? Linear. We internally help
other people and understand this.
Internally we use the metaphor that Notion's
a small bus. The bus, the smaller the bus,
it's easier to turn corners, easier to accelerate,
easier to maneuver. The bigger the bus it is,
bigger the boat or bigger the bus, slow down.
And as a leader in the company, you decide
who sit around you on the bus seats. That dictates
how fast our overall bus moves, dictate your work
and life experience at this company because you
pick your roommate, you pick your seat mates.
That metaphor clicks with people inside a company
and overall help us optimize to make the bus link.
I've never heard of that metaphor before.
It probably came up somewhere
but... Or it does not.
Small bus. So along these lines actually, so I
visited the office recently and I noticed that
it's just a very cozy vibe. And I learned that
you had a rule of no shoes in the office for a
long time until the last office, that you
all ate around one table for a long time,
that you try 30 different shades of warm
white on the walls before you chose. Why
is that important to you? Why is it so important
to be so thoughtful about the office experience?
Maybe there are two dimension part of it. One
is the pragmatic part. You just want office to
be a pleasant experience to be at. Therefore, most
office, the top light feels like hospital. You're
just like, "Oh, man." And the white is so pale and
the floor is so dark. Why use some kind of cream,
make floors more friendly colors? And
don't use top light. Top light is evil.
So just the office feels cozy so people
spend more time. You feel more creative,
more at ease in the office space.So the
vision work we have is should feels like
artist studio or should feel like your
home. And that's why most our office
furniture are home furnitures. It just feels
cozy. That's more so people spend more time,
feels more creative, juices flow better.
The other world just like at least personally
for me, it hurts the eyes if you just see ugly
things. It's more from a value aesthetic front.
It's like we talk about ergonomic chairs. Does
it hurt your back when you sit on bad chairs?
But you have more visual improve from, at least
for me from the eyes. If the chair looks ugly,
the wall looks ugly, it hurts. So it's
better to not have thing that hurts.
You also have a really interesting naming
convention for your conference rooms.
Yeah, that's true. Yeah. We name our conference
room after timeless tools in history. So there,
I'll give you an example. iPhone's
obvious one, original Macintosh,
various different form of chairs, Lamy's 2000
pens, Toshiba rice cookers, and other ones
because they're inspirations. They're just like at
the end of the day, we're creating a tool. We're
creating a meta tool. A lot of people to create
tools, software tools. And Toshiba rice cooker
changed how people eat rice in Asia for a hundred
million, tens of a hundred million people. The
Sony transistor radio is the first one to shrink
something small and useful for people. And those
things change people's life and last for decades.
What it's like to create a software product like
that? I want to inspire my team to think that
way. Because software, and especially tech,
it's every six months, every 12 months cycle. We
don't think enough about creating something that
lasts. I care creating something that at least
the form factor lasts longer than 18 month.
There's a quote that you tweeted once that
I think of as you talk about this from
Steve Jobs. "The problem is that there's
just a tremendous amount of craftsmanship
between a great idea and a great product."
I don't know if you remember tweeting that,
but just what do you think of when you hear that?
Yeah, I think the key word here is craft.
Internally, our company philosophy called crafts
and values. Craft is your skill set, your taste.
Value is your personal value and how do you see
the world. Craft is interesting word. It's like
about apply your value to some technical know-how
and to make more clever trade-offs to create
something new and useful and just keep doing that.
My wife often refer me as a wood cabinet builder.
That's how at least my mindset training towards
building Notion is like, "Oh, can I make this wood
cabinet more beautiful and more useful and feels
nicer on your hand?" And that's like you have
aesthetic direction towards it and you have your
technical know-how to actually make things happen.
Then you need to do permutation and trade-off in
your head where on paper and to get there. That
to me, that's craft. And building product, to me
at least, to me feels that way. Building business
feels that way. Building company feels that way.
It's interesting that so much of this
conversation is this and the way you
think about building this company
is this balance between practical,
useful things people need and business and
practical stuff, and then the value of building
something you're proud of and craft. And there's
always this trade-off almost of speed and quality,
and I know that's an important element for you.
Just thinking about trade-offs between decisions,
so talk about just trade-offs, just
how you think about making a trade-off.
Yeah, I think this is quite relevant especially
for product makers and business makers is there's
no free lunch. You don't get something
for free. You have to give up something.
Then what do you give up? It's essentially
you give up the right thing that market or
your user wants at that given space and time.
It's just the craft of building a business or
building a product. And that the market is so
dynamic, especially now with AI. The optimized
function for the market changes so then you
need to make new trade-off and new technology
emerges. I always feels like AI language model
feels like a new type of wood. It feels like
aluminum. It's a new type of material. So you
can make... Mass air travel wasn't available
until aluminum become cheap enough that people can
make airplanes that support this at cost. And it's
like computer wasn't there until semiconductor
becomes... It's like require new technology to
unlock new way to making trade-offs, and
then you need to balance the technology
trade-off with human behavior trade-off.
As a human, ever since we got out of Africa,
we're set, right? That's a constraint. It's
invariable. And every generation pick up
some new things but after you're 16 years old you
don't want to learn new things. So those are there
are the people trade-off, technology trade-off.
There's some macro. There's a different dimension
of things just cooking together that come together
as a product more as a business than what is that?
And I think a product maker, business maker's job
is to find that sweet spot of all the multiple
dimensions, then create something has a right
to exist. At least it's more durable to exist.
And I'm hearing there's this thread
of just like with new technologies,
what is now possible. And I know you guys are
doing some cool stuff with AI that I'm going to
get to that is unlocking some cool new ideas. But
before I get there, I want to talk about just you
as a leader. At this point, you've been
at this for 12 years, something like that.
Like that, yeah.
And if you don't mind me saying, you're
a soft-spoken leader, which is you're not
like the archetype of what people imagine is like
the CEO of a 10 billion... And I'm sure you guys
are valued much more now. I don't even know. That
was probably an old valuation. I think it's great
for people to see leaders like you that are
not necessarily the classic archetype of CO,
and I imagine there are things you've had to
work on and build and lean into that aren't
natural to you to step into this role of this
increasingly growing, high-scale business. What
are some of the areas you've had to most build
and learn to do that didn't come naturally to you?
I guess you've never been in a business meeting
or brainstorm session with me. You're not there.
Haven't seen that side of Ivan Zhao.
Yeah, I wouldn't say I'm the most soft interaction
person at work. It's actually the reverse is true
because I grew up in China. People way more
direct. People just say what they want, say
what they think. And you move to California, you
move to US, you move to the West, you felt wow,
everybody says everything's wonderful,
everything's nice, but that's not true.
I would say Notion's ethos probably more
like a East Coast rather than West Coast,
so somewhere in between. It's more direct.
What do you want to learn? A bunch of things.
I think the early days is we talk about that the
world's not like you. The world don't care about
you so you have to shave off the idealistic
part of you to go something that's like the
world actually cares, the sugar coat of
broccoli. You have to hide the broccoli
within something, the sugar pills. So that's
one. That's more self. That's more myself.
As company grows, you realize... I'm pretty good
at storytelling. So that's a one-to-one influence.
But as a company grows, you realize you need
to be one-to-many storytellers. That's a skill.
The one reason I try not to do podcasts and all
those things, oh, it's actually it drains energy
in a different ways. I prefer just building
product and brainstorm sessions. Then you
realize it's a necessary craft for me to pick
up in order to change the shape of the company,
the business I'm building. I treat it like a
craft. There's some things skill that's in the
video game. You need to pick up something to
unlock something else and to make new demand,
you trade off with yourself and the
business. That's fun though. Every 12,
18 month, Notion's like a new company or at least
they require different skill set coming from me.
So I need to pick up new things. And it's an
infinite game and infinite games are more fun.
I love this idea. I love that you keep coming
back to this idea of there's the ideals and the
values and the vision and what you're trying
to do, and then you have to find the way to
frame it and package it so that people actually
understand and want it. And that's how you get in.
Yeah. It's like human minds are resistant to
change, and how do you land in people's head?
Through my best word marketing and positioning
are for. So you need to find the sweet spot
to get in. And you also be truthful. It's not
just deceiving. So deceiving is not truthful.
You can fool other people once or twice, then
there's no future. It has to be actually tied
back to something genuinely the value creating
or the exchange with the other person. So yeah,
it's a craft. Storytelling is the
vast dimension of making trade-offs.
I love this word, trade-offs. Comes up again
and again too. It's so interesting that there's
these threads that have come up again and
again in our chat. Along that journey of
becoming this leader that you've become,
what would you say has maybe the biggest
surprise or most unexpected part of the
journey of something you've had to learn
to do or something that didn't turn out the way
you expected? Just as a personal growth story.
If you use the product in the past three years,
you realize Notion product, you realize, "Hey, we
actually ship bunch of things not so great." Two
years ago. Actually last year, 2024, is the year
that I can say we ship good stuff at good velocity
and good quality and align with our values. We
get lost there for a year, a year and a half
shipping something not according to our value,
not according to my value. Notion, we call Notion
is Lego for software. We ship non-Lego pieces
into our product. We're still there. We're still
cleaning up part of it. That's a realization. It's
like going back to the value part, it's like
if you create this thing called a product or
business, you attract people are value aligned
to it. Then if you're trying to optimize too
much on this competition revenue side of things,
forced to introducing something anti-your-value,
then the system, it's like there's organ rejection
with your employees, with your customers.
I'll give you a concrete example. For a while and
still is, project management is one of the most
important use cases for Notion. And you can get a
better project management tool just by hard coding
things like sprints, milestones, all those things
into your product, or you can do it in the way the
Notion are being, through Lego pieces. What are
the sprint? Sprints are clusters of a task that
group together. So it's a new Lego. So introducing
Lego is much harder, slower. You can instead we
hard-code a sprint concept into the product.
And this doesn't quite fit. And took me at
least a year, a year and a half to realize that's
not the way we should continue building Notion. We
should go back the original Lego way of building
the product. So we changed quite a bit internally.
Now, it feels good now. Building according to
your values is the meta point, at least for me.
Okay, I got to follow this thread. What is it
that you changed that allowed you to come back
to your first principles? Was it like you step...
Is it founder mode was the answer? Is it people,
personnel shift? What allowed you
to change the way things were going?
I would say all of that above, but especially
just release the sprint product through our
community and customers. Then it's like what
is this? It's like underpowered compared to
other competitor products to doing product
management and it doesn't work well with
the rest of Notion like I said. And if you
talk with engineers, they'll say, "Okay,
there's this part of Notion you have to
touch the code base. That's just weird.
That's your hardcore too much into it. From all
the dimension technical front, calling a customer.
And when you use the thing it just doesn't
feel right." So there's another saying that
if you build in a Lego way inside Notion in the
code base or product, the system work for you.
If you're building non-Lego way, the system work
against you. So in some sense, we're creating a
tool that has emergent behavior, inter-channeling
that emergent behavior to unlock more values.
So I'm hearing as you launched it, it just didn't
go well. Everyone's just like, "What is this? This
isn't feeling good." And there's a moment of
realization of I see. Here's what we did wrong
here and we should come back to this original
abstraction vision of what we're trying to build.
That took nine months, a year to realize sometime.
Along those lines actually, people come
on this podcast and they share all these
stories of things are going awesome all
the time. And this was a great example of
it didn't. I'm curious if there's another story
of let's say a crisis that you all went through
when things were looking pretty bleak for
Notion along the journey of building Notion.
Yeah, one of the bleakest one, it's when we...
During COVID, we just couldn't scale up our
infrastructure. For the longest time, Simon's
really good at don't do premature optimization,
so for the longest time, we Notion runs on one
instance of Postgres database. And then we find
the beefiest machine. We keep scrolling, find a
beefier future machine to scale our user base,
but then we're running off even the largest
instance there is for Postgres. So there's a
doomsday clock that when we're going to truly
run out of this space to store everything in
Notion and Notion got a complete shutdown.
So we stopped building any new features,
all hands on deck, almost every
engineer in the company trying
to solve that problem. Eventually
we did, but it was a close call.
How close are we talking about?
If I recall correctly, probably in
weeks running out of the time. And then
as you approach the limit of what Postgres can do,
behavior becomes sporadic. You really don't know
which day going to hit you. But we just need to
go as fast as you can to become sharding problem.
Yeah, I was going to ask, so the
solution is sharding the database?
Yeah, sharding.
Okay, cool.
Don't do as late. Yes. Don't do premature
optimization but plan ahead
a little bit. Don't go late.
How long did you have from when
you launched this doomsday clock
to time running out? Was that a few months?
Maybe a bit longer. Yeah, in the month, less than
six but more than three, something like that.
The bittersweetness of COVID just
ramping up certain businesses.
People just run like they have to use online
productivity software, collaboration tools.
Yeah, blessing and a curse. Speaking of a
blessing and curse, this is a great segue
to where I wanted to go in the final area
I want to spend time on which is building
horizontal software and building software
that bundles together a bunch of different
stuff. Notoriously hard to build a horizontal
platform that does a lot of things when there are
often point solutions that are very, very good at
that one thing. And it's interesting. If you look
at the timelines of companies that have built
horizontal products, they all take a long time
to build and finally find product market fits.
It's actually a really common pattern. And when
we were talking about what would be fun to
talk about, the way you described it is the
joy and pain of building horizontal products.
So let me just ask broadly just what have you
learned about what it takes to successfully
build a horizontal platform type of product?
First of all, no regret. And second, I wouldn't
want to build anything else because going back
to the value, Lego for software doesn't exist
and Lego is a horizontal thing. So that's the
thing we want to build. We always want to
do that. So we did not start to optimize for
business but we're optimized for that vision.
Learning-wise, I think segmentation is quite
important because people can use a Lego for
different things. Only hardcore Lego fans
care about Lego bricks. Most people care
about Lego boxes. And they actually want
the Lego box to be ready-made. When you unpack
the box, the set is there for you, right? That's
what we're learning a lot, especially move up
market. There's this term that took me a while
to learn. It's called solutions. You need
to be a solution for enterprise customer,
you need to sit somewhere on a P&L to optimize for
their business where due third risk. That's Lego
box. It's not a Lego brick. Segmentation related
to that. So you need to shift your mindset as you
more towards B2B, more towards move out market. I
wish we have done earlier. For the longest time,
I've stalled too much in the Lego brick
mindset, now in the solution Lego box mindset.
That's such a good metaphor. I feel like even
if you're not building Legos for business,
just this idea of what is the box
that you are selling to people,
how's it being positioned? How do you picture it?
What are the value? Props such a good metaphor.
If you're building vertical software and
naturally your vertical is the box, right?
So you know you have 1 or 2% of your selling to.
Pretty straightforward that your market constrains
you and no judgment. People like you, you can go
that way, but then you just hit the wall off the
market. The advantage of building horizontal,
there's no wall, at least for in our space. We,
Notion, go after entire software market, but
then you need to create a wall yourself. So to
make your go-to-market distribution, to create the
spot in people's mind, your customer's mind more
clearly for them and for your go-to-market teams.
That's why where solutions is one of my favorite
word internally to rally the sales team or the
product team. You think that way, but then you
need to hold in your head, make sure you're still
building bricks behind the scene. Otherwise, you
pigeonhole yourself into the best spot, like what
we did with project management sprints features.
So speaking of that, so I don't know if you know
this. I ran a survey recently where I asked my
readers what tools they use most, what tools
they love most. And it went out to my entire
subscriber base. We've got 6,500 people filling
out the survey. And Notion more than any other
company placed very highly in many categories.
For example, I have the notes here, it was the
second most popular project management tool after
Jira. It was the fourth most popular docs. Which
is interesting because you think Notion would...
Notion is known for docs and it's interesting,
that was the lowest one actually. And then it was
third in CRM, just behind Salesforce and HubSpot.
Yeah, we did not intend to build CRM, but what is
a CRM is relational database. That's why we give
people that brick. That's a relational database
and they can build CRM themselves. I think the
good advantage is if a customer use Notion, they
can address those three, four use cases in one
place. Especially for our startup mid-market
companies, their need for each of the vertical
use case is not as complex so they can
have all the information in one place,
good for their teams, good for AI actually. That's
a huge market change that's like we did not expect
until recently. And save their costs, which is
more and more people care about the bundling
purchase nowadays. And our approach for that
is, yes, we're number two in project management,
number what? Number four in CRM, but we're
interested in more bricks to make us number...
Move up the categories in ranking. So it
just takes time, but that's our approach.
Yeah. Well, it's working whatever you're doing
there. So say someone is trying to build a
horizontal tool like yours. There's a lot of
founders that are trying to build something
that can do a lot of things really well. Do
you have any advice for that first use case?
Just figuring out something that initially
works like you're talking about segmentation,
is there something there of like, "Do this if you
want to find any success with a horizontal tool"?
First, I wouldn't recommend it.
But you wouldn't do it differently?
I wouldn't do it differently myself, but I
wouldn't recommend it. It's a problem. The problem
space too large to have best practice, but I can
share something that's relevant for us. Notion,
we always want to build a meta tool, a tool
to build the lack of our software. We somehow
stand up upon document notes as one use case.
And that just gave us a large top of the funnel
that there's a 1 billion plus people use this
use case every day. So that fuels our growth.
We call our internal strategy called B2C2B. All
those consumers, personal user use Notion for the
most simple way you can use a computer or your
phone, which is note-taking or document-sharing.
And then they realize, "Oh, Notion can do more
of that." There's relational database power,
you can do tasks, you can manage track other
things. Then they bring Notion to work.
Half our B2B customers coming from prior
personal users, and most of them are using
Notion for notes and talk in the first place. So
pick. Well, at least we stumble upon a use case,
a horizontal use case to give us a large top of
funnel that help us grow our more verticalized
enterprise use cases, and that's the reason
where we ship a calendar product last year
because which other category of software has
1 billion plus users? There's document notes,
there's calendar, there's email, right? That's why
we're also working on the email product right now.
Yeah, man. Watch out, everyone. And then you
mentioned AI and it's such a good point that
AI is best when it has data. And the
fact that you have all of this stuff
already in there gives you a lot of really
interesting opportunities to leverage AI.
We definitely did not expect language model.
It's such a gift for everybody building tools,
right? Complete change the material
you can work with. One realization,
it's you have a surface area that people spend
daily work with, especially during writing and
managing your tasks and project. It's really easy
to slice the language model writing AI capability
into it. So that's the first part we built. That
realization is AI is so good at reasoning and
understanding and searching things, and we can
do a much better job of finding and searching
things if all the information are together.
That's what we realized. AI is really good
with bundled offerings. AI is really good with
horizontal tools. So that's the second phase,
we call it. The first product was our
AI writer product. Second product is
AI Q&A or connectors. Please look at all the
information in Notion and give your answer.
And then we also need to work with the external
connector because there's things that are living
in Jira, living in Zendesk that other customers
still rely on. So we need to build AI connectors.
But more and more information coming back to
the Notion core. I would say the third one,
which is even more fascinating, it's for
the longest time and it's still is one of
the biggest weaknesses of building for Legos, it's
hard to piece together. It's not everybody can put
together a Lego set from scratch. There's always
the builders and user with the Legos. But guess
who is really good at piecing things together,
assemble things? Especially things like since
Sona 3.5. AI is so bad at writing code. Coding
is just assembling things together. So now we're
looking at holy shit, we spent the last five, six
year building all those Lego blocks for knowledge
work. If we're just putting AI coding agent on
top of it, you can create any kind of knowledge,
customer software, customer agent for
whatever your vertical use cases you need.
So that's the most fascinating approach
for me, and we did not expect this at all.
Thank you, AI. Is there anything
else along the lines of building
horizontal products and bundling
that you think is interesting to
share or important? Otherwise, I have
one last question I want to ask you.
I think market is like waves. There's... Who said
this? There's two-way to build business, bundling
and bundling, right? There's too much of a zig and
the zag. Actually, my favorite version of this is
there's a classic Chinese literature called
Romance of Three Kingdoms. It's great novel.
It talked about the three kingdom era of China
and the opening sentence of this novel, it's,
"Empires long united must divide, long divided
must unite." That has always been bundling,
unbundling. It's one of my favorite book to
read when I was a kid, but business works same
way. When there's too much, you can see this.
It's like before computers, everything works on
paper. Our knowledge work are done through
papers is fully democratized medium. Then
PC happens during the '80s. The first era is a
piece there actually are so many applications.
There's early database software, dBASE, it's
quite famous. It started dBASE 2 because it
gives them credibility. Oh, they have been
stick around for some time. So that's the
first unbundling phase of software computing.
Then Microsoft bundled everything back into
one suite in the '90s. Then the SaaS unbundled
it. Now, we're at the tail end of SaaS. There's
so many verticalized SaaS average company to
use almost a hundred tools. It's madness. So
there's more the market shifting towards more a
bundling approach. And with AI and with the macro,
so there's more value to be created through
bundling, at least for now. The market could
shift again. So understand this trend, I
think, helpful to see should you build a
vertical solution or should you build horizontal
solution because it does different things.
I love that story. Okay, so last question.
Something that one of your early investors,
Finn Barnes, suggested to ask you. I'm curious
where this goes. There's this, and you've touched
on this a number of times, just the way you think
about Notion, it's almost like a philosophy of
how to work and be versus just a productivity
tool. And so I'm just curious how you think
about the relationship between tools and human
potential and humans and how we live in the world.
The tools are extensions of us. That's why
our office room named as timeless tools. They
extend us a little bit. And once they extend us,
once we shape them, once we bring them to world,
they can come back to shape us.
One of my favorite quotes like the
Marshall MacLean quotes, "We shape our tools.
Then after, our tools shape us." I think that's
probably too philosophical for building product or
business, but there is a sense thinking what are
you bringing to the world that will come back to
bite you or shape you? And are you extending the
part, the so-called good part of human nature,
or are you extending the part that might be
more zero-sum, might be more negative, right?
For me, what is Legos? Lego is creativity. Lego
is beauty. Software to me feels like lacking both.
It's definitely lacking a lot of creativity. It's
so rigid. So I believe both are human nature that
worth amplifying. You can build another business
that amplifies a different part of human nature.
There was Sequoia famously invests in seven
sins or seven human natures of human because
they're so powerful if you just latch onto them,
you can create a business, you can create
a product. But at least I prefer to amplify
creativity and beauty in the domain of software.
To me, that's aligned with my values and I think
can at least shape the market, shape our user of
our product towards the better part of themself.
It must feel so good to have a product that
is so aligned with the way you want to see
the world and actually working and growing
at this rate and scaling and becoming this,
I don't know, part of the ether of the world.
It feels good. Yeah, it feels good that
some of the most heartwarming thing is
still it never gets old when you walk by
coffee shop and see people using Notion.
Oh, it feels good. And it feels good
that we see people in our community can
create a living selling Notion template,
Notion apps, that they're not a software
engineer. And going back to the original
mission of when people create software,
I think that's one of the most fulfilling thing,
at least as a maker of tools can experience.
That last point, I think people don't
realize, so people are making millions
of dollars selling Notion templates on the
internet like at Etsy and other places.
Consulting templates, yeah, and they're not
programmers. I think I would say that's the heart
of that because their domain expertise, they're
YouTubers or creators. They have lifestyle brand.
They know certain things but they're not makers of
software. Then they can use Notion, package their
workflows and expertise into Notion and templates
and make limit with it. It's awesome, all that.
Yeah, millions of dollars is it's crazy. Ivan,
before we get to an abridged lightning round,
I'm curious if there's anything else
that you wanted to touch on think might
be useful for folks to hear before we
get to a very exciting lightning round.
I think people in tech, I wish more people look
beyond tech to steal good ideas. It's like Tech
Hacker News Twitter are so focused on the now and
what's in front of it, what happened six months
ago, versus humanity. If you just read books in
other industry, you can look sideways. If you
go back to history, there's a massive amount of
patterns and shapes and trade-offs you can steal
from and you can make what's in front of you much
more interesting. You could give you... People
figure out clever patterns in whatever domain in
the past. You can just take in front of you. And
I wish more people do that. I think it would
be a very interesting way for product makers,
business maker to solve the problem in front
of them by stealing outside of from the domain
of tech and business. So at least it's very
inspiring, very useful for me personally.
It makes me think of the quote, "Good
artist copy. Great artists steal."
Great artists steal, yeah. Well, Steve Jobs stole
that from Picasso or something who
stole from former artist probably.
Well, this is actually an amazing segue
to our very abridged lightning round. And
the first question is... And by the
way, welcome to the lightning round.
Oh, okay.
The first question is just what are a couple of
books that you find yourself recommending most to
other people? Could be along the lines of what
you just described or could just be generally.
I think the domain that are interesting the most
is the complex system domain. You can look up the
term. I think more and more people talk about
this, but thinking a system, complex system
when all the different things merge together, it
creates emergent properties. Talking about ants,
talk about beads, talk about life itself. It's
just so fascinating how do with few primitives,
few Lego bricks, you can create a thing called
life. That thing just, it's sugar for me. So I
love reading in that domain. And this
is really helpful for create product,
at least a horizontal product because
you're trying to channel the energy,
smaller parts to create something that
the sum is much larger than its parts.
Is there a specific book that comes to mind
or is it just generally that's a cool area?
That's a cool area to your attention to.
Next question. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show you've really enjoyed?
I like to watch old documentaries. Maybe this
is another area or category too. There's quite
a few on YouTube. People make really good
documentary in the '80s, in the '70s. That's
like all the old BBC ones, they're just excellent
and they have a strong opinion in them. It's no
longer just general education thing. They have a
direction. They have a taste. Go look it up. Oh,
yeah. One is a really good one to get started
called Connections. I think it's called but
the gentleman's name is Burke. It's about
how different things from different domains
inspire other domains, and usually he used 30
minutes or 60 minutes to chain together a bunch
of connection of stories. It's really good
for technologists to watch. Highly recommend.
I feel a very consistent pattern throughout all of
these answers and your entire conversation of just
emerging properties, connections,
Legos, building abstractions.
Yeah, I think I did Enneagram. My Enneagram,
it's 7 and 7. 7 is, it is actually perfect
with what we just talking about. 7 is creative,
finding connection, see the forest and tree. 8 is
they call Challenger. It's like competitive
AR optimizing. So true energy accessing me.
Oh, wow. It's all makes sense. I got to take this
Enneagram. This comes up a bunch on this podcast.
Right, yeah.
Final question. Do you have a life
motto that you often think back to,
that you often repeat in your head of
just like when times are hard or just
to keep going with something you're
working on that you find useful?
I like to think things as a craft. You
just make it better. Make for yourself.
If it's unique enough for yourself and
useful for others, things will follow.
Ivan, thank you so much for being here. Two
final questions, working folks find you online
if they want to follow-up on anything, and
then how can listeners be useful to you?
Probably find on me on Twitter, Ivan Z-H-A-O.
It's helpful give us feedback about Notion,
about our product. That's the best help.
What's the best way to do that?
Is it like DM, Ivan, or is it-
Yeah, just DM me.
Okay.
DM me. Yeah, that's probably the best way.
Okay. Oh boy, here you go. And then you guys
are hiring. Anything specific you're looking
for? Anything people should know if they're
like, "Oh shit, I want to go work here"?
We're trying to hire misfits. So if
you think you're a misfit, if you're
exceptional at many things especially,
you want to build Lego for software,
you want to take interesting spin on
AI with Lego for software, then DM me.
Amazing. Ivan, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you for having me.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.