Everyone is striving for talented, skillful,
smart people. Revolut values way more raw
intellect and this unquenched hunger
to build things rather than experience.
I hear one of the ways you approach early products
differently is you guys invest a
lot in actually making it good.
It's not getting traction. Is it because the
underlying idea is wrong? Or maybe your product
just sucks? By forcing everyone to build a product
that people will love, we kind of cut out this
part of uncertainty. We can cut down the product
in terms of functionality to just most critical
features, but we will never compromise
on the quality and UX and the aesthetics.
Is there anything that you've figured out about
just how to set up new products for success?
If something is 99% done, it's
closer to 0% rather than 100%.
Today, my guest is Dmitry Zlokazov. Dmitry
is global head of product at Revolut,
which is a finance super app offering customer
savings and checking accounts, crypto, investing,
joint accounts, even mortgages. Not only was
it last valued at over $60 billion, but in the
research that I've been doing into which companies
hire and incubate the best product managers,
Revolut was right at the top alongside Palantir
and Intercom. And so in our conversation, we dig
into what Revolut has learned about producing and
hiring great product leaders, including a focus
on ownership, having people solve really painful
and complex problems while making the experience
wow and lovable by users. Also indexing towards
hiring really smart and driven people early in
their career versus people with a ton of
experience in the space and so much more.
If you're looking for a job that will accelerate
your product career or want to help your product
team level up, this episode is for you.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget
to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also,
if you become an annual subscriber of my
newsletter, you get a year free of Linear,
Superhuman, Notion, Perplexity, and Granola.
Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com and click
bundle. With that, I bring you Dmitry Zlokazov.
This entire episode is brought to you by Stripe.
There's a reason that I've had more guests on
this podcast from Stripe than any other company.
It's because they hire the best people and they
build incredible products. You probably know them
for their payments platform, which powers my
newsletter, and also companies like NVIDIA and
Salesforce and Zoom and DoorDash. What you may not
know is that they have several other products that
can help accelerate your revenue, such as Stripe
Billing, which powers billing for companies that
you may have heard of. OpenAI, Anthropic, Figma,
Atlassian, and over 300,000 other companies.
Stripe Billing lets you bill and manage customers
however you want from simple recurring billing to
usage-based billing to sales-negotiated contracts.
There's also Stripe's Optimized Checkout suite,
which is a plug-and-play super optimized
payment flow that natively supports over
100 global dynamic payment methods. There's also
a product called Link, which is an accelerated
checkout experience built specifically to increase
your checkout conversion. Every single one of the
Forbes top 50 AI companies that have a product
in the market today use Stripe to monetize it.
Half of Fortune 100 companies use Stripe.
$1.4 trillion flows through Stripe annually,
which is equivalent to over 1% of global GDP.
Use Stripe to handle all of your payment-related
needs, billing, manage revenue operations,
and launch or invent new business models.
Learn more at stripe.com. Dmitry, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Hi, Lenny. I'm happy to be here.
As you know, I've been doing a bunch of research
into which companies hire and create the best
product managers, and I've been triangulating
this across a bunch of different data points.
I've been looking at which companies alumni
product managers get promoted most when they
leave the company, become chief product officers
at the highest rate when they leave the company,
become the first PM at a startup, also start
their own companies. And when I triangulate it
across all these different data points, there's
three companies that are kind of sat at the top,
you guys, Revolut, Palantir, and Intercom.
Clearly you guys are doing something
really special. I don't think a lot of people,
especially in the US know a ton about Revolut,
and so I'm really excited to have you here.
I'm really excited to basically extract as
much wisdom as I can from you about what
you guys have figured out in helping in
hiring and training product managers. So I
want to actually start with giving people
a slight understanding of what is Revolut.
I think a lot of people in the US especially
don't know much about it. So what's the
simplest way to understand what you guys do?
Revolut challenges banks in 50 different
countries and it all started 10 years ago
in London. So maybe let me give you a bit of a
context, especially for someone based in the US,
it's important to understand that European banking
landscape is very diverse. In the US if you travel
from state to state, things are different,
but for example, you always pay in US dollars,
right? In the UK you pay in British Pound. If you
travel to mainland Europe, you will pay in Euro,
but if you go to Switzerland, you'll pay in
Swiss francs. If you go to Sweden, you'll pay
in Swedish Krona and so on and so-and-so.
Overall, there are 25 different currencies
and every time you were traveling and paying
in a different currency, banks were charging
you exorbitant fees on top of terrible foreign
exchange rates, and that's when Revolut launched
as a multi-currency card and people loved it.
They loved that Revolut was saving them 50 or
100 euros, but even more so they loved the
transparency and simplicity of the product
and that's why when we started rolling out more
and more products based on those principles,
they were quickly getting trust of people. They
were quickly getting traction. So that's how
P2P transfers appeared, and then frictionless
crypto buying and withdrawal to a bank account
appeared. And then more and more products
created products, savings products and so on.
Awesome. And then just to give people
a few kind of scale of the company,
how many employees are there roughly? I
think the last valuation something around
60 billion. I don't know if you can even
comment on that, but just what are some
numbers real quick for people to understand
the scale of the company at this point?
The headcount is not something we're trying
to increase, to be honest. Actually Revolut
tries to stay as lean as possible, but
I think it's just that our appetite
for growth is so big that I think we're
currently at maybe 6 or 7,000 employees.
Wow. Okay, cool. So let's get into what
you've learned about building an amazing
product team and also hiring an amazing
product team. So first of all, you call
your product managers product owners, and when
we were chatting through initially it was like,
"Oh, I see. It's just like a big scrum business,"
and they just have all these product owners who
many times on this podcast people have talked
about that's not actually a product manager,
but that's not at all how you work. So in this
context, product owner's an actual owner. Talk
about just the story behind why you call
your product managers, product owners.
Yeah, it's not a scrum term for us, it's just our
take on emphasizing how ownership is important,
really. So product owners are central to the
company and its growth. They are end-to-end
responsible for the product, for this part of
the business, and for their customers to be
happy. And for that, they do really everything.
They run the teams, they define which roadmap
we need to build to improve certain
business metrics, and they also contribute
to high-level company strategy, but then most
importantly, they execute on it relentlessly and
they are ultimate responsible for the
product to be shipped and achieve results.
There's always this term of mini-CEO, PM as a
mini-CEO, and it feels like in your context,
that's actually what you try to do with your
product team is they're essentially mini-CEOs.
They have a lot of power. I think engineers,
designers report to them. Is that right?
Yeah, correct. Well, I prefer to say local CEO.
Local CEO. Okay, let's talk
about that. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, but that's true. So the way we operate,
we have these fully cross-functional teams,
meaning they're staffed with all necessary
functions, engineers data, analysts, designers,
operational managers and so on. And we also
operate in metrics. So everyone has a line manager
and a functional manager. So product owner is
always the line manager for everyone on the team,
meaning product owner defines what they need to
do, but then functional managers, they define how
these things are need to be built and essentially
with the right level of quality and so on.
I love this because it's so fun just to learn
about such different ways of operating. Another
fact that I saw is that there's two types
of product owners. There's kind of like
a UX product owner, and then there's a
different like technical product owner.
We actually have three.
Three.
And the third type becomes increasingly more
important. So the first type is UX product owners.
Then there are technical product owners, and
then there are data science product owners. So UX
product owners are the ones who work on consumer
facing part of the product. Usually they have a
great taste for things and they understand what
constitutes UX that will work and which things
will not work. So they also have this expertise in
the industry. Then tech product owners, they are
the ones who delve deepest into details. Usually
those are former engineers who grew into making
decisions and driving business. And the data
science product owners are usually former data
scientists who decided to grow into management
positions, but they're still very hands-on.
And you know what? There are way more things that
are common to each of these three specializations.
So what we see sometimes is people just shifting
them because I would say that what defines the
specialization is probably 5, 10, 15% while
85 to 90% is common to each one of them. And
those things are, so first of all, being a great
problem solver and have a great linear thinking,
but also have a creative approach towards
nonlinear problems. Then building this context
for customer and building empathy towards
customer and translating it into the team.
Then going down to details very, very deep because
in our domain there are no obvious things and
you need to get to the root cause of the
problem really, really deep to understand
what will work and what will not work. And that
means that you also need to be quite technical,
even if you are an expert, you still need to
often go as deep as sitting with engineers and
reading code. And then I would also emphasize
the importance of business acumen because
we tend to measure and quantify product
performance a lot. And you need to understand,
okay, what things will we build that will drive
eventually that business metric and that target?
So I love this idea of the product owners having
to go really deep. I think a lot of people hearing
this, they think they can go deep, go deep, really
understand the details of what they're working
on. I'm curious if there's an example that's
illustrative of just what you actually mean here.
For example, to provide the best possible
product in every country of presence,
we need to have necessary licenses. In Europe,
it means that we need to launch local branches
of our European bank, for example, a branch
for France, a branch for Germany, or a branch
for Italy. To launch a branch, you need to fully
comply with all necessary regulation. You need to
report necessary data on customers to various
regulators and authorities. You need to register
with local payment systems. And each of these
things, they have a lot of projects nested within.
We have a very lean team of just a few people
who need to scope everything and do it at the
scale of 50 countries. So the way we do it is
we go very deep on example of each of these
projects. For example, we launched a branch in
Ireland, we launched a branch in Netherlands.
Then we reverse engineered what was the best
process to do it, and then we went back up on
top level and we said, okay, but what's the
ideal framework of doing it at scale? And
then we formalized it into a process really
like an algorithmic process with steps and
quality gates and assay needs, what people
do we need to hire and how soon do we need
to start doing that before we want to launch a
new country. Then, so it's not only going deep,
but also being flexible and doing this switch
between zooming in very deep and then raising
on the level of helicopter view and then
understanding, okay, so this seems very,
very complex in details, but then when you
zoom out, how can we simplify it and build
a robust process around it, which is scalable?
And that's something that we have to do a lot.
As you're talking and we go through this chat,
I'm keeping kind of track of what I think is
most contributing to your alumni product owners,
product managers becoming so successful. So a
couple of things so far that I think are probably
contributing to this is one is just having a
lot of ownership over what they're building,
which leads to building skills to start companies
and become leaders at other companies. So these
product owners that you have are just own
a lot and are essentially GMs of whatever
product they're working on. And then there's
this depth and complexity where you have to
really get good at understanding a problem really
deeply. I imagine many of these people go on to
work on something like that later, somewhere
else because they've spent all this time,
or they just get really good at dealing
with complex many layered problems. So is
there anything else just kind of along those
lines as I say that you think is important?
I would probably add an obsession
with building wow product.
Wow. W-O-W?
W-O-W.
Cool.
I think in FinTech overall, this is
probably the most neglected part usually,
but it's also a part that we at Revolut, we pay
enormous attention to. So it's not only when you
do a trade in the app or when you send money,
it's very important for it to be very fast and
cheap process for you so that you don't
pay a lot of fees. But we also pay a
lot of attention to look and feel of
the app and how smooth it is and how
frictionless the process. Not only we invest
in reducing clicks and optimizing finals,
but we also want people to feel that we really
cared about them. We also want people to feel that
we love our customers and we applied extra effort
for the product to look great and feel great. And
I hear this a lot from our customers, like the
app is something they really love and it helps
them solve their problems. It's at least one
of the ingredients of the company's success.
And I think people that work at Revolut, they
built habit of paying attention to these small
nuances, small details that make the product
lovable. And then second is handling this context
because it's a lot of details where you need
to dive, but there are also a lot of dimensions
where you need to dive into different details.
And I think this ability to keep this large
context in your mind and consider second order
effects and view subjects from multiple angles,
I think that this is also a very important
skill that people usually train at Revolut.
Okay, cool. So we have three bullet
points on the ingredients of great
product managers slash owners that
you guys incubate. On this wow piece,
which I love. How do you operationalize this
sort of thing? I imagine a big part of it is
hiring people that are really good at this and
value building lovable products. Is there any
way you kind of have a process around making
sure the things you ship are wow and lovable?
Two things that you need to understand about how
Revolut operates is that we operate in small lean
teams that are tasked to build products and as I
mentioned, and having end-to-end responsibility
for products. And usually they're the ones who
build it from zero and then they're growing and
developing this product. And then another thing
is that company is very flat and hierarchy is very
flat. We still have our founders, Nick and Vlad,
very hands-on going down to details for every
product and every part of the business. And every
week they have product reviews with every team
giving an opportunity to every product
owner present directly to CEO and CTO and
show what increment has team achieved
in the last week, but also get steering
from founders, which is super valuable.
Essentially founders of the company,
they still review a hundred percent of screens
that are being shipped and everything that you
will see in the app pass this review. And there
are a lot of eyeballs that were scrutinizing this
and thinking of all possible edge cases
and nuances that we need to consider to
make sure that every single customer will
be happy in this product, in this flow.
That seems to be a consistent theme
in products that are incredible is
the founders are deeply involved in the
experience and review everything. How
many product owners are there at Revolut?
Just to give people a sense by the way?
Oh, I'm afraid to say it's already
more than 150 people, maybe 170.
Cool. That's what I would expect. And then you
said that there's kind of these three types,
there's kind of like the eng
type, the PM, traditional type,
and there's the data product owner. When
you hire the UX type of product owner today,
is their previous role usually a
product manager at another company?
Yes, but I would say that not necessarily
it's a very experienced product manager.
Well maybe even it's way more important to
have this hunger for building things and
having the raw intellect. And we always try to
find people with these intrinsic traits rather
than hiring people who are very experienced but
maybe are not super excited about building things.
What percentage of your product owners come
from internal transfers from other functions?
It's a quite substantial part of product owners
who eventually become very successful by the
way. So it's like a positive self-select, so
it means that someone already succeeded in
another role. So it's a guaranteed culture
match, it's a guaranteed domain knowledge,
and then they simply grow. Usually it could
be operations managers or engineers. They
grow into someone who now manages the team
and that's why it's a very successful path.
So the other company on the list of top three
companies that produce and hire the best PMs,
according to the research I've done, Palantir.
I just had someone that was at Palantir for a
long time and we talked about exactly all
the same questions. And interestingly so
far we have kind of these three bullet points
in terms of what product owners within Revolut
get to do. There's a lot of ownership, there's a
lot of depth and complexity, and there's a lot of
focus on wow lovable products. So interestingly
at Palantir also tons of ownership, also tons
of depth and complexity. The other ingredient
that I want to ask you about is they also have
this concept of a forward deployed engineer
where they put an engineer in the office of
the company they're building the product from,
they sit there building it for them with them.
And so there's a lot of skills built in terms
of understanding customer problems, talking to
customers, getting empathy building, things like
that. Is there anything you guys do or focus on
around just like talking to customers, the way
you approach having your product owners work
with customers, understand problems, things like
that that might be helpful for people to hear?
For us, it's a bit easy to reach out to customers
simply because the customer base is so big,
it's more than 50 million people and usually
we ourselves are power users of the product. We
receive our salary into Revolut and then we spend
with Revolut, our friends the same. So it's like
a no-brainer to talk to people continuously
and even if you are not proactive in it,
they will reach out. If you have a problem in the
product, I guarantee that we know about it very,
very soon. We've also built tools for product
owners and designers to have an easy access to
a panel of users via different tools so that they
can just start an interviewing process or a survey
or a test of different designs in a few clicks.
For me, it was very important to build this direct
connection to customers because when you delegate
such an important thing as customer research and
collecting their feedback to someone, you will get
a refined filtered version. You won't get these
nuances of how people describe things, which
emotions they feel like and so on, and where
they think stuck. It's very easy to lose all those
important bytes of information in this process. So
I'm a strong believer that it's very important to
have direct communication channel to customers.
As you describe this, it's funny how you guys are
at the extreme opposite end of the spectrum from
Palantir in terms of how easy it is for you to
get feedback. They build stuff for the government
and for Airbus where employees would never use
a product like that or need a product like that.
You guys are getting paid in Revolut using Revolut
to pay for things and constantly in the product.
And so I could see why there's less of a need for
something like a forward deploy engineer. Okay,
amazing. Let's talk about hiring then. Is there
anything unique about how you approach hiring,
sourcing, looking for people, what
you look for in people that you think
might be contributing to your alumni
being so successful down the road?
I think everyone is striving for talented,
skillful smart people and experienced people.
Revolut values way more raw intellect and this
unquenched hunger to build things rather than
experience. So let me maybe bring an example.
Imagine we saw this, you hire a great experienced
professional with amazing regalia of achieving
a lot of things, but then what I see in product,
the adoption curve is usually longer than
in other functions because product owners
by definition are the ones who are the experts
in that domain and in all those intricacies of
how product is built and how it's used. So what
we see from these professionals is they still
take a lot of time to ramp up and sometimes they
also take time to adapt to new culture or worse,
they just rest on their laurels. But you already
have super inflated expectations and usually
their compensation is by the way, quite high and
which adds up to these expectations. And I myself,
after conducting maybe 400 or 500 interviews
with product owners at Revolut, I also see this.
Unfortunately, professionals with a lot of
years of experience from established companies,
they don't have this strong urge to change status
quo, which by the way will require toil, tears,
and sweat. And that's why even if a candidate
doesn't have a lot of years of experience,
but they love building things, they've done it,
they worked with engineers maybe by the way, maybe
in their own startup or one of the best profiles
that I've seen is a tech co-founder. So I think
that's probably the best way to boost career is
to go and found something work in a startup, build
things yourself or with a very small team, work in
all different areas because in startup you have to
work in all different areas. And then these kind
of people, they really thrive at Revolut and even
if they don't have a lot of years of experience,
they actually attack a specific problem.
They have a sense of what can cause customer
pain, and they are very fast moving to solve it
quickly and then that's how they get appreciation
from everyone around. The team starts respecting
these people because they solve some specific
problem and then they take another problem,
they solve it and then they take another
and that's how they grow in the company.
Essentially what I'm hearing is you hire kind of
more junior or super high raw, intellect driven,
passionate, how do you describe, hungry
people? And this explains why so many
people get promoted so much more that leave
Revolut because they start their earlier
in their career and you help them learn all
these skills, ownership, depth, understanding,
working in complex environments, building amazing
products. So this all makes a lot of sense.
Is there anything you figured out about where
to find these people? Because this is the dream,
hire amazingly smart people that are super
driven that nobody knows about yet and then
make them awesome. Have you found anything
about where to source and find these folks?
So the way we work, we have a weekly catch-ups
with the recruitment team. So essentially they
are also a team that runs in sprints. So every
sprint we define what do we want to focus on,
which areas, which companies. One of the
great sources is actually looking into
products and apps that we love ourselves.
So if someone built a great product,
then it's likely a high performer. So
usually we provide some great products
in specific areas that are more important
for us to the sourcing team and they just
try to source targeting those companies. It
could be also different areas. It could be
even schools, like good schools. And
so it varies from sprint to sprint.
That makes sense. Gokul had this really good
piece of advice, I think it was on the podcast,
if not he tweeted about it, where you
look at there's successful companies,
but then there's also what function in that
company is the key to their success. And
so you want to go like a company A for
sales, company B for customer support,
company C for design. And so it sounds like that's
kind of the way you guys think about it a little
bit. Yeah, very cool. Okay. I love how we're
uncovering and we're uncovering this mystery.
This entire episode is brought to you by Stripe.
Every single one of the Forbes top 50 AI companies
that has a product in the market today uses Stripe
to monetize it. $1.4 trillion flows through Stripe
annually, which is equivalent to over 1% of
the entire global GDP. And Stripe isn't just a
payments platform. They also have a product called
Stripe Billing, which powers billing for companies
that you may have heard of, OpenAI, Anthropic,
Figma, Atlassian, and over 300,000 other
companies. Stripe Billing lets you bill and manage
customers no matter your pricing model from simple
recurring billing to usage-based billing to sales
negotiated contracts. Collect and retain more
revenue, automate revenue management workflows,
and accept payments globally. Use Stripe to handle
all of your payment related needs, including
billing, revenue operations, checkout flows,
or simply launching or inventing new business
models. Learn all the ways that Stripe can
grow revenue for your business at stripe.com.
Let me go in a different direction and see if
there's more to learn here. When it comes
to running your teams, is there something
that is kind of fairly contrarian in how
you approach running the product team that
is maybe not how other companies operate
that you think is key to your success?
I've changed in how I operate after I joined
Revolut probably because Revolut is a founder-led
company and probably it's because it's self-led,
and also because my role is quite spread across
many things. So my role at Revolut is leading
product function across company, but also leading
retail, which is a core part of Revolut business.
And it's very easy to be spread thinly across
all those domains and catching up with 50 or 70
projects that are being executed simultaneously,
which would mean that you will just spend
your entire week just catching up on statuses,
not really adding value to anyone, but it's
also scary to not do it because what if there
are some things going wrong and you won't be
able to stop it or steer in a better direction.
So I think that's why also a lot of managers,
especially in senior positions, they kind of
stay high level and they don't go very deep into
details. But how we did differently at Revolut is
to go very deep into details. We take
maybe 7 or 10 projects which are most
impactful for customers right now. And we
go super deep into them, really, really deep
sitting with engineers like reading code level
and understanding, okay, how it's built exactly
and what's the underlying issue. And you could
think that, okay, but what about others? Let's say
50 or 60 items that are being executed. But the
thing is that it actually, it's counterintuitive,
but it works really well because first of
all, teams, they talk to each other, there
are formal and informal ways of communicating
through meetups or just meeting in the office
and they know which areas are being scrutinized
right now and which team is being scrutinized.
And it also gives information on what are
the current priorities in the company. But
in addition, it's signaled to other teams that
if they are not proactively executing things
on the expected level, paying attention to all the
details and being meticulous in all those details,
especially in quality, they will be the ones that
will be reviewed to a such deep level, next phase,
next cycle. So as a result, it also builds a
great discipline. And since Revolut is such a high
concentration of very ambitious people who thrive
for being best versions of themselves and grow,
and it's very important for them to prove that
they can deliver great things and build next
great company. As a result, they do everything to
operate autonomously. And when you start diving
deep into details, you see that everything is
fine, you see their modus operandi and you can
understand, okay, if this team is on good track or
not on good track. And if it's not on good track,
it means that it probably will be
one of your next areas as of focus.
Okay. So what I'm hearing is you said there's 50
to 60 things kind of projects being built at once.
Maybe closer to a hundred, actually.
Okay. Okay. So there's like
a hundred things happening
at any point like features being
built, products being launched,
and this is you and the founders choose
7 to 10 to focus on, or is it just you?
No, it's just me.
Just you. Okay. And by the way, do you
have a leadership team that you're a
part of with a design lead or is
it just you basically at the top?
So the way it's structured, my responsibility
is a product function. We also have a head of
design function. It's also part of my team,
but then all the other functions, they are
separate like engineering and data function,
and all of them report directly into a CEO.
Got it. Okay. So out of a hundred things you
choose, here's the 7 to 10 things I'm going
to go deep on. These are the things that matter
most to the business that if they don't go well,
it'll have the most downside. And then you
basically said you sit next to the engineers,
you get really involved in every detail.
Yeah, correct.
Awesome. Okay. That is definitely
counterintuitive. We had Brian Chesky
in the podcast and the way he approached
this problem is he just cut down how many
things happen at Airbnb because he wants to
be involved in everything. And so I think
it's cool to hear a different approach
where we can still do a lot of stuff,
but I'm going to choose, I'm going to
go deep on the things that matter most.
No, I think we'll never cut down things, it's just
the appetite for growth and also entrepreneurial
approach in the company is so high that we'll
never allow ourselves to give up on some great
opportunities, but also this approach is way
more scalable. So while leadership and obviously
founders themselves keep everyone accountable,
go deep into details, it doesn't mean that they
micromanage everyone. That's actually a very
important thing. So the ideal position for any
product owner is to be fully autonomous. And
again, it doesn't mean that you will never be
challenged, but if when you're challenged, you
can show all the logic behind decisions you've
made behind the roadmap. And even if metrics are
not yet there, you will still let's say have this
credit of trust to keep building things the way
you want to build them. Eventually, yeah, you
will be presenting the outputs of your activity
on these weekly product reviews, but again,
it's not a micromanagement either. It's more like,
let's say a last line of control to make sure that
what we're building all makes sense and that's
value and is thoroughly thought in all details.
And then you said still every screen that is
shipped, the founders review at some point,
so it's not like someone's shipping stuff
without the founders seeing it in some form.
Yeah, yeah, exactly. They have a full overview
over everything, but also it allows us to build
so many things because there is actually little
micromanagement. If founders had to be involved
into everything, they had to cut things down. But
by giving people autonomy, they actually boost
company growth. And as a result, I think Revolut
is a strong outlier in the industry in terms of
how many products being shipped and how fast they
shipped. Another thing here is what I mentioned
previously is us investing heavily into platform
so that every solution is scalable from the get
go so that we don't have any custom solutions. And
for example, take our credit team, they ship new
products like loans or credit cards in the country
literally every month. And it is just maybe 300
people. And I think that a credit division in an
incumbent bank is maybe 2 or 3000 people building
just credit products for a single country.
And our team is building it for 50 countries.
And yeah, it's enabled through this approach
with platforms which we build on top of small
lean teams which are fully equipped with
necessary functions and also have autonomy
in defining what they're building and
the flat hierarchy with everyone being
accountable and founders having direct view
of everyone and intervening if necessary.
I'm going to give people a list of the things you
guys do. I didn't do this at the beginning because
it would take too long, but you talk about all the
products you're building and all the things that's
going on. So I have a list here. It's probably
incomplete, but just to give people a sense,
so you guys have credit cards, debit cards,
savings accounts, multi-currency accounts,
domestic international transfers, joint accounts,
minor accounts for less than 18 years old,
stock trading, cryptocurrency purchasing,
loans. Is there anything big I missed?
I mean, some of those things are a huge by itself,
let's say stock trading. It's not just stocks,
it's also ETFs, bonds, and we're working on
tax efficient accounts in different countries
and crypto. We also allow staking crypto for
example, we have on-ramp, off-ramp products,
we have acquiring products. On credit, we have
loans, we have a buy now per later product,
we even launched mortgages. We launched
first mortgages in Albania recently.
And then all of these across 50
different currencies and countries.
Yeah, 50 different jurisdictions each with
its own regulation, with its own requirements.
Oh, boy. It's a good example of Paul Graham has
this concept of schlep blindness or schlepping
where people want to avoid hard problems,
but that's where the big opportunities are,
solving really gnarly, painful problems.
And that's basically what you guys did.
Yeah, that's one of the things
that excites me maybe the most
at Revolut. The market is so big and there are
still a lot of very inefficient players, and
as a result, customers have a lot of problems
that are unsolved. While we grow insanely
and I think will soon be... When I joined, we had
maybe just slightly north to 20 million customers.
Now we are 50 million customers. Soon we'll be at
100 million customers. The degree of surrounding
each customer with the ecosystem of our products
extends a lot. So they become more and more people
start using Revolut as their main bank account.
They start receiving their salary into Revolut,
holding their savings into Revolut because they
love the product more. And so we can easily do
another, I don't know, 2, 3X, 4X in customer base
growth, but we can also do another 10X growth in
how actively these people are using the product.
So it's let's say what, 30, 40X to current,
45 billion valuation. Right? So it's a
like a trillion-dollar company easily.
And on that note, I mean what I'm hearing
is it's still a good time to join. There's
a massive upside. So I know you guys are
hiring, we'll just note that real quick.
You're hiring product owners and
a bunch of other roles, I imagine?
Yeah, yeah. Well, as someone
who owns the product function,
I'm especially interested
in product owners obviously,
but we hire a lot of roles. I think we have
maybe 3 or 400 open positions currently.
Oh my God. Okay. I want to talk a bit
about new stuff that you work on. So
new products that you decide to invest in.
Is there anything that you've figured out
about just how to set up new products
for success? Because a lot of the stuff
we've been talking about is staying on
top of stuff that you're iterating on
and making better. What have you learned
about just helping new products succeed?
Yeah, so we launched quite a few products
that you actually maybe wouldn't expect from
a bank starting with crypto that was insanely
successful, but also non-financial services
like booking a hotel through Revolut
app, our loyalty program, rev points,
which is sort of disrupting European market where
people don't get great benefits from spending with
card. In the US you can easily get, like what?
2% cashback with a credit card or in some sort
of point. In Europe they don't have it. And we
are actually the first to build a program on card
spend rewarding people with really meaningful or
monetary rewards. In the manner that I described.
We understood, okay, what's the recipe of
this success to then scale it and reproduce?
So we built a new bets framework and essentially
everyone can come up with a new idea. It could be
a product owner, but it could be anyone, and
they need to show some key important things
which you usually can expect from a startup
like market is there, business case is there.
We know that we can do it way better than
competitors leverage and for example, some things
that we have obviously some concepts of product
and then what customer problem we're solving and
so on. And there is very little bureaucracy,
again, thanks to having founder hands-on,
we can easily get a green light on anything, start
launching it quickly. What we do is assemble same
lean team with just a few people to build first
version and then iterate and iterate. And the main
thing here is to build first version very quickly
to get feedback, but then not scale it before you
polish the product. But then after we make sure
that all metrics are fine, retention is great, we
start scaling it. And the good news is that it can
be instantly multiplied by our 50 million customer
base and get great traction. So for example, one
of the products that you mentioned, joint accounts
essentially an account that you could have with
a significant other one was one of the recently
launched feature and it grew significantly
and now it has over a million active users.
I hear one of the ways you kind
of approach these early products
differently is you guys invest
a lot in actually making it good
and not just like a scrappy MVP. Does
that ring a bell? Does that resonate?
Indeed, that's what I may be meant by keeping
your first version narrowed down to a small user
base. But even in this case, we still make
sure that the product is well. So no one is
excluded from this requirement of building
a super polished product. It takes time,
but it pays off. The thing is that when you launch
a scrappy version and it's not getting traction,
how do you know? Is it because the underlying
idea is wrong or maybe your product just sucks
and you need to improve it? So by forcing
everyone to build a product that people will
love by building a wow product, we kind of cut
out this part of uncertainty. So bottom line,
we can cut down the product in terms of
functionality to just most critical features,
but we will never compromise on the
quality and UX and the aesthetics.
An interesting advantage you guys have that I'm
realizing as you talk is most of the stuff you
launch is stuff that is clearly something people
will want because it's stuff that they get other
places, but they get the advantages of
it being integrated into all the other
features and products you have. So it's like a
cryptocurrency product. It's kind of like, okay,
yeah, people would love a great cryptocurrency
product built into this or joint accounts. So
there's almost like a benefit of just like,
okay, the people will want this, now let's
just make it work really well with everything
else we got and not hurt. You almost don't
need to be the best at every product, although
it sounds like you still try to be the best.
But we must be the best. Yeah, a hundred percent.
But there's also, if you don't
have the best joint account,
but all the other stuff is awesome,
people are like, "All right,
it's fine. It just makes my life easier."
But tell me what I might be missing because-
So I think there are those kind of table stakes
that we're building that anyone would expect from
a bank. For example, savings account, right?
It's just a basic thing that if a bank is not
providing savings account, you wouldn't even
consider it. But then we make sure that our
rates are very competitive, if not the best. Then
we make sure that there is no bad UX. Some banks,
for example, they don't allow you to withdraw
instantly and there are delays or they don't pay
interest on daily basis. We will never do that.
We will allow you if you want to move money out,
you will be able to do it. You won't lose
any interest. And interest is being paid
daily and this is a fully flexible product.
And then on top of it, what I would call
maybe some delighters is we will allow you to
open the savings account in many currencies.
So we want to add different currencies
because now interest rates are going down,
so people might find it valuable to open a savings
account in, for example, I know in Europe, Swedish
Krona interest rates are higher than Europe, but
it could be even something like Brazilian Real
with 12% interest rate versus 2 or 3% on euros.
And then as the cherry on top, there is this
all that in an amazing, you have very smooth, you
can set custom wallpapers, you can set goals, you
can automate a spare change towards your savings
and all those features. So there is an underlying
basic fundamental layer that where you need to
be just on par with competition, but then there
are a lot of things on top that just make people
love your product way more. And obviously there
are a lot of synergies in between those things.
So yeah, thinking of crypto, you can just receive
crypto on your wallet and then you can just
instantly convert it to cash on your account
or just spend it with your card. How amazing
can it be? Just buy a coffee with Ethereum.
I love that. Okay, let me take this opportunity to
try to summarize what I've learned from you so far
in terms of what you guys have figured out about
creating incredible product leaders. They go on
to do wonderful things and basically one of the
top three most successful companies at this. So
there's kind of these two buckets as I talked to
you and the Palantir guy, there's kind of like
the hiring piece and then there's what you do to
help incubate this kind of forge for incredible
product leaders. So in what you do internally,
kind of the four bullet points I've got here
is give people a lot of ownership. They're
essentially GMs of the product, the feature.
There's a lot of focus on depth and complexity
and getting really good at solving really gnarly
problems. And then there's a focus on building
wow products, amazing lovable products that
have a very high bar. And then there's kind of a
subtle point that I think is probably impactful
here is just working closely with detail-obsessed
founders or product leaders like you and learning
from you all and just seeing the value and impact
of being super detail oriented. On that bucket,
is there anything else that you think is super
core that I missed before we get to hiring?
Yeah, I would just maybe highlight the aspect of
this going deep into details. There are two main
streams. First is let's say being technical,
understanding how underlying systems work,
but second is also building empathy towards
customers. Understand the possible contexts
and making sure that your product
will satisfy each one of them.
That's a great point. So it's actually
understanding the bare metal of what is
happening and how it's possible, and then making
the experience as simple and wowable as possible.
There is also a third aspect, but it's
a boring one and it's complying with all
possible regulations and making sure that
your product will satisfy the regulator,
but it's also an important part of the job.
What I get from that is just
building patience with all-
I would say it's actually being able to unblock
your team and that sometimes require product
owners to steam roll changes because it also means
that you could easily get stuck with a lot of
people just looking into each other and thinking,
"Okay, can they approve it? Can they not approve
it?" We try to innovate on it. We try to automate
as many things as possible. We use even AI models
for that, but it also requires a product owner
to be able to get things done, just getting
people down to consensus and understanding
how your stakeholders, how to get them to
the necessary decision and then blocking UTM so
that eventually the value is shipped to customers.
Awesome. So essentially it's just getting done,
plowing through blockers,
dealing with many stakeholders.
Yeah. That's always the most important.
Okay. That's a great addition. I could see
why that would be really helpful for folks
that are trying to get ahead in their
career. And then on the hiring piece,
what you look for is raw intellect, drive hunger,
passion essentially. Those are the first two.
And then interestingly, non-senior, not people
with a ton of experience in the problem space,
more so focusing on intellect and hunger.
Is there anything else in that bucket that
you think is important that leads
to people being really successful?
Most importantly, it's again, getting things done,
getting your hands dirty, and great product owners
are very hands-on. They don't think of themselves
as managers who just give tasks to people and wait
them to complete it. They just go and get things
done and they understand that most important
things they will likely have to do themselves,
and they understand that there needs to be
relentless focus on execution, and if something
is 99% done, it's closer to 0% rather than 100%.
Whoa, say more there. Is the kind of insight
there is just things seem like they're 99% done,
but they're actually very far from being done?
Sometimes the product is built, but then product
owners are the ones who also make sure that,
for example, customer care team or sales and
marketing team are using it to a full extent
because without it, it could be just another
useless feature, and no one knows about it.
That is super cool. I like that mentality. Let me
ask you something completely different.
What's kind of the story of you landing
at Revolut? I know you had to move
your family. It was a whole adventure.
My journey into Revolut actually coincided with
me moving to the UK, so it was a completely new
environment for myself. It's a huge stress
load for the brain as well. And it's not only
about using the other side of the lane on the
road in the UK, but also it's a lot of things,
for example, in the industry, some concepts
that I've never heard about, and actually I've
never worked at FinTech before, so I also
changed the industry. So it was a complete
turnaround for me and for my career, but I was
very determined and excited about it because
everyone who I've been talking to, they were
saying Revolut is like it's top talent is at
Revolut, all best product people are at Revolut,
and I really wanted to be part of this great team.
Eventually it actually appeared to be
advantageous for me because I also had
this fresh view on things and even in
the Revolut app, which is actually way,
way better than other banks products. But even
there I found some things that for me, because
of this lack of context, they were not intuitive
and I worked hard with the team to change that.
Okay, great. I'm going to take us to recurring
segment of the podcast. I'm going to take us
to Fail Corner. So in Fail Corner, the
idea here is people come on this podcast,
they share all these stories of success,
everything's always going great, but in reality,
things don't often go great, and there's
a lot of things that don't go right. Is
there a story you could share where things went
wrong in your career, where you failed with a
product you were building or a moment in your
career where things were looking really bad?
I think the most spectacular failures is probably
were on the earliest stage of my career, which I
studied back at university and maybe in my second
year of university I started building some things,
different startups, and one of them was actually
a product that makes me proud even now because it
was like what, 15 years ago? So 2010, meaning
still no one really had even iPhones back then
and me and my friends, we started building a
website that allows people to buy tickets to
the cinema so that they can skip the line so
they don't need to come in advance to select
best seats and they can just buy a ticket online
and go to the seats directly. Something that today
seems as a commodity. Back then no one had it.
People were using pieces of paper and we built
an end-to-end system because not only we needed
to build a website, but we also needed to build
hardware to scan those tickets, for example.
And to have these tickets in digital format,
we needed to hack SMS standard because
again, people didn't have smartphones.
They had these Nokias and we were
sending images, QR codes inside an SMS,
which is like a hack of the standards in a way.
And then we were scanning those things with our
own devices and we built our own devices with
scanners, and we actually created these beautiful
devices made from stainless steel, which
looked really nice inside the cinema halls.
And I remember how I was excited about it with
my friends. We were like, "What an amazing
thing." It's like, look, we are bringing future
here, but we actually spent all our investment
on this hardware and we were expecting that
everyone will just rush into using our system.
But it was a very low share of customers who
started buying tickets online because people
were not ready for it, which was growing quite
slowly. And eventually we had to close it because
we simply ran out of money because we spent all
of it on this hardware without any proven business
model. So something that currently looks like an
obvious mistake back then, we were just enjoying
building a product that we would love to use
ourselves, which I think is the right principle,
but it also was a very painful lesson. You need
to stay lean, you need to validate things before
you scale them. You need to think way more about
the run rate of your business. So there were a
lot of painful lessons for me. Since then,
I also try to avoid working with hardware.
I was just going to say that's a common challenge
for startups trying to get right into hardware,
although I wouldn't be surprised now if
Revolut launches something another product,
and this is a new product line of Revolut
now that you've had that experience.
We launched a POS terminals required.
All right, there we go. Dmitry, before we
get to our very exciting lightning round,
is there anything else that we haven't touched
on that you think might be really helpful for
listeners to hear? Maybe a last wisdom
nugget that you haven't already shared,
or even just something to kind of double
down on that you've already shared?
No, I think that it was an amazing chat and
thanks, Lenny. We covered a lot of different
topics. I would just maybe summarize that
if you're excited to build certain things,
never hesitate to do it. The best way to do it is
probably your own startup, and it also what will
give you the steepest possible learning curve, but
then if you want to join a company, try to choose
the one that has the highest entrepreneurial
spirit and that will allow you to work as closer
to a mode of a founder as you possibly can.
That's a recurring theme in these conversations
I'm having with companies that produce
the PMs that have the steepest career
trajectory. And so that advice is exactly
what I'm taking away from this too,
assuming you want your career to accelerate really
quickly after you go work at this company. Okay,
Dmitry, with that, we've reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yes. Let's go.
Here we go. Okay. First question,
what are two or three books that you've
recommended most to other people?
The Hard Thing About Hard Things by
Ben Horowitz. Actually read it quite
some time ago, but I found myself recommending
it to other product managers most often.
It's actually illustrative that to be a
great product manager, someone needs to
strive to being a great CEO. And besides this book
emphasizes the importance of building systematic
solutions and scalable solutions, which is
critical for scaling a company. Also being
honest on how important it is to grind stuff.
And then second book is, I read it more recently,
Build by Tony Fadell. I was really inspired by
this one, especially given how I appreciate how
it's not easy to build hardware and what Tony
was describing there is just super exciting
and inspiring. And also I think that there are
different archetypes of product managers. There
are people who tend to disrupt things more.
Personally I think about myself as a builder,
so Tony's principles that he highlighted in
the book that they resonate with me a lot.
I'm trying to get Tony on the podcast. If anyone
listening knows Tony Fadell and can nudge him,
"Hey, say yes to Lenny," that'd be
great. I've been in touch with his
team, but he's not doing podcasts right
now, but I'm trying to get him on. Okay,
moving on. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you've really enjoyed?
I think the last movie I watched was Oppenheimer
and I really liked it. I always love watching
biopics. I think they give kind of a perspective
and let you think about things in perspective.
Is there a favorite product you recently
discovered that you really love?
Manus is a great thing.
The AI agent?
Yeah. Yeah. It's just like I was super impressed
how... I was mesmerized. It's so autonomous and
smooth, and I just spent a few hours vibe coding
and I created this JavaScript app that sends
me a rare English word every day to learn and
remember, and it worked, and I was just amazed.
What's a word you learned?
Ineffable. It was the yesterday's word.
I love that. It's still going. That's
great. Do you have a favorite life
motto that you often come back to,
you find useful in work or in life?
I love this phrase. I think Eisenhower said it,
"Plans are worthless, but planning is everything."
It's like we often say how important
it is to be flexible and agile and
adjust to change in circumstances, but it
doesn't allow us to actually not have a
plan at all. It's important for us to
remember that we always need to think
many steps ahead and while being flexible,
we also need to think things thoroughly.
Final question. For folks that are maybe
checking out Revolut for the first time
that want to play with it or already users.
What's the most underrated feature? What's
something that you think people should
check out maybe they're not aware of,
or even just like a UX, I don't know, animation,
something fun that people may not know about?
The thing that is not yet widely used, but
I really loved it, is what we call a wealth
protection. So if you go to settings, you can
enable a limit for any transfers outside of
Revolut. If you want to do a transfer above
this limit, you'll have to do a selfie check,
which is our proprietary technology. We do
a video selfie here. It allows us to make
sure that it's you, no one else is doing the
transfer, and it's actually almost as smooth
as face ID and the way the team built it is
really great. I'm really proud of those guys.
Dmitry, you guys are doing something very
special. I really appreciate you spending
so much time with me chatting through
all the things you guys have figured
out. I think this is going to help
a lot of different companies level
up the way they think about product and
for people to join Revolut that want to
experience this and accelerate their career. So
thank you for being here. Two final questions.
Where can folks find you if they want to reach
out and how can listeners be useful to you?
I think the best way is to find me on LinkedIn
and yeah, I would be happy to receive a note
from anyone on how we can improve the product
and any feedback on the product. And also
if you know someone who can be a great fit to
Revolut after you've listened to what I've told,
then yeah, I would be grateful for that as well.
Awesome. You're about to get a flood of
applications. Get prepared. Dmitry, thank you.
Yeah, Lenny, thanks a lot. It was
amazing time. Thank you very much.
Same. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.