I want to dive right into talking about your
advice on having difficult conversations,
where like in performance review season,
what do you suggest when someone's being
told they're not going to get the promotion?
Hope for the future is so important. I know
this is going to be challenging for you to hear,
not going to promote you, but I want you
to know this. It's really important to
me that you're able to succeed in your
career here, and so I want to continue
to help you find opportunities to
build your skills and to advance.
You're big on helping leaders understand that
their job is not to make employees happy.
They're trying now to be the leader who
everyone loves, but what really needs
to happen very often is, we need to drive
towards results. This employee continuing
to not really do a great job at their job, you
don't want to push them because you don't want
to upset them. You don't want to give them
difficult feedback, so you're just going
to keep hoping it works out. Ultimately,
that leads to the demise of your company.
You have some cool advice on just how to make
meetings more effective and how
to especially end the meeting.
My three questions to end the meeting are...
Today my guest is Alisa Cohn. Alisa is an
executive coach who has worked with C-suite
execs at both startups like Etsy, Wirecutter,
Venmo, and DraftKings, along with Fortune 500
companies like Microsoft, Google, Pfizer, and
the New York Times. She was named one of the
top 50 coaches in the world by Thinkers50 and
the number one startup coach for the past four
years by Global Gurus. What I love about Alisa
is that she gives her clients very specific and
actionable advice. In her conversation, Alisa
shares specific language and phrases that you
can use when having a difficult conversation
with your reports to make these conversations
go much smoother and be less difficult. Also,
three questions you should ask at the end of
every meeting to make the most possible forward
progress after each meeting. Plus, why your job
as a leader isn't to make people happy and what
you should be focused on instead, and a set of
questions that she calls the founder prenup that
you should talk through with potential founders
to make sure that these are the people that you
want to be working with for a long, long time.
There's also so much more advice. If
you're a leader of people or a founder,
and especially if you dread hard conversations,
this episode is for you. If enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. It's the
best way to avoid missing future episodes and
it helps the podcast tremendously. With that,
I bring you Alisa Cohn. This episode is brought
to you by Eppo. Eppo is a next generation A/B
testing and feature management platform built
by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake for modern
growth teams. Companies like Twitch, Miro,
ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to power
their experiments. Experimentation is increasingly
essential for driving growth and for understanding
the performance of new features. And Eppo
helps you increase experimentation velocity
while unlocking rigorous deep analysis in
a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things
that I loved most was our experimentation
platform where I could set up experiments, easily
troubleshoot issues, and analyze all on my own.
Eppo does all that and more with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time and accessible
UI for diving deeper into performance and
out-of-the-box reporting that helps you avoid
annoying prolonged analytic cycles. Eppo also
makes it easy for you to share experiment insights
with your team, sparking new ideas for the A/B
testing flywheel. Eppo powers experimentation
across every use case, including product,
growth, machine learning, monetization, and email
marketing. Check out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny
and 10X your experiment velocity. That's get
E-P-P-O.com/lenny. This episode is brought to
you by Rippling, a single platform to build and
scale your startup on. Rippling handles all the,
can't get it wrong admin work of payroll and
benefits giving you back hours every week,
but it does a lot more than that. Rippling is a
game changer for the entire company with tools
for HR, IT and spend, all built from the ground
up and designed to work together seamlessly.
Just hired someone? Rippling makes onboarding
easy. Whether your new hire is sitting next to you
or halfway across the world, in just a few clicks,
Rippling automatically generates an offer letter,
ships a laptop with the necessary apps and
permissions, and even delivers a corporate
card. An employee needs to update their benefits
contribution. When they do it in Rippling,
the change automatically syncs to payroll. CTO
forgot her laptop in an Uber? Lock it remotely
with Rippling. Many startups I've invested in
like Sprig, [inaudible 00:04:30] and ClassDojo,
use Rippling because it's a force multiplier
for lean teams, helping them eliminate major
headaches and operate their business
more efficiently. For a limited time,
Rippling is giving Lenny's listeners three months
off. To redeem, visit rippling.com/lenny. That's
rippling.com/lenny. Alisa, thank you so much
for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Lenny, it's so great to be
here and thanks for having me.
I want to dive right into talking about your
advice on having difficult conversations. I
personally dread difficult conversations. I feel
like I practice ahead of these things. I'm like,
"I'm going to say these things. It's
going to go like this," and it never
goes as well as I hope. I always
say the wrong thing. I feel like
this is very relatable. They're called
difficult conversations for a reason.
Totally.
I know you work with a lot of execs on this
specifically, and what I love is you've actually
come up with a bunch of scripts that help people
make these conversations less difficult. So how
about we talk through some of these scripts
that people can actually start applying?
Let's do that. I love that idea. And also Lenny,
as you just said, very relatable and also,
so you're not alone. If I could ask you a
question, if you're picturing a difficult
conversation that you have had, should have, might
have, and you're nervous about, it's hard for you,
can you sum it up? What's hard about it? Because
it's helpful to clarify what is hard about it?
Great question. I just don't want to make people
sad and upset, and I worry about their reaction,
how to deal with that, and them just getting
really upset and mad and just like, "Oh,
man. This really made things worse."
So I worry about the reaction, I guess.
Okay, about making things
worse or about their reaction?
The reaction, just making someone
upset and sad. I don't want to do that.
Making someone upset. Okay, good. And again,
you're not alone about that. Just one more
question on that. What's the problem if they're
sad and upset? What does that mean to you?
Oh, I love this life coaching we're doing. Yeah,
so it's like what happens
if they get sad and upset?
Yeah.
I feel like it's stuff that I'm going to have to
deal with. It's like this drama all of a sudden,
this new fire I have to think about. And yeah,
it's like the additional work it creates and also
just, I don't know. Yeah, it's a good question.
You can think about it some more, right? I'm
not going to put you on the spot right now,
but just to say for all of us, the
reason they're difficult, to your point,
they're difficult. But we're putting meaning on
things all the time, every day, all the time,
and I think it's important, it's actually helpful
in motivating you to have difficult conversations,
but also in helping them go well. If you can get
to the bottom of what you're putting on top of it,
what you're weighting it with, because I can
understand that again, you are not alone.
I don't want to make people upset. Totally.
And also, I would just say on the other hand,
when you're enlightening someone or you're working
out a situation with someone and it's difficult,
if you don't give them the opportunity to hear
what you have to say, if you don't bring this up,
then you're never going to have the opportunity
to help them see something differently or help
them improve or help you improve the relationship
or whatever it is you're trying to do. And so,
I can understand it's a natural thing.
I don't want to make them upset.
No one wants to make anybody upset, but
through that upset on the other side of that,
can often be a whole new possibility and a
whole new revelation, and actually a lot of
joy and freedom. I think that we forget about
all the other possibilities that come out of
difficult conversations and we just land on
these really uncomfortable parts about like,
"oh, it's going to be a lot of extra
work" or like, "They're going to get
uncomfortable or even maybe cry." And
I think it's just really helpful to tap
into what you make it mean and then also
what other possibilities it could mean.
I love that. And it's one thing to hear that
and say that, it's another to actually feel that
deeply and feel like I shouldn't be as worried
as I am. I think part of it is doing these enough
times where you're like, "Okay, it's actually not
so hard." And the other is having some of this
support. To make this even more real, let's give
some examples of what we say when we say difficult
conversations. There's like, "You're not getting a
promotion that you thought you would, we're going
to let you go." What other examples or common
difficult conversations that you run across?
Those are two very common ones. And then of
course, the most common one is just difficult
performance feedback. Or [inaudible
00:08:56] what we say, quote unquote,
"constructive performance feedback," which we
never made positive. It only is the sort of
things that you're not doing well. I think there
are two flavors of that. One is, "You're screwing
up" and the other is, "Developmentally, I'd like
to see you add something or change something."
Yes. And as you say that, one of the other
fears I have is them just disagreeing and
me feeling like maybe it's not right,
maybe I'm wrong and feeling shit maybe.
I didn't see something and then just
looking worse after the whole thing.
Yeah. And so then I think what's also really
helpful to, and part of the process that we can
talk about this for sure is getting a difficult
conversation is number one, tapping into what's
uncomfortable for it, for you, about it. And then
number two, also getting your mindset right. So
to say the obvious, are you doing this to
hurt someone's feelings? No, never, right?
The opposite.
That's not the reason that anyone's
doing it. Sometimes people are giving
the performance feedback or talking about
something that's been bothering them
in order to express themselves and vent. And
actually, that is very helpful to identify
for yourself, that's why I'm doing
it. And then, maybe not do it then,
until you can transform your reasoning. But at
the end of the day, the hope is as a manager,
the reason that you're giving someone this
so-called constructive feedback is because
you're helping them get better. You need them to
change the behavior. They'll never get promoted if
they keep doing that. They'll never be successful
if they keep doing that. And so, it's your job
as a leader and as a manager, to help them out of
that problem and help them do something different.
The best story I've heard to make that really
real for me, I think it was Kim Scott when she
came on the podcast. She told a story of, I
think it was Bob, where everyone just knew
he was terrible and it was like, everyone's was
just like knew he was not good and eventually,
the boss had a conversation with him
eight months into it and told him,
"It's not going to work out. You're just doing
a bad job." And he's like, "Why didn't anyone
tell me? I didn't realize that. If you told me, I
would've changed." And everyone assumed he knew.
And so I think to your point, this is to
help the person. It's not not to hurt them.
Yeah, a hundred percent. One of my clients, he was
running a division and one of his people was not
doing it right, not doing it right, not getting
the right kind of data, not having to do the
right kind of analysis, whatever it was. We were
talking about it and I said, "Well, how come you
have another feedback with her?" And he said,
"You know, she's just going to cry. She's just
going to cry. She's older, whatever, she's just
going to cry. It's going to be too uncomfortable,
whatever." So we worked, we talked and talked
and talked. I gave him a script. We really worked
it out and he agreed that he would go in and
have that conversation with her, which he did.
And he reported back to me and he was shaken. She
cried. Of course she did. She cried. That's what
he knew she was going to do. And so she was upset
and she went home early and the whole thing. The
next day she came in and she said, "Thank you
so much for telling me that. I wish someone
had told me that 15 years ago. I think I could
have had a different career." And I think that
is so meaningful for all leaders and people who
are responsible for other people to understand
that you're uncomfortable when they start crying,
of course, or they have this difficult reaction
or whatever. But honestly, the only way you're
going to be able to help someone grow in their
career and become the best person they can be
is by leaning into these tough conversations.
What I love about the scripts we're going to talk
about, which we probably should transition to,
is it's again, one thing to hear that and be
like, "Yes, okay, I need to do this. I need
to get better at typical conversations. I need to
have that talk without someone that we should let
go." It's another when it's like tomorrow is the
meeting and you're like, "Oh, my God. I have to
have this conversation now." And so, I love that
you actually give people a really simple approach
to how to lay this stuff out in various different
contexts. So let's talk through some of these
approaches and scripts you've come up with. What
do you think would be a good one to start with?
Well, we can start with performance feedback and
we can just sort of take a typical example. So
first of all, once you've done your work to
get your mindset right to kind of know what
you're doing it, and then you just really
want to really be able to wrap your mouth
around the words. So what that looks like is
practicing, and the script could be, "You know,
Matilda, I want to chat with you about the
way you're interacting with your peers. So
what I'm hearing from them is that you're missing
deadlines on a regular basis and not letting them
know you're missing the deadlines, and that also
you're not fully keeping your team up to speed.
And so they're kind of confused running around.
Now, we both know that the most important way you
can be successful here and also achieve your
goals is to make sure that you are working
with your peers in a way that's consistent and
that they can count on you and you can count on
them. So I wanted to let you know about this.
I want to certainly hear what you have to say,
but the most important thing is that we leave
this discussion knowing how you're going to
make sure that you're keeping your peers in
the loop and also your team in the loop."
Yeah, there's so many elements there that
are really interesting. Just focusing
on what I'm hearing versus just coming from
you or something you've done wrong. It's,
here's what I'm hearing from multiple
sources. I think that helps people. Okay,
it's not just you and just
like, "Oh, my manager hates me."
Right.
It's like, "Okay, other people are saying
this." And then I love this phrase of,
we both know where it's not just me telling
you this. It's like, "You also know this. I
know you're smart and you also know that this
is, something is wrong here." And then this
goal of, here's what we need to [inaudible
00:14:31]. You're like very clear call to action,
almost action item, like leave this meeting
with, "Let's just be aligned on this thing."
Yeah, thanks for calling those out. I hope, and
again, what I'm trying to convey in my tone is
also, "You know what? It's Tuesday. We got to
have this conversation. I'm sure it's going to
end well. I'm not mad." The whole point about
my manager hates me, right? "I'm not yelling
at you." The more even keeled and even matter
of fact you can be about something that's kind
of just run-of-the-mill feedback, the better. And
I think it's just also what I didn't say before,
and I think it's also important is that, as
you are recognizing that one of your jobs is
to give this feedback, is that you have to build
a relationship with people so they can hear you
through the lens of, "Oh, Alisa wants to help me."
Not, "Oh, Alisa hates me. It's always a problem."
How did you start that phrase again? Because
the starting is always the hardest part for me.
How do you kick off the conversation?
What was the couple sentences used?
I wanted to have a conversation with
you about some things I've been hearing
from your peers about the way that
you all are interacting together.
Awesome. So there's an element of, don't
make it feel like a huge deal. Just like,
"I want to have this conversation with
you about something." And it's just like,
"Let's have this conversation and here's what
we want to leave this conversation with."
Yes. And I can't stress enough that it's
actually really helpful to also have spent
some time with Matilda or whoever saying, "Great
job on the way that project landed." Or, "Hey,
launches, when they happen
on time and they're smooth,
sometimes we don't notice anything. I want
you to notice, we didn't notice anything.
That's fantastic. You did a good job in that
launch," or whatever it is. Because then,
you've had the conversation with them to give them
positive feedback and point out what's working,
that builds the relationship so that you have
the lens of, "Oh, yeah. When something's working,
they tell me. When something's not working, they
tell me, too." That's how you build trust as well.
They want to be criticizing them
[inaudible 00:16:25]. We need to have
another conversation what we're hearing
about, problems [inaudible 00:16:28].
Yep.
Obviously, if you say it the same way every
single time, they're going to feel like this
is weird. Do you recommend it's this kind of Mad
Libs approach or is it make it your own as much as
you can? What are kind of the key? Or is it like,
here's actually how you want to say it every time?
In my book and when I work with my clients, I
give specific scripts and what I will regularly
say when I'm working with my clients is, "Okay, so
this is how I would do it," and then I'll land it
for them. But they have to make it their own. You
always have to make it your own and I don't think
it's a problem of doing it the same way every
time. It's not like people are going to notice
you because you're talking about different topics,
theoretically. If you have a formula that can work
for you, that's going to motivate you to do it,
that is what's important. And what's important
is that it's neutral, not loading on or not
venting on someone and not unloading on someone.
I love that we started with this one because
it feels like the most common one of just your
employee is underperforming and you want to
make sure they understand and adjust. What
if you're not hearing something from a bunch
of people? What if it's just your perception
of their writing? You need to work on your
writing skills or you're coming in late. Is
there another way you phrase it where it's
not, "I'm hearing it from other people?"
Oh, absolutely. Absolutely. So I'll talk about
writing. I think it would be something like, okay,
"Matilda, part of your job is to be able to create
these documents and I appreciate that you do them
on time. What I've observed is that they can often
be not as structured as I'd like them to be and
they also lack a conclusion. So what I'd love you
to do is look at these three or four examples of
some folks who are doing them really well and see
if you can model your writing on theirs. If you
need to take additional classes or if you need
help in any way, let me know. But ultimately,
I want to get your writing to the level where
everybody is appreciating what you bring to
the table because the level of your writing
really reflects the level of your thinking."
Mm-hmm. Wow, I like that. I'd want to follow
your advice if I got that. So the way you
started that is what I've observed, which
also is not like, "Here's what I think" or
"Here's what you just need to do." It's more like,
"Here's what I've noticed, here's what I've seen,
here's what I've observed about what you're
doing." And then it reminds me of, what is it,
nonviolent communication, that whole
framework of just focus on what you see,
not what is wrong with them,
not what they've done. I guess,
is there anything there you want to say of
just the importance of focusing on what you've
heard from people or what you've observed
versus maybe what people often do instead?
Yeah, I mean you just really said it and
I think it's such an important point,
observable facts. The idea that this is not a
judgment. This is not... Sort of as less judgy
as possible is also very helpful. It makes it
neutral. It's observable facts and it's also
sort of based on expectations, right? So the
writing is, we expect it to be at a certain
level and it's not that way. And here are the
reasons it's not, the specific reasons, it's not.
The way you interact with your peers, it's
important to be at a certain standard, and here's
why. Because when we all work together, we're
going to be able to execute and when we don't,
unfortunately we won't be able to. So you staying
in sync with them is important and the observation
is that they don't feel fully in sync with you.
And so every time we talk about this, it doesn't
become this, "Oh, I don't know. I just feel..."
By the way, some things you have to give feedback
on and they are kind of a feeling and those are
more difficult, but so many things if you do the
work to really think about what is the observable
data, I always ask my clients, what's my evidence
that this is happening? And you have to spend
some time thinking about it, but it's really
worth it because it makes the feedback easier
for you to give and easier for them to hear.
Is there anything else along the lines
of this specific type of feedback that
is worth sharing before we move on
to a different type of feedback?
Well, I think just that the reason, one of the
many reasons that people have gone uncomfortable
giving feedback is that somebody might
get defensive or they might start crying
as we talked about. And so I have a script
also, which is if someone gets defensive,
which is it's like I'm giving you this feedback
and you're getting defensive and I say, "Well,
let's pause for a second. First of all, I want
you to know that I'm telling you this actually,
just to make you better because I know how
important your career is to you. I know how
important the success is to you and it's important
to me too as your leader. The second thing is,
my observation is that you're getting a little
bit emotional. I want to know if we can continue
having this conversation now or if we need to
kind of pause it. At the end of the day, we
really have to have this conversation and I really
want to see you make changes, but I understand
you might need a few moments to digest it."
The importance of that for you is not even what
you say, but that you have prepared and you are
prepared for if someone has that kind of reaction
and that you don't have to, yourself, react to
it. You know, "No, I'm not doing that. No, no,
no, no, whatever." And you can say, "Yes, you
are." Now we're in a fight and that is not cool
for anybody. It's certainly not cool for you
as a leader. So it gives you the opportunity
to recognize that you have another tool
in your toolkit rather than just react.
So if you find yourself feeling
defensive or they are just not
hearing and just fighting back, the tool is
just pause. Let's just pause for a moment
and it feels like there's kind of two
parts to which you just shared. One is,
remind them why this is important to them and
why you're talking about this. And then two is,
if there's just emotions kind of taking over,
give them a chance to like, "Let's just pause
and maybe come back to this because maybe you're
not in the right state right now to listen."
Yeah, exactly.
Sometimes people get upset when you mention like,
"You're getting emotional," or I don't know. Is
that a thing that you deal with of just like, "How
dare you say I'm feeling emotional?" I'm just...
I'm not emotional. Why do you think
[inaudible 00:22:31] emotional? Right,
exactly. Yes, of course. Now, when someone's
crying, they're obviously getting emotional.
When they're defensive, it's possible that
you might want to use a different word. I
can see that this is really upsetting
you or this is really triggering you,
or I can see that the temperature between
us has just changed. You could say something
like that. I do think also it's helpful
to know your people because sometimes you
could realize that actually they can deal
with that, but then sometimes you have to
really [inaudible 00:23:00] the delicate words
that you need to use to pause the conversation.
Yeah. And I find, to your point, it's helpful
to you too as the person giving it. And I feel
like sometimes, you may be feeling like I should
just pull back and maybe I'm wrong, maybe they're
right, maybe I should stop and instead this gives
you a chance to know I'm actually, I can't. I need
to stay strong about what I believe because
I... You put so much thought and effort into
this already, it's unlikely you're just like,
oh, totally wrong about what you're saying.
Yeah, exactly. There's something going on.
There's something going on. And then also,
the whole point about it being a conversation
is that actually it's a conversation. Actually,
Lenny, if you have a different point of view,
I would like to hear it. Let's talk about
it, but we can't keep going on like this,
where I don't feel I can count on you for
whatever it is that we're talking about. So
we need to have this conversation and recreate a
set of expectations between ourselves. Ultimately,
that kind of conversation has the potential to
really build the relationship and build trust,
and that's another reason I encourage everybody to
get over their discomfort and to lean into having
these conversations because on the other side
of that, is a much better, stronger connection.
And especially if you do them well.
Yes.
Following this advice. So okay, so again, if
somebody's feeling defensive, can you again say
how you start that, if you notice that? And then
I'll highlight the two elements again of the...
So the way to pause is to actually say,
"Let's just pause for a second because
I'm feeling the energy has changed and I can
see that you're getting a little bit heated
by what I'm saying and I want you to know that I
have no intention of upsetting you. I just want
to be able to talk to you about the things
that are going to help you in your career."
Awesome. And I love, again, just the reminder
of here's why this is important to you,
here's the benefit to you and why this will help
you. And then it's like, "Okay, let's just maybe
take a pause and come back to this conversation
if you're feeling like this isn't the best time."
Awesome. Anything else along that line before
we go to another type of a hard conversation?
I mean, I can talk all day about this
[inaudible 00:25:06], but I'm happy to move on.
Well, let's pick another topic. I know
you have kind of five buckets and types
of conversation. Maybe the promotion one.
That feels like I think we're in performance
review season. It feels like these are
happening a bunch. What do you suggest
when someone's being told they're not going
to get the promotion they expected or wanted?
Of course that's challenging. So again,
getting your mindset right, recognizing they're
disappointed, they're going to be disappointed,
recognizing how you felt, the time that when you
didn't get a promotion or whatever. And so kind
of coming to it with some compassion. And also,
you have to get your reasoning right. So sometimes
people think they should get a promotion because
they were here for a year or whatever. Sometimes
they're the only internal candidate who's
qualified for this or they might have a sense
of themselves succeeding or achieving that is more
inflated maybe than you see them. So trying to
think about where they're coming from.
And then the conversation is just,
"Matilda, I know this is going to be challenging
for you to hear. I know you were hoping to get
that promotion, but I want to let you know that we
are going to actually be looking for an external
candidate. I want to give you a few thoughts
about why. First of all, in discussing this with
my peers, I'm realizing that we need someone
who has done this role multiple times in the
past and has that experience. Number two, I think
it's really important that they have an expertise
in a specific realm that we've identified
as really important. So for those reasons,
we're going to bring someone in from
the outside, not going to promote you,
but I want you to know this. Number one,
it's really important to me that you're able
to succeed in your career here. And so I want
to continue to help you find opportunities to
build your skills and to advance. And then number
two, when we bring this person in, I'm committed
to finding someone who's a great people leader,
who is going to help you build those skills."
So a few elements there that stood out to
me. One is just being very upfront and not
bearing the lead. Telling them very early,
"Here's what I've decided." As you said it,
I could see my heart sinking immediately when I
feel that. So at least that's over and then it's,
here's why. And that starts
to help you feel like, "Okay,
I get it. I understand at least how you
thought about this." And then there's the
hope for the future, your painting of,
here's how I can get there eventually.
Yes, that hope for the future is so important
and I think sometimes we're such in a rush
to kind of deliver the bad news that we forget
there's a human being over there who needs hope
for the future. And hopefully. If they're a good
employee, hopefully they have hope for the future.
I love that. Is there anything
else to that script that you
think is really highlighting or do you
think I touched on the key elements?
I think you touched on the key elements.
Okay. And again, the way you started is,
I have some bad news for you or I
have some disappointing news for you.
Yes, because it's just [inaudible 00:27:50].
Just get right into it. Yeah.
Yeah, just get right into it. Yeah. By
the way, the other piece on that might be,
if it's appropriate, I'd love you to digest this
information and then let's talk about it again
next week to see what you've come up with or see
how you feel about it because you want to send,
this is not the script, this is for me to you.
You want to send the, I care about you message
because that's the other thing. In the workplace,
people, they're going through all their feelings,
all their emotions, disappointments. They're
going to go home and tell their spouse,
didn't get the promotion or whatever. It's going
to loom large. It's going to be demoralizing.
When you, as a leader signal a lot, I care
about you, I care about your feelings,
I care that you're disappointed, I care about
your career, you are always going to be able
to help people stay resilient in the face
of setbacks and ultimately, do extra work,
do the right work for you and be engaged in your
company because you've spent the time and energy
making sure they know that even when things are
not going their way, they have an ally in you.
What do you do if they just
disagree, if they're just like,
"But I do have those skills and I
don't think this is fair." Thoughts
on responding to that sort of feedback?
I guess, that's the defensiveness stuff.
Yeah, that's the defensiveness stuff. And again,
I hope you've done your homework to identify that
actually that person doesn't have those skills and
if there is a [inaudible 00:29:16] for example,
but I do have those skills or sometimes
people, I think more, even more often,
they don't respond to what you just said.
They will instead explain to you that
they've been here for a year or they're the only
internal candidate or their peer got promoted.
Right, they'll sort of explain to you things
which are not part of your decision-making
process and then it's helpful for you to
say something like, "Yeah, listen, Matilda,
I really understand that you were thinking that
after a year, you'd get promoted around here. And
in the past, I do think because of the stage of
our company, probably people have been promoted
at that period. That's not the place we're
at right now. As we scale, we really need to
think about not just what we need for today
and tomorrow, but for the future. And that's
why I want these specialized skills in here. I
think it's going to help the entire company."
So that's an example of a discussion that you
could have. I do have the skills. That's kind
of interesting. I'd love to hear what you
see as those skills. And it's not a problem
to have the conversation right there then, but if
there's a "Yes, I do, no, I don't, yes, I do, no,
you don't," that pushback is never productive.
And so, that's where you want to probably again
take a pause and say, "Listen, I totally hear
you. You and I have a different point of view
about this. I'm not sure if it's productive
to continue to discussing right now. Let's
talk about it again in a week. But I also want
you to know this is a decision that I've made."
I love though, when they come back to you and
like, "But here's X, Y, Z." And you're like,
"That's not what I was saying necessarily." I
love that you basically mirror back. I hear what,
I understand you believe, I understand you've
been here for a year. I understand you're the
only internal candidate," like making them feel
very heard. That's a really powerful mechanic
there. That is a good tool. Is there
another script that you think might
be helpful to talk through that is a
common hard conversation people have?
Well, the hardest conversation is firing someone.
Let's do it. Let's get into it.
[inaudible 00:31:13]. I'm willing to get into
it. I just want to say two things about that.
First of all, when you're firing someone,
the hope is that it's not a surprise to
them. You've had multiple conversations with them
that they're not living up to your expectations.
It's essential because the truth is, you want to
create a culture where people are not surprised
by being fired. And that's not even true for this
one person you're dealing with. That's true for
the entire company. So just kind of getting in the
mindset of recognizing that if you shied away from
those conversations, kind of like, "You're the
problem here and you have some catch up to do."
The second thing is that before you fire
someone, I think it's helpful to have the
conversation before the firing conversation
because something you said Lenny is like, "Oh,
but maybe I'm wrong. Maybe I'm not sure." And
that bleeds into, "Maybe I haven't been clear
with this person." Regularly with my clients,
I'll say, "Okay, have you been crystal clear
about what you need from this person?" And what
they always do is the hand motion like well,
sort of, but well, maybe. Which means no, which
means no. You've not been crystal clear or you
don't perceive even crystal clear. The way to
make sure that you're crystal clear is by having
the conversation before it comes to that.
What that looks like is, "Listen, Matilda,
we have to have a difficult conversation right
now. I've talked to you multiple times about
coordinating with your peers and not having them
surprised about missed deadlines, and I've talked
to you multiple times about keeping your team in
the loop on different things. After six months of
these conversations, I want you to know that
the peers continue to feel like that you're
operating on your own without coordinating
with them. And I continue to hear from your
team that they're not fully on the same page.
I need you to know that this is very important.
I need you to fix this within the next
30 days. Otherwise, I'm sorry to say,
we're going to have to find a way to
part ways because I can't keep this
going with you. I know you have it in you to
change. I value all you bring to the table,
but if you don't fix these things, we're
not going to have a future together."
That is very crystal clear.
Yes, crystal clear.
Yeah. Okay.
What do you think of that?
Yeah, that was great. So it starts with being
upfront. This is a difficult conversation, just
to set expectations. They're like, "Oh, shit."
And then it seems like you come back to, again,
multiple times this happened, observing here's
what's happening. It's happened multiple times.
I keep hearing from multiple people, [inaudible
00:33:44] be a problem. And so it's just like,
"I need you to know," and you're just very clear.
"Here's what will happen if this doesn't change."
Yes.
Yeah. And I love that you also give them
a little, there's always that hope for who
they are and how you see them as. They're not
worthless. It's just like, "You are great at
a lot of things. You have these skills. You're
great at blah, blah, blah, but still this is a
big problem." And it's communicating how
critical this is. [inaudible 00:34:08].
Yeah, and it's a deal breaker.
It's a deal breaker. Right?
Yeah.
If you have so many talents, but
if you can't do these two things,
then it's a deal breaker for all of us.
Yeah.
And I think it's important to really sort of
see that both. Sometimes people think, "Well,
but I'm so talented." Yeah, but your talents are
not going to make up for these two deal breakers.
Yeah. And I feel like I know we were going
to talk about the firing conversation,
but I think this is even more
important than that because hopefully,
this addresses the problem and you don't
need to fire them, which is more valuable.
Yes. Yeah, hopefully. But even if you
do, it's actually easier because you've
already had the conversation. Right? They're not
surprised. It's clear. We've had the discussion.
Yeah. So basically the script is like, "There's
going to be a difficult conversation. I've seen
multiple times this thing and we've
talked multiple times and it's still
not fixed and here's what I just want
to be very clear about." Is there also
a script you have for just actually doing
the firing or is that less scriptable?
Well, the script for doing the firing is again,
please everybody, talk to your HR professional.
Talk to your lawyer. Okay, I'm not a lawyer, I'm
afraid. So you have to make sure that you're all
buttoned up on what you're going to do. But
the conversation is actually very simple,
which is just, "Matilda, we talked about this
multiple times. The last time we had this
conversation, I told you I needed you to make
these changes. You haven't made these changes
and we're going to part ways. So I
have here, Sarah from HR or whatever,
and we're going to talk through the
logistics of that. I'm happy to have a
longer conversation with you, but I want you to
know we've made the decision to terminate you."
Feels very reasonable to me. Is there
anything else along these lines?
I think what I want to say is that the
conversations you need to have at work are
not just difficult conversations. What I call
them is sort of delicate conversations because
what I think people also shy away from is just
simple praise, specific praise. And I think it's
really important to get in the habit of pointing
out what your people are doing well as carefully
as you need to prepare for pointing out what they
need to improve. And sometimes leaders feel like,
"Yeah, it's all working. It's all working. I
don't have to tell you." Or if I do tell you,
it's kind of like "Good job." Right? One
time a leader or a manager I was doing
in a training program, she said, "I don't like
getting positive feedback. I only like getting
negative feedback." And I said, "How come?" And
she said, "Oh, positive feedback is just like,
oh, good job. Negative feedback, you can
learn something. You get something from it."
So the positive feedback should have the same
standard, which is, "I saw the way you ran that
launch, it was fantastic. All these different
benefits came from it. You're so organized,
keep doing that." Or "The way you're keeping your
peers in the loop, considering you've only been
here three months is extraordinary. I've never
seen someone so communicative. It's fantastic.
Keep doing that. That's really working for you."
If you do that often enough, you do get in the...
First of all, it's positive, obviously. You
become in the habit of getting better at positive
feedback, which is extremely motivating to people
at work. It helps them see their progress because
that person I just mentioned, she's barely keeping
her head above water and she's having trouble
fitting in or whatever, but you come around and
point out the things that are working. Again,
it's very morale boosting. She knows where
she stands, and then one day, if you have
to give her these difficult messages, you've
already sort of laid the reservoir of goodwill.
I love giving positive feedback.
It's obviously so much easier,
but to your point, it's like you have to really
think about how to do it well. It's not just a,
it's not that easy if you do it well, which is
a really good point. And [inaudible 00:37:49]
needs scripts for how to give really good
positive feedback and have great conversations.
Yeah.
That's interesting. There's
less demand for that. How do
I have better great conversations or compliments?
Right, right. True.
No man. Today's episode is brought to you
by Liveblocks, the platform that turns
your product into a place that users want to
be. With ready-made collaborative features,
you can supercharge your product with
experiences that only top tier companies
have been able to perfect until now. Think AI
copilots like Notion, multiplayer like Figma,
comments and notifications like Linear and
even collaborative editing like Google Docs,
and all of that with minimal
configuration or maintenance required.
Companies from all kinds of industries and stages
count on Liveblocks to drive engagement and growth
in their products. Join them today and give your
users an experience that turns them into daily
active users. Sign up for a free account today at
liveblocks.io/lenny. I want to go on a little bit
of a tangent, something that it's kind of touches
on all the things we've been talking about,
which is, you're big on helping leaders
understand that their job is not to make
employees happy. What is your job instead?
Why do people think this is their job to
make their employees happy and what should they
be thinking instead is their job as a leader?
[inaudible 00:39:09], I work with a lot
of founders and so, don't forget that the
entry-level position for a founder is leader,
and they have it, they often not had a lot of
other experiences being a leader or a manager,
and so they're just doing the best they can.
It makes sense, right? And they kind of get all
this information from other people and their HR
leader wants to have a happy engaged workforce
and they don't want to upset people for all
the reasons we talked about, why you don't want
to upset people. Nobody wants to upset people.
And so there's this idea of, they're trying to
now be now be the leader who everyone loves and
makes people happy. So they would often
bend over backwards to make people happy,
to keep people, their morale up. But what
really needs to happen very often is,
we need to drive towards results. And the way
this system is working is not going to drive us
towards results or this employee continuing to
not really do a great job at their job and not
really pushing themselves. And you don't want to
push them because you don't want to upset them,
you don't want to give them difficult feedback,
so you're just going to keep hoping it works out.
Ultimately, that leads to the demise of
your company. I mean, ultimately right,
as you're a startup? If you're not in
a startup and you're a large company,
it still is very subpar performance, obviously.
And you're dancing around hoping and praying
they're going to get there and they don't really
know there's a problem. And so, I think it's very
misguided for leaders to have this notion
that their most important role is to keep
people happy, is to create this high engagement
workforce. High engagement workforce is great.
I think what that comes from is winning culture,
which means we're set up for success. We've got
the structure for success, we have the culture
for success, everyone understands their role,
they know the impact of their role. So doing
the work to figure out and help them figure out
the impact of their role and that when they
work together and achieve these milestones,
they win and then we celebrate the wins and
then we do it all over again. And when you
create that kind of a workforce,
I think it's much more dynamic,
even though sometimes in doing that, you have
to redirect people and ruffle their feathers.
Essentially, the way I think about it is
you think making people happy is not having
hard conversations, not pushing them, when
really, it's almost working backwards from,
if we win and are killing it, people will
be happy and what does it take to do that?
A hundred percent. And then the right
people are going to want to join your team,
people who like to win and like to get results.
Is there a story, an example of
a founder you worked with or that
comes to mind of this kind of where
they thought this was their approach
and then they shifted? Or is there
kind of a pattern you see often?
One company comes to mind. One leader I worked
with. Sometimes I think to myself, if I'm writing
a book, the book would start with, "It all started
with the avocado toast," because he wants to do
right by his workforce. And so they have avocado
toast at 10 AM, like tea time kind of a thing. And
it became this great ritual where people would
kind of hang out together and that was great.
And then that turned into other longer periods
of just hanging out together. Again, these are
good things. And that turned into evening socials
and everybody was enjoying spending time together,
but they continued to be not fully clear on what
they were actually supposed to do. And there began
to be kind of a cliquey, gossipy culture of who's
in and who's out. And that would take up a lot of
the socialization time discussions. So rather
than talk about expectations about the work
and about results, and again, the results were
not showing. So it wasn't a lot to celebrate.
They started at a culture committee. So they
had a culture committee to talk about how we
can make people happier around here. And you can
imagine there's now layers and layers of things
where we're trying to focus on engagement and
we're trying to focus on the employees having a
great experience. And the leader I'm working with
is completely sincere. It actually want to have a
great workplace. But I think the misguidedness
was that he hadn't done a great job setting
expectations. He had not done a great job of quote
unquote "codifying their culture" because culture
is not just avocado toast and working together
and having socials, culture is things like,
we go the extra mile or culture is we make
sure, or it could be, we measure twice and cut
once. Those are kinds of things that are really
about the way we get work done around here. And
certainly, a focus on results is like, are we
following the process to then get the revenue
and to then build a profitable company or
are we just kind of hanging out together?
So he had to come to terms with his own discomfort
of addressing this with employees and his own
discomfort in being a corporate drone of,
"Oh, expectations and in the workplace and
how we do things." And it turned out that's the
whole thing with coaching and with working with
people is that you kind of see what their
underlying assumptions and beliefs are and
there's a reason everyone does what they do. So
there's a reason he's doing what he's doing. We
had to come to terms with that and then he had
to really courageously make some changes about
the way he was operating. And ultimately, they
had to part ways with one or two really toxic
people who were creating this gossipy culture and
making people feel not included and not focused
on results. And then when they all got on the same
page, they were able to gain a lot more traction.
I feel like a lot of leaders
and founders can relate to this,
of wanting to create a great culture and
keep it nice and friendly and everyone's
a family and then things don't quite work out
often in those cases. And there's a shift to,
"Okay, we actually need to
make a business that works."
Right.
It always reminds me, Sheryl Sandberg came to talk
at Airbnb once and people are asking, "What do you
do with all this...? We're just constantly in
chaos. Things are always reorging or changing,
just never... I'm on different teams every six
months. Our goals are shifting. What do you do
with all this... Our culture's changing as
we grow." And she's like, "That is a sign
of hyper growth and success. And the opposite
is even worse when you are not growing and you
don't want that. And so you should be happy
this is the challenge you're running into."
I love that. It's so true.
So along these lines, you talk about how
a lot of founders have to come to terms,
and it's not just founders, it's just execs and
leaders you work with, have to come to terms with,
"Here's what I thought leadership was
going to be and how to be a great leader,
and here's what it really is." Is there
anything more there that you find is commonly
what they're wrong about or what they
miss and what they have to realize?
Yeah. And I think as we grow as leaders, we
all have to realize our own blind spots and
the difference between what we thought and
what is actually going on. So I worked with
a founder who she wanted to be was a visionary
leader, which is fantastic. I would love that.
And she was an incredibly visionary person,
very inspirational. But what she didn't see
is that what her company needed was somebody to
structure and hold people accountable and help
them create goals and achieve milestones and
course correct when they got off course. And she'd
be very frustrated when all those things happened.
People got off course, people didn't have goals,
people weren't structured to work together. But
what she didn't realize was that was, in one way
or the other, her job to make that happen.
Now, maybe she needed to have, and I would
talk to her a lot about this, a partner, like
a COO or somebody else who could be the person
who would be sort of managing the internal while
she got to be more visionary, inspirational,
but ultimately, it was her job to make sure
that that was in place. And she didn't sort
of see that and she did not adjust her style.
And so there's a lot of wheel spinning that
happens from that. Even though, by the way,
she was an incredibly inspirational person
and incredibly inspirational leader and she
meant so well. There was nothing malicious
about it. It's just that she didn't see the
situation for what it was and then adjust.
It reminds me, we had this coach on
the podcast, Joe Hudson, and he had
this phrase that I think a lot of people use,
but it just stuck with me. What you resist,
persists. So if you hate confrontation, you're
going to have much more confrontation. If you
hate structure... Actually, this reminds me,
Joe Gebbia at Airbnb. He was very anti-process
at the beginning of Airbnb. He's like, "We're
not going to have a process. I hate process.
We're going to run... That's the big company
stuff." And then it just chaos constantly.
And then eventually it's like, "Okay, we need
to have some process to how we build things."
Yeah.
And so it's interesting. A lot of
people have to realize the thing
they think was bad is actually,
I see why people do it this way.
Yeah, totally. Actually, I'd like to say
something about that because so many...
Founders are kind of mavericks and they come
into a situation or they start at this company
and they want to do things their own way and
that's fantastic. Otherwise, they wouldn't be
a founder. That's actually fantastic. And so
many of the founders I've worked with want to
reinvent leadership. Right? They want to have it
with no process, they want to have no hierarchy,
they want to have autonomy, whatever it is.
And my feeling is like, "God bless. You
should absolutely try to do that." But
at the end of the day, what happens is,
they kind of invent for themselves the
understanding that they need to have process,
hierarchy, roles and responsibilities, goals,
OKRs, whatever it is. And I think it's helpful
sometimes to go through that fire of thinking
we can do it a different way. But ultimately,
I think that the ways to structure a group of
people and get them organized so that they can
win, are kind of well trod. And I would
say that it's helpful to get through
that stage quickly so that you don't have to
constantly reinvent the wheels of leadership.
Such an important context. Obviously, one of
the... The most successful founders come up with,
have first principles thinking into how to do
stuff, and oftentimes they find something no
one has ever thought about. So it's always
this balance of try a bunch of stuff,
a lot of it won't [inaudible 00:49:34]. Some
of it was, what will help you win. And I think
that's a really good point. I want to get into a
couple more tactical things that you often work on
with founders. One is, running meetings. Meetings
come up a lot on this podcast. People hate them,
people love them. There's some are great, some
are bad, most are bad. You have some cool advice
on just how to make meetings more effective and
how to especially end a meeting to help you move
forward. Talk about what your advice is there and
just generally any advice for better meetings.
Yeah. I'm one of the few people that loves
meetings. Or I should say I don't love meetings. I
love the potential for meetings. We have all this
smart people in the room. We have the potential to
talk about these great things and make decisions.
And unfortunately, they don't go that way. So what
happens often, I mean there's so many downfalls
with meetings, but one thing that happens is,
we keep meeting. Either we make decisions or
we don't make decisions, but then we come back
to meet again and we don't have any continuity
from the last. So then we re-meet, we re-decide,
and that is a big problem. So my three questions
to end the meeting are, what did we decide here?
Who needs to do what by when? And who else
needs to know? And if you can capture those,
articulate those as deliverables, I promise
you, you're going to have better meetings.
Okay, so it's, what did we decide
here? Who's going to do what by
when? So basically, action
items with dates. And then,
who needs to know about what we
decided here? Is that how you put it?
Yes. Who else needs to know? There's so many
executive teams that I've worked with and at
first, they go into their room, they have their
meeting, they make their decisions and then they
leave and they don't tell anyone. "I made this
promise for my team that you guys need to kind
of go do." Or, "We decided on a policy of some
sort and we forgot to tell everybody." And again,
no, absolutely no maliciousness, just
that they forget or they're too busy
and there's not part of the protocol and
the process inside of the company that
encourages and really insists that people share
important information, so cascading that down.
But even the first question, what did we
decide here? If you really go around the
room at the end of a meeting or six people in
the meeting, let's say, and you say to everybody,
"What did we decide here?" And they all write
it down, you will get six different answers,
even though we're in the same meeting.
I love that it's so powerful, but also,
so helpful to really raise that up, to surface
that and then to figure out what to do about it.
I love that you highlighted that. I was
going to say exactly the same thing,
that everyone in their head has the
thought of, "Here, oh yeah. Here's
what we decided." And to your point, it's
often not the same. So is the advice here,
is this like a template or something you fill
out at the end of a meeting or is it someone's
job to make sure these three things happen or
how do you operationalize these three questions?
I like it that it's someone's job, the person
that I sort of think of as the meetings are.
And typically, that's somebody who enjoys
follow-up, who enjoys putting lists together
and putting things into boxes and whatnot, and
there's usually someone like that on the team.
And so then it's kind of exciting for them to
be the follower upper. But one way or the other,
so you could use a template. I think that
actually baking it in as a ritual to the meeting,
because the other thing about meetings is that we
never have enough time. We go right to the end and
we don't leave the five or 10 minutes at the end
to make sure that we ask these three questions
and make sure that we have an understanding of
what the follow through is on these meetings.
What I'm imagining is, say it's the product
managers. Put this doc on the screen in the
meeting as the meeting's ending and
just have it filled out basically,
and just confirm, "Does
this look good to everyone?"
Love that. That's a great way to
do it. By the way, with... Well,
I just would say what's interesting about that
is that if we ask people what did we decide here,
I think there's value in just asking
that question in particular because
somebody might say, "We decided," I don't know,
"Something." And other people would say, "No,
we didn't. But that's actually a good idea. It
sort of crystallizes what we did talk about in
a more comprehensive way." I think there's value
in raising the differences and I think there's
value in stitching those together. So just
putting it up on the board is good, especially
if you're running short of time. I worry that
somebody might not weigh in and say, "Actually,
I have a very different point of view of what we
decided here." So maybe it's also about building
the culture to break in and say, "No, that's
not what I see. Let's spend some time on that."
Let's actually spend more time on this because
this is really, I think, really this specific
detail I think could be really powerful if you
do it right. So say you're the PM in the meeting,
who do you ask? Do you say to the room, "What
did we decide here?" Or do you look at the
most senior person? Otherwise, it feels like it
could just lead to a whole discussion the last
couple of minutes, which I guess could be
valuable, but who do you point this question to?
Yeah. So I picture this for let's say,
a six-person executive team meeting,
which means everyone go around quickly and say,
"What did we decide here?" Now, if you're in a
meeting with a large executive team, which I
do work with sometimes or non-executive team,
like a group of some sort, then you probably
want to get a few people just to... I would
just even say as a facilitator, two or
three people, "Okay, two or three people,
what do we decide here?" And if you can
kind of get common, great. That's fantastic.
Got it. Okay. So if it's a small meeting,
go around the room and everyone just shares,
here's what we decided here. And they could
just be like, "Yep, he's got it or she's
got it." Awesome. Okay. This is great. So the
advice here is, next time you have a meeting,
especially an exec meeting, just at the end of
the meeting, you, the listener of this podcast,
just ask, "Okay, everyone. Let's just make sure
we're on the same page. What did you decide here?
Who needs to do what by when?" And then everyone
chimes in and you're writing this in this doc,
and then what else? Who needs to
know about what we decided here?
Yeah. Lenny, I love that because also, do
you have to be the leader of the meeting to
do that? No. You could just be the person in
the meeting and just chime in and just start
it yourself. And if you do that and everyone
kind of picks it up, it can become a ritual
just by virtue of your own agency. So I love
that you just encouraged everyone to do that.
And this is how you become a leader, is you just
start doing these things and people are like,
"Oh, Alisa is so helpful. She's just
on top of it. Every time she's in a
meeting, the meetings go better. We
get things done." So I think just
doing the thing that is useful
to everyone is how you move up.
Exactly.
Amazing. Okay. Another topic that I know you
spend a lot of time on is something you call
the founder prenup. And what I love about this is,
a lot of the problems that a company trickle down
from the founders having their challenges with
each other. And I started a company in the past
and I don't think people realize how significant
this decision is in your life. It's basically,
you are marrying someone in a business context and
you're stuck with this person for a long time and
you basically came up with a prenup, which is
a set of questions of just things you need to
talk about to make sure you're aligned before you
start this company. Is there any context around
this thing before we talk through actually the
questions that you recommend people talk through?
Well, I just want to reiterate what you
just said. Exactly right. And it turns
out that according to Noam, Noam Wasserstein,
65% of startups fail because of conflict with
founders or the founding team. So it's really
essential to get this right, and I agree that
people step into this relationship with a lot less
care than they should. And bad things can happen
because you haven't done the work of getting to
know each other before you decide to co-found.
Yeah. It's so easy just to like, "Yeah, I'll
start a company. We have this cool idea. Let's
just do it. It's going to be so awesome."
And then you don't realize how much you're
committing to and how often things don't work out
because of that quick decision. And oftentimes,
it's like friends and then it becomes even
more challenging because I want to be friends,
but we're in business together.
So yeah. Let's talk about what
you recommend folks talk through
as much as we can on this podcast.
So I do have kind of an extensive questionnaire,
so we just touch on a few things, but one thing
I think first and foremost is, what are your
values? And I think it's really essential to
do some sort of values clarification exercise.
You can find a ton of them online. You can find
a list of values and just pull out your core
values and just compare them with each other
because when you are aligned, it's great.
Or when you're adjacent, it's also great.
I might care a lot about excellence, Lenny,
you might care a lot about learning. Fantastic.
Those are great values that we can kind of,
go together. I might care about excellence
and you might care about work-life balance. Wow,
let's talk about that because I think it's going
to be really important as we go through our
startup journey that we understand both of us,
what does work-life balance mean and
what does excellence mean? Because
those two things can at times be at odds
with each other, just as kind of an example.
So talking through those core values in advance
and updating them regularly, even as you go
down the path together is so essential. Just so
you know where the other person's coming from.
Because the other problem is, someone acts in a
certain way, you don't know them that well maybe,
or maybe you've known them as an eighth grader.
A lot of founders do know each other from their
youth and they've matured into different kinds of
people. And so you think they're acting strangely,
but actually, they're acting in accordance
with their values. And so getting a handle
on that upfront can solve, I would just say,
solve a lot of problems before they start.
So signs that your values don't align. It's
basically you both can't be true is almost the way
I think about it as we talk. It's hard to be the
excellent, focus on excellence and also not work
long hours, which it's possible, but it's hard.
Those are challenging and worth the conversation.
Yeah, worth the conversation because in
fact, as you say that, I'm like, "Well,
I guess you can do that. Right. You can do that."
And so therefore, that's where the conversation
has to figure out how you're going to marry
these two values, which might be at odds or
might be aligned, but let's talk through what
work-life balance means to you and let's talk
through what excellence means to me, and let's
see if we can have a meeting of the minds about
it or at least I know where you stand.
One of the founders I worked with,
he would text or Slack his co-founder on weekends
and the co-founder wouldn't respond. And that
was extremely frustrating to the person, to the
co-founder I was talking to. And it turned out,
after they finally addressed it, it really was
about wanting to have some downtime and some,
quote unquote, "Balance." Nothing wrong with
that, but because they didn't talk about it,
both sides made [inaudible 01:00:20] big
assumption about it and then it caused
this conflict that didn't have to happen
if they'd had the conversation in advance.
Comes back to where we started of having
these conversations is necessary and almost
helps the other person because this small
issue could become a huge issue over time,
if you just start assuming and it keeps happening
and it keeps scratching and scratching at you.
And letting that person's [inaudible
01:00:45] is screwed up because you're,
"I can't do this with you anymore."
Right? So it's just another reminder
of how it's good for the other person for
you to engage in a difficult conversation.
Yes, very true.
Okay, what else? So values. By the way,
is there a values framework you most love
that you can point people to or there just
a bunch and don't worry too much about
which one you go [inaudible 01:01:05]?
I mean, the one I use is super simple, which
is on the thing called the internet. There's
a lot of lists of values and I think when
you see a list of values, you can pull out
the ones that are most meaningful to you, and
that's a very simple and helpful and free tool.
Got it. So you just Google list of values,
there's a PDF, and just circle the ones that
are most and pick whatever small number,
don't... Half of [inaudible 01:01:27]-
Actually, well, just to give you the
process, right? It's helpful to pick 20,
for example. Great. And then you
winnow them down to, let's say,
10. And then you do the difficult work
of winnowing them down to three to five
that you feel are core to you. And that's a
good exercise for everyone to do actually,
every year because things can change. It also
forces you to make the difficult decisions about
when it comes down to it, what are the things
that really are important to me? The more you
know your values, the more you can operate in
the world with just more clarity for yourself.
Awesome. All right. So values. What else?
Yeah. So another one is, vision of the
company. So when this company is successful,
what does that look like? And what that
might look like is, we're in control of our
destiny and we are able to operate this business
independently and we have a lot of freedom. What
that might look like is a big venture outcome
that we all read about. And if you are both
assuming that you both think the same thing
but aren't talking about it explicitly or
talking about the trade-offs you need to make
inherent in that, then what often happens if you
have differences is they come home to roost
while it's too late or when it's too late.
So an example is the two co-founders I worked
with, one of them would said to me wistfully, this
is like five or six years into the company, and
the company was going well, but it was challenging
and they had all their growing pains and like
you mentioned about Sheryl said all the chaos.
And he said to me, "Gosh, I don't see why we have
to grow. I just wish we could actually have fewer
employees. And I used to love it when I knew
everybody's name and I would just much prefer
an environment where we didn't have to grow."
Well, unfortunately, they were already venture
backed and also, the other co-founder had a very
lofty ambition for a very big company. And since
they hadn't talked about that, it was way too
late to even have that conversation and it was a
very painful reckoning for both of them
to realize they were not on the same page.
Totally, see the value of this one. I could
totally see how people would have different
goals. I imagine it also changes over
time, so there's probably an element of,
if something has shifted for you, you should
probably also have that conversation. I don't
want to build an IPO venture scale business, I
just want to build something chill. So basically,
a line on what is... How would you phrase
that? What does winning look like to you?
Yeah, what does success look like?
What does success look like to you?
Or what's the vision for the company
when it reaches its full potential?
Okay. Great. What else?
Another one is, it's sort of a two part
question. How do you handle conflict? So
how do you handle conflict? But then, you might
want to ask your spouse, someone close to you,
"How do I handle conflict?" Because you might
think, "Oh, I handle conflict with such an
enlightened person. I'm so neutral about it.
I'm so great at bringing things up." But the
person who's close to you might say, "You seethe
until you're ready to bring something up and it's
really uncomfortable in the seething period." So
it just gives you a little more self-awareness
about how you actually handle conflict.
And that's really important because I
might be the kind of person who wants to bring up
conflict and talk about it immediately. The other
person might be a person who totally wants to
talk about the conflict but wants to let it settle
first and wants to also go through their own
thinking process about what's important to
them and might actually feel like they've
resolved it themselves without having to
have a conversation with you. And if you're
the person who's like, "Let's talk about it,
let's talk about it, let's talk about it." And
they're like, "I'm working through it myself."
Now you have conflict over the conflict and it
just turns into dynamic that's not necessary.
As you go through these questions, it's absurd
to imagine people don't do this when they find
a co-founder and work through stuff, and I know
nobody does. The percentage of people that do this
sort of work ahead of time, it's very low. And so
I love that we're helping this percentage go up,
but it also reminds me of just how crazy it
is people don't have these conversations and
how it explains why so many founder relationships
don't work out. So these are awesome. What else?
I know you have a whole list and we'll link
to it, right? There's a PDF we can link to?
Yes.
With the questions or-
For sure.
[inaudible 01:05:55] post.
Awesome. Let's do a few more.
Another one is, how do we decide when we
disagree? And that is a very good thing
to explore because there's actually a lot of
different ways to decide when you disagree
and they're all good. And if you have it sort of
upfront and it's just for an ongoing discussion,
but if you have it up front like when we disagree,
because that's definitely going to happen,
let's assume that the person who cares the most
can win that argument. That would be a great
way to do it. It might be, the person who's got
the best perspective and the most expertise can
win that argument. It might be, we'll go back
and forth when we really disagree. First you
win and then I win, like that, back and forth.
There's so many different ways to handle it and
if you talk about it upfront, you'll be much
more likely to be able to actually put that
into practice when you do disagree because you
will definitely disagree. There's no way around
that. And that's not even a bad thing. You're
smart people. You have this dynamic tension in
the relationship. You bring different things to
the table. You've got different perspectives.
Disagreeing is normal. Working through it and
having a practice and a process of working through
it, will help it be a good conversation rather
than this sort of sulky difficult conversation.
I love it. Maybe one more?
Yeah. So another one is, what kind of
company culture do I think is important?
People definitely don't talk about this before
they found the company and they assume they're
on the same page. So one founder might be, "I
want to have this great company where everyone
loves it and we're all loving together
and working hard together. And it feels
like a..." To use your word before,
"It feels like a family." By the way,
that's great. That's fantastic. "I want to have a
get it done, results-focused culture where we're
just executing the hell out of everything
and that we're just focused on winning."
By the way, those two can actually exist together.
But if you're pushing in one direction without the
other and your co-founder is pushing the other
direction without yours, it really can feel like
two different companies. And that's... When I
go into a situation at one of my client sites,
often I will hear from the employees, "It
feels like we have two different companies and
two different cultures depending on whose team
you're on." And that, of course, leads to lack
of coherent working together and certainly even
just lack of different standards and expectations.
Awesome. Okay. To kind of start to wrap
our conversation, I want to take us to a
recurring segment of this podcast that I call,
Fail Corner. We've talked a lot about failure
at this point and just all the ways people
fail. I'm curious if, in your career or life,
there's a story that might be helpful
for folks to hear when things didn't
go great and you've failed, and if you learn
something from that experience. And the reason
this is something I do is I feel like people
listening to this podcast, everyone's like,
"Sounds so amazing, everything's always going
great. They're killing it." When in reality,
that's not actually how things go. So these
end up being really helpful for people like,
"Oh, wow. Even Alisa had a really hard time
sometime." Is there a story that you could share?
Absolutely. I mean, so many examples. I'm
going to give two quick examples. One is,
when I first started my coaching practice,
I just kind of started and so I just did
everything I could to get clients, to
build a business, to build a practice,
to build my brand, all the things. And I
was working so hard and I think I'd had
this conversation with somebody that didn't go
very well. And I just thought, in my mind's eye,
I thought, "Well, what will become of me?" That
was my voice in my head for quite a long time,
"What will become of me?" And I was living
in Boston at the time. I got onto the floor,
my hardwood floors in my Brookline condo,
and I just balled in the fetal position.
I just balled and balled and balled for an
hour. It wasn't 10 minutes, it was an hour.
And I was so frightened and just upset. Am
I going to be able to make this work? And
it was a while and I got into the couch and
took a little stress nap. And then I got up
from my stress nap and I just started making
more calls and doing more things. And that was
definitely a rock bottom moment for me. And I
think what I learned is, you have to literally
pick yourself up from the ground and pull yourself
forward. And when you keep taking action, action,
action, win or lose, win or lose, you'll
get where you need to go. And that turned
out to be true. But in those moments, I was not
thinking that was going to turn out to be true.
Wow. Amazing story. I imagine
many people feel those moments
and it's empowering to hear that
it can all turn out really well,
even when you're lying in the floor crying for an
hour. An hour is a long time to cry on the floor.
It is a long time to cry. It really...
I thought about it because most people
just cry for 10 or 15 minutes. I was
crying for an hour. I'm positive. Yeah.
Great story. You said you had another story.
Yeah. I'll tell you a second story, which
is more focused on actually my work life.
So one thing that I do is I do coaching of
course and I do off sites. And this was early,
early days of my coaching career and I was
doing this off site and it wasn't going well.
And I was debriefing with my client during the
breaks and at one point she said something like,
"I just think we should end this offsite. I just
think we should just decide it's over and it's
not working." And I felt horrible, obviously,
humiliated, certainly, and just like that's a
failure. That's like, "Oh, fail." And I know that
what I took away from it was that I can improve
my skills in every aspect of running an offsite.
So getting aligned with the client in advance,
making sure that I had the right activities
getting us to our goal, being very goal-oriented
and focused, and making sure that I had kind of
understood the rhythm of what it takes to bring
people together. So I took some training on that.
I worked my mentor on that, and I got so great at
offsites after that experience. I'll tell you
that was a real low because in the moment, in
that moment, I'm not thinking, "I'm going to get
great at offsites." In that moment I'm thinking,
"Oh, my God. I'm going to get... What will become
of me?" But I turned it into, in my mind's eye,
or I should say, I turned it into the ability
to build my skills. And I just want to tell
everybody, even at your lowest moments, anything
that you're learning from that, can then be
turned into fuel to build your skills to get
great at the thing that you're not great at.
What I also love about this is there's this
feeling of imposter syndrome, is specifically
this fear that I do something wrong and it'll
all crumble and everyone will see I suck and I
never... I don't know anything and everyone will
see it. And I love both these stories are like,
it doesn't go well and doesn't crumble.
You build from there. And no one's like,
"Oh, Alisa's terrible forever." No, it's
like move on to the next thing. And then
you use that as fuel to become really
good at this thing that didn't go great.
Yeah, that's really well said.
Amazing. Alisa, we covered a lot of stuff. Is
there anything that you were hoping to cover or
you think might be useful for folks to hear before
we move to our very exciting lightning round?
The only last thing I want to talk about, just
sort of circling back to your role as a leader, I
was one time working with the CEO who was handling
the fact that this launch was not going well,
as in the launch wasn't happening. [inaudible
01:13:25] foot off, foot off, foot off. And his
point of view was, you need to have patience
with it as it goes. And my point of view is,
because I've talked to a lot of the people
around, was that there was a massive process
problem going on that he was not kind of touching
into and really investigating because the product
manager wasn't experienced, was kind of hiding
it because he knew he didn't have the skills, was
fighting with engineering, it just wasn't working.
And when the CEO was telling me, and we really had
a long discussion about this where I kind of
enlightened him about some of the issues that he
needed to get involved and fix, he kept thinking,
"I need to have patience." So what I want to say
to everybody is, sometimes you need to have
patience and sometimes you need to look at the
process. And I think you, as the leader, need to
have the wisdom to know the difference, but also
your finger on the pulse to recognize, is this
an issue with patience or an issue with process?
I guess, is there a sign that
you're like, it's probably a
process thing and you're just ignoring a
glaring problem that everyone else sees?
I think the sign is when, if you search your
mind, you don't really know how this thing
is going to come together. There's no plan in
your mind. You haven't touched in with people
or talked to people about what's going
on. You kind of hear this uncomfortable
silence about it. Those are symptoms that
you just need to dive deeper and just be a
little more in touch with what's going on and
talk to some folks and look at some data. And
by the way, it might not be a massive process
problem. It might just be one little thing that
needs to get unstuck but you, as the leader, need
to recognize that and figure out a way to make
that unstuck. And if there's, of course, a big
problem that needs to somehow be just surfaced.
So if there's this hope this'll work out
versus I see a path to this working out,
it's probably a problem. Awesome.
Yeah, well said.
Is there anything else that you wanted to share
or touch on that you think might be helpful?
We talked a little about the co-founders
prenup, which I think people would think,
"Well, I'm not a co-founder, I don't need that." I
just want to invite everyone to also think about a
different tool that I have, which is called the
Personal Operating Manual. And it helps prompt
you to talk about working style together because
you may not be co-founders, of course, but you're
working on a team with a bunch of people and
they all have their different working style.
So it's kinds of questions like, what
communication style do you like the best?
How do you like to work? Do you like large
uninterrupted blocks? Do you like meetings
here and there? When I'm trying to get
a hold of you for something important,
what's the best way to do that? What is one
of your pet peeves or some of your pet peeves?
How can I get a gold star with you? Also, this
is my favorite. What's your delegation style?
Do you want me to check in with you regularly,
like once a week as I'm working down the path
of a project? Or do you want me to just
let you know when it's done and just tell
you at the end that it's been complete?
So lots of different ways people assume
other people work because it's like your style,
but actually it's just your style. So those kinds
of conversations can be great for working
together and also be a great team activity.
So this kind of what goes into these
READMEs people put together, here's how to-
Yes.
... work with me. I really love the gold
star concept because I feel like people
want to know how do I be super awesome?
How do I be really successful working for
you? And I like that visual of the gold
star and the pet peeves. I feel like a
lot of people will identify that. What
are my pet peeves so that people don't
do these things because they don't know,
right? They don't know until you tell them.
Nobody knows what's your operating style until
you tell them. And the more you can showcase,
the more everybody will be able to do it right for
you and you'll be able to do it right for them.
And then you'll be able to have better workplace
harmony and save your conflict with things that
are really important. Not just because like, "Oh,
you didn't text me when I wanted you to text me."
Being clear. What do you know? Is there
anything else that you think might be
helpful to share before we get to
a very exciting lightning round?
No, just that.
Well, with that, Alisa, we reached our very
exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
I can't wait. I'm ready.
Here we go. First question, are
there two or three books that you
find yourself most recommending to other people?
So we already talked about Kim Scott, the
wonderful, amazing Kim Scott and her book,
Radical Candor, is one I recommend a lot to
people. It's fantastic. Working Backwards by gosh,
Colin Bryar and Bill something, is about sort
of the Amazon way of working backwards from
the customer. Super geeky and tactical. I
love it. I slurp it up like Harry Potter.
It's so good. And I definitely recommend to my
clients about Amazon's Management Science. And
the third is Walt Disney by Neil Gabler
because it really shows how Walt Disney,
sort of it's everything about his youth and
how he turned into a very bad entrepreneur
and ultimately into a fantastic inventive
entrepreneur. And it shows all the origins
of how he invented these different pieces
that now make up the Walt Disney Company.
The first two recommendations we've had on the
podcast, Kim Scott and Bill Carr, is the other-
Bill Carr.
... co-author. He's been on
the podcast and people love
that episode. I haven't had Walt
Disney on. I got to work on that.
Or the writer, Neil Gabler
Or the writer. Yeah, yeah. Good tip. Okay,
next question. Is there a favorite
recent movie or TV show you really enjoy?
Yeah, I enjoyed Inside Out 2. I thought it
was fantastic, the idea [inaudible 01:18:49].
I could see why you love it. I feel
like it's for all coaches in the world.
Totally. Just the idea that like, oh yeah, we're
all this complex stew of emotions and it's okay.
Mm-hmm. I also love that movie.
Next question. Do you have a
favorite product you recently
discovered that you really love?
Yes, the Ninja Creami. So good.
Say more.
The Ninja Creami turns anything into ice cream.
So you can actually make ice cream. Good,
God bless. But I take my protein shake,
which is okay, and turn it into ice cream,
which is delicious. And it takes 10 minutes
and very little prep, and it's simple to
use and it works as expected, which so many
things do not. The Ninja Creami, go get it.
That's the first for the Ninja Creami. And
I love, the holidays are coming around,
so this is going to be good for
people. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often come back
to you find useful in work or in life?
This quote by Joseph Campbell
animates my life, which is,
"If you can see your path all the way through
to the end, you are following someone else's
path. Your path only becomes clear moment
by moment as each foot hits the ground."
Wow, that's so good. It's so empowering
because it helps you realize if you don't
see where it's all going, that's normal and
that's good. Wow. Great one, good one. I need
to do something with all these mottos. They're
so good. I need to create a poster or something.
That's a great idea. Or your newsletter.
Here we go.
Send them out.
Yeah, that's the easy path. Okay. Last question.
So I'm curious, and not to create more competition
for you, but I feel like a lot of people think
about becoming a coach of some kind, like a
product coach, exec coach. If someone is thinking
about going down that path, is there one piece
of advice you could share to help them pursue
this path, even explore if it's right for them?
If you think you want to become a coach
and you immediately want to build up
your coaching skills, listen to people
more deeply and ask deeper questions,
not just respond to what they just said, but why
do you think that? Or where is that coming from?
And you will see if you enjoy that process of
really going deeper with people. I think that
would be helpful for everyone to do. But
certainly if you want to become a coach,
I think that's essential to be able
to get really beneath the surface.
I love how your energy just changed into
coaching mode when you said that. I love
that. That was such an interesting thing to see
and that was great advice. That's easier said
than done. And it's interesting, you could tell
people are so good at that specific skill versus
not. And so I love that that's the thing to work
on, is ask better questions, think deeper about
the person and what they're coming from. Alisa,
this was incredible. Two final questions. Where
can folks find you if they want to reach out,
maybe work with you, what kind of people do you
work with in case people are interested in that,
and finally, how can listeners be useful to you?
Oh, thank you. Well, I work with executives at
startups and also at large public companies,
so feel free to reach out if you want to have a
conversation about coaching. And you can find me
at alisacohn.com. And actually, I'm going to take
some resources and put them at a special link,
which is alisacohn.com/lenny. If you want
to download the Co-Founder Prenup. I also
have a Personal Operating Manual and a few other
resources I will put there. So alisacohn.com/lenny
and you can also join my newsletter from there.
And I think in terms of helping me, I guess
there's two things I want to say. My life's work
genuinely is to make a difference. When I became
a coach, it was because the music in my head was
to make a difference. And so I hope I've made a
difference for all of you today and I would invite
you to try one thing that makes you uncomfortable,
this week. As soon as you hear this,
this week, try something that makes you
uncomfortable and feel free to let me know on
LinkedIn or even send me an email and let me
know what you did that made you uncomfortable.
So that would be very meaningful to me. And the
second thing that would be very meaningful to
me is if you would go find my podcast called,
From Start-Up to Grown-Up and give it a listen.
Maybe give it a rating and review because as you
know, Lenny, the way people find your podcast is
when other people are interested in your podcast.
From Start-Up to Grown-Up. I love that title.
Thank you.
Alisa, thank you so much for
being here. This was awesome.
Thank you so much for having
me, Lenny. It was great.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.