The AI models that you're using today is the
worst AI model you will ever use for the rest
of your life, and when you actually get that
in your head, it's kind of wild. Everywhere
I've ever worked before this, you kind of
know what technology you're building on,
but that's not true at all with AI. Every two
months, computers can do something they've never
been able to do before and you need to completely
think differently about what you're doing.
You're chief product officer of maybe the
most important company in the world right
now. I want to chat about what it's just
like to be inside the center of the storm.
Our general mindset is in two months,
there's going to be a better model and
it's going to blow away whatever the current
set of limitations are. And we say this to
developers too. If you're building and
the product that you're building is kind
of right on the edge of the capabilities
of the models, keep going because you're
doing something right. Give it another couple
months and the models are going to be great,
and suddenly the product that you have that
just barely worked is really going to sing.
Famously, you led this project
at Facebook called Libra.
Libra is probably the biggest disappointment of my
career. It fundamentally disappoints me that this
doesn't exist in the world today because the world
would be a better place if we'd been able to ship
that product. We tried to launch a new blockchain.
It was a basket of currencies originally. It was
integration into WhatsApp and Messenger. I would
be able to send you 50 cents in WhatsApp for free.
It should exist. To be honest, the current
administration is super friendly to crypto.
Facebook's reputation is in a very different
place. Maybe they should go build it now.
Today my guest is Kevin Weil. Kevin
is chief product officer at OpenAI,
which is maybe the most important and most
impactful company in the world right now,
being at the forefront of AI and AGI and maybe
someday super intelligence. He was previously
head of product at Instagram and Twitter. He
was co-creator of the Libra Cryptocurrency
at Facebook, which we chat about. He's also
on the boards of Planet and Strava and the
Black Product Managers Network and the Nature
Conservancy. He's also just a really good guy
and he has so much wisdom to share. We chat
about how OpenAI operates, implications of AI
and how we will all work and build product,
which markets within the AI ecosystem,
companies like OpenAI won't likely go after and
thus are good places for startups to own. Also,
why learning the craft of writing evals is quickly
becoming a core skill for product builders, what
skills will matter most in an AI era and what he's
teaching his kids to focus on and so much more.
This is a very special episode and I am so excited
to bring it to you. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in your
favorite podcasting app or YouTube. If you become
an annual subscriber of my newsletter, you
get a year free of Perplexity Pro, Linear,
Notion Superhuman and Granola. Check it out at
lennysnewsletter.com and click bundle. With that,
I bring you Kevin Weil. This episode is brought
to you by Eppo. Eppo is a next-generation A/B
testing and feature management platform built
by alums of Airbnb and Snowflake for modern
growth teams. Companies like Twitch, Miro,
ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo to power
their experiments. Experimentation is increasingly
essential for driving growth and for understanding
the performance of new features and Eppo
helps you increase experimentation velocity
while unlocking rigorous deep analysis in
a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform where
I could set up experiments easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my own.
Eppo does all that and more with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time and accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance and out-of-the-box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying prolonged
analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for
you to share experiment insight with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use
case, including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Persona, the
adaptable identity platform that helps businesses
fight fraud, meet compliance requirements,
and build trust. While you're listening to
this right now, how do you know that you're
really listening to me, Lenny? These days, it's
easier than ever for fraudsters to steal PII,
faces and identities. That's where Persona comes
in. Persona helps leading companies like LinkedIn,
Etsy, and Twilio securely verify individuals and
businesses across the world. What sets Persona
apart is its configurability. Every company
has different needs depending on its industry,
use cases, risk tolerance and user demographics.
That's why Persona offers flexible building blocks
that allow you to build tailored collection and
verification flows that maximize conversion while
minimizing risks. Plus Persona's orchestration
tools automate your identity process so that you
can fight rapidly shifting fraud and meet new
waves of regulation. Whether you're a startup
or an enterprise business, Persona has a plan for
you. Learn more at withpersona.com/lenny. Again,
that's withpersona.com/lenny. Kevin, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much for having
me. We've been talking about
doing this forever and we made it happen.
We did it. I can't imagine how insane your life
is, so I really appreciate that you made time
for this and we're actually recording this the
week that you guys launched your new image model,
which is a happy coincidence.
My entire social feed is filled
with ghiblifications of everyone's life and
family photos and everything, so good job.
Yep, mine too. My wife, Elizabeth, sent me
one of hers, so I'm right there with you.
Let me just ask, did you guys expect this kind
of reaction? It feels like this is the most viral
thing that's happened in AI, which a high bar
since, I don't know, ChatGPT launched. Just like,
did you guys expect it to go this well?
What does it feel like internally?
There have been a handful of times in my career
when you're working on a product internally and
the internal usage just explodes. This was
true by the way when we were building stories
at Instagram. More than anything else in my
career, we could feel it was going to work
because we were all using it internally and we'd
go away for a weekend. Before it launched we were
all using it and we'd come back after a weekend
and we would know what was going on and be like,
"Oh, hey, I saw you were at that camping
trip, how was that?" You were like, "Man,
this thing really works." ImageGen was definitely
one of those, so we'd been playing with it for,
I don't know, a couple months and when it
first went live internally to the company,
there was kind of a little gallery
where you could generate your own,
you could also see what everyone else was
generating and it was just nonstop buzz.
So yeah, we had a sense that this was going
to be a lot of fun for people to play with.
That's really cool. That should be
a measure of just confidence into
something going well that you're launching
is internally everyone's going crazy for it.
Yeah. Especially social things because you have
a very tight network as a company socially,
so you know each other and you're experts in
your product hopefully. And so there's some
sense in which if you're doing something
social and it's not taking off internally,
you might question what you're doing.
Yeah, and by the way, the Ghibli
thing, is that something you guys
seeded or how did that even start?
Was that an intentional example?
I think it's just the style people love and
the model is really capable at emulating
style or understanding what... It's very
good at instruction following. That's
actually something that I think people...
I'm starting to see people discover with it,
but you can do very complex things. You can give
it two images, one is your living room and the
other is a whole bunch of photos or memorabilia
or things you want and you say, "Tell me how
you would arrange these things." Or you can say,
"I'd like you to show me what this will look like
if you put this over here and this thing to the
right of that and this one to the left of this,
but under that one." And the model actually will
understand all of that and do it. It's incredibly
powerful. So I'm just excited about all the
different things people are going to figure out.
Yeah. All right. Well, good job. Good job
team OpenAI. Let's get serious here and let's
zoom out a little bit. The way I see it is you're
chief product officer of maybe the most important
company in the world right now. Just not to set
the bar too high, but you guys are ushering in AI,
AGI at some point, super intelligence at some
point. No big deal. I have more questions for
you than I've had for any other guest. Actually
put out a call-out on Twitter and LinkedIn and
my community just like what would you want to ask
Kevin? And I had over 300 well-formed questions
and we're going to go through every single one.
So let's just get started. I'm just joking.
Cool.
I picked out the best and there's a
lot of stuff I'm really curious about.
Well, it's 1 PM here. It doesn't get
dark for a while, so let's do it.
Okay, here we go. Okay, so first of all,
I'm just going to take notes here. When
is AGI launching? When in December?
I mean, we just launched a good
ImageGen model. Does that count?
It's getting there. It's getting there.
There's this quote I love, which is "AI is
whatever hasn't been done yet" because once it's
been done, when it kind of works, then you call it
machine learning, and once it's kind of ubiquitous
and it's everywhere, then it's just an algorithm.
So I've always loved that we call things AI when
they still don't quite work and then by the time
it's like an AI algorithm that's recommending you
follow, oh, that's just an algorithm, but this
new thing, like self-driving cars, that's it. I
think to some degree we're always going to be
there and the next thing is always going to be
AI and the current thing that we use every day and
is just a part of our lives, that's an algorithm.
It's so interesting because in the Bay Area you
see self-driving cars driving around and it's so
normal now when four years ago and three years
ago, you would've seen this and you'd be like,
"Holy shit, what is... We're in the future."
And now we're just so take it for granted.
I mean there's something like that
with everything. If I showed you...
When GPT-3 launched, I wasn't at
OpenAI then. I was just a user,
but it was mind-blowing. And if I gave you
GPT-3 now I just plugged that into ChatGPT
for you and you started using it, you'd be
like, "What is this thing?" It's like mess.
Flop, flop.
I had the same experience when I first got into
a Waymo, your very first ride, at least my very
first ride, my first 10 seconds in a Waymo,
it starts driving and you're like, "Oh my God,
watch out for that bike." You're holding onto
whatever you can. And then five minutes in,
you've calmed down and you realize that you're
getting driven around the city without a driver
and it's working. You're just like, "Oh my God,
I am living in the future right now." And then
another 10 minutes, you're bored, you're doing
email on your phone, answering Slack messages,
and suddenly this miracle of human invention
is just an expected part of your life from
then on. And there is really something in the
way that we all are adapting to AI that's kind
of like that. These miraculous things happen
and computers can do something they've never
been able to do before and it blows our mind
collectively for a week and then we're like,
oh, yeah. Oh, now it's just machine
learning on its way to being an algorithm.
The craziest thing about what you just
shared actually is, I don't know, ChatGPT,
which is now feels terrible. 3.5 was a couple
years ago, and imagine what life will be like
in a couple years from now. We're going to get
to that, where things are going, what you think
is going to be the next big leap. But I want
to start with the beginning of your journey
at OpenAI. So you worked at Twitter, you worked
at Facebook, you worked at Planet, Instagram.
At some point you got recruited to go and come
work at OpenAI. I'm curious just what that story
was like of the recruiting process of joining
OpenAI as CPO. Is there any fun stories there?
If I'm remembering the timeline right,
we communicated at Planet I was leaving
and I was planning to just go take some
time. I wasn't going to stop working,
but I was also happy to take the summer. This was
maybe April or something. I was like, cool, I'm
going to have the summer with my kids. We're going
to go to Tahoe or something and I'll actually get
to hang out rather than what I usually do going
up and down and all that. And then Sam and I had
known each other lightly for a bunch of years and
he's always involved in so many interesting things
like companies building fusion and all these
things. So he'd always been somebody that I
would call occasionally if I was starting to think
about my next thing because I like working on big
tech forward, sort of next wave kind of things.
And so I called him and I think Vinod also
helped to put us in touch again. And this time it
wasn't like, "Oh, you should go talk to these guys
working on fusion." He said, "Actually, we're
thinking about something, you should come talk
to us." I was like, "Okay, that sounds amazing.
Let's do it." And it goes really fast, really,
really fast. I met most of the management
team in a brief period of time, a few days,
and they were telling me, 'Look, we're basically
going to move as fast as we want to move. And
if you talk to everyone, everyone likes you,
you're ready to go." Sam came over for dinner
and we had a great evening together just talking
about OpenAI in the future and getting to know
each other better. And at the end I was like,
I was going to go in the next day for a bigger
round of interviews and Sam was saying, "Hey,
it's going really well. We're really excited."
And I said, "Cool. So how do I think about
tomorrow?" And he said, "Oh, you'll be fine.
Don't worry about it. And if it goes well, we're
basically there." And so I go in the next day,
meet a bunch of people, have a great time. I
really enjoyed everybody I met with. In any
interview, you can always second guess yourself
like, oh, I shouldn't have said that thing or
that thing I gave a bad answer on I wish I could
redo, but I came away feeling like I think that
went pretty well. And I was expecting to hear
that weekend basically because they sort of set
expectations as soon as if this goes well, we're
ready to go. And I didn't hear anything. And then
it was like Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, I still
didn't hear anything and I reached out to folks on
the OpenAI side a couple of times, still nothing.
And I was like, "Oh my God, I screwed it up. I
don't know where I screwed it up, but I totally
screwed it up. I can't believe it." And I was
going back to Elizabeth, my wife and being like,
"What did I do? Where do you think I..." Getting
all crazy about it and then it's still nothing.
And finally it was like nine days later, they
finally got back to me and it turned out there was
a bunch of stuff happening internally and this,
that and the other thing, and there's just
a million things happening. And they finally
were like, "Oh yeah, that went well. Let's
do this." And I was like, "Oh, okay, cool,
let's do it." But it was nine days of agony and
they were just super busy on some internal stuff
and there I was fretting every single day and
re-going over every line of our interview process.
It makes me think about when you're
dating someone and you've texted
them and you're not hearing anything
back, you assume something is wrong.
Yeah, totally.
They might just be busy.
I have a hard time about it still.
That's wild. I love that it worked out. And I
guess the lesson there is
don't jump to conclusions.
Yeah. Have a little bit of chill.
Speaking of that, I want to chat about what
it's just like to be inside the center of
the storm. Again, you work at a lot of, let's
say traditional companies even though they're
not that traditional, Twitter and Instagram and
Facebook and Planet, and now you work at OpenAI.
I'm curious, what is most different about how
things work in your day-to-day life at OpenAI?
I think it's probably the pace. Maybe it's two
things. One is it's the pace. The second is
everywhere I've ever worked before this, you
kind of know what technology you're building
on. So you spend your time thinking about what
problems are you solving? Who are you building
for? How are you going to make their lives
better? How are you going to... Is this a big
enough problem that you're going to be able
to change habits? Do people care about this
problem being solved? All those good product
things. But the stuff that you're building on
is kind of fixed. You're talking about databases
and things and I bet the database you used this
year is probably 5% better than the database
you used two years ago, but that's not true
at all with AI. It's like every two months
computers can do something they've never been
able to do before and you need to completely
think differently about what you're doing.
There's something fundamentally interesting
about that makes life fun here. There's
also something we will maybe talk about evals
later, but it also really, in this world of...
Everything we're used to with computers is about
giving a computer very defined inputs. If you look
at Instagram for example, there are buttons that
do specific things and you know what they do. And
then when you give a computer defined inputs, you
get very defined outputs. You're confident that if
you do the same thing three times, you're
going to get the same output three times.
LLMs are completely different than that. They're
good at fuzzy subtle inputs. Then all the
nuances of human language and communication,
they're pretty good at. And also they don't
really give you the same answer. You probably get
spiritually the same answer for the same question,
but it's certainly not the same set of words every
time. And so you're much more, it's fuzzier inputs
and fuzzier outputs. And when you're building
products, it really matters whether there's some
use case that you're trying to build around.
If the model gets it right 60% of the time,
you build a very different product than if the
model gets it right 95% of the time versus if
the model gets it right 99.5% of the time. And
so there's also something that you have to get
really into the weeds on your use case and
the evals and things like that in order to
understand the right kind of product to build.
So that is just fundamentally different. If
your database works once, it works every
time. And that's not true in this world.
Let's actually follow this thread on evals. I
definitely wanted to talk about this. We had this
legendary panel at the Lenny & Friends Summit. It
was you and Mike Krieger and Sarah Guo moderating.
That was fun.
So fun. The thing that I heard that kind of stuck
with people from that panel was a comment you made
where you said that writing evals is going
to become a core skill for product managers,
and I feel like that probably applies
further than just product managers. A
lot of people know what evals are. A lot
of people have no idea what I'm talking
about. So could you just briefly explain
what is an eval and then just why do you
think this is going to be so important for
people building products in the future?
Yeah, sure. I think the easiest way to think
about it is almost like a quiz for a model,
a test to gauge how well it knows a certain
set of subject material or how good it is
at responding to a certain set of questions.
So in the same way you take a calculus class
and then you have calculus tests that see if
you've learned what you're supposed to learn.
You have evals that test how good is the model
at creative writing? How good is the model at
graduate level science? How good is the
model at competitive coding? And so you
have these set of evals that basically perform as
benchmarks for how smart or capable the model is.
Is it a simple way to think about
it, like unit tests for model?
Yeah, unit tests, tests in
general for models. Totally.
Great, great. Okay. And then why is this
so important for people that don't totally
understand what the hell's going on here with
evals? Why is this so key to building AI products?
Well, it gets back to what I was saying. You
need to know whether your model is going to...
There are certain things that models will get
right. 99.95% of the time and you can just be
confident. There are things that they're going
to be 95% right on and things they're going to
be 60% right on. If the model's 60% right
on something, you're going to need to build
your product totally differently. And by the way,
these things aren't static either. So a big part
of evals is if you know you're building for some
use case. So let's take our deep research product,
which is one of my favorite things that we've
released maybe ever. The idea is with deep
research for people who haven't used it, you
can give ChatGPT now an arbitrarily complex
query. It's not about returning you an answer
from a search query, which we can also do.
It's here's a thing that if you were going to
answer it yourself, you'd go off and do two hours
of reading on the web and then you might need to
read some papers and then you would come back and
start writing up your thoughts and realize you had
some gaps in your thinking. So you go out and do
more research. It might take you a week to write
some 20 page answer to this question. You can let
ChatGPT just like chug for you for 25, 30 minutes.
It's not the immediate answers you're used to,
but it might go work for 25, 30 minutes and do
work that would've taken you a week. So as we
were building that product, we were designing
evals at the same time as we were thinking
about how this product was going to work and
we were trying to go through hero use cases.
Here's a question you want to be able to ask.
Here's an amazing answer for that question.
And then turning those into evals and then
hill climbing on those evals. So it's not
just that the model is static and we hope
it does okay on a certain set of things,
you can teach the model. You can make
this a continuous learning process. And
so as we were fine-tuning our model for deep
research to be able to answer these things,
we were able to test is it getting better
on these evals that we said were important
measures of how the product was working? And
it's when you start seeing that and you start
seeing performance on evals going up, you start
saying, "Okay, I think we have a product here."
You made a kind of a comment along
these same lines around evals
that AI is almost capped in how
amazing it can be by how good
we are at evals. Does that resonate?
Any more thoughts along those lines?
I mean, these models are their
intelligences and intelligence is
so fundamentally multidimensional so you
can talk about a model being amazing at
competitive coding, which may not be the same
as that model being great at front-end coding-
... may not be the same as that model being
great at front-end coding or back-end coding
or taking a whole bunch of code that's written in
COBOL and turning it into Python. And that's just
within the software engineering world. So I think
there's a sense in which you can think of these
models as incredibly smart, very factually aware
intelligences, but still most of the world's data,
knowledge, process is not public. It's behind
the walls of companies or governments or other
things. And same way, if you were going to
join a company, you would spend your first
two weeks onboarding. You'd be learning the
company-specific processes. You'd get access
to company-specific data. The models are
smart enough, you can teach them anything,
but they need to have the raw data to learn from.
So there's a sense in which I think the future is
really going to be incredibly smart, broad-based
models that are fine-tuned and tailored with
company-specific or use case-specific data so
that they perform really well on company-specific,
or use case-specific things. And you're
going to measure that with custom evals.
So what I was referring to is just like these
models are really smart, you need to still teach
them things if the data's not in their training
set, and there's a huge amount of use cases that
are not going to be in their training set because
they're relevant to one industry or one company.
I'm just going to keep following the
thread that you're leading us down,
but I'm going to come back because I have
more questions around some of these things.
So you came to a space that I think a lot
of AI founders are thinking about is just,
where's OpenAI not going to come squash me in
the future? Or one of the other foundational
models. So it's unclear to a lot of people just
like, "Should I build a startup in this space
or not?" Is there any advice you have or any
guidance for where you think OpenAI, or just
foundational models in general likely won't go and
where you have an opportunity to build a company?
So this is something that Ev Williams used to
say back at Twitter that's always stuck with me,
which is, "No matter how big your company
gets, no matter how incredible the people are,
there are way more smart people outside your
walls than there are inside your walls." And
that's why we are so focused on building a great
API. We have 3 million developers using our API.
No matter how ambitious we are, how big we grow,
by the way, we don't want to grow super big,
there are so many use cases, places in the
world where AI can fundamentally make our
lives better. We're not going to have the
people. We're not going to have the know-how
to build most of these things.
And I think, like I was saying,
the data is industry-specific, use case-specific,
behind certain company walls, things like that.
And there are immense opportunities in every
industry and every vertical in the world to go
build AI-based products that improve upon the
state of the art. And there's just no way we
could ever do that ourselves. We don't want
to. We if we did want to, and we're really
excited to power that for 3 million-plus
developers and way more in the future.
Coming back to your earlier point about the
tech changing constantly and getting faster,
not exactly knowing what you'll have by the
time you launch something in terms of the power,
the model. I'm curious what allows
you to ship quickly and consistently
in such great stuff? And it sounds like
one answer is bottoms-up empowered teams
versus a very top-down roadmap
that's planned out for a quarter.
What are some of those things that allow you
to ship such great stuff so often, so quickly?
Yeah. I mean, we try and have a sense of
where we're trying to go, point ourselves
in a direction so that we have some rough sense
of alignment. Thematically, I don't for second,
and we do quarterly roadmapping. We laid out a
year-long strategy. I don't for a second believe
that what we write down in these documents is
what we're going to actually ship three months
from now, let alone six or nine. But that's
okay. I think it's like an Eisenhower quote,
"Plans are useless. Planning is helpful,"
which I totally subscribe to, especially
in this world. It's really valuable. If you think
about quarterly road roadmapping for example, it's
really valuable to have a moment where you stop
and go, "Okay. What did we do? What worked? What
went well? What didn't go well? What did we learn
and now what do we think we're going to do next?"
And by the way, everybody has some dependencies.
You need the infrastructure team to do the
following things, partnership with research
here. So you want to have a second to check
your dependencies, make sure you're good to go
and then start executing. We try and keep that
really lightweight because it's not going to be
right. We're going to throw it out halfway because
we will have learned new things. So the moment of
planning is helpful even if it's only partially.
So I think just expecting that you're going
to be super agile and that there's no sense
writing a three month roadmap, let alone a
year long roadmap because the technology's
changing underneath you so quickly. We really
do try and go very strongly bottoms up,
subject to our overall directional alignment. We
have great people. We have engineers and PMs and
designers and researchers who are passionate about
the products they're building and have strong
opinions about them and are also the ones building
them. So they have a real sense of what the
capabilities are too, which is super important.
So I think you want to be more bottoms up in this
way. So we operate that way. We are happy
making mistakes. We make mistakes all the
time. It's one of the things I really appreciate
about Sam. He pushes us really hard to move fast,
but he also understands that with moving fast
comes, we didn't quite get this right or that we
launched this thing, it didn't work. We'll roll it
back. Look at our naming. Our naming is horrible.
That was a lot of questions people
had for you. Model names, yeah.
It's absolutely atrocious and we know it, and
we will get around to fixing it at some point,
but it's not the most important thing and
so we don't spend a lot of time on it.
But it also shows you how it doesn't matter.
Again, ChatGPT the most popular, fastest growing
product in history, it's the number one AI, API
and model. So clearly it doesn't matter that much.
And we name things like o3 mini high.
Man, I love it. Okay. So you talked about
roadmapping and bottoms up and I'm really curious,
is there a cadence or a ritual of aligning with
you or Sam or you review everything that's going
out? Is there a meeting every week or every
month where you guys see what's happening?
On key projects. So we do product reviews
and things like that, like you would expect.
There isn't a ritual because there isn't... I
would never want us to be blocked on launching
something, waiting for a review with me or Sam,
if we can't get there. If I'm traveling or Sam's
busy or whatever, that's a bad reason for us
not to ship. So obviously for the biggest,
most high priority stuff, we have a pretty close
beat on it, but we really try not to, frankly.
We want to empower teams to move quickly, and I
think it's more important to ship and iterate.
So we have this philosophy, we call iterative
deployment, and the idea is we're all learning
about these models together. So there's a real
sense in which it's way better to ship something
even when you don't know the full set of
capabilities and iterate together in public.
And we co-evolve together with the rest of
society as we learn about these things and
where they're different and where they're good
and bad and weird. I really like that philosophy.
I think the other thing that ends up
being a part of our product philosophy is
the sense of model maximalism.
The models are not perfect.
They're going to make mistakes. You could spend
a lot of time building all kinds of different
scaffolding around them. And by the way, sometimes
we do because sometimes there are kinds of
errors that you just don't want to make, but we
don't spend that much time building scaffolding
around the parts that don't match that because
our general mindset is in two months there's
going to be a better model and it's going to blow
away whatever the current set of limitations are.
So if you're building, and we say this to
developers too, if you're building and the product
that you're building is right on the edge of the
capabilities of the models, keep going, because
you're doing something right because you give it
another couple months and the models are going to
be great, and suddenly the product that you have
that just barely worked is really going to sing.
And that's how you make sure that you're really
pushing the envelope and building new things.
I had the founder of Bolt on the podcast,
StackBlitz is the company name, and he shared
this story that they've been working on this
product for seven years behind the scenes and it
was failing. Nothing was happening. And then all
of a sudden it was, sorry to mention a competitor,
but Claude came out or a Sonnet 3.5 came out and
all of a sudden everything worked and they've been
building all this time and finally it worked. And
I hear that a lot with YC, just like things that
never were possible now are just becoming possible
every few months with the updates to the models.
Yeah, absolutely.
Let me actually ask this, I
wasn't planning to ask this,
but I'm curious if you have any quick
thoughts just why is Sonnet so good at coding,
and thoughts on your stuff getting
as good and better at actual coding?
Yeah. I mean, kudos to Anthropic. They've built
very good coding models. No doubt. We think that
we can do the same. Maybe by the time this
podcast has shipped, we'll have more to say,
but either way, all credit to them. I think
intelligence is really multi-dimensional and
so I think the model providers... It used to
be that OpenAI had this massive model lead,
12 months or something ahead of everybody else.
That's not true anymore. I like to think we
still have a lead. I'd argue that we do, but it's
certainly not a massive one. And that means that
there are going to be different places where the
Google models are really good or where Anthropic
models are really good, or where we're really
good and our competitors are like, "We got to
get better at that." And it actually is easier
to get better at a certain thing once someone's
proved it possible than it is to forge a path
through the jungle and doing something brand new.
So I just think as an example, it was like
nobody could break 4 minutes in the mile,
and then finally somebody did and the next year
12 more people did it. I think there's that all
over the place and it just means that competition
is really intense, and consumers are going to win
and developers are going to win and businesses are
going to win in a big way from that. It's part of
why the industry moves so fast, but all respect to
the other big model providers. Models are getting
really good. We're going to move as fast as we
can and I think we've got some good stuff coming.
Exciting. This makes me also think about, in many
ways other models are better at certain things,
but somehow ChatGPT is the... If you look at
all the awareness numbers and usage numbers,
it's like no matter where you guys are in
the rankings, people seem to just think of AI
ChatGPT almost as the same. What do you think
you did right to win in the consumer mindset,
at least at this point and awareness in the world?
I think being first helps, which is one of the
reasons why we're so focused on moving quickly. We
like being the first to launch new capabilities.
Things like deep research. Our models, they can
do a lot of things. So they can take real-time
video input, you have speech to speech, you can
do speech to text and text to speech. They can
do deep research. They can operate on a canvas,
they can write code. So ChatGPT can be this one-
stop-shop where all the things that you want to
do are possible. And as we go forward in it, we
have more agentic tools like Operator where it's
browsing for you and doing things for you on the
web, more and more you're going to be able to come
to this one place to ChatGPT, give it instructions
and have it accomplish real things for you in the
world. There's something fundamentally valuable
in that. So we think a lot about that. We try to
move really fast so that we are always the
most useful place for people to come to.
What would you say is the most counterintuitive
thing that you've learned after building AI
products or working at OpenAI, something
that's just like, "I did not expect that?"
I don't know, maybe I should have expected this,
but one of the things that's been funny for me is
the extent to which you're trying to figure
out how some product should work with AI,
or even why some AI thing happens to be true,
you can often reason about it the way you would
reason about another human and it works. So
maybe a couple examples. When we were first
launching our reasoning model, we were the first
to build a model that could reason, that could,
instead of giving you just a quick system one
answer right away to every question you asked,
it was the third Emperor of the
Holy Roman Empire, here's an answer.
You could ask it hard questions and it would
reason. The same way that if I asked you to do
a crossword puzzle, you couldn't just snap fill
in everything. You would be, "Well, okay. On this
one across, I think it could be one of these
two, but that means there's an A here. So that
one has to be this, away, back track, step-by-step
build up from where you are." Same way you answer
any difficult logistical problem, any scientific
problem. So this reasoning breakthrough was big,
but it was also the first time that a model needed
to sit and think. And that's a weird paradigm
for a consumer product. You don't normally
have something where you might need to hang
out for 25 seconds after you ask a question.
So we were trying to figure out what's the UI
for this? With deep research where the model's
going to go and think for 25 minutes sometimes,
it's actually not that hard because you're not
going to sit and watch it for 25 minutes. You're
going to go do something else. You're going to
go to another tab or go get lunch or whatever,
and then you'll come back and it's done
when it's like 20, 25 seconds or 10 seconds,
it's a long time to wait, but it's not
long enough to go to do something else.
So you can think, if you asked me something
that I needed to think for 20 seconds to answer,
what would I do? I wouldn't just go mute and not
say anything and shut down for 20 seconds and then
come back. So we shouldn't do that. We shouldn't
just have a slider sitting there. That's annoying.
But I also wouldn't just start babbling
every single thought that I had. So we
probably shouldn't just expose the whole
chain of thought as the model's thinking,
but I might go like, "That's a good question.
All right." I might approach it like that and
then think. You're maybe giving little updates
and that's actually what we ended up shipping.
You have similar things where you can find
situations where you get better thinking sometimes
out of a group of models that all try and attack
the same problem, and then you have a model that's
looking at all their outputs and integrating it
and then giving you a single answer at the end.
I mean, sounds a little bit like brainstorming. I
certainly have better ideas when I get in a room
and brainstorm with other people because they
think differently than me. So anyways, there's
just all these situations where you can actually
reason about it like a group of humans or an
individual human and it works, which I don't know,
maybe I shouldn't have been surprised but I was.
That is so interesting because when I see these
models operate, I never even thought about you
guys designing that experience. To me, it just
feels like this is what the LLM does. It just sits
there and tells me what it's thinking. And I love
this point you're making of let's make it feel
like a human operating and well, how does a human
operate? Well, they just talk aloud. They think,
here's the thing I should explore. And I love
that deep sequence to the extreme of that where
they're just like, "Here's everything I'm doing
and thinking." And people actually like that too,
I guess. Was that surprising to you, "Maybe that
could work too. People seem to like everything?"
Yeah. We learned from that actually because when
we first launched it, we gave you the subheadings
of what the model was thinking about, but not
much more. And then deep seek launched and it
was a lot and we went, I don't know if everyone
wants that. There's some novelty effect to seeing
what the model's really thinking about. We felt
that too when we were looking at it internally.
It's interesting to see the model's chain
of thought, but it's not... I think at the
scale of 400 million people, you don't want
to see the model babble a bunch of things.
So what we ended up doing was summarizing
it in interesting ways. So instead of just
getting the subheadings, you're getting one or two
sentences about how it's thinking about it and you
can learn from that. So we tried to find a middle
ground that we thought was an experience would be
meaningful for most people, but showing everybody
three paragraphs is probably not the right answer.
This reminds me of something else you said
at the summit that has really stuck with me,
this idea that chat, people always make fun
of chat is not the future interface for how
we interact with AI, but you made this really
interesting point that may argue the other side,
which is, as humans we interface by talking
and the IQ of a human can span from really
low to really high and it all works talking
to them and chat is the same thing and it
can work on all kinds of intelligence levels.
Maybe I just shared it, but I guess anything
there about just why chat actually ends up
being such an interesting interface for LLMs?
Yeah. I don't know, maybe this is one of those
things I believe that most people don't believe,
but I actually think chat is an amazing interface
because it's so versatile. People tend to go,
"Chat. Yeah. We'll figure out something
better." And I think it's incredibly
universal because it is the way we talk. I can
talk to you verbally like we're talking now.
We can see each other and interact. We can
talk on WhatsApp and be texting each other,
but all of these things is this unstructured
method of communication and that's how we operate.
If I had some more rigid interface that
I was allowed to use when we spoke,
I would be able to speak to you about far fewer
things and it would actually get in the way of us
having maximum communication bandwidth. So
there's something magical. And by the way,
in the past it never worked because there wasn't
a model that was good at understanding all of
the complexity and nuances of human speech, and
that's the magic of LLMs. So to me, it's like an
interface that's exactly fit to the power of these
things. And that doesn't mean that it always has
to be just like I don't necessarily always want
to type, but you do want that very open-ended,
flexible communication medium, it may be that
we're speaking and the model's speaking back
to me, but you still want the very lowest common
denominator, no restrictions way of interacting.
That is so interesting. That's really changed
the way I think about this stuff is that point
that chat is just so good for this very specific
problem of talking to superintelligence basically.
By the way, I think it's not that it's only chat
either. If you have high volume use cases where
they're more prescribed and you don't actually
need the full generality, there are many use
cases where it's better to have something that's
less flexible, more prescribed, faster to specific
task, and those are great too, and you can build
all sorts of those. But you still want chat as
this baseline for anything that falls out of
whatever vertical you happen to be building
for. It's like a catch-all for every possible
thing you'd ever want to express to a model.
I'm excited to chat with Christina
Gilbert, the founder of OneSchema,
one of our long-time podcast
sponsors. Hi, Christina.
Yes. Thank you for having me on, Lenny.
What is the latest with OneSchema? I know you
now with some of my favorite companies like Ramp,
Vanta, Scale and Watershed. I heard
that you just launched a new product
to help product teams import CSVs from
especially tricky systems like ERPs?
Yes. So we just launched OneSchema FileFeeds,
which allows you to build an integration with
any system in 15 minutes as long as you can export
a CSV to an SFTP folder. We see our customers all
the time getting stuck with hacks and workarounds,
and the product teams that we work with don't have
to turn down prospects because their systems
are too hard to integrate with. We allow our
customers to offer thousands of integrations
without involving their engineering team at all.
I can tell you that if my team had
to build integrations like this,
how nice would it be to be able to
take this off my roadmap and instead,
use something like OneSchema and not just to
build it, but also to maintain it forever.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of multi-day outages from
even just a handful of ad records. We are
laser-focused on integration reliability to
help teams end all of those distractions
that come up with integrations. We have
a built-in validation layer that stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and OneSchema will notify your team
immediately of any data that looks incorrect.
I know that importing incorrect data can
cause all kinds of pain for your customers,
and quickly lose their trust. Christina, thank
you for joining us. And if you want to learn more,
head on over to oneschema.co. That's oneschema.co.
I want to come back to that you talked about
researchers and their relationship with product
teams. I imagine a lot of innovation comes
from researchers just like having an inkling
and then building something amazing and then
releasing it, and some ideas come from PMs and
engineers. How do those teams collaborate?
Does every team have a PM? Is it a lot of
research-led stuff? Give us a sense of just
where ideas and products come from mostly.
It's an area where we're evolving
a lot. I'm really excited about it,
frankly. I think if you go back a couple of years
when ChatGPT was just getting started,
obviously, I wasn't in OpenAI, but...
Obviously I wasn't an Open AI, but... We
were more of a pure research company at the
time. Chat GPT, if you remember,
was a low-key research preview.
For many years.
Yeah. It wasn't a thing that the team launched
thinking it was going to be this massive product.
Oh, Chat GPT. Yeah.
And it was just a way that we were going
to let people play with and iterate on the
models. So we were primarily a research
company, a world-class research company,
and as ChatGPT has grown and as we've built our
B-to-B products and our APIs and other things,
now we're more of a product company than we were.
I still think we can't... Open AI should never be
a pure product company. We need to be both a
world-class research company and a world-class
product company, and the two need to really work
together, and that's the thing that I think we've
been getting much better at over the last six
months. If you treat those things separately
and the researchers go do amazing things and
build models and then they get to some state
and then the product and engineering teams go take
them and do something with them, we're effectively
just an API consumer of our own models.
The best products though are going to be,
it's like I was talking about with deep
research, it's a lot of iterative feedback.
It's understanding the products you're trying
to sell or the problems you're trying to solve,
building evals for them, using those evals to go
gather data and fine-tune models to get them to
be better at these use cases that you're looking
to solve. It's a huge amount of back and forth
to do it well. And I think the best products
are going to be ENG product design and research
working together as a single team to build novel
things. So that's actually how we're trying to
operate with basically anything that we build.
It's a new muscle for us because we're kind of
new as a product company, but it's one that people
are really excited about because we've seen every
time we do it, we build something awesome,
and so now every product starts like that.
How many product managers do
you have at Open AI? I don't
know if you share that number, but if you do.
Not that many, actually. I don't know, 25. Maybe
it's a little more than that. My personal belief
is that you want to be pretty PM light as an
organization just in general. I say this with
love because I am a PM, but too many PMs
causes problems. We'll fill the world with
decks and ideas versus execution. So I think
it's a good thing when you have a PM that
is working with maybe slightly too many
engineers because it means they're not
going to get in and micromanage. You're going to
leave a lot of influence and responsibility with
the engineers to make decisions. It means you
want to have really product-focused engineers,
which we're fortunate to have. We
have an amazingly product focused,
high agency engineering team. But when you have
something like that, you have a team that feels
super empowered, you have a PM that's trying
to really understand the problems and gently
guide the team a little bit but has too much
going on to get too far into the details,
and you end up being able to move really fast.
So that's kind of the philosophy we take.
We want Product ENG leads and product engineers
all the way through. We want not too many PMs,
but really awesome, high quality ones, and
so far that seems to be working pretty well.
I imagine being a PM at Open AI is a dream come
true for a lot of people. At the same time,
I imagine it's not a fit for a lot of
people. There's researchers involved,
very product minded engineers. What do you look
for in the PMs that you hire there for folks
that are like, "Maybe I shouldn't go work
there. I shouldn't even think about that."
I think, I've said this a few times, but high
agency is something that we really look for,
people that are not going to come in and wait
for everyone else to allow them to do something,
they're just going to see a problem and go
do it. It's just a core part of how we work.
I think people that are happy with ambiguity,
because there is a massive amount of ambiguity
here, it is not the kind of place, and we have
trouble sometimes with more junior PMs because
of this, because it's just not the place where
someone is going to come in and say, "Okay,
here's the landscape, here's your area, I want
you to go do this thing." And that's what you
want as an early career PM. I mean, no one here
has time and the problems are too ill-formed and
we're figuring them all out as we go. And so
high agency, very comfortable with ambiguity,
ready to come in and help execute and move
really quickly. That's kind of our recipe.
And I think also happy leading through influence
because... I mean it's usual as a PM, people don't
report to you, your team doesn't report to you,
et cetera, but you also have the complexity of
a research function, which is even more sort of
self-directed and it's really important to build
a good rapport with the research team. I think the
EQ side of things is also super important for us.
I know at most companies, a PM
comes in and they're just like,
"Why do we need you?" And as a PM you have
to earn trust and help people see the value,
and I feel like at Open AI it's probably a very
extreme version of that where they're like,
"Why do we need this person? We have researchers,
engineers, what are you going to do here?"
Yeah, I think people appreciate it done right, but
you bring people along. I think one of the most
important things a PM can do well is be decisive.
So there's a real fine line. You don't want to be
making... I mean it's kind of like, I don't love
the PM as the CEO of the product illusion all
the time, but just like Sam in his role would be
making mistakes if he made every single decision
in every meeting that he was in. And he would also
be making mistakes if he made no decisions in any
meetings that he was in, right? It's understanding
when to defer to your team and to let people
innovate. And when there is a decision to be made
that people either don't feel comfortable with
or don't feel empowered to make, or a decision
that has too many different disparate pros and
cons that are spread out across a big group and
someone needs to be decisive and make a call,
it's a really important trait of a CEO.
It's something Sam does well, and it's
also a really important trait of a PM
kind of at a more microscopic level. So
because there's so much ambiguity, it's not
obvious what the answer is in a lot of cases,
and so having a PM that can come in and... And
by the way, this doesn't need to be a PM, I'm
perfectly happy if it's anybody else, but I kind
of look to the PM to say, if there's ambiguity and
no one's making a call, you better make sure
that we get a call made and we move forward.
This touches on a few posts I've done of just,
where is AI going to take over work that we do
versus help us with various work? So let
me come at this question from a different
direction of just how AI impacts product teams
and hiring, things like that. So first of all,
there's all this talk of LM's doing our coding
for us, and 90% of code is going to be written
by AI in a year. Dario at Anthropic said that. At
the same time, you guys are all hiring engineers
like crazy, PM's like crazy. Every function is
dead, but you're still hiring every single one.
I guess just, first of all, let me just ask
this, how do you and the team, say engineers,
PMs, use AI in your work? Is there anything
that's really interesting or things that you
think people are sleeping on in how
you use AI in your day-to-day work?
We use it a lot. I mean, every one of us is
in Chat GPT all the time summarizing docs,
using it to help write docs with GPTs that
write product specs and things like that,
all the stuff that you would imagine. I
mean talk about writing evals, you can
actually use models to help you write evals
and they're pretty good at it. That all said,
I'm still sort of disappointed by us, and I
really mean me, in, if I were to just teleport
my five-year-old self leading product at some
other company into my day job, I would recognize
it still. And I think we should be in a world,
certainly a year from now, probably even more now,
where I almost wouldn't recognize it because
the workflows are so different and I'm using
AI so heavily, and I'd still recognize
it today. So I think in some sense,
I'm not doing a good enough job of that.
Just to give an example, why shouldn't
we be vibe coding demos right, left and
center? Instead of showing stuff in Figma,
we should be showing prototypes that people are
vibe coding over the course of 30 minutes to
illustrate proofs of concept and to explore
ideas. That's totally possible today, and we're
not doing it enough. Actually, our chief people
officer, Julia, was telling me the other day,
she vibe coded an internal tool that she had at a
previous job that she really wanted to have here
at Open AI and she opened, I don't know, Windsurf
or something, and vibe coded it. How cool is that?
And if our chief people officer is doing it,
we have no excuse to not be doing it more.
That's an awesome story. And some people may not
have heard this term vibe coding.
Can you describe what that means?
Yeah, I think this was Andrej's term.
Karpathy. Yeah.
Andrej Karpathy. Yeah. So you have these tools
like Cursor and Windsurf and GitHub Copilot that
are very good at suggesting what code you might
want to write. So you can give them a prompt and
they'll write code and then as you go to edit
it, it's suggesting what you might want to do.
And the way that everyone started using that
stuff was, give it a prompt, have it do stuff,
you go edit it, give it a prompt, and you're
kind of really going back and forth with the
model the whole time. As the models are getting
better and as people are getting more used to it,
you can kind of just let go of the wheel a little
bit. And when the model's suggesting stuff,
it's just like, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap.
Keep going. Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
And of course the model makes mistakes or it
does something that doesn't compile, but when
it doesn't compile, you paste the error in and you
say, go, go, go, go, go. And then you test it out
and it does one thing that you don't want it to
do, so you enter in an instruction and say, go,
go, go, go, go, and you just let the model
do its thing. And it's not that you would
do that for production code that needed to be
super tight today yet, but for so many things,
you're trying to get to a proof of concept,
you're getting to a demo and you can really
take your hands off the wheel and the model
will do an amazing job, and that's vibe coding.
That's an awesome explanation. I think the
pro version of that, which is, I think,
the way Andre even described it as you
talk, there's a step like whisper or super
whisper or something like that where you're
talking to the model, not even typing.
Yeah, totally.
Oh man. So let me just ask, I guess, when
you look at product teams in the future,
you talked about how you guys should
be doing this more, instead of designs,
having prototypes, what do you think might be
the biggest changes in how product teams are
structured or built? Where do you think
things are going in the next few years?
I think you're definitely going to live in a
world where you have researchers built into
every product team. And I don't even mean just
at foundation model companies because I think
the future... Actually, frankly one thing that
I'm sort of surprised about about our industry
in general is that there's not a greater use
of fine-tuned models. A lot of people... These
models are very good, so our API does a lot of
things really well, but when you have particular
use cases, you can always make the model perform
better on a particular use case by fine-tuning it.
It's probably just a matter of time. Folks aren't
quite comfortable yet with doing that in every
case. But to me, there's no question that that's
the future. Models are going to be everywhere just
like transistors are everywhere, AI is going to
be just a part of the fabric of everything we do,
but I think there are going to be a lot of
fine-tuned models because why would you not
want to more specifically customize a
model against a particular use case?
And so I think you're going to want sort of
quasi researcher machine learning engineer
types as part of pretty much every team because
fine-tuning a model is just going to be part of
the core workflow for building most products.
So that's one change that maybe you're starting
to see at foundation model companies that
will propagate out to more teams over time.
I'm curious if there's a concrete
example that makes that real,
and I'll share one that comes to mind as you talk,
which is, when you look at Cursor and Windsurf,
something I learned from those founders is
that they use a Sonnet, but then they also
have a bunch of custom models that help along
the edges that make the specific experience
that's not just generating code even better like
auto-complete and looking ahead to where things
are going. So is that one or any other examples
of which you... What is a fine-tuned model?
Do you think teams will be building
with these researchers on their teams?
Yeah. I mean, so when you're a model, you're
basically giving the model a bunch of examples
of the kinds of things you want it to be
better at. So it's, "Here's a problem,
here's a good answer. Here's a problem, here's
a good answer," Or, "Here's a question, here's
a good answer times a thousand or 10,000."
And suddenly you're teaching the model to
be much better than it was out of the gate at that
particular thing. We use it everywhere internally.
We use ensembles of models much more internally
than people might think. So it's not, "I have
10 different problems. I'll just ask baseline
GPT four oh about a bunch of these things."
If we have 10 different problems, we might solve
them using 20 different model calls, some of
which are using specialized fine-tuned models,
they're using models of different sizes because
maybe you have different latency requirements
or cost requirements for different questions.
They are probably using custom prompts for each
one. Basically you want to teach the model to be
really good at... You want to break the problem
down into more specific tasks versus some broader
set of high level tasks. And then you can use
models very specifically to get very good at each
individual thing. And then you have an ensemble
that tackles the whole thing. I think a lot of
good companies are doing that today. I still
see a lot of companies giving the model single,
generic, broad problems versus breaking the
problem down, and I think there will be more
breaking the problem down using specific models
for specific things, including fine tuning.
And so in your case, because this is really
interesting, is that you're using different
levels of Chat GPT, like a 1 0 3 and
stuff that's earlier because it's cheaper.
There'll be parts of our internal stack.
I'll give you an example. Customer support,
with 400 plus million weekly active users,
we get a lot of inbound tickets. I don't
know how many customer support folks we have,
but it's not very many, 30, 40, I'm not sure,
way smaller than you would have at any comparable
company, and it's because we've automated a lot of
our flows. We've got most questions using
our internal resources, knowledge base,
guidelines for how we answer questions, what kind
of personality, et cetera. You can teach the model
those things and then have it do a lot of its
answers automatically, or where it doesn't have
the full confidence to answer a particular
question, it can still suggest an answer,
request a human to look at it and then that
human's answer actually is its own sort of fine
tuning data for the model. You're telling
it the right answer in a particular case.
We're using... At various places. Some of these
places, you want a little bit more reasoning,
is not super latency sensitive, so you want a
little more reasoning, and we'll use one of our
O series models. In other places, you want a quick
check on something and so you're fine to use four
oh mini, which is super fast and super cheap. In
general, it's like specific models for specific
purposes and then you ensemble them together to
solve problems. By the way, again, not unlike how
we as humans solve problems, a company is arguably
an ensemble of models that have all been fine
tuned based on what we studied in college and what
we have learned over the course of our careers.
We've all been fine tuned to have different sets
of skills and you group them together in different
configurations and the output of the ensemble is
much better than the output of any one individual.
Kevin, you're blowing my mind. That
sounds exactly correct. And also,
different people, you pay them
less, they cost less to talk to,
some people take a long time to answer,
some people hallucinating. This is...
I'm telling you. This is a mental model
but really does work in thinking...
Oh, right. Yeah. This is great. Some people are
visual, they want to dry out their thinking,
some people want to talk word cell. Wow,
this is a really good metaphor. So again,
coming back to your advice here because
I love that we circled back to it,
you're finding a really good way to think about
how to design great AI experiences and LMs,
I guess, specifically is think
about how a person would do this.
Well, it's maybe not always the answer is to think
about how a person would do it, but sometimes to
gain intuition for how you might solve a problem,
you think about what an equivalent human would do
in those situations and use that to at least
gain a different perspective on the problem.
Wow, this is great.
Because some of this really is talking
to a model. There's a lot of prior art
because we talk to other humans all
the time and encounter them in all
sorts of different situations, and
so there's a lot to learn from that.
Okay, so speaking of humans, I want to chat about
the future a little bit. So you have three kids,
and a community member asked me this hilarious
question that I think it's something a lot of
people are thinking about. So this is
Patrick [inaudible 01:04:47]. I worked
with him at Airbnb. He says ask what he's
encouraging his kids to learn to prepare
for the future. I'm worried my 6-year-old by
the year 2036 will face a lot of competition
trying to get into the top roofing or
plumbing programs and need a backup plan.
That's funny. So our kids, we have a
10 year old and eight year old twins,
so they're still pretty young. It's amazing how
AI native they are. It's completely normal to
them that there are self-driving cars. That
they can talk to AI all day long. They have
full conversations with Chat GPT and Alexa
and everything else. I don't know, who knows
what the future holds? I think things like coding
skills are going to be relevant for a long time,
who knows? But I think if you teach your
kids to be curious, to be independent, to
be self-confident, you teach them how to think, I
don't know what the future holds, but I think that
those are going to be skills that are going to
be important in any configuration of the future.
And so it's not like we have all the answers, but
that's how Elizabeth and I think about our kids.
And do you find that AI... There's a
lot of talk about AI tutoring. Is that
something you guys are doing?
I know they're using Chat GPT,
I love all the photos you post where they're
playing with prompts and stuff, but I guess
is there anything there you're experimenting with
or you think is going to become really important?
This is something that... It's maybe the most
important thing that AI could do. Maybe that's
a grand statement. There are lots of important
things that AI can do, including speeding up
the pace of fundamental science research and
discovery, which maybe is actually the most
important thing AI can do. But one of the
most important things would be personalized
tutoring. And it kind of blows my mind that
there is still... I know there are a bunch of
good products out there. Khan Academy does great
things. They're a wonderful partner of ours. Vinod
Khosla has a non-profit that's doing some really
interesting stuff in this space and is making an
impact. But I'm kind of surprised that there
isn't a 2 billion kid AI personalized tutoring
thing because the models are good enough to do it
now, and every study out there that's ever been
done seems to show that when you have... Like,
education is still important, but when you combine
that with personalized tutoring, you get multiple
standard deviation improvements in learning speed.
And so it's uncontroversial, it's good for kids,
it's free. Chat GPT is free, you don't need to
pay, and the models are good enough. It still just
kind of blows my mind that there isn't something
amazing out there that our kids are using and your
future kids are using, and people in all sorts of
places around the world that aren't as lucky as
our kids to be able to have this sort of built-in,
solid education. Again, Chat GPT is free. People
have Android devices everywhere. I really just
think this could change the world and I'm
surprised it doesn't exist and I want it to exist.
This kind of touches on something I want
to spend a little time on, which is a lot
of people also worry a lot about AI, where it's
going, they worry about jobs it's going to take,
they worry about the super intelligence squashing
humanity in the future. What's your perspective
on that and just the optimistic case
that I think people need to hear?
I mean, I'm a big technology optimist. I
think if you look over the last 200 years,
maybe more, technology has driven a lot
of the advancements that have made us the
world and the society that we are today.
It drives economic advancements, it drives
geopolitical advancements, quality of
life, longevity advancement. I mean,
technology's at the root of just about everything,
so I think there are very few examples where
this is anything but a great thing over the longer
term. That doesn't mean that there aren't...
... a great thing over the longer term. That
doesn't mean that there aren't temporary
dislocations or where there aren't individuals
that are impacted, and that matters too. So
it can't just be that the average is good.
You've got to also think about how you take
care of each individual person as best you can.
It is something that we think a lot about and as
we work with the administration, as we work with
policy, we try and help wherever we can. We do a
lot with education. One of the benefits here is
that ChatGPT is also perhaps the best reskilling
app you could possibly want. It knows a lot
of things. It can teach you a lot of things
if you're interested in learning new things.
These are very real issues. I'm super optimistic
about the long run, and we're going to
need to do everything we can as a society
to ensure that we make this transition as
graceful and as well-supported as we can.
To give people a sense of where things might be
going. That's a big question in a lot of people's
minds. So someone asked this question that I love,
which is, "AI is already changing, creative work
in a lot of different ways, writing and design
and coding, what do you think is the next big
leap? What should we be thinking is the next
big leap in AI-assisted creativity specifically,
and then just broadly, where do you think things
are going to be going in the next few years?"
Yeah. This is also an area where I'm a big
optimist. If you look at Sora, for example.
I mean we talked about ImageGen earlier and the
absolute fount of creativity that people are
putting across Twitter and Instagram and other
places. I am the world's worst artist like the
worst. Maybe the only thing I'm worse at than art
is singing. Give me a pencil and a pad of paper
and I can't draw better than our eight-year-old.
But give me ImageGen and I can think some creative
thoughts and put something into the model
and suddenly have output that I couldn't
have possibly done myself. That's pretty cool.
Even you look at folks that are really talented.
I was talking to a director recently about
Sora, someone who's directed films that we
would all know, and he was saying, for a film
that he's doing, take the example of some sort
of sci-fi-ish, think of Star Wars, and you've got
some scene where there's a plane zooming into some
Death Star-like thing. And so you've got the
plane looking at the whole planet, and then you
want to cut to a scene where the plane's kind of
at the ground level, and all of a sudden you see
the city and everything else. How are we going
to manage that cut scene? And that transition?
And he was saying, "In the world of two years
ago, I would have paid a 3D effects company
a hundred grand and they would've taken a
month, and they would've produced two versions
of this cut scene for me. And I would've
evaluated them. We would've chosen one,
because what are you going to do? Pay another
50 grand and wait another month. And we would've
just gone with it. And it would be fine. Movies
are great. I love them. And there've been..."
Obviously, we can do great things with the
technology that we've had, but you now look
at what you can do with Sora. And his point
was, "Now, I can use Sora, our video model,
and I can get 50 different variations of this cut
scene just me brainstorming into a prompt and the
model brainstorming a little bit with me. I've
got 50 different versions. And then of course, I
can iterate off of those and refine them and take
different ideas. And now I'm still going to go to
that 3D effects studio to produce the final one,
but I'm going to go having brainstormed and had a
much more creative approach with an outcome that's
much better. And I did that assisted by AI."
My personal view on creativity in general is that
it's no one's going to... You don't type into
Sora like, "Make me a great movie." It requires
creativity and ingenuity, and all these things,
but it can help you explore more. It can help
you get to a better final result. So, again,
I tend to be an optimist in most things, but
actually, I think there's a very good story here.
I know Sam Altman, I think it was him who tweeted
recently, the creative writing piece that you
guys are working on where it's... He is very
bad at writing creative stuff, and he shared
an example where it's actually really good.
I imagine that's another area of investment.
Yeah, there's some exciting
stuff happening internally
with some new research techniques. We'll have
more to say about that at some point. But yeah,
Sam sometimes likes to show off
some of the stuff that's coming,
which is smart. By the way, it's very
indicative of this iterative deployment
philosophy. We don't have some breakthrough and
keep it to ourselves forever, and then bestow it
upon the world someday. We kind of just talk
about the things we're working on and share
when we can and launch early and often, and then
iterate in public. I really like that philosophy.
I love all these hints that a few things
coming. I know you can't say too much.
You talked about how there might be a coding
leap coming in the near future maybe by the
time this comes out. Is there anything
else people should be thinking about,
might be coming in the near future? Any things
you can tease that are interesting? Exciting?
Man, this hasn't been enough for you?
Only everything is getting better every day.
Yeah. I'm like, man, I hope we get some of
this stuff out before the episode launches so-
This is your new timebox.
... I don't piss people off. The amazing thing
to me is we were talking earlier about how far
models have come in just a couple of years. If
you went back to GPT-3, you'd be disgusted by
how bad it was, even though Lenny of two years ago
was mind-blown by how good these were. And for a
long time, we were iterating every six to nine
months on a new GPT model. It was like GPT-3,
GPT-3.5, 4, and now with this o-series
of reasoning models, we're moving even
faster. Every roughly three months, maybe
four months, there's a new o-series model,
and each of them is a step up in capability.
And so the capabilities of these models are
increasing at a massive pace. They're also
getting cheaper as they scale. You look
at where we were even a couple of years
ago. I think the original, I don't know,
what was it, GPT-3.5 or something
was like 100 x the cost of GPT-4o
mini today in the API. A couple of years,
you've gone down two orders of magnitude in
cost for much more intelligence. And so I
don't know where there's another series of
trends like that in the world. Models are
getting smarter, they're getting faster,
they're getting cheaper, and they're getting
safer too. They hallucinate less every iteration.
And so the Morse Law and transistors becoming
ubiquitous. That was a law around doubling the
number of transistors on a chip every 18 months.
If you're talking about something where you're
getting 10 x every year, that's a massively
steeper exponential. And it tells us that
the future is going to be very different than
today. The thing I try and remind myself is,
the AI models that you're using today is
the worst AI model you will ever use for
the rest of your life. And when you actually
get that in your head, it's kind of wild.
I was going to actually say the
same thing, and that's the thing
that always sticks with me when I watch
this thing. You're talking about Sora,
and I imagine many people hearing that are
like, "No, no. It's not actually ready. It's
not good enough. It's not going to be as good
as a movie I see in the theater." But the point
is what you just made that this is the worst
it's going to be. It will only get better.
Yeah, model maximalism. Just keep building
for the capabilities that are almost there,
and the model's going to catch up and be amazing.
Escape to where the puck is going to be.
Yeah.
This reminds me, I was just using...
I was duplifying everything the other
day and I was just like, "What is taking so long."
As one does.
Just like cut... What was that?
I said, as one does.
As one does these days. I was just like,
"It's taking a minute to generate this image
of my family in this amazing way." Come on,
what's taking so long. You just get so
used to magic happening in front of you.
Yeah, totally.
Okay, final question. This is going to go in a
completely different direction. A lot of people
asked about this. So famously, you led this
project at Facebook called Libra, which is now
called Novi. A lot of people always wondered,
"What happened there? That was a really cool
idea." I know some people have a sense there's
regulation challenges, things like that. I don't
know if you've talked about this much. So I guess,
could you just give people a brief summary of just
what is Libra? This project you working on, and
just what happened, and how you feel about it?
Yeah. I mean, David Marcus led it, and
I happily work for him and with him. I
think he's a visionary and also a mentor
and a friend. Honestly, Libra is probably
the biggest disappointment of my career. When
I think about the problems we were solving,
which are very real problems. If you look
at, for example, the remittance space,
people sending money to family members in other
countries, it is maybe... I mean it's incredibly
regressive, right? People that don't have the
money to spend are having to pay 20% to send
money home to their family. So outrageous
fees, it takes multiple days, you have to
go then pick up cash from... It's all bad.
And here we are with 3 billion people using
WhatsApp all over the world, talking to each
other every day, especially friends and family,
and exactly the kind of people who'd send money
to each other. Why can't you send money as
immediately, as cheaply, as simply as you send
a text message? It is one of those things when
you sit back and think about it, that should just
exist. And that was what we set out to try and do.
Now, I don't think we played all of our cards
perfectly. If I could go back and do things, there
are a bunch of things I would do differently.
We tried to get it all at once. We tried to
launch a new blockchain. It was a basket of
currencies originally. It was integration
into WhatsApp and Messenger, and I think the
whole world kind of went like, "Oh my God,
that's a lot of change at once." And it happened
also to be at the time that Facebook was at the
absolute nadir of its reputation. And so that
didn't help. It was also not the Messenger that
people wanted for this kind of change. We
knew all that going in, but we went for it.
I think there are a bunch of ways that we could
do that that would've introduced the change a
little bit more gently, maybe still gotten
to that same outcome, but fewer new things
at once and introduced the new things one at a
time. Who knows? Those were decisions we made
together. So we all own them. Certainly, I
own them. But it fundamentally disappoints
me that this doesn't exist in the world today
because the world would be a better place if
we'd been able to ship that product. I would
be able to send you 50 cents in WhatsApp for
free. It would settle instantly. Everybody would
have a balance in their WhatsApp account. We'd
be transact... I mean, it should exist.
I don't know. To be honest, the current
administration is super friendly
to crypto. Facebook's reputation,
Meta's reputation is in a very different
place. Maybe they should go build it now.
I was looking at the history
of it, and apparently,
they sold the tech to some private
equity company for 200 million bucks.
Yeah, yeah, and-
They had to buy it back.
There are a couple of current blockchains
that are built on the tech because the tech
was open-sourced from the beginning.
Aptos and Mistin are two companies
that are built off of this tech. So
at least all of the work that we did,
did not die and lives on in these two companies,
and they're both doing really well. But still,
we should be able to send each other
money in WhatsApp, and we can't today.
Hear, hear. Well, thanks for sharing that story,
Kevin. Is there anything else you want to share or
maybe a last negative advice or insight before
we get to our very exciting lightning round?
Ooh, the lightning round. Let's just go do that.
Let's do it. With that, Kevin, we reached our
very exciting lightning round. Are you ready?
Yeah.
Let's do it. Okay. What are
two or three books that you
find yourself recommending most to other people?
Co-Intelligence by Ethan Mollick, a really good
book about AI and how to use it in your daily life
as a student, as a teacher. He's super thoughtful.
Also, by the way, a very good follow on Twitter.
The Accidental Superpower by Peter Zion. Very
good if you're interested in geopolitics and the
forces that sort of shape the dynamics happening.
And then I really enjoyed Cable Cowboy, I don't
know who the author is, but the biography of John
Malone. Just fascinating. If you like business,
especially if you want to get into... I
mean the man was an incredible dealmaker
and shaped a lot of the modern cable
industry. So that was a good biography.
These are all first-time
mentions, which is always a great,
Oh, good.
Next question. Do you have a favorite recent
movie or TV show that you really enjoyed?
I wish I had time to watch a TV show, so I'm-
Just Sora videos.
Yeah, right. I don't know. When I was a
kid, I read the Wheel of Time series and
now Amazon has it as they're in the third
season of it, so I want to watch that. I
haven't yet. Top Gun 2 was an awesome
movie. I think that's no longer new.
That shows when the last
time you watched a movie was.
But I like the idea. I want more Americana. I want
more being proud of being strong. And I thought
Top Gun 2 did a really good job of that. Pride and
patriotism, I think the US could use more of that.
Is there a favorite product that you've
recently discovered that you really love,
other than your super intelligence internal tool
that you all have access to? I'm just joking.
That's right. Internal AGR.
Yeah, that's right.
Well, I think vibe coding with products like
Windsurf is just super fun. I'm having a great
time doing that. I still just love that
our chief people officer vibe coded some
tools. Maybe the other one is Waymo. Every
chance I get, I'll take a Waymo. It's just a
better way of riding, and it still feels like
the future. So they've done an amazing job.
That's awesome. By the way, I had the founder of
Windsurf on the podcast. It might come out before
this or after this. And also Cursor's CEO is
coming on the podcast either before or after this.
Oh, cool. I have a ton of respect for what those
guys are doing. Those are awesome products.
Just changing the way everyone
builds product. No big deal.
Yeah.
A couple more questions. Do you
have a favorite life motto that
you often repeat yourself, find
really useful in work or in life?
Yeah. So actually, this is interestingly
enough, it is more of a philosophy,
but then I thought Zuck encapsulated it one time
on a Facebook earnings call. So I actually had
this made into a poster. It sits in my room. But
somebody was asking Mark. This is literally on
an earnings call, so it's like an analyst on an
earnings call asking him. It was some quarter
when Facebook had grown a lot. This was back in
the 20 teens sometime, I think. But he's like,
"So what did you do? What was it that you
launched? What was the one thing that drove
all this growth for you?" And he said something to
the effect of, "Sometimes it's not any one thing,
it's just good work consistently over a long
period of time." And that's always stuck with me.
And I think it is. I mean I run ultra marathons.
It's like it's just about grinding. I think people
too often look for the silver bullet when a lot of
life and a lot of excellence is actually showing
up day in and day out, doing good work, getting
a little bit better every single day, and you may
not notice it over a week or even a month. And
a lot of people then kind of get dismayed and
stop. But actually, you keep doing it. The gains
keep compounding. And over the course of a year,
two years, five years, it adds up like crazy. So
good work consistently over a long period of time.
I love that. I got to make a
poster of this now. That is-
We'll get you one.
I so resonate with that. Okay, I'll take it. That
is so good. Okay, final question. I'm going to ask
if you have any prompting tricks, and I'm going
to set it up first. But think about if you have
a trick that you could recommend to people
for prompting LLMs better. I had a guest,
Alex Komorowski, come on the podcast.
He's from Stripe and writes his weekly
reflections on what's happening in the
world. A lot of them are AI-related.
And he once described an LLM as a zip file of all
human knowledge. All the answers are in there,
and you just need to figure out the right
question to ask to get the answer to every
problem basically. And so it just reminded me
how important prompt engineering is and knowing
how to prompt well. You're constantly
prompting ChatGPT. What's one tip,
one trick that you found to be helpful
in helping you get what you want?
Well, I'll say, first of all, I want to kill the
idea that you have to be a good prompt engineer.
I think if we do our jobs, that stops being
true. It's just one of those sharp edges of
models that experts can learn. But then,
just over time, you shouldn't need to know
all that. The same way you used to have to
get deep into, "What's your storage engine
in MySQL? Are you using InnoDB 4.1?" There's
still use cases for that if you're at the deep
edge of MySQL performance. But most people
don't need to care. And you shouldn't need
to care about minute details of prompting if
AI is really going to become broadly adopted.
But today, we're not totally there. I think
by the way, we are making progress there. I
think there is less prompt engineering than
there had to be before. But in line with
some of the fine-tuning stuff I was talking
about and the importance of giving examples,
you can do effectively poor man's fine-tuning by
including examples in your prompt of the kinds of
things that you might want and a good answer. So
like, "Here's an example and here's a good answer.
Here's an example, and here's a good answer.
Now, go solve this problem for me." And the
model really will listen and learn from that.
Not as well as if you do a full fine-tune, but
much more than if you don't provide any examples.
And I think people don't do that often enough.
That's awesome. One tip that I heard,
I'm curious if this works is you tell it,
"This is very, very important to my
career." Make it really understand like,
"Someone will die if you don't
answer me correctly." Does that work?
It's really weird. There's probably a good
explanation for this. But you can also say
things. So, yes, I think there is some validity to
that. You can also say things like, "I want you to
be Einstein. Now, answer this physics problem for
me," or, "You are the world's greatest marketer,
the world's greatest brand marketer. Now here's
a naming question." And there is something where
it sort of shifts the model into a certain
mindset that can actually be really positive.
I use that tip all the time actually. I
always... When I'm coming up with questions
for interviews and I use it occasionally to
come up with things I haven't thought of,
I actually type, "You're the
world's best podcast interviewer."
Right.
I have Kevin Weil coming on the
pod... Yeah, it actually works.
By the way, back to our other point that we
made a few times. You do do that sometimes
with people. You sort of put them... You frame
things, you get them into a certain mindset,
and the answer is completely different. So I think
there are human analogs of this one more time.
Kevin, this was incredible. I was just
thinking about a way to end this. The
way I feel like... I feel like not only are
you at the cutting edge of the future. You
and the team are kind of actually the edge
that is creating the future. And so it's a
real honor to have you on here and to talk
to you and to hear where you think things
are going and what we need to be thinking
about, so thank you for being here, Kevin.
Oh, thank you so much for having me. I
get to work with the world's best team,
and all credit to them, but really appreciate
you having me on. It's been super fun.
I forgot to ask you the two final
questions. Where can folks find
you if they want to reach out, and
how can listeners be useful to you?
I am @kevinweil, K-E-V-I-N-W-E-I-L on pretty much
every platform. I'm still a Twitter DAU after all
these years. I guess an X DAU, LinkedIn, wherever.
And I think the thing I would love from people,
give me feedback. People are using ChatGPT.
Tell me where it's working really well for you
and where you want us to double down. Tell
me where it's failing. I'm very active and
engaged on Twitter. I love hearing from people,
what's working and what's not, so don't be shy.
And I learned following you helps you figure out
all the stuff that you're launching. You share all
the things that are going out every day, or week,
month, so that's also a benefit. And by the way,
400 million weekly active users all
emailing you feedback. Here we go.
Yes, let's do it.
It's going to work out great. Okay. Well,
thank you, Kevin. Thanks for being here.
All right, man, thanks so much. See you soon.
Bye, everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.