You're CTO of Meta. You
are a co-CEO of Salesforce,
you're chairman of the board at OpenAI. How do
you think the AI market is going to play out?
The whole market is going to go towards agents.
I think the whole market is going to go towards
outcomes-based pricing. It's just so obviously
the correct way to build and sell software.
This makes me think about, I had
Marc Benioff on the podcast. You
guys were co-CEOs. He was extremely agent-pilled.
It's so hard to sell productivity
software, which I learned the hard way.
What's a story that comes to mind when
you think about your biggest mistake?
I was the product manager
for, it was called Google
Local had a pretty tough product
review with Marissa and Larry,
and to not do that well with a link from
the Google homepage is embarrassing.
I think it's really empowering for people to hear
it's possible to succeed in spite
of a massive failure like this.
They gave me another shot to do the V2
of it that resulted in Google Maps. We
got about 10 million people
using it on the first day.
What mindset contributed to you being
successful in such a variety of roles?
Waking up every morning, what is the
most impactful thing I could do today?
Today, my guest is Bret Taylor. Bret is an
absolute legendary builder and founder. He
co-created Google Maps at Google. He co-founded
the social network, FriendFeed invented the like
button and the real-time newsfeed, which he sold
to Facebook. He then became CTO at Facebook. He
then started a productivity company called Quip,
which he sold to Salesforce for $750 million. He
then became co-CEO of Salesforce. He's also
currently chairman of the board at OpenAI.
At one point he was chairman of the board
at Twitter. Today, co-founder and CEO of
Sierra an AI started building agent to help
companies with customer service sales and more.
In our conversation, we cover so much ground,
including what skills and mindsets have most
helped Bret be so successful in so many roles,
why we're all still sleeping on the impact that
agents are going to have on the business world.
How coding is going to change in the coming years,
where the biggest opportunities remain
for startups, lessons on pricing and
go-to-market in AI, the story behind the like
button and so much more. This is a truly epic
conversation with a legendary builder.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget
to subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you become
an annual subscriber of my newsletter, you get
a year free of a bunch of incredible products,
including Replit, Lovable, Bolt, n8n, Linear,
Superhuman, Descript, Wispr Flow, Gamma,
Perplexity, Warp, Granola, Magic Patterns,
Raycast, ChatPRD, Mobbin and more. Check
it out at Lenny'snewsletter.com and click
bundle. With that, I bring you Bret Taylor.
This episode is brought to you by CodeRabbit,
the AI code review platform transforming how
engineering teams ship faster with AI without
sacrificing code quality. Code reviews are
critical, but time-consuming CodeRabbit acts
as your AI co-pilot providing instant code
review comments and potential impacts of every
pull request. Beyond just flagging issues,
CodeRabbit provides one click fix suggestions and
lets you define custom code quality rules using
AST GREP patterns, catching subtle issues that
traditional static analysis tools might miss.
Coderabbit also provides free AI code reviews
directly in the IDE. It's available in VS. Code,
Cursor and Windsurf. CodeRabbit has so far
reviewed more than 10 million PRs installed
on 1 million repositories and is used by over
70,000 open source projects. Get CodeRabbit for
free for an entire year at CodeRabbit.ai
using code, Lenny. That's CodeRabbit.ai.
This episode is brought to you by Basecamp.
Basecamp is the famously straightforward
project management system from 37signals.
Most project management systems are either
inadequate or frustratingly complex, but Basecamp
is refreshingly clear. It's simple to get started,
easy to organize and Basecamp's visual tools
help you see exactly what everyone is working
on and how all work is progressing. Keep all your
files and conversations about projects directly
connected to the projects themselves so that
you always know where stuff is and you're not
constantly switching contexts. Running a business
is hard. Managing your project should be easy.
I've been a long time fan of what 37signals has
been up to and I'm really excited to be sharing
this with you. Sign up for a free account at
basecamp.com/Lenny. Get somewhere with Basecamp.
Bret, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me.
My pleasure. There's so much that I want to
talk about. You've done so many incredible
things over the course of your career. Just
boggles the mind, the things that you've done,
and we're going to talk about a lot of that
sort of stuff, but I want to actually start
with the opposite. I want to talk about a time
that you messed up, a time that you screwed up
in a big way. We have this recurring segment
on the podcast called Fail Corner, and so, I
thought it'd be fun to just start there before we
get into all the great stuff you've done. What's
a story that comes to mind when you think about
maybe your biggest mistake in building a product?
It may not be the biggest, but it was my first
prominent mistake as a product manager at
Google. So for me, it feels big because it was
very formative for me as a product designer.
So I joined Google in late 2002, early 2003, and I
was one of the earliest associate product managers
at the company and first, was working on the
search system, essentially expanding our index
from 1 billion webpages to 10 billion, which was a
big deal at the time. It seems quaint now. Then I
did a decent job and so my boss, Marissa Meyer,
gave me the opportunity to lead a new product
initiative, which was a big bet on me and it was
both an opportunity to do something for Google,
but I was also being pretty scrutinized just
as a young new product manager and the premise
given to me was work on local search.
At the time, the Yellow Pages was still
dominant and well, Google was really good at
searching the web. It wasn't really good for
finding a plumber or a restaurant just because it
wasn't really a huge part of the internet at the
time. So this content wasn't necessarily on the
internet and even if it was, you didn't really
want to find plumbers in Manhattan, you wanted
to find plumbers in San Francisco, if you're
me. And so it was both a technical problem
and a product problem and a content problem.
We launched the first version of that product
that I was the product manager for, was called
Google Local and it was, I'll be a little bit more
critical now than I might've been at the time, but
it was a little bit of a me too version of Yahoo
Yellow Pages, essentially grafting on Yellow Pages
search on top of Google Search and with a properly
crafted query you could see those listings at the
top of your search results but a standalone
site at local.google.com. Actually, it was an
important enough initiative that actually, there
was on the Google homepage, it had Web, Images and
Local was up there as well, so it's got top bill.
I mean you could put almost any link on the Google
homepage and get a lot of traffic to it. And
despite that, it didn't do that well and to not
do that well with a link from the Google homepage
is embarrassing. There's not much one can do more
than giving you that kind of traffic to give
you an add that as a product leader or a product
manager. And the product was fine, it worked, but
it really wasn't differentiated. And in many ways,
I think, again, I think I've had these reflections
more sense than at the time, that I had some of
the time, but why use this instead of Yahoo Yellow
Pages? But more than anything else, why use this
instead of the Yellow Pages? It was a digital
version of something that had come before. Had a
pretty tough product review with Marissa and Larry
and others and it was fine. I wasn't about to get
fired or something, but it was, I don't know, the
shine on my reputation was waning a little bit.
And they gave me another shot to do a V2 of it and
I got the impression it wasn't like my last shot,
but I certainly was feeling a little dejected from
going from a hot shot, new PM to a new thing. So,
we spent a lot of time thinking about how can you
make something that's just much more compelling
and not just a digital version of the Yellow
Pages and not just so similar to some of the
other products out there. And that ended up being
the thread that we pulled that resulted in Google
Maps. We had licensed from MapQuest, the ability
to put this little map next to the search results,
it was always the ugliest part of the product
and we always made these backhanded comments
about it internally and we spent a lot
of time saying, what if we inverted the
hierarchy here and made the map the canvas?
We ended up finding Lars and Jens Rasmussen
who had been working on this Windows mapping
product and we got them into the company and
started exploring this space and it ended up
where, through that exploration we ended up
integrating a lot of different products. We
ended up integrating mapping local search,
driving directions, like all of these products at
the time were actually separate product categories
and ended up with something that redefined the
industry and certainly my career. But it took,
I think for me as a product leader, it
changed the way I think about product just
because there's feature and functionality and
then there's like why should I use this thing
in the first place? And it was notable,
there was a couple of interesting moments.
When we launched Google Maps we got about
10 million people using it on the first day,
which at that scale of the internet at the
time was huge. And then in August of 2005,
we integrated satellite imagery from a recent
acquisition called Keyhole, which became Google
Earth and we got 90 million people using it on
the same day. Everyone wanted to look at the
top of their house when the imagery came out.
And it was really interesting because there's
so many subtle product lessons in there. First
is, I think as you have these new technologies,
rather than literally digitizing what came before,
if you can create an entirely new experience,
it answers the question for a new customer,
why should I give this the time of day? And so,
really disassembling the Lego set and reassembling
into something new rather than just digitizing
what was there before. Certainly, that
was the lesson I think in Google Maps,
really was native to the platform in
a way that a paper map couldn't be and
that was a really meaningful breakthrough.
And then with satellite imagery, it honestly
wasn't the most important part of Google Maps,
but it was the sizzle to the steak and it created,
I don't think the term viral was a thing
people said back then, but it created a
viral moment. We were on Saturday Night Live,
which is the coolest thing. Andy Samberg in,
I think it was called Lazy Sunday rapped about
Google Maps and Lars and I were texting each
other. We did it. We're on Saturday Live.
Mission accomplished. And it was also showing
that as you're there thinking about products,
there's the why you decide to use a product and
then what is the enduring value. And those are
deeply related but not all the same thing. And
I just learned so many lessons that I took with
me for every subsequent product that I worked on.
That is an awesome story. One I think
it's really empowering for people to hear,
even you Bret, who I'm going to
share all the successes you've had,
have had a massive failure with the CEO of
Google [inaudible 00:11:30] just like Bret,
you screwed up. And it was such a big bet. So
one, just it's possible to succeed as you have
succeeded in spite of a massive failure like this.
And then some of the product lessons you shared,
just to highlight a few of these things
because I think this is great, is just
you will often not win if you just make something
that's a better copy of something else, what you
want to look for is something that is an entirely
new experience, something that's differentiated,
something that's a lot more compelling. Let's
flip to talk about what you've learned from
actually being very successful at a lot of things.
So I was looking at your resume and you basically
have been very successful at every level of
the career ladder and in such a huge variety
of roles. So let me just read a few of these
things for folks that aren't super familiar
with your background. You were CTO of Meta, you
were co-CEO of Salesforce, you're also CPO and
COO at Salesforce. At Google, you joined as an
associate product manager where you famously,
you didn't mention this but you rebuilt Google
Maps on weekend. We're not going to talk about
that. You're chairman of the board at OpenAI. You
were chairman of the board at Twitter. You've also
founded three different companies, one social
network, one productivity docs company called
Quip, and now, Sierra. Fun fact, at FriendFeed
you invented the like button and I don't know if
people know that and also just the newsfeed, I'll
just throw that out there to give you some credit.
So you're basically an associate product manager,
an IC product manager, an engineer, CPO, COO, CTO,
CEO of three different companies including
a public company. Very rare that somebody
is successful at all these types of roles and
all these levels. So, let me just ask you this
question. What mindsets or habits or just ways of
working have you worked on building in yourself
that you think have most contributed to you being
successful in such a variety of roles and levels?
Yeah. It's actually something I am proud of.
I like the fact I've worn different hats. It's
actually amusing when I meet colleagues that I've
known from one of those jobs, they'll often think
of me through the lens of that job. And so, I'll
go to meet folks from Facebook and they think of
me largely as an engineer. I'll meet folks from
Google, they think me largely as a product person.
At Salesforce, a lot of the folks there interacted
with me as like a, lack of a better word, a suit,
the boss. And I'm not sure they think of me as an
engineer at all, even though I was still probably
coding on the weekends for fun. And one of
the things that is a principle for me is to
have a really flexible view of my own identity. I
probably would self-describe as an engineer, but
more broadly I think of myself as a builder and I
like to build products and I think companies are
one of the most effective ways to build products.
There's also things like open source, but I think
I'm a huge believer in the confluence
of technology and capitalism to produce
just incredible outcomes for customers.
And as a consequence, I think to really
build something of significance, I think to be
a great founder, you really need to be able to
not have such a ossified view of your identity
that you can't transform into what the company
needs you to be at that point. And every founder
you'll talk to, one day, I think selling is a
big part of being a founder. You have to sell
investors on wanting to invest in your company.
You have to sell candidates on wanting to work
at your company. You have to sell customers
to want to use the product that your customer
produces. You have to have good design taste,
not just for your product but for your marketing
and essentially, soliciting your customers.
You have to have good engineering. If you're
building a technology company, the technology
comes first. It's why this industry is so
transformative. I probably credit, and I've told
this story before, but I'm very grateful for her,
but I probably credit Sheryl Sandberg for really
changing the way I approach new jobs. The story,
and I might be embellishment a little bit, but I
think it's broadly accurate. So I had just become
the chief technology officer of Facebook and when
I first got the job, it was the flavor of CTO or
that relatively small group reporting into me,
but contributed almost as a very senior architect
on a number of projects. And then at some point,
Mark Zuckerberg reorganized the company and
split it into a bunch of different groups.
I ended up with a very large group, 100 under
me and I was essentially running our platform
and mobile groups, products, design engineering.
So I went from a handful of reports to, I don't
know, over 1,000 or something. It was a big group.
And it was the largest management job. I had
become a manager at Google, but a modest team. And
so, I was doing okay but not great. And I had this
moment where Sheryl saw me, I think I was editing
a presentation for a partner just because the
presentation I got didn't meet my quality bar and
I was editing it and griping about it. She pulled
me into a room and gave me talking to a little bit
about holding my team to as high of a standard as
I have. If someone wasn't meeting my expectations,
what was my plan to manage them out of the company
or... Just giving me management one-on-one.
And she's a remarkable mentor in the sense
she can give you feedback that's very
direct and often, a bit uncomfortable,
but you know she cares about you. And so it was
the type of feedback you listen to. I went home
that night and I was stewing on it and not very
happy. I was like, you get naturally a little
defensive in those moments. Is that really true?
Am I really fucking it up or is she overreacting?
And then I woke up the next day, I was like, "No,
she's right." And I had realized this subconscious
limiter that was limiting my success in the job,
which is, I was trying to conform the job to the
things I thought I liked to do. So, I was spending
a lot of my time on some product and technology
things that I was passionate about, thinking I'm
the boss. I should focus on what I want to focus
on instead of thinking about, okay, I'm running
the mobile and platform teams at Facebook. What's
the most important thing to do today to make
our mobile and developer platform successful?
And when I reframed the job that way, I did
different things. And the thing that was the
biggest pleasant surprise to me was I liked
it. I thought I liked engineering and product,
but in fact, when I changed an organization
and it turned out to be more successful,
I derived a great deal of joy from seeing that
success. Our developer platform had a lot of
partners and when there was an issue there and
I'd spend time on partnerships and it worked
and our platform became healthier, the partner
became more successful. I took pride in that
success and then I just started being better
at my job and I realized that the actual act
of engineering or product design or all the things
I thought I liked, what I really liked is impact.
And so, that conversation led to my waking up
every morning, sometimes literally, but certainly,
in the broadest sets of the words saying, "What
is the most impactful thing I can do today?" And
really thinking almost like, if you had an
external board of advisors telling you what
are the things where if you focus on them, you
can maximize the likelihood that what you're
trying to achieve will happen? Sometimes, it's
recruiting, sometimes, it's product, sometimes,
it's engineering, sometimes, it's sales. And I've
become much more self-reflective just about what
is important to work on. And I have become much
more receptive to doing things that I previously
would've said aren't my favorite things to do
because I derive so much joy from having an
impact that I enjoy a lot more things now. And
so, I really credit Sheryl, I'm so grateful.
And actually, it's interesting, I think a lot
about this when I give feedback to people now,
just those moments that can change the trajectory
of your career. I give her all the credit for it.
There's so many people that share
stories of Sheryl Sandberg giving
them advice and that changing
their life. What a mensch.
Yeah.
My biggest takeaway from this, which
is this question of what is the most
impactful thing I could do today? Such a powerful
heuristic just to keep in mind. To your point,
you may realize you don't want to be doing sales
or hiring, but if that's the most impactful thing
and you end up doing it, you may realize I like
this and I'm good at this and have thought about-
Can I double click on that though for a second?
Absolutely.
I think it's really hard. One of the
dangers for founders and product managers,
but I think particularly for founders
is incorrect storytelling. People don't
like my product because of X. And if you tell
that to yourself and you tell it to your team,
all of a sudden, it goes from being an intuition
to being a fact. Well, you better hope you're
right because if you orient your strategy
around fixing a problem and you're wrong,
your company's going to fail. So why did you lose
a deal? You could talk to the salesperson who is
on the account or perhaps maybe a product
manager was involved in the conversation.
It's very important to have intellectual
honesty in those moments because you could
say something like, "Oh, they didn't buy
it because the platform cost too much."
And that's something a salesperson might say.
Maybe the real reason is they didn't actually
see much value in your platform. So it was
communicated to the salesperson as it was
too expensive. But in fact, the problem was
product differentiation. And you could end up
going into a discussion on pricing when in fact,
there was a much deeper, much harder problem to
solve there. But just like when you break up
with someone, you don't say, it's because I
don't like you anymore. You say it's not you,
it's me. You say all these pleasantries because
we're all social animals and you want to
be pleasant with the people around you.
So literally taking what a customer says or what a
user says in a focus group or a usability study is
rarely correct. It often is related to what the
truth is, but it's very important to get right.
And so, I think one of the things I've observed
with first time founders in particular is you're
often a single issue voter based on your skillset.
So if you're a great engineer, the answer to
almost every problem in your business is
engineering. If you're a product designer,
the answer almost to the proverbial redesign,
I joke, it's like the dead cap balance of a
consumer product like this next redesign will fix
all of our problems. I don't know if it's ever,
ever worked. And then I met a lot of entrepreneurs
who come from a business development background,
they're always thinking about partnerships and
oh, if we just get this partnership done for
this distribution channel, everything's going to
change. And I think it's really important when
you're a founder to be self-aware that you will
naturally, subconsciously pick the thing that is
your strength, your superpower as a solution to
more problems. And in fact, if you think that's
a solution to your problem, it may be right,
but you probably by default should question it.
If you think the thing that you've been doing
your whole career is the way to fix your problem,
it's at least 30% likely that you've chosen
that because of comfort and familiarity not
truth. And so, I think one of the skills I think
is, it really goes around to do you have a good
co-founder? Do you have a good leadership team?
If you're a product manager, you're a partner
in engineering, you're a partner in marketing,
you really want to have very real conversations
to ensure that you're actually working on the
actual correct thing. And I think it's easy
to say what's the most impactful thing to do
today? My guess, if a lot of people try that,
they'll lie to themselves more often than
not. And it's a very challenging question
to answer. The question's interesting. Being able
to answer it accurately is actually the hard part.
This feels like such an important lesson
you've learned. Is there an example that
comes to mind where you learned this the
hard way where you actually ended up-
Oh, yeah. You just want to spend this whole
thing on my failures, but I'm fine with that.
You've had too much success.
Frontier was my first company. At our peak we
had 12 employees, 12 of the best people I've ever
worked with. Started the company with Jim Norris,
who's an engineer I've known since Stanford and
Paul Buhite and Sanjeev Singh who Paul started
Gmail. Sanjeev was the first engineer at Gmail,
so we had the Google Maps people and
Gmail people. It was a pretty awesome
founding team. We made a social network, as you
said. We invented a lot of concepts that became
popular in the newsfeed. We invented the like
button. It was really neat. It was a fun time.
We were only really popular in Turkey, Italy and
Iran, and at one point, we were blocked in Iran,
so we were only popular in Turkey and Italy
and Silicon Valley. To this day, actually a
lot of folks in Silicon Valley are like, "I
love FriendFeed." I'm like, that's awesome.
It wasn't really a successful business. We
were a follower-oriented social network,
not a friendship-oriented social network,
which meant a lot of our content was more
like X or Twitter than it is Facebook in that
respect. And a lot of sharing newspaper articles,
interests, scientific communities, things like
that. And there was a period when Twitter,
which was one of our competitors at the
time, that there was a lot more social
networks at the time. I am probably screwing
this up a little bit. I think Obama, Ashton
Kutcher and Oprah Winfrey all went on Twitter
in a summer and we just got our ass kicked.
And it was a great example of you... I think
11 of those 12 people were engineers and we
were just making product and I think it was
Biz Stone. If you talk to the Twitter folks,
they could give you the history on this, but
I think Biz was really focused on getting
celebrities and public figures onto Twitter, which
is totally obvious. If you have a social service
that's oriented towards following people, put some
people on there worth following and instead, we
were exclusively focused on polishing the product.
And we actually, I think at our peak of
popularity, we were very confident just, I think
it was a time when Twitter had the fail whale
and it was down half the time and people couldn't
even use it. And our product, we were innovating
faster, we had more features, people liked it and
we were up 100% of the time and we totally lost
for no reason related to product at all. And it
was an example of, I think somewhat famously not
a lot of great entrepreneurs have come out
of Google because Google was so successful,
I think it's hard as a product manager to see
distribution and product design and even business
model when you have AdWords and money's raining
from the sky. There wasn't as much scrutiny and I
think folks like the PayPal Mafia I think learned
a lot more about entrepreneurialism than a typical
PM at Google. So, we're just getting punched
in the face and learning this the hard way.
And so, that was probably the most prominent
example of it and I think we probably did have
a... I can tell you all the flaws of that
product, but I don't think that was the
reason why we lost. There's a lot of reasons. I
think there was a lot of flaws of the product,
but it was a lot of other stuff. And so, I've
learned, accumulated these skills over time,
but I say the hard part of that question is
answering it correctly, is it's hard when you
don't have experience in something, than to have
intuition in it. So I think if there's probably a
structural flaw, it wasn't that... I don't know
if I could have figured out how to reach out to
Ashton Kutcher [inaudible 00:27:28], it's
not he's on my Rolodex. But I probably
wasn't soliciting advice from the right people.
I think that what's great about the technology
industry is there's a lot of advice. Choosing whom
you listen to is actually quite difficult, but
I think we're somewhat myopic. We're in our own
little world, creating this product and we weren't
asking people from the outside in to say, what
are you seeing that could go wrong? What are you
seeing that could go right? What are you seeing in
the industry that we're not doing that you think
we might want to do? And this is why boards are
important. This is why finding the right advisors,
the advisors will actually tell you what you not
[inaudible 00:28:09] want to hear, but you need to
hear. I think that was probably the missing part.
I'm not sure I was great at market at the time,
but if I had solicited the right advice, I could
have learned that that was a shortcoming. And I
think that was a deep lesson I took from that. I'm
a huge believer in boards and getting good advice.
Any heuristics or advice for people to
know whose advice to listen to? What do
you pay attention to when you're like, okay,
ignore this person but listen to this person?
Yeah, that one's tough. It does come down to good
judgment and being judge of people's character.
One thing that is particularly hard is there's
not a strong correlation between the confidence
with which someone expresses an opinion
and the quality of that opinion. I don't
want to say it's inversely correlated, but
that's funny, with all the podcasts out now,
if there's topics I know a lot about, sometimes
the most eloquent, confident statements about
things I know a lot about, are the least accurate
and it sounds extremely persuasive. And so,
it does require very good judgment. One thing is
I think, not just asking for advice but asking
people, who should I talk to get good advice? And
you'll find some common answers there and that's
often a really strong signal of good judgment.
And then one thing I found is when you ask for
advice, don't just ask what to do but why. Be
an obnoxious two-year-old kid, why? Why? Why?
Why? And really try to understand the framework
that someone is using to give you advice. The
interesting thing about advice is people are often
extrapolating from relatively few experiences.
So they will say, never do this or always do
that. And it's because they had one experience
where something backfired or something could have
gone better if they had done it. So it's a useful
anecdote, but if you don't ask why and understand
they had one experience and here's what happened,
it can come across as a rule when in fact,
it's [inaudible 00:30:08] data and if you
ask advice of three people and they all have
very similar interactions, you can create
a first principles framework from which that
advice emerges. And when you start applying it,
you're applying it with a degree of nuance that
you couldn't if you're just following a rule. So,
I think one is, it does come down to good
judgment, I think. I don't know how to teach that.
I'm a huge believer in good judgment. It's
one of the things I hire for. I just think
that's something that probably comes from a
mix of self perfection. You really need to
hold yourselves accountable as an entrepreneur,
as a product manager. If you made a bad decision,
spend time reflecting on it, number one. And
really, try to understand why and try to always
improve your judgment. I think at the end of the
day, that is why you are a good entrepreneur,
a good product manager. And number two, when
you get advice, really understand where it's
coming from and why so that you can create your
own independent view of where that advice came
from and recognize that no one's advice is
statistically significant or very rarely is
it. If you're getting advice on investing from
Warren Buffett, yeah, okay, it's statistically
significant, but most advice is like something
happened to you once and you have regrets.
I love that you're like, I don't know if I
have a great answer then you just give us
an incredible answer to this question. I want to
go in a different direction. You mentioned that
you describe yourself as an engineer. I know I
heard you code to relax still. Let me just ask
you this question, something a lot of people in
college are thinking about. Do you think it still
makes sense to learn to code? Do you think this
will significantly change in the next few years?
I do still think studying computer science
is a different answer than learning to code,
but I would say I still think it's extremely
valuable to study computer science. I say that
because I think computer science is more than
coding. If you understand things like Big O
notation or complexity theory or study algorithms
and why a randomized algorithm works and why two
algorithms with the same Big O complexity, one can
then practice perform better than others and why a
cache miss matters and just all these little...
There's a lot more to coding than writing the
code. The reason I think that is I do think the
act of creating software is going to transform
from typing into a terminal or typing into
Visual Studio code to operating a code-generating
machine. I think that is the future of creating
software. But I think operating a code-generating
machine requires systems thinking and I think that
computer science, there are other disciplines as
well, but computer science is a wonderful major to
learn systems thinking and at the end of the day,
AI will facilitate creating this software.
We may do a lot more in the next few years
we can't even imagine, but your job as the
operator of that code-generating machine is
to make a product or to solve a problem and you
really need to have great systems thinking and
you're going to be managing this machine that's
doing a lot of the tedious work of making the
button or connecting to the network. But as you're
thinking of the intersection of a technology and
a business problem, you're trying to affect a
system that will solve that problem at scale
for your customers and that systems thinking is
always the hardest part of creating products.
I'll just give you, it's this cheesy simple
example, but I think it's representative.
At Facebook, we spent a lot of time designing
the newsfeed and if you ever had a really,
really good designer and they showed you at the
time, a Photoshop mock-up of the newsfeed, it was
just all as beautiful. The photos, the family was
happy and the photo was a perfect photo and the
posts were all perfectly grammatically correct and
of a completely normal length and the comments and
there was the like... Everything was just perfect.
And then you'd implement that design and you'd
look at your own newsfeed and it looked like shit
because it turns out not everyone's photos were
made by a professional photographer. The posts
were all these different lengths. The comments
were like, you suck and... All that stuff.
And then all of a sudden you realize that
designing a newsfeed, Photoshop is the easy part.
You need to actually design a system that produces
both in content and visual design, like a
delightful experience given input you don't
control. And that's a system, it's sort of a
design and it's just, what we did practically,
I am sure it's changed a lot since I left in
2012, but we made a system so designers had
to show their newsfeed designs with real
newsfeed data that was messy rather than
anything artificial because I think it
forced the process to be more realistic.
But I say that because I think that whether
AI is writing code or doing the design or
doing all these other things, you need to learn
how to have a system in your head. You need to
understand the basics of what's hard and what's
easy and what's possible and what's impossible.
And AI can help you do that too, by the way. But
I do think that's a really useful skill. I think
in general, with the advent of AI agents and AI
approaching super intelligence in certain domains,
I think the tools with which we do our job will
change a lot. I think it's very important to have
a very loose attachment to the way we do our
jobs and that story that we won't talk about
when I rewrote Google Maps, everyone talks
about that story and I think it's because of
Paul [inaudible 00:35:57] who told it on some
podcasts and that's where it made the rounds.
I think that's going to end up this vestige of the
past, almost like the human calculators at NASA
before the computers were invented, like wow, a
person was a calculator? Whoa, that's fun. Tell me
that story. I think just what I was good at will
no longer be useful in the future or certainly not
valuable in the future and that's okay. So I think
we need to have a really loose view of it, but the
idea that you shouldn't study these disciplines,
it's like people say, I don't want to study math
because I'm not going to use it in my career for
X. Well, studying maths is quite important. It
teaches you how to think. It teaches you how the
world works, physics, math, and I think computer
science especially, at least the foundations of
it, will continue to be the foundations of how
we build software and understanding that when
you're interacting particularly with something
that's smarter than you, producing code you might
not completely understand how you constrain it and
how you get it to produce these outcomes. I think
it will require a lot of sophistication actually.
That's such a great answer. There's
this always sense of this binary,
should I learn to code or not? And your point
here is learn to understand how engineering
works and how systems work and what your
code does and how it all interconnects,
but the way you actually do the coding at your
desk will change significantly. This reminds me of
something you mentioned on a podcast recently.
This idea that you think there's going to,
or there should be a new programming language
that is more designed for LLMs versus humans.
Can you just talk about that because I think
a lot of people aren't thinking about that?
I don't know if it's a language, I would call it a
programming system because I think language might
be too limited. My reductive version of the
past, what 40 years of computers maybe more,
is we created the hardware for computers, then we
created punch cards, which is the way in the late
'70s you would tell a computer what to do or
maybe mid to late '70s. Then we invented early
operating systems and time-sharing systems from
the invention of things like Unix at Bell Labs and
Berkeley, you ended up with the C programming
language, Fortran and a lot of higher level
programming languages. I think Fortran and then C.
And we moved up the layers of abstraction. No one
does punch cards anymore, obviously. Few people
write assembly language. Some people write C,
some people write REST. But a lot of people write
Python and TypeScript and things like that. And as
we've invented more and more abstractions, we've
made it easier to do high-leverage things. So,
if you look at how remarkable Google was back
in the day or Google Maps, you could probably
give a lot of react programmers the task of make
a draggable map now and I think a lot of people
could do it. That was true RND back in the day.
When Salesforce was created in 1998, just putting
a database in the cloud was hard and that alone
was a technical moat that is now trivial with
Amazon Web Services and that technical moat is
comically narrow, but the product moat is quite
large. I think that if the act of writing code
is going from something that is very costly to
the marginal cost of that going to zero, how many
of the abstractions that we've built are based on
human program or productivity? I think a ton.
I always laugh that I assume Python is probably
the most common generated code just because
of how much it's in the training data and
data scientists love Python and I love Python too.
It's such a comically bad thing for AI to generate
just because it's one of the most inefficient
programming languages of all time. If you know
the global interpreter lock and just slow. And
I've written a lot of high-scale web services and
it's just quite slow and it's very hard to verify.
It's not as bad as Perl, but if you have a big
Python program, how many errors will you find
at runtime versus before releasing it? So,
Python was designed to be very ergonomic,
almost looked like pseudo code for humans,
for me to write code in a delightful way. That's
why data scientists love it so much. So as we move
to a world where let's just postulate, and
I'm not sure this will be completely true,
that we're not going to write a lot of code
as people. We're going to be operating these
code-generating machines. We probably don't care
how ergonomic the programming language is. What we
care about is when this machine generates code, do
we know that it did what we wanted it to do? And
if it doesn't do we want it to do, can we change
it easily? I think there's a lot of insights in
programming languages that could serve this.
So Rust I think, is interesting because if
I asked you to look at a C program and say,
"Does it leak memory?" You probably couldn't
do it that well just because it's really hard
and if it's a very, a million line C program,
it's going to be very, very hard. If I asked you
to verify that a Rust program doesn't leak memory,
you would just have to compile it. And
because it has compile time, memory safety,
just the act of compiling successfully tells
you that's true. I think we need more things
like that because if an AI is generating this
code, by definition, if you have to read every
line that is going to be the limiting factor for
producing the code or worse, you're just not going
to read every line and you're going to emit a
bunch of unsafe unverified code into the wild.
And so, the question is how do you enable humans
to have as much leverage as possible? Which means
using computers to do the work on your behalf. You
could have obviously the simplest form of this,
is AI supervising AI and doing code reviews and
that's great. Certainly, self-reflection is a
really effective way of improving the robustness
of an AI system. But I do think if it doesn't
matter how tedious it is to write the code,
you could probably layer on some techniques
that are out of fashion, like formal verification,
unit testing, other things. And if you layer all
these on, I'm thinking about it as, I as a...
It's like the guy in the matrix with the green
letters coming down, how can I make something so
I as a operator of the code generating machine can
produce incredibly complex scale software,
incredibly quickly and know that it works?
If you start with that as your design center,
I think you'd probably changed the languages,
you'd probably changed the systems, you'd
probably change all these things and you're
probably going to bring to bear a lot of things.
And what's really fun about it is you can loosen
a lot of constraints, like coding is free.
Okay, so that's neat. With that in mind,
what do you want to do? What would be best suited
for the language, the compiler for testing,
for self-reflection, for supervisor models,
all these things. I think that's more of a
programming system than a language, but I
think when we create something like that,
it can really enable creators, builders to create
incredibly robust, incredibly complex systems.
And I'm super excited about VibeCoding, but I
don't know generating a prototype has been the
limiting factor in software ever. It's actually
building increasingly complex systems and actually
changing them with agility. If you look at the
famous Netscape one to Netscape two rewrite,
somewhat, a lot of people attribute that
to part of their failure against Internet
Explorer. It's like making these things is not
hard. Maintaining them is hard and ensuring
they're robust is hard. And I think we're
in the very early phases of defining what
this new system for developing software looks
like and I'm very excited to see what emerges.
I feel like we're definitely living in the
future when someone like you is suggesting
that we build a matrix like experience and
that's going to be potentially the future
of coding and building. I can't wait for that. It
feels like a great opportunity and a fun project.
This episode is brought to you by
Vanta and I'm very excited to have
Christina Cacioppo CEO and co-founder Vanta
joining me for this very short conversation.
Great to be here. Big fan of
the podcast and the newsletter.
Vanta is a long time sponsor of the show,
but for some of our newer listeners,
what does Vanta do and who is it for?
Sure. So we started Vanta in 2018 focused
on founders helping them start to build out
their security programs and get credit
for all of that hard security work with
compliance certifications like SOC 2 or ISO
2701. Today, we currently help over 9,000
companies including some start-up household
names like Atlassian Ramp and LangChain,
start and scale their security programs
and ultimately, build trust by automating
compliance, centralizing GRC, and
accelerating security reviews.
That is awesome. I know from experience
that these things take a lot of time and
a lot of resources and nobody
wants to spend time doing this.
That is very much our experience, but
before the company and to some extent,
during it. But the idea is
with automation, with AI,
with software, we are helping customers
build trust with prospects and customers
in an efficient way. And our joke, we started
this compliance company so you don't have to.
We appreciate you for doing
that. And you have a special
discount for listeners. They can get
$1,000 off Vanta at vanta.com/lenny.
That's V-A-N-T-A .com/lenny for $1,000
off Vanta. Thanks for that, Christina.
Thank you.
Okay. One more question along these lines and then
I want to zoom out on just where AI is heading and
something I love to ask folks like you that
are at the cutting edge of AI is what you're
teaching your kids. I know you have kids,
I feel like the world is going to be very
different when they grow up. What are you
encouraging them to learn that you think is
different maybe from previous generations to help
them be successful in a world of AI abundance?
I don't know if I'm teaching them
differently, but I'm really trying
to encourage them to make AI a part of
their lives. I was reflecting actually
when I took the AP calculus exams in '97, '98 AB
and BC, I could use a graphing calculator. And
I haven't done this research I was meaning to
plug this into ChatGPT before our conversation,
but I'll do it after. Did the calculus exam change
before and after they allowed the calculator in
the exam? I assume it did. But essentially,
to when you allow the calculator in the exam,
you need to make sure that none of the questions
benefit people for having a calculator or not,
which actually forces you to rethink the
problems to test calculus knowledge that
don't benefit from like road arithmetic or the
other things you can do on a graphing calculator.
I think that a lot of education doesn't
presume you have a super intelligence in
your pocket. And so, if you ask someone to
write an essay on a book that they read,
you could probably hallucinate one pretty easily
from one of the big providers like ChatGPT. And
maybe if you are skilled enough that prompting,
maybe even your teacher won't know it's written
by an AI. So what do you do? How do you teach kids
differently? It's really hard for teachers right
now because I think we haven't gone through the
transition of adding calculators to the exams. So,
I think a lot of the mechanisms we have to
evaluate students are broken by the existence
of ChatGPT and the like. So I think we're in
a very awkward phase, but I think we can still
both teach kids how to think and teach kids how to
learn. And I think our education system can catch
up and I actually think these models can be one of
the most effective educational tools in history.
I don't know if you're a visual learner or reading
learner. I like to read. I didn't love going to
lectures. I don't learn that well from them. I
like to read the book and if you have a teacher
who doesn't teach in your style, you can now
go home and ask ChatGPT to teach you in another
mechanism. My kids use ChatGPT to quiz them before
a test. You can use audio mode or chat mode. It's
better than cue cards. My daughter took home a
Shakespeare book, she took a picture of a page she
didn't understand and ChatGPT explained it to her
way better than I would've as well. I think every
child in this world has a personalized tutor that
can teach them in the way that they best learn,
visually, over audio, reading. We have a
platform that can test you, that can quiz you.
I think it's really an amplifier of agency.
I think the kids who have agency, who have
aspirations to learn something, I think you have
what is the best combination of every teacher
you've ever had and these models and you can use
it. So with my kids, my oldest daughter learned
how to code and she was making a website and every
time she had a question for me, I would just make
her use ChatGPT. Not because I was trying to
be an obnoxious father, but I'm like she needs
to learn to use this tool because it's amazing.
So, I really am trying to have them learn how to
use it constructively in their lives. But all
that said, I just feel a ton of empathy for
public school teachers right now. It's very hard
because the technology is moving faster than our
educational system. And I think particularly
as it relates to evaluation, it's just really
challenging for teachers right now. And I worry
because these technologies amplify agency, the
opposite can also be true. If you are a student
trying to not learn something, I think these tools
probably provide a lot of mechanisms to avoid
it as well. And so, I think there's a challenge
for parents and teachers and I think we're
going to end up with a handful of years here.
But I brought up the calculus AP exam because
obviously, a graphing calculator is not ChatGPT,
don't get me wrong. But I think we've been
able to figure out a way to conform homework
and in-class learning and tests around
the technologies available to us fairly
successfully to date. And I'm fairly confident
we'll figure it out and I think it's going to...
And on the much more positive side, I don't
know, I went to public schools, I don't know
if you did too. You end up with some pretty bad
teachers at times and now, you have an outlet.
You don't need to be the rich kid who can afford
a tutor anymore to get tutoring. If you are a kid
who excels in math and your school doesn't have
advanced statistics classes, well, now you do.
So I think this is just an incredibly
democratizing force with kids who have
agency and I think that's very exciting. I'm
hopeful that there's a 11-year-old right now
who's going to start a really amazing company
10 years from now whose ChatGPT is going to
be their primary tutor that led to that
outcome. And I think that's pretty cool.
I have a two-year-old and it feels
like there's a new milestone of,
there's like when to give them a phone,
when to give them, I don't know, Snapchat,
whatever kids use these days and then
it's like when to give them their first
ChatGPT account. Well no, I wonder
how soon that's supposed to happen.
I think my personal take is, it's different than
the former two. I don't think mobile phones are
great in school or great for kids and I personally
advocate for waiting a long time. But I think that
ChatGPT is more like Google search and it's
one thing to have a device in your pocket
that's addictive and has push notifications, but
it's another thing to use AI to learn. And so,
I think the two are different. And I really think
of AI fundamentally as a utility. I don't think a
lot of parents before ChatGPT said, "When should I
let my kid use Google search?" That's a different
type of tool. I think thinking of it like that
is the way I think about these technologies.
Is the form factor for your kids like
an iPad or a laptop or something?
Yeah. They use the computer on the desk.
Got it. All right. Good tips. This is good for me
to learn all these things as my kid ages. Okay,
I'm going to zoom out and let's talk about
business strategy AI. One of the biggest questions
a lot of founders think about these days is just
where should I build? What will foundational model
companies not squash and do themselves? Being
someone building a very successful AI business
and also being on the board of OpenAI, feel like
you have a really unique perspective on what is
probably a good idea and it's probably not a good
idea. How do you think the AI market is going to
play out and where do you think founders
should focus and also just try to avoid?
I think there's three segments of the AI market
that will end up fairly meaningful markets and
then I'll end with how I think it's going to
play out. So first is the frontier model market
or foundation model market. I think this will end
up the small handful of hyperscalers and really
big labs just like the cloud infrastructure
as a service market. And the reason for that
is that creating a frontier model is entirely
a function of CapEx. And you need a company
with huge amounts of CapEx capacity to build one
of these models. All of the companies that were
startups that tried to do this have already
been consolidated or almost all of them,
inflection, adapt, character and others. And
I think there doesn't appear to be a viable
business model for a startup because of the
amount of CapEx required and there's just not
enough fundraising runway to get to escape
velocity. And also, the models deteriorate
in value fairly quickly as an asset class.
And so, you need just a lot of scale to make
a return on the investment for a model that
deteriorates in value so quickly. So, I think
that's going to end up probably no entrepreneur
should build a frontier model. That's my take.
Unless you're Elon.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. He's different. And he has the
capacity to raise billions in capital and my
guess is most of your other listeners don't, and
then he is the greatest of all time for reason
and he's different. You don't compare yourself to
him. The other part of the market is the tooling,
and I think there's a lot of folks selling
pickaxes in the Gold Rush. This is data labeling,
services. This is data platforms, it's eval tools.
More specialized models like 11 Labs has a great
set of voice models that a lot of companies use
that are really high quality and it's like if
you're trying to be successful in AI, what are
the different tools and services that you need?
There is some risk to the tooling market
because it's pretty close to the sun. So,
if you look at the infrastructure as a service
market and the cloud tooling market like the
Confluent and Databricks and Snowflake, a lot of
the Amazon and Azure and others have competing
products in those areas because they're very
adjacent to the infrastructure itself and every
infrastructure provider is trying to differentiate
by moving up the stack and you're right there.
So, there's some real meaningful companies as I
mentioned, like Snowflake, Databricks, Confluent
and others, but there's a lot of others that were
obviated by technology from the infrastructure
providers themselves. So those companies probably
are the most at risk for a developer day from one
of these big foundation model companies releasing
exactly what they do. So there's probably a lot
of people who need your tool, but the question
will be if or when is probably the right way to
think about it, one of these large infrastructure
providers introduces a competitor, why will people
continue to choose you? So it's a good market
but it's a little bit close to the end as I said.
Then there's the applied AI market. I think this
will play out for companies who build agents. I
think agent is the new app. I think that's going
to be the product form factor. There's companies
like Sierra, we help companies build agents to
answer the phone or answer the chat for customer
experience and customer service. There's companies
like Harvey that make agents for both a legal,
paralegal profession, anti-trust reviews,
reviewing contracts etc, etc. There's companies
that do content marketing. There's companies that
do supply chain analysis. I think this is like
the software as a service market. They'll probably
be higher margin companies because you're selling
something that achieves a business outcome
as opposed to being a byproduct of the models
themselves. They will almost certainly pay taxes
down to the model providers, which is why those
model providers will end up extremely large scale
but probably slightly lower margin and I think the
market for them will be probably less technical.
If you think about the purest form of software as
a service, it's not like you ask what database
do you use? It's really about the feature and
function. I think that's where agents will go. I
think it's going to be more about product than it
is about technology over time. Just going back to
my metaphor, in 1998 when Mark and Parker started
Salesforce, just getting that database running
in the cloud was like a technical achievement.
Nowadays, no one asks about that because you can
just spin up a database in AWS or Azure and it's
like no problem. I think today, orchestrating
an agentic process on top of the models,
sounds really fancy and it's really hard and all
that stuff. I'm pretty sure that's going to be
easy in three or four years. It's just like
just as the technology improves. And so,
over time you say, what is an agent
company? Well, it looks a little bit
like [inaudible 00:57:30] as a service.
You talk a little bit less about how you
deal with the models in the same way modern
SaaS, few people ask what database you use,
but you'll probably ask a lot about the
workflows and what business outcomes that
you're driving. Are you generating leads for a
sales team? Are you minimizing your procurement
spend? Whatever value you're providing,
it's going to slowly evolve towards that.
I'm very excited. I don't think startups
should probably build foundation models.
But you can shoot your shot if you have
a vision for the future, go for it. But I
think it's probably a challenging market that's
already consolidated. I'm very excited about the
other two markets. I'm particularly excited as
building agents becomes easier, to see a lot of
long tail agent companies come out. I was looking
at a website for the top 50 software companies in
the stock market and obviously, the top five are
the big, big boom ones like Microsoft, Amazon,
Google, all that, but the next 50 are all SaaS
companies and some of them are very exciting,
some of them are super boring, but this is how
the software market has evolved and I think we're
going to see something similar with agents.
It's not just going to be these huge markets
like we're in customer service and software
engineering. It's going to be a lot of things
where people are spending a lot of time
and resources that an agent can just solve,
but it requires an entrepreneur who actually
understands that business problem, and deeply,
and I think that's where a lot of the value
is going to be unlocked in the AI market.
That is incredibly helpful. This makes me
think about, I had Marc Benioff on the podcast,
you guys were co-CEOs and he was extremely
agent-pilled. All he wanted to talk about
was Agentforce. Clearly you're also
very agent-pilled. What is it that-
I've never heard the term
agent-pilled [inaudible 00:59:18].
Clearly you guys saw something that was
just like, okay, we need to go all in on
agents. This is the future. What is it you
think people are missing about just why this
is such a critical change in the way software
is going to work? What are people not seeing?
If you talk to an economist like Larry Summers
who, on the OpenAI board with me, they'll talk
about what is the value of technology? Will
it help strive productivity in the economy.
And if you look at one of the big jumps in
productivity in the economy was in the '90s,
and I think a lot of folks I talked to think it
was actually that very first wave of computing
where people made ERP systems and just put
accounting into computers and databases,
even mainframes, we're talking like the PC
era. Because it was such a huge step-up,
just imagine the ledgers of numbers that you'd
have for a large multinational company before
and it truly just transformed departments.
I'll give you a little toy example. My dad
just retired. He was a mechanical engineer and
he was talking about when he first started his
career in the late '70s and he went into a
mechanical engineering firm, the majority of
the firm were drafts people. So basically, you
take an engineering design but you needed to do
all the different vantage points and for all the
different floors and to give to the contractor to
do the thing. Now, there are zero drafts people
at his company. You just make the design in first
AutoCAD and now Revit and it's a 3D model and
the drafting has actually been eliminated. It's
just not a thing one needs to do anymore. The
actual design and drafting, drafting is not a
thing that exists. It's just a design. That's
true productivity gains, right? It's like the
job of the mechanical engineering firm was to do
a design. The drafting was this necessary output
for the contractor, but it wasn't really adding
value. It was just like the supply chain change.
If you look at the history of the software
industry from the PC on, there's been meaningful
productivity gains but just not nearly as
meaningful as that first huge jump. And I'm
not smart enough to know exactly why, but it
is interesting, the promise of productivity
gains from technology hasn't been as realized
I think as some people thought. I think agents
will truly start to bend the curve again like we
did in the very early days of computing because
software is going from helping an individual be
slightly more productive to actually accomplishing
a job autonomously. And as a consequence,
just like you don't need drafts people in a
mechanical engineering firm, you just won't need
someone doing that thing anymore. It means they
can do something else that's higher leverage
and more productive and you can actually...
A smaller group of people can accomplish more and
truly drive productivity gains in the economy.
And I think if you've ever sold enterprise
software, you end up in these discussions as a
vendor with the customer where you'll have a value
discussion and you'll do these somewhat convoluted
things like okay, it's like you're selling a
sales thing. Okay, well, if every salesperson
sells 5% more... And you should pay us a million
dollars. And it's roughly that conversation and
it's so unattributable especially... And it's
why it's so hard to sell productivity software,
which I learned the hard way, it's just hard
to know what's the value of making everyone 10%
more productive? Did you actually make them 10%
more productive or did something else change? You
don't really know all these things. But now
with an agent actually accomplishing a job,
not only is it actually truly driving productivity
in a very real way, but it's measurable as well.
So all those things combined means I think
this is actually a step change in how we
think about software because it does a job
autonomously, which is more self-evident,
a productivity driver. It's measurable so people
value it differently as well, which is why I also
believe in outcomes-based pricing for software.
And all of that combined to me, it feels like
as significant as the cloud or I think more
technologically, but just in terms of how it
transforms the business model of the software
industry where there's going to be a before
and after. I don't know how many people still
sell perpetually licensed on premises software,
but it's de minimis at this point. I think we're
going to go through a similar transition. The
whole market is going to go towards agents. I
think the whole market is going to go towards
outcomes-based pricing, not because it's the
only way, but the market is going to pull
everyone there because it's just so obviously
the correct way to build and sell software.
Let me pull on that last thread. So we
had Madhavan on the podcast recently,
pricing expert, legend, monetizing innovation
author and he talked about pricing strategy
for AI companies and he was very much in your
camp of, if you can, you need to price your
product as an outcome-based product and
the access uses exactly what you shared,
which is, you can do that if you can attribute
the impact and it's autonomous, it's running on
its own. And he actually used Sierra as one of
the shining examples of this being successful.
Can you just briefly just explain a little bit
what is outcome-based pricing for people that
haven't heard this term before and then just
how does it work for Sierra to give an example?
Yeah, I'll start with the example and
then I'll broaden it. So at Sierra,
we help companies make customer facing AI agents
primarily for customer service, but more broadly,
for customer experience. So if you have a problem
with your [inaudible 01:04:58], you'll call or
chat with Harmony, who's their AI agent. If
you have ADT home security and your alarm
doesn't work, you can chat with their AI
agent. Sonos speakers, a lot of different
consumer brands. And if you think about running a
call center, there's a cost for every phone call
that you take. Most of it is labor costs,
but if you have, let's just say a typical
phone call is anywhere between 10 and $20 USD.
Some of it's software, some of it's telephony,
but a lot of it is just like the hourly
wage of the person answering the phone.
So if an AI agent can take that call and solve
it, that is in the industry often called a call
deflection or a containment. And that essentially
means you saved, call it $15 because you didn't
have to have someone pick up the phone. So in
our industry, basically we say, "Hey, if the
AI agent solves the customer's problem, they're
happy with it and you didn't have to pick up the
phone," there's a pre-negotiated rate for that
and we call it resolution based. There are other
outcomes as well. We have some sales agents being
paid a sales commission, believe it or not. We do.
We really think of our agents as truly customer
experience like the concierge for your brand and
we want to make sure that our business model
is aligned with our customer's business model.
As you said, these agents need to be
autonomous and the outcome has to be
measurable. That's not always possible, but I
think it's broadly possible. And what's really
neat about it is if you talk to any CFO or
head of procurement with their big vendors,
they look at the bill of materials and it's
overwhelming and it's impossible to know if
you're getting the value that you hoped from that
contract. I think consumption based, which was
popular particularly in the infrastructure
space is closer to it. But I'm not sure a
token is actually a good measure of value from AI
either. I always use the analogy, like right now,
most of the coding agents are priced per token or
per utilization, but there's this famous story of
an Apple engineer who had a bad manager who's
like had you report how many lines of code you
wrote every day? Which every engineer in the world
knows is an idiotic way to measure productivity.
He famously went in with a report that had a
negative number because I think he did a big
refactoring, deleted a bunch and it was his
way of saying like, fuck you to the man. I
think tokens are similar. Yeah, you used a lot
of tokens, like good for you, did it produce a
pull request that was good? And I think that's
the whole point of all this. I think there's
a huge difference between outcomes-based pricing
and usage based pricing because especially in AI,
they're not necessarily even correlated and you
could have a long phone call and not solve the
customer's problem and they give you a negative
review online and call the call center again,
all that effort was for nothing. In fact,
you might've added negative value. And so,
I am a huge believer in this.
And what's fun about it is it
really just aligns... I think every technology
company aspires to be a partner, not a vendor.
And I think at Sierra, we are truly a partner
to every single one of our customers because
we're all aligned on what we want to achieve. And
I think that is really where the software industry
should go. It requires a lot of different shape
of a company. You have to be able to help your
customers achieve those outcomes. You can't just
throw software at the wall because you'll never
get paid if it doesn't. Your orientation becomes
so extremely customer-centric when you do this the
right way. I think it's just a better version of
the software industry. So I think it's right from
first principles, it's right for procurement
partners and I think it's right for the world.
We've been chatting a little
bit about productivity gains.
There's a lot of skepticism in the headlines
these days of just like what is AI actually
doing? Is it actually helping people be more
productive? There was a recent study actually,
I don't know if you saw, where they
showed engineers were less productive
with AI because it was just putting them in
different directions. They had to research
all what's going wrong here? So I think CX is
a really good example where you clearly are
seeing gains. Are you seeing actual gains at your
company or any other company you work with outside
of CX in terms of productivity that is like
clearly yes, this is working and a huge deal?
I'm extremely bullish on the productivity gains
from AI, but I do think the tools and products
right now are somewhat immature and it's quite
counterintuitive. So, for example, almost every
software engineering firm I know uses something
like Cursor to help their software engineers.
Most people use Cursor right now as a coding
autocomplete, though they have a lot of agentic
solutions and there's a lot of... OpenAI has Codex
and Cloud has... I can't remember the Anthropic
products. So there's lots of agentic agents
coming as well. One of the interesting things
because the technology is immature, the code it
produces often has problems. There's a lot of
people approaching this to actually realize those
productivity gains because as any engineer who's
written a lot of code will tell you, it's pretty
easy to look at and edit and fix code you wrote.
Reviewing other people's code or particularly
finding a subtle logical error in someone else's
code is actually really hard. It's actually much
harder than editing code that you wrote yourself.
So if the code produced by a coding agent is often
incorrect, it actually can take a lot of cognitive
load and time to fix it. And in fact, if you end
up producing lots of issues with your customers,
you could end up producing a lot of features,
but actually, is like mucking up the machine
a little bit and having something that's not
ideal. There's a couple of techniques that I
think are interesting. First, I think there's a
lot of AI starts now working on things like code
reviews. I think this idea of self-reflection in
agents is really important. Having AI supervise
the AI is actually very effective. Just think
about it this way, if you produce an AI agent
that's right 90% of the time, that's not that
great, but how hard would it be to make another
AI agent to find the errors the other 10% of
the time? That might be a tractable problem.
And if that thing's right 90% of the time, just
for argument's sake, you can wire those things
together and have something that's right 99%
of the time. So it's just a math problem and
it turns out that you can make something
to generate code, you can make something
to review code and you're essentially using
compute for cognitive capacity and you can
layer on more layers of cognition and thinking
and reasoning and produce things increasingly
robust. So I'm very excited about that. The other
thing though is root cause analysis. So we have an
engineer at Sierra who exclusively focuses on the
model context protocol server serving our cursor
instance. And our whole philosophy is, if cursor
generated something incorrect, rather than just
fixing it, try to root cause it. Try to get it so
the next time Cursor will produce the correct code
and essentially, is context engineering.
What context did Cursor not have that would've
been necessary to produce the right outcome? So
I think people who are trying to get productivity
gains in departments like software engineering
need to stop waiting for the models to magically
work if they want to see the gains now. And you
really have to create root cause analysis and
systems and say, how do we go root cause every bad
line of code and actually give the right context
and produce the right system so the models can
do it today? Over time that'll probably be less
necessary and you'll have less context engineering
necessary to do it, but you really have to think
of this as a system and I think people are waiting
for the models to just magically get better. And
I'm like, well that will happen eventually, but if
you want the gains now you got to put in the work.
That's essentially why applied AI companies exist.
And the work is non-trivial, but you can do it.
And so, for customers using platforms like Sierra,
yeah, AI agents aren't perfect, but we're creating
a system that lets customers create a virtuous
cycle of improvement. If you want to go from a
65% automated resolution rate to 75%, we have
a billion tools to let AI help you do that,
identify opportunities for improvement, figure out
why people are frustrated, what new capabilities
can we add to our agent to improve the resolution
rate? And you let AI put the needles at the
top of the haystack on your behalf and I think
that's really the way to optimize these systems.
I've never heard of this technique of
improving Cursor by adding additional
context. What's the actual way of doing that?
You build an MCP server that everything runs
through or is it like you add Cursor
rules? What's the actual approach there?
I'm probably out of my depth here, but it's
essentially MCP because that's how you provide
context to Cursor. And I think that almost always
when you have a model making a poor decision,
if it's a good model, it's lack of context. And
so, you really want to find the intersection of
your particular product and code base with
the context available to these coding agents
and systems and fix it at the
root is the principle here.
Got it. That is very cool. I hadn't heard of
people doing that, model context protocol,
makes sense. We've talked about productivity gains
outside TX. Just to give you a chance to share
how amazing what you've built is, what are some
of the gains you see from people using Sierra?
Yeah, our customers see anywhere between 50
and 90% of their customer service interactions
completely automated, which I think is really
exciting. And we serve just a really, really
broad range of customers. We serve the health
insurance industry, the healthcare provider space,
banks. You can actually refinance your home
using an agent. One of our customers built on
our platform to the telecommunications industry,
DIRECTV, SiriusXM to a lot of retailers as well,
which is really fun. Everyone from Wayfair to
clothing retailers like OluKai and Chubbies
Shorts. What's really neat about it is it's
a pretty diverse range of use cases and it's
everything from helping you sign up for... We
have an agent that helps with customer support in
one of the big dating applications to helping you
upgrade or downgrade your SiriusXM plan. Actually,
it's really funny, we do technical support
from everything from home alarm systems
to sonar speakers to more recently, CAT
scan machines, which I think is amazing.
So technicians going in and fixing the CAT
scan machine can chat with an AI agent to help
them guide them through that process. We're the
leader in the space, we're trying to enable every
company in the world to create their agent with
their brand at the top that I think will become
as meaningful of a digital touch point as their
website or their mobile app. In the short term,
it can really transform the costs of running a
customer service team. And what's remarkable is
do so with really high customer satisfaction
scores. That Weight Watchers agent, I believe
has a customer satisfaction score of 4.6 out
of five, which is pretty amazing. And what's
interesting about service too, it's often people
having a problem. And so, when you have a clear,
I don't know if you use them in the airport, I
think that agent has a CSAT score of 4.7 out of
five people are coming in with a problem
and [inaudible 01:16:19] delighted. And
I think that's really the opportunity here.
And our whole vision is that we're going to
move towards a world where every single one of the
interactions with your customers can be instant.
It can be multilingual, it can be over audio, it
can be over chat, it can be digital, it can be
over the phone and it can be very personalized.
And I think that's really, really exciting.
And if you think about all the best moments you've
had with a brand, it's like that store associate
who you know, and it's like for me, it's like the
butcher at the grocery store. I love to cook, he
knows me. We talk. Can you actually produce that
at scale for a company with 100 million customers
and can you do it in a really personal way? And I
think we're really on the cusp of enabling that.
Let me ask you one more question before we get to
a very exciting lighting round. There's a lot of
founders struggling with go-to-market in AI with
their AI apps. There's so many apps these days,
so many products, so many things coming
at buyers, at large B2B companies. Clearly
you guys have figured something out. I
imagine your name helps, investors help,
but what have you learned about just how to
successfully do go-to-market with an AI product,
say an agent-specific product that you think would
be helpful for folks trying to do this better?
I think there's a small handful of go-to-market
models that have been proven to work, and I think
it's important to choose the right one for the
product category you're going after. One category
I would say is developer-led. This is somewhere
famously Stripe and Twilio where probably two
of the original that did this exceptionally. And
essentially, the go-to-market motion there is to
appeal to an individual engineer often within the
department of the CTO who have accountability and
a fair amount of latitude to choose a solution.
This works if your product is a platform product.
It doesn't work, for example, if your product
is trying to help a line of business because
lines of business typically don't have dedicated
engineering teams or let alone, the latitude to
just go download a new library or start using a
web service like that. It particularly works well
if you sell to startups just because startups
tend to have engineering teams with quite a
bit of latitude to choose services to help
them solve the problem given by the founder.
Then there's product-led growth. It's a broad
term, obviously every company's product matters,
but product-led growth more specifically
means users can sign up from the website,
often get put on a trial. Often you can buy a
couple of seats with a credit card and those
work where your user and your buyer are the
same person. So it works for small business
software almost always because sole proprietors do
everything. And so you're selling small business
software like Shopify in the early days and
there's a lot of other products like that
where you're trying to sell to small merchants.
That's great. It doesn't work well when your
buyer and the user of the software are different.
So I'll use the example of something like expense
reporting software. The user of that software
is an individual employee, but the buyer is
often a finance department. And so having sign
up and buy with your credit card doesn't make
sense because the person using is not the person
with the credit card and it just doesn't work.
And then there's direct sales. And direct sales
had gone, I don't want to say out of fashion,
but if I think of the best direct sales companies,
probably there's a lot of lineage from Oracle,
but you think SAP, Oracle, ServiceNow, Salesforce,
Adobe perhaps, and there's others as well. And
these were companies that sold into large lines of
business in a relatively traditional sales motion.
I think because product-led growth became very
popular. I think a lot companies use that, which
is great, that motion produces great products,
but if PLG means that you aren't actually engaging
with the buyer of your software, you're not going
to grow. And so, I've actually seen more recently,
with a lot of AI companies, direct sales come
a little bit more back into fashion because I
think so many of the opportunities in AI actually
meet that qualification where the buyer and the
user are not necessarily the same person and
it really requires that go-to-market motion.
Where I see entrepreneurs stumble is they'll
choose a go-to-market motion without thinking
through what is the process of purchasing this
software? What is the process of evaluating the
value of this software? And I think people
just need to be much more first principles
about it and much more thoughtful about it.
And candidly, I think a lot of companies
should leverage direct sales more than
they do. And even though because of the
sometimes justified reputation of the quality of
products of some of these direct sales companies,
it had gotten a bad name. And I think I'm thankful
to see it coming back in a lot of the AI market.
I feel like this message is something a
lot of founders need to hear, especially
founders that aren't from a business
background that sales turns them off,
they don't think they're going to be great at
sales. Just this push of this might be what you
have to get really good at and this is how you win
and you can't just rely on product like growth.
Yeah.
Bret, is there anything else that you wanted to
share? Any last nugget of wisdom? Anything you
want to double click on before we get
to our very exciting lightning round?
No, go ahead.
Okay, let's do it. Here we go. Welcome
to our very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you. Are you ready?
Yeah, go ahead.
What are two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
I don't read a lot of nonfiction, but probably
if I had to pick one in the area of the topics
we talked about, Competing Against Luck, which
was the book that produced Jobs to be Done,
which is a framework I really believe in.
My only critique is I think most of these
business books should be like an article. So
maybe buy the book and punch it into ChatGPT
and get the summary. But buy the book
it's Clayton Christensen talked about it,
but it's a really good framework for thinking
about delivering value with your products.
And I think it definitely influenced me.
Actually one book I do recommend is Endurance,
which is the story of Shackleton's trip
to go to the South Pole. Half the book
is him starving to death and eating seal meat
with his crew of people frozen in their boat.
I've never seen a better story of grit in
my entire life. It's remarkable that it's a
true story and if you're an entrepreneur going
through a hard time, read that, you'd be like,
okay, it could be worse. It's a great book too.
It's just remarkable that it's a true story.
And one thing he did a great job at is setting
expectations for folks that
joined that famous newspaper-
That ad. That newspaper ad. I don't know if
that's true. It's remarkable if that's true.
Oh, it might not be true.
I don't know. The internet. Who knows?
Goddam. Deep fakes even back then. Okay. Do you
have a favorite recent movie or TV
show that you've really enjoyed?
I haven't gone to any new TV
shows recently? We just watched
Inception with the kids and
they loved it and made me
appreciate Christopher Nolan and what a cool
movie. It's the type of movie when you watch
the film and you can a conversations for two
days afterwards about it. So, just a great film.
I saw someone using I think VO 3 to create
their own Inception videos where the worlds
wrapping in on each other. Oh, man.
Okay. Do you have a favorite product
that you have recently discovered that you
love or one you've loved for a long time?
I'm really a big fan of Cursor. I think
it's changed. I love creating software
and I'm excited though for agents. I've
been really excited. I was very excited
to see Codex from OpenAI and others. So I
think Cursor will be in its current form,
is a transition product. And I know they're
working on agents as well, but I really enjoyed
taking something I love and it's been my life's
passion and really diving into this AI tool and
seeing how it transforms how I create software.
So I've just been spending a lot of time with
the product just because it's so core to what I
love to do and it's a really well crafted product.
I think that's the first time someone's
actually mentioned Cursor in this answer,
so might be the beginning of a trend. Michael
Trell was on the podcast and he actually
had a very similar message as you had at the
beginning of this chat about the future of code,
what comes after code and this concept that
there's going to be this additional pseudo code
layer on top of code. Very aligned with
your thinking. Do you have a favorite
life motto that you often come back
to and find useful in work or in life?
The best way to predict the future is to
invent it, which I think I attribute to Alan
Kay of Xerox PARC. He invented a lot of the core
abstractions that we use in computing today. I'm
an entrepreneur, it's why I love to build
things and it's definitely a life motto for me.
I feel like many people say this, I
feel like you've actually done this
so many times. You're really living this
motto. Final question. We talked about you
inventing the like button at FriendFeed. Were
there other thoughts of what they would call
it other than like? Was it just obviously
like? Or was there other thinking there?
This was before emoji. So, if you read the
comments on FriendFeed posts, at least 70%
of them are cool or wow or yeah or neat. And one
of the principle uses of FriendFeed was to have
discussions about things. So you'd have a post
and then a pretty fulsome discussion underneath.
And compared to Twitter and others, it was a
great place to have those discussions. And so,
the product problem we were trying to solve is
get all the one word answers out so that the
discussion was actually actual comments as opposed
to acknowledgements that you read the thing.
So, the original framing was one click comment.
That was how we thought about it. And so,
the first version that I made had a heart, and she
denies remembering this, but Anna Yang, now Anna
Muller who has worked at the company, she hated
it. She said, "If I look at hearts on every post,
I'm going to vomit. It's too much." And it also
was interesting, we were simulating, it was like
an article about a tragedy or something. A heart
was just not the right thing. Like which actually
turned out to be really hard to translate
was just a much more neutral sentiment,
and that's why it was hard to translate because it
was subtle. So that's how we ended up with this.
We started with a heart, and I don't know if
we ever heard the word love, but we definitely
started off with the iconography and then like,
which just felt like this positive yet as neutral
as possible within the realm of positive so
that it could work for a more complex story.
But it was all because we needed a one-click
comment. That's where the concept came from.
Wow. I've never heard the story
before. It makes me think about
LinkedIn now. They're basically trying
to solve that same problem. They have
all these auto-reply pill tag things. I
don't think people like those very much.
Yeah. They have a lot of features.
So many AI features. Bret, this was incredible.
This was an honor. I so appreciate you coming
on this podcast. Two final questions, where can
folks find you online if they want to reach out,
maybe go see if they want to work at Sierra
and how can listeners be useful to you?
If you want an AI agent to
help with customer service,
go to sierra.ai. If you want to
apply here, sierra.ai/careers where
we have offices in San Francisco and New
York, Atlanta and London and are hiring
pretty aggressively in every department.
So please reach out if you're interested.
And how can listeners be useful to you?
Is it tryout Sierra, anything else there?
Yeah, tryout Sierra. I'm a single issue voter.
[inaudible 01:28:26] message. I love it.
Yeah.
Bret, thank you so much for being here.
Yeah, thanks for having me.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
Lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.