... our goal with Cursor is to
invent a new type of programming,
a very different way to build software. So
a world kind of after code, I think that
more and more being an engineer will start to
feel like being a logic designer, and really,
it will be about specifying your intent for
how exactly you want everything to work.
What is the most counter-intuitive thing
you've learned so far about building Cursor?
We definitely didn't expect to be doing any of
our own model development. And at this point,
every magic moment in Cursor
involves a custom model in some way.
What's something that you wish you
knew before you got into this role?
Many people you hear hire too fast, I think
we actually hired too slow to begin with.
You guys went from $0 to 100
million ARR in a year and a half,
which is historic. Was there an inflection point
where things just started to really take off?
The growth has been fairly just
consistent on an exponential. And
exponential to begin with feels fairly
slow when the numbers are really low,
and it didn't really show off
to the races to begin with.
What do you think is the secret to your success?
I think it's been...
Today, my guest is Michael Truell. Michael
is co-founder and CEO of Anysphere,
the company behind Cursor. If you've been
living under a rock and haven't heard of Cursor,
it is the leading AI code editor, and is at the
very forefront of changing how engineers and
product teams build software. It's also one of the
fastest growing products of all time, hitting 100
million ARR just 20 months after launching, and
then 300 million ARR just two years since launch.
Michael's been working on AI for 10 years. He
studied computer science and math at MIT, did
AI research at MIT and Google, and is a student
of tech and business history. As you'll soon see,
Michael thinks deeply about where things are
heading, and what the future of building software
looks like. We chat about the origin story of
Cursor, his prediction of what happens after code,
his biggest counter-intuitive lessons
from building Cursor, where he sees things
going for software engineers, and so much more.
Michael does not do many podcasts. The only other
podcast he's ever done is Lex Fridman, so it was
a true honor to have Michael on. If you enjoy this
podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow it
in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also,
if you become an annual subscriber of my
newsletter, you get a year free of Perplexity,
Linear, Superhuman, Notion, and Granola. Check
it out at lennysnewsletter.com, and click bundle.
With that, I bring you Michael Truell.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo.
Eppo is a next-generation A/B testing and feature
management platform built by alums of Airbnb and
Snowflake for modern growth teams. Companies like
Twitch, Miro, ClickUp, and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth, and for
understanding the performance of new features, and
Eppo helps you increase experimentation velocity,
while unlocking rigorous deep analysis in
a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that
I loved most was our experimentation platform,
where I could set up experiments easily,
troubleshoot issues, and analyze performance
all on my own. Eppo does all that and more,
with advanced statistical methods that can
help you shave weeks off experiment time, an
accessible UI for diving deeper into performance,
and out-of-the-box reporting that helps you
avoid annoying, prolonged analytics cycles.
Eppo also makes it easy for you to share
experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use case,
including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny, and 10X your
experiment velocity. That's getE-P-P-O.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Vanta.
When it comes to ensuring your company
has top-notch security practices, things get
complicated fast. Now, you can assess risk,
secure the trust of your customers, and
automate compliance for SOC 2, ISO 27001, HIPAA,
and more with a single platform, Vanta. Vanta's
market-leading trust management platform helps
you continuously monitor compliance, alongside
reporting and tracking risk. Plus, you can save
hours by completing security questionnaires with
Vanta AI. Join thousands of global companies
that use Vanta to automate evidence collection,
unify risk management, and streamline security
reviews. Get $1,000 off Vanta when you go to
vanta.com/lenny. That's V-A-N-T-A.com/lenny.
Michael, thank you so much for
being here. Welcome to the podcast.
Thank you. It's great to be
here. Thank you for having me.
When we were chatting earlier, you
had this really interesting phrase,
this idea of what comes after code. Talk
about that, just the vision you have of
where you think things are going in terms
of moving from code to maybe something else.
Our goal with Cursor is to invent sort of a new
type of programming, a very different way to
build software, that's kind of just distilled down
into you describing the intent to the computer for
what you want in the most concise way possible,
and really distilled down to just defining how
you think the software should work, and how you
think it should look. With the technology that we
have today, and as it matures, we think you can
get to a place where you can invent a new method
of building software that's [inaudible
00:05:16] higher level, and more productive,
in some cases, more accessible too.
And that process will be a gradual
moving away from what building software looks
like today. I want to contrast it with maybe
the vision of what software looks like in the
future that I think... A couple of visions that
are in a popular consciousness that we at
least have some disagreement with. One is,
there's a group of people who think that
software building in the future is going
to look very much like it does today, which mostly
means text editing, formal programming languages,
like TypeScript, and Go, and C, and Rust.
And then there's another group that kind of
thinks you're just going to type into a bot, and
you're going to ask it to build you something,
and then you're going to ask it to change
something about what you're building, and it's
kind of like this chatbot, Slackbot style where
you're talking to your engineering department.
And we think that there are problems with both
of those visions. I think that on the chatbot
style end of things... And we think it's going
to look weirder than both. The problem with the
chatbot style end of things is that lacks a
lot of precision. If you want humans to have
complete control over what the software looks
like, and how it works, you need to let them
gesture at what they want to be changed in
a form factor that's more precise than just,
"Change this about my app." In a text box,
removed from the whole thing. And then
the version of the world where nothing changes we
think is wrong, because we think the technology
is going to get much, much, much better.
And so a world after code, I think that it
looks like a world where you have a representation
of the logic of your software that does look more
like English, you have written down... You
can imagine in [inaudible 00:07:08] form,
you can imagine in kind of an evolution of
programming language towards pseudocode. You
have written down the logic of the software,
and you can edit that at a high level,
and you can point at that. And it won't be
the impenetrable millions of lines of code,
it'll instead be something that's much Terser, and
easier to understand, easier to navigate. But that
world where the kind of crazy, hard to understand
symbols start to evolve towards something
that's a little bit more human-readable, and
human-editable, is one that we're working towards.
This is a profound point. I want to make sure
people don't miss what you're saying here,
which is that what you're envisioning in
the next year essentially is kind of when
things start to shift, is, people
move away from even seeing code,
having to think in code in JavaScript and Python,
and there's this abstraction that will appear,
essentially pseudocode, describing what the
code should be doing more in English sentences.
Yep. We think it ends up looking like that,
and we're very opinionated that that path goes
through existing professional engineers, and it
looks like this evolution away from code. And it
definitely looks like the human still being
in the driver's seat, and the human having
both a ton of control over all aspects of the
software and not giving that up. And then also
the human having the ability to make changes very
quickly, having a fast duration loop and not just
having something in the background that's super
slow and takes weeks, go do all your work for you.
This begs the question for people
that are currently engineers,
or thinking about becoming engineers,
or designers, or product manager,
what skills do you think will be more and more
valuable in this world of what comes after code?
I think taste will be increasingly more valuable.
And I think often when people think about tastes
in the realm of software, they think about
visuals, or taste over smooth animations, and
coloring things, UI, UX, et cetera on the visual
design of things. And the visual side of things is
an important part of defining a piece of software,
but then, as mentioned before, I think that the
other half of defining a piece of software
is the logic of it, and how the thing works.
And we have amazing tools for specing out
the visuals of things, and then when you get
into the logic of how a piece of software works,
really, the best representation we have of that is
code right now. You can kind of gesture at it with
Figma, and you can gesture at it with writing down
notes, but it's when you have an actual working
prototype. And so I think that more and more,
being an engineer will start to feel like being
a logic designer, and really, it will be about
specifying your intent for how exactly you want
everything to work. It'd be more about the whats,
and a little bit less about how exactly
you're going to do things under the hood.
I think taste will be increasingly important.
I think one aspect of software engineering,
and we're very far from this right now, and there
are lots of funny memes going around the internet
about some of the trials and tribulations people
can run into if they trust AI for too many things
that comes to engineering, around building apps
that have glaring deficiencies, and problems,
and functionality issues. But I think we
will get to a place where you'll be able to
be less careful as a software engineer, which,
right now, is an incredibly, incredibly important
skill. We'll move a little bit from carefulness,
and a little bit more towards taste.
This makes me think of vibe coding, is that
kind of what you're describing when you talk
about not having to think about the details
as much, and just kind of going with the flow?
I think it's related. I think that vibe
coding right now describes exactly this
state of creation that is pretty controversial,
where you're generating a lot of coding, you
aren't really understanding the details. That is a
state of creation that then has lots of problems,
you don't really... By not understanding
the details under the hood right now,
you then very quickly get to a place where
you're kind of limited at a certain point,
where you create something that's big enough that
you can't change. And so I think some of the ideas
that we're interested around, how do you give
people continued control over all the details
when they don't really understand the code? I
think that solutions there are very relevant
to the people who are vibe coding right now. I
think that right now, we lack the ability to let
the tastemakers actually have complete control
over the software. One of the issues also with
vibe coding, and letting taste really shine
through from people is, you can create stuff,
but a lot of it the AI making decisions that
are unwieldy and you don't have to control over.
One more question along these lines. You threw out
this word taste. When you say
taste, what are you thinking?
I'm thinking having the right idea for what
should be built. It will become more and more
about effortless translation of, here's
exactly what you want built, here's how
you want everything to work, here's how you want
it to look. And then you'll be able to make that
on a computer, and it will less be about this kind
of translation layer of, you and your team have a
picture of what you'd want to build, and then you
have to really painstakingly, labor-intensive,
lay out that into a format that a computer
can then execute and interpret. I think
less than the UI side of things, maybe
taste is a little bit of a misnomer,
but just about having the right
idea for what should be built.
Awesome. Okay. I'm going to come back to
these topics, but I want to actually zoom
us back out to the beginnings of Cursor.
I have never heard the origin story,
I don't think many people know how this
whole thing started. Basically you guys
are building one of the fastest growing
products in the history of the world,
it's changing the way people build products,
it's changing careers, professions, it's changing
so much. How did it all begin? Any memorable
moments along the journey of the early days?
Cursor kind of started as a solution search of a
problem, and a little bit where it very much came
from reflecting on how AI was going to get better
over the course of the next 10 years. There were
kind of two defining moments, one was being really
excited by using the first beta version of Code
Pilot, actually. This was the first time we had
used an AI product that was really, really, really
useful, and was actually just useful at all,
and wasn't just a vaporware kind of demo thing.
And in addition to being the first AI
product that we'd use that was useful,
Code Pilot was also one of the most useful, if
not the most useful dev tool we'd ever adopted,
and that got us really excited. Another moment
that got us really excited was the series of
scaling on papers coming out of OpenAI and
other places that showed that even if we
had no new ideas, AI was going to get better
and better just by pulling on simple levers,
like scaling up the models, and also scaling
up the data that was going into the models.
And so at the end of 2021, beginning of 2022,
this got us excited about how AI products were
now possible, this technology was going to mature
into the future. And it felt like when we looked
around, there were lots of people talking about
making models, and it felt like people weren't
really picking an area of knowledge work and
thinking about what it was going to look like
as AI got better and better. And that set us
on the path to an idea generation exercise,
it was like, "How are these areas of knowledge
work going to change in the future as this tech
gets more mature? What is the end state of the
work going to look like? How are the tools that
we use to do that work going to change? How are
the models going to need to get better to support
changes in the work? And once scaling and
pre-training ran out, how are you going to
keep pushing for technological capabilities?"
And the misstep at the beginning of Cursor is
we actually worked on... We sort of did this
whole grand exercise, and we decided to work on
an area of knowledge work that we thought
would be relatively uncompetitive, and sleepy,
and boring, and no one would be looking at
it, because we thought, "Oh, coding's great,
coding's totally going to change with this AI,
but people are already doing that." So there was
a period of four months to begin with, where we
were actually working on a very different idea,
which was helping to automate and
augment mechanical engineering,
and building tools for mechanical engineers.
There were problems from the get-go in that.
Me and my co-founders, we weren't mechanical
engineers. We had friends who were mechanical
engineers, but we were very much unfamiliar
with the field. So there was a little bit of
a blind man and the elephant problem from
the get-go. There were problems around,
how would you actually take the models that exist
to today and make them useful for mechanical
engineering? The way we netted out is, you need to
actually develop your own models from the get-go.
And the way we did that was tricky, and there's
not a lot of data on the internet of 3D models
of different tools and parts, and the steps
that I expect to build up to those 3D models,
and then getting them from the sources that
have them is also a tricky process too.
But eventually what happened was, we came to our
senses, we realized we're not super excited about
mechanical engineering, it's not the thing we want
to dedicate our lives to. And we looked around,
and in the area of programming, it felt like
despite a decent amount of time ensuing,
not much has changed, and it felt like
the people that were working on the space
maybe had a disconnect with us, and it felt like
they weren't being sufficiently ambitious about
where everything was going to go in the future,
and how all of software creation was going to
blow through these models. And that's what
set us off on the path to building Cursor.
Okay. So interesting. Okay, so first of all, I
love that... This is advice that you often hear
of go after a boring industry because no one's
going to be there, and there's opportunity. And
sometimes it works, but I love that in this
journey, it's like, "No, actually, go after
the hottest, most popular space, AI coding, app
building." And it worked out. And the way you
phrased it just now is, you didn't see enough
ambition potentially, that you thought there
was more to be done. So it feels like that's an
interesting lesson. Even if something looks like,
"Okay, it's too late, there's GitHub, Code
Pilot's out there." Some other products. If
you notice that they're just not as ambitious
as they could be, or as you are, or you see
almost a flaw in their approach, that there's
still a big opportunity. Does that resonate?
That totally resonates. A part of it is, you
need there to be leapfrogs that can happen,
you need there to be things that you can do.
And I think the exciting thing about AI is,
in a bunch of places, and I think this
is very much still true of our space,
and can talk about how we think about
that and how we deal with that, but
I think that just the ceiling is really
high. And yes, if you look around,
probably even if you take the best tool, any
of these fields, there should be a lot more
that needs to be done over the next few years.
Having that space, having that high ceiling,
I think is unique amongst areas of software, at
least the degree to which it is high with AI.
Let's come back to the IDE questions. So
there's a few routes you could have taken,
and other companies are doing different routes.
So there's building an IDE for engineers to work
within and adding AI magic to it, there's another
route of just a full AI agentic dev product,
and then there's just a model that is very good
at coding, and focusing on building the best
possible coding model. What made you decide
and see that the IDE path was the best route?
The folks who were from the get-go working
on just a model were working on end-to-end
automation programming. I think they were trying
to build something very different from us,
which is, we care about giving humans control
over all of the decisions in the end tool that
they're building. And I think those folks were
very much thinking of a future where end-to-end,
the whole thing is done by AI, and maybe the
AI is making all the decisions too. And so,
one, there was a personal interest
component. Two, I think that always,
we've tried to be intense realists about
where the technology is today, very, very,
very excited about how AI is going to mature
over the course of many decades. But I think
that sometimes people... There's an instinct
to see AI do magical things in one area, and
then kind of anthropomorphize these models, and
think it's better than a smart person here, and
so it must be better than a smart person there.
But these things have massive issues, and
we... From the very start, our product development
process was really about dogfooding, and using the
tool intensely every day. And we never wanted
to ship anything that wasn't useful to us,
and we had the benefit of doing that because
we were the end users part of our product. And
I think that that instills a realism in you
around where the tech is right now, and so
that definitely made us think that we need the
humans to be in the driver's seat, the AI cannot
do everything. We're also interested in giving
humans that control too for personal reasons,
and so that gets you away from just your model
company that also gets you away from just this
end-end stuff without the human having control.
And then the way you get to an IDE versus maybe
a plug-in to an existing coding environment is the
belief that programming is going to flow through
these models, and the active programming is going
to change a lot over the course of the next few
years. And that the extensibility that existing
coding environments have is so, so, so limited,
so if you think that the UIs may change a lot,
if you think that the form factor programming
is going to change a lot, necessarily need
to have control over the entire application.
I know that you guys today have
an IDE, and that's probably the
bias you have of this is maybe where the
future is heading, but I'm just curious,
do you think a big part of the future is also
going to be AI engineers that are just sitting
in Slack and just doing things for you? Is
that something that fits into Cursor one day?
I think you'll want the ability to move between
all of these things fairly effortlessly,
and sometimes I think you will want to have the
thing kind of go spin off on its own for a while,
and then I think you'll want the ability to pull
in the AI's work, and then work with it very,
very, very quickly, and then maybe have it go
spin off again. And so these kind of background
versus foreground form factors, I think you
want that all to work well in one place. And
I think the background stuff, there's a segment
of programming that it's especially useful for,
which is type of programming tasks where it's
very easy to specify exactly what you want
without much description, and exactly what
correctness looks like without much description.
Bug fixes are a great example of that, but it's
definitely not all of programming. So I think that
what the IDE is will totally change over time,
and our approach to having our own editor was
premised on, it's going to have to evolve over
time. And I think that that will both include,
you can spin off things from different surface
areas like Slack, or your issue tracker, or
whatever it is, and I think that will also include
the pane of glass that you're staring at is going
to change a lot. We just mostly think of an IDE
as the place where you are building software.
I think something people don't talk enough
about with talking about agents and all these
AI engineers that are going to be doing all this
stuff for you, is basically we're all becoming
engineering managers, with a lot of reports
that are just not that smart, and you have
to do a lot of reviewing, and approving,
and specifying. I guess thoughts on that,
and is there anything you could do to make that
easier? Because that sounds really hard. Anyone
that has had a large team, being like, "Oh my god,
all these junior people just checking in with me
doing not high quality work over and over." It's
just like, "What a life. It's going to suck."
Yeah. Maybe you [inaudible 00:23:12]
one-on-ones with [inaudible 00:23:15].
So many one-on-ones.
Yeah. So the customers we've seen have most
success with AI I think are still fairly
conservative about some of the ways in which
they use this stuff. And so I do think today,
the most successful customers really lean on
things like our next edit prediction, where your
coding is normal, and making the next into actions
you're going to do. And then they also really lean
on scoping down the stuff that you're going to
hand off to the bot, and for a fixed percent of
your time spent reviewing code, from an agent,
or from an AI overall, you could... There's two
patterns. One is, you could spend a bunch of time
specifying things up front, the AI goes and works,
and then you then go and review the AI's work,
and then you're done. That's the whole task.
Or you can really chop things up. So you can
specify a little bit, AI writes something,
review, specify a little bit, AI writes
something, review. Autocompletes all in
the way of that spectrum. And still we see
often the most successful people using these
tools are chopping things up right now, and
keeping things fairly [inaudible 00:24:28].
That sounds less terrible. I'm glad there's
a solution here. I want to go back to you
guys building Cursor for the first time. What was
the point where you realized this is ready? What
was a moment of, "Okay, I think this is time
to put it out there, and see what happens"?
So when we started building Cursor, we were
fairly paranoid about spinning for a while,
without releasing to the world. And so to begin
with too, we actually... The first version of
Cursor was hand-rolled. Now we use VS Code as a
base, like many browsers use Chromium as a base,
and hit foot off of that. To begin with, we
didn't, and built the prototype of Cursor from
scratch, and that involved a lot of work.
We had to build our own... There were a
lot of things that go into a modern code editor,
including support for many different languages,
and navigation support for moving amongst the
language, error tracking support for things.
There's things like an integrated command
line, the ability to use remote servers,
the ability to connect to remote servers to
view and run code. And so we kind of just
went on this blitz of building things incredibly
quickly, building our own editor from scratch,
and then also the AI components.
It was after maybe five weeks that
we were living on the editor full-time,
and had thrown away our previous editor,
and we're using a new one. And then once it got
to a point where we found it a bit useful, then we
put it in other people's hands, and had this very
short beta period. And then we launched it out to
the world within a couple of months from the
first line of code, I think it was probably
three months. And it was definitely a, "Let's
just get this out to people and build in public
quickly." The thing that took us by surprise
is we thought we would be building for a couple
hundred people for a long time. And from the
get-go, there was an immediate rush of interest,
and a lot of feedback too. That was super helpful,
we learned from that. That's actually why we
switched to being based off of VS Code instead
of just this hand-rolled thing. A lot of that
was motivated by the initial user feedback, and
then had been iterating in public from there.
I like how you understated the traction that you
got. I think you guys went from $0 to 100 million
ARR in a year, year and a half or something like
that, which is historic. What do you think was
the key to success of something like this? You
just talked about dogfooding being a big part of
it. You built it in three months, that's insane.
What do you think is the secret to your success?
The three-month version wasn't very good, and
so I think it's been a sustained paranoia about,
there are all of these ways in which this thing
could get better. The end goal is really to invent
a very new form of programming that involves
automating a lot of coding, as we know today.
And no matter where we are with Cursor, it feels
like we're very, very far away from that end goal,
there's always a lot to do. A lot of it hasn't
been over rotated on that initial push, but
instead is the continued evolution of the tool,
and just making the tool consistently better.
Was there an inflection point after those three
months where things just
started to really take off?
To be honest, it felt fairly slow to begin with,
and maybe it comes from some impatience on our
part. I think there's the overall speed of the
growth which continues to take us by surprise.
I think one of the things that has been most
surprising too is that the growth has been
fairly just consistent on an exponential, of just
consistent month-over-month growth, accelerated at
times by launches on our part and other things.
But an exponential to begin with feels fairly
slow and the numbers are really low, and so it
didn't really feel off to the races to begin with.
To me this sounds like build it and they
will come actually working. You guys just
built an awesome product that you loved
yourselves as engineers, you put it out,
people just loved it, told everyone about it.
It being essentially all just us, the team working
on the product, and making the product good in
lieu of other things one could spend one's time
on. We definitely spent time on tons of other
things, for instance, building the team was
incredibly important, and doing things like
support rotations are very important. But some of
the normal things that people would maybe reach
for in building the company early on, we really
let those fires burn for a long time, especially
when it came to things like sales and marketing.
And so just working on the product, and building a
product that you like first, your team likes, and
then also then adjusting it for some set of users,
that can kind of sound simple, but then, as you
know, it's hard to do that well. And there are
a bunch of different directions one could have
run in, a bunch of different product directions.
I think focus, and strategically picking the right
things to build, and prioritizing effectively is
tricky. I think another thing that's tricky about
this domain is, it's kind of a new form of product
building, where it's very interdisciplinary
in that we are something in between a normal
software company and then a foundation model
company, in that we're developing a product
for millions of people, and that side of things
has to be excellent, but then also one important
dimension of product quality is doing more and
more on the science, and doing more and more on
the model side of things in places where it makes
sense. And so that element of things doing that
well too has been tricky. The overall thing would
note is maybe some of these things sound simple
to specify, but doing them well is hard, and
they're a lot of different way you can run in.
I'm excited to have Andrew Luo joining
us today. Andrew is CEO of OneSchema,
one of our podcast sponsors. Welcome, Andrew.
Thanks for having me, Lenny. Great to be here.
So what is new with OneSchema? I know that
you work with some of my favorite companies,
like Ramp, and [inaudible 00:30:46], and
Watershed. I heard you guys launched a new
data intake product that automates the hours
of manual work that teams spent importing,
and mapping, and integrating CSV in Excel files?
Yes. So we just launched the 2.0 of OneSchema
FileFeeds. We've rebuilt it from the ground
up with AI. We saw so many customers coming to
us with teams of data engineers that struggled
with the manual work required to clean
messy spreadsheets. FileFeeds 2.0 allows
non-technical teams to automate the process of
transforming CSV and Excel files with just a
simple prompt. We support all of the trickiest
file integrations, SFTP, S3, and even email.
I can tell you that if my team had to
build integrations like this, how nice
would it be to take this off our roadmap
and instead use something like OneSchema.
Absolutely, Lenny. We've heard so many
horror stories of outages from even just
a single bad record, in transactions,
employee files, purchase orders,
you name it. Debugging these issues is often like
finding a needle in a haystack. OneSchema stops
any bad data from entering your system,
and automatically validates your files,
generating error reports with the
exact issues in all bad files.
I know that importing incorrect data can cause all
kinds of pain for your customers and quickly lose
their trust. Andrew, thank you so much for
joining me. If you want to learn more, head
on over to oneschema.co., that's oneschema.co.
What is the most counterintuitive thing you've
learned so far about building
Cursor, building AI products?
I think one thing that's been counterintuitive
for us, [inaudible 00:32:14] added a little bit
before, but is, we definitely didn't expect
to be doing any of our own model development
when we started. As mentioned, when we got into
this, there were companies that were immediately
from the get-go going and just focusing on
training model from scratch. And we had done
the calculation for what it to train before, and
just knew that that was not [inaudible 00:32:36]
going to be able to do. And also felt a bit
like focusing one's attention in the wrong area,
because there were lots of amazing models
out there, and why develop all this work
to replicate what other players had done.
Especially on the pre-training side of things,
taking a neural network that knows nothing,
and then teaching it the whole internet.
And so we thought we weren't going to be doing
that at all, and it seems clear to us from the
start that the existing models, there were lots
of things that they could be doing for us that
they weren't doing, because there wasn't the
right tool built for them. In fact though,
we do a ton of model development, and internally,
it's a big focus for us on the hiring front,
and have assembled a fantastic team there.
And it's also been a big win on the product
quality side of things for us. And at this
point, every magic moment in Cursor involves
a custom model in some way. So that was definitely
counterintuitive, and surprising, and it's been a
gradual thing, where there was an initial use case
for training our own model, where it really didn't
make sense to use any of the biggest foundation
models. That was incredibly successful, moved
to another use case that worked really well, and
had been going from there. And one of the helpful
things in doing this sort of model development
is picking your spots carefully, not trying to
reinvent the wheel, not trying to focus on places,
and maybe where the best foundation models are
excellent, but instead kind of focusing on their
weaknesses, and how you can complement them.
I think this is going to be surprising
to a lot of people hearing that you have
your own models. When people talk about
Cursor and all the folks in the space,
they would kind of call them GPT wrappers, they're
just sitting on top of ChatGPT or Sonnet. What
you're saying is that you have your own models,
talk about just the stack behind the scenes.
Yeah, of course. So we definitely use the biggest
foundation models a bunch of different ways,
they're really important components of bringing
the Cursor experience to people. The places where
we use our own models, so sometimes it's to
survey a use case that a foundation model
wouldn't be able to serve at all for cost or
speed reasons. And so one example of that is
the autocomplete side of things. And so this
can be a little bit tricky for people who don't
code to understand, but code is this weird form
of work, where sometimes, really, the next 5,
10, 20, 30 minutes of your work is entirely
predictable from looking over your shoulder.
And I would contrast this with writing. So
writing, lots of people are familiar with
Gmail's autocomplete, and the different forms
of autocomplete that show up when you're trying
to post text messages, or emails, or things like
that. They can only be so helpful, because often,
it's just really not clear what you're going
to be writing just by looking at what you've
written before. But in code sometimes,
when you edit a part of a code base,
you're going to need to change things, and in
other parts of code base, and it's entirely
clear how you're going to need to change things.
So one core part of Cursor is this really suit
to autocomplete experience, where you predict the
next set of that you're going to be doing across
multiple files, across multiple places within a
file. And making models good at that use case,
one, there's a speed component of, those models
need to be really fast, they need to give you
a completion within 300 milliseconds. There's
also this cost component of, we're running tons,
and tons, and tons of molecules, every keystroke,
we need to be changing our prediction for what
you're going to do next. And then it's also
this really specialty use case of, you need
models that are really good, not at completing
the next token, just a generic tech sequence,
but are really good at autocompleting a series
of diffs, looking at what's changed within a code
base, and then creating the next set of things
that are going to change, both deleted and added
and all of that, and we found a ton of success
in training models specifically for that task.
So that's a place where no foundation models
are involved, it's kind of our own thing. We
don't have a lot of labeling or branding about
this in the app, power is a very core part of
Cursor. And then another set of places where a
user own models are to help things like Sonnet,
or Gemini, or GPT, and those sit both
on the inputs of those big models,
and on the output. On the input side of things,
those models are searching throughout a code base,
try to figure out the parts of a code base to
show to one of these big models. You can kind
of think about this as a mini Google search that's
specifically built for finding the relevant parts
of the code base to show one of these big models.
And then on the output side of things,
we take the sketches of the changes that these
models are suggesting, you make with that code
base. And then we have models that then fill
in the details of, the high level thinking
is done by the smartest models, they spend
a few tokens on doing that, and then these
smaller specialty incredibly fast models, coupled
with some inference tricks, then take those high
level changes and turn them actually into full
code diffs. And so it's been super helpful for
pushing on quality in places where you need a
specialty task, and it's been super helpful for
pushing on speed, which is such an important
dimension of product quality for us too.
This is so interesting. I just
had Kevin Weil on the podcast,
CPO of OpenAI, and he calls this the
ensemble of models, that's the same way-
Yes.
... they work, to use the best feature of each
one, and to your point, the cost advantages
of using cheaper models. These other models,
are they based on Llama and things like that,
just open source models that
you guys plug into and build on?
Yeah. So again, we try to be very pragmatic
about the place that we're going to do this work,
and we don't want to reinvent the wheel. And so
starting from the very best pre-trained models
that exist out there, often open source ones,
sometimes in collaboration with these big model
providers that don't share their weights out into
the world, because the thing we care about last
is the ability to read line by line, the matrix of
weights that then go to give you a certain output.
We just care about the ability to train these
things, to post-train them. And so by and large,
yes, open source models, sometimes working with
the closed source providers too to tune things.
This leads to a discussion that a lot of AI
founders always think about and investors,
which is moats, and defensibility in AI.
So it feels like one is custom models,
is a moat in the space. How do you just think
about long-term defensibility in the space,
knowing there's other folks, as you said,
launching constantly trying to eat your lunch?
I think that there are ways to build in inertia
and traditional moats, but I think by and large,
we're in a space where it is incumbent on us
to continue to try to build the best thing,
and everyone in this industry. And I truly
just think that the ceiling is so high that
no matter what entrenchment you build, you can
be leapfrogged. And I think that this resembles
markets that are maybe a little bit different from
normal software markets, normal enterprise markets
of the past. I think one that comes to mind is the
market for search engines at the end of 1999, or
at the end of the '90s and beginning of the 2000s.
I think another market that comes to mind that
resembles this market in many ways, it's actually
just the development of the peripheral computer
and many computers in the '70s, '80s, '90s.
And I think that, yes, in each of those markets,
the ceiling was incredibly high, it was possible
to swish. You could keep getting value for the
incremental hour of a smart person's time, the
incremental R&D dollar for a really long time,
you wouldn't run out of useful things to
build. And then in search in particular,
not on the computer case, adding distribution was
helpful for making the product better too, in that
you could tune the algorithms, you could tune the
learning based off of the data and the feedback
you're getting from users. And I think that all of
those dynamics exist in our market too. And so I
think maybe the sad truth for people like us, but
then the amazing truth for the world is, I think
that there are many leapfrogs that exist, there's
more useful things to build. We're a long way away
from where we can compete in 5, 10 years, and
it's incumbent in our state to keep that going.
So what I'm hearing, this sounds like a
lot more like a consumer sort of moat,
where it's just, be the best thing
consistently so that people stick with
you versus creating lock-in and things like
that, where they're just... Like Salesforce,
where it's just contracts with the entire
company, and you have to use this product.
Yeah. I think the important thing to note is,
if you're in a space where you run out
of useful things to do very quickly,
then that's not a great situation to be in. But
if you're in a place where big investments, and
having more and more great people working
on the right path can keep giving you value,
then you can get these economies of scale of R&D,
and you can deeply work on the technology in the
right direction, and get to a place where that is
defensible. But yes, it is... I think there's a
consumer-like tendency to it, and I really think
it's just about building the best thing possible.
Do you think in the future there's
one winner in this space, or do you
think it's going to be a world of
a number of products like this?
I think the market is just so very big. You asked
about the IDE thing early on, and one thing that
I think a trip of some people that were thinking
about the space is, they looked at the IDE market
of the past 10 years, and they said, "Who's
making money off of the editors?" It's this
super fragmented space where everyone kind of
has their own thing, with their own figuration,
and there's one company that actually
makes money off making great editors,
but that company is only so big. And then the
conclusion was, it was going to look like that
in the future. And I think that the thing
that people missed was that there was only
so much you could do building an editor in
the 2010s for coders, and the company that
made money off of editors was doing things like
making it easy to navigate around a code base,
and doing some error checking and type checking
for things, and having good debugging tools.
Which were all very useful, but I think that
the set of things you can build for programmers,
I think the set of things you can build for
knowledge workers in many different areas just
goes very far and very deep. The problem in front
of all of us is the automation of a lot of busy
work and knowledge work, and really changing all
the areas of knowledge work in front of us to be
much higher level and more productive.
So that was a long-winded way to say,
I think the market's really, really big that
we're in. I think it's much bigger than people
have realized than the other building tools for
developers in the past. And I think that there
will be a bunch of different solutions. I think
that there will be one company, to be determined
if it's going to be us, but I do think that there
will be one company that builds the general tool
that builds almost all the world's software,
and that will be a very, very generationally
big business. But I think that there will be
kind of niches you can occupy in doing something
for a particular segment of the market, or for a
very particular part of the software development
life cycle. But the general programming shifts
from just writing formal programming languages
to something way higher level. This is
the application you purchase and use to
do that. I think that there will be generally one
winner there, and it will be a very big business.
Juicy. Along those lines, it's interesting
that Microsoft was actually at the center of
this first, with an amazing product, amazing
distribution, Copilot you said was the thing
that got you over the hump of, "Wow, there could
be something really big here." And it doesn't
feel like they're winning, it feels like they're
falling behind. What do you think happened there?
I think that there are specific historical reasons
why Copilot might not have lived up... So far have
lived up to the expectations that some
people have for it, and then I think that
there are structural reasons. I think the
structural reason is... And to be clear,
Microsoft, in the Copilot case, obviously a
big inspiration for our work, and in general,
I think they do lots of awesome things,
and we're users of many Microsoft products,
but I think that this is a market that's
not super friendly to incumbents, in that
a market that's friendly to incumbents might
be one where there's only so much to do,
it kind of gets commoditized fairly quickly,
and you can bundle that in with other products,
and where the ROI between different products
is quite small. And in that case, perhaps it
doesn't make sense to buy the innovative
solution, it makes sense to just kind of
buy the thing that's bundled in with other stuff.
Another market that might be particularly helpful
for incumbents is one where there's... From
the get-go, you have your stuff in one place,
and it's really, really excruciatingly hard to
switch, and for better or for worse. I think in
our case, you can try out different tools, and you
can decide which product you think is better. And
so that's not super friendly to incumbents, and
that's more friendly to whoever you think is going
to have the most innovative product. And then the
specific historical reasons, as I understand them
are the group of people that worked on the
first version of Copilot have, by and large,
gone on to do other things at other places. I
think it's been a little hard to coordinate among
all the different departments and parties that
might be involved in making something like this.
I want to come back to Cursor. A question I like
to ask everyone that's building a tool like this,
if you could sit next to every new user that uses
Cursor for the first time, just whisper a couple
tips in their ear to be more successful, most
successful with Cursor, what would be 1 or 2 tips?
I think right now, and we'd want to fix this at
a product level, a lot of being successful with
Cursor is kind of having a taste for what
the models can do, both what complexity of
a task they can handle, and how much you need to
specify things to that model, but having a taste
for the quality of the model, and where its gaps
exist, and what it can do and what it can't. And
right now, we don't do a good job in the
product of educating people around that,
and maybe giving people some swim
lanes, giving people some guidelines.
But to develop that taste, would give two tips.
So one is, as mentioned before, would bias less
toward, trying in one go to tell the model, "Hey,
here's exactly what I want you to do." Then seeing
the output, and then either being disappointed or
accepting the entire thing for an entire big task.
Instead what I would do is I would chop things up
into bits, and you can spend basically the same
amount of time specifying things overall, but
chopped up more. So you're specifying a little
bit, you're getting a little bit of work,
you're specifying a little bit, getting a
little bit of work, and not doing as much the,
"Let's write a giant thing telling the model
exactly what to do." I think that will be a
little bit of a recipe for disaster right now.
And so biasing toward chopping things up.
At the same time, and it might make sense
to do this on a side project and not on your
professional work, I would encourage people to,
especially developers who are used to
existing workflows for building software,
I would encourage people to explicitly try to fall
on their face, and try to discover the limits of
what these models can do by being ambitious in
a safe environment, like perhaps a side project,
and trying to kind of go around town, use AI
to the fullest. Because a lot of the time,
we run into people who haven't given the AI yet a
fair shake, and are underestimating its abilities.
So generally biasing towards chopping things
up and making things smaller, but to discover
the limits of what you can do there, explicitly
just try to go for broke in a safe environment,
and get a taste for... You might be surprised in
some of the places where the model doesn't break.
What I'm essentially hearing is build
a gut feeling of what the model can do,
and how far it can take an idea versus
just kind of guiding it along. And I
bet that you need to rebuild this gut
every time there's a new model launch,
when it's on... I don't know, 4.0 comes out, you
have to do this again. Is that generally right?
Yes. For the past few years, it hasn't been
as big as I think the first experience people
have had with some of these big models.
This is also a problem we would hope to
solve much better just for users, and
take the burden off of them. But each
of these things have slightly different
quirks and different personalities.
Along these lines, something that people
are always debating tools like Cursor,
are they more helpful to junior engineers, or
are they more helpful to senior engineers? Do
they make senior engineers 10X better?
Do they make junior engineers more like
senior engineers? Who do you think
benefits most today from Cursor?
I think across the board. Both of these
cohorts benefit in big ways. It's a little
hard to say on the relative ranking. I will
say, they fall into different anti-patterns.
The junior engineers we see going a little
too wholesale, relying on AI for everything,
and we're not yet in a place where you can kind
of do that end-to-end on a professional tool,
working with tens, hundreds of other people
within a long-lived code base. And then the
senior engineers... For many folks, it's not
true for all, and we actually often... One of
the ways these tools are adopted is, there's
developer experience teams within companies,
often those are staffed by incredibly senior
people, because often, those are people who
are building tools to make the rest of the
engineers within an organization more productive.
And we've seen some very, very boundary pushing
kind of... We've seen people who are on the front
lines of really trying to adopt the technology as
much as possible there. But by and large, I would
say on average, as a group, the senior engineers
underrate what AI can do for them, and stick to
their existing workflows. And so the relative
ranking is a little hard, I think they fall
into different anti-patterns, but they both, by
and large, yet get big benefits with these tools.
That makes absolute sense. I love
that it's two ends of the spectrum,
expect too much, don't expect enough.
It's like the three bears allegory.
Yeah.
Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Maybe the sort of senior,
but not staff, right in the middle.
Interesting. Okay. Just a couple more questions.
What's something that you wish you knew before
you got into this role? If you could go back
to Michael at the beginning of Cursor, which
was not that long ago, and you could give him some
advice, what's something that you would tell him?
The tough thing with this is, it feels like so
much of the hard-won knowledge is tacit, and a bit
hard to communicate verbally. And the sad fact of
life feels like for some areas of human endeavor,
you kind of do need to fall on your face to...
Either need to fall on your face to learn the
correct thing, or you need to be around someone
who's a great example of excellence in the thing.
And one area where we have felt this is hiring. I
think that we actually were... So we tried to be
incredibly patient on the hiring front.
It was really important to us that,
both for personal reasons and also for, I
think actually for the company's strategy,
having a world-class group of engineers and
researchers to work on Cursor with us was
going to be incredibly important. Also, getting
people who fit... A certain mix of intellectual
curiosity and experimentation, because there
can be so many new things we need to build.
And then also an intellectual honesty, and
maybe micro-pessimism, bluntness, because if
all the noise, and... Especially as the company's
grown, and the business has grown, keeping a level
head I think is incredibly important too.
But getting the right group of people into
the company was the thing that maybe more than
anything else, apart from building the product,
we really, really fussed over. We actually waited
a long time to grow the team because of that.
And I think that many people you hear hired too
fast, think we actually hired too slow to begin
with. I think it could have been remedied,
I think we could have been better at it.
And the method of recruiting that we ended up
eventually falling into and working really well
for us, which isn't that novel, of going after
people that we think are really world-class,
and recruiting them over the course of, in some
cases, many years, ended up working for us in
the end, but I don't think we were very good at
it to begin with. And so I think that there were
hard-won lessons around both who was the right
profile, who actually made sense in that team,
what did greatness look like, and then how
to talk with someone about the opportunity,
and get them excited if they really
weren't looking for anything. There
were lots of learnings there about how to do
that well, and that took us a bit of time.
What are some of those learnings
for folks that are hiring right
now? What's something you missed or learned?
I think to start with, maybe we actually
biased a little bit too much towards
looking for people who fit the archetype
of well-known school, very young,
had done the things that were high credential
in those well-known school environments. And
actually, I think found... Were lucky early on
to find fantastic people who are willing to do
this with us who were later careered. I think we
should kind of spent a bunch of time on maybe a
little bit the wrong profile to begin with, and
part of that was a seniority thing. Part of that
was kind of an interest and experience thing
too, we have hired people who are excellent,
excellent, excellent and very young, but they
maybe look in some cases slightly different
from being straight out of central casting.
Another lesson is just, we very much evolved our
interview loop, and so now, we have a hand-rolled
set of interview questions, and then core our...
Core to how we interview too, is actually, we have
people onsite for two days, and do a project with
us, a work test project. And that has worked
really well, that increasingly you're finding
that. I think how to learn about what people are
interested in, and put our best foot forward,
and letting them know about the opportunity
when they're really not looking for anything,
and have those conversations. There's definitely
been... Gotten better at that over time.
Do you have a favorite interview
question that you like to ask?
I think this two-day work test which we
thought would not scale past a few people
has had surprising staying power.
And the great thing about it is,
it lets someone go end-to-end on it like
a real project. It's not work that we use,
it's canned list of projects. But it gives you
two days of seeing a real work product, and
it doesn't have to be incredibly time-enhancing
other teams from time. You can take the time you
would spend in a half day or one day onsite, and
you kind of spread it out over those two days,
and give someone a lot of time to do work on their
projects, and so that can actually help it scale.
It helps to enforce, do you want to be around
this person type test, because you are around
this person for two days, a bunch of meals with
them. We didn't expect that one to stick around,
but that has been really, really important to
our value to process, and then also important to
getting people excited at, especially the very
early stages of the company. Because before,
people are using the product, and know about
it. And when the product is comparatively not
very good, really, the only thing you have going
for you is a team of people that some people find
special and want to be around. And the two days
would give us a chance to just have this person
meet us, and in some cases, hopefully get
convinced that they want to throw in with us.
That one was unexpected. Not exactly an interview
question, but kind of like a forward interview.
The ultimate interview question. So just to
be very clear about what you're describing,
you give them an assignment, like, "Build
this feature in our actual code base,
work with the team to code it and
ship it." Is that roughly right?
Yes. So we don't use the IP, not shift end-to-end,
but it's like a mock... Very often in our code
base, "Here's a real mini two-day project.
You're going to do it end-to-end." Largely
being left alone, there's collaboration too.
And then we're a pretty imprisoned company,
in almost all cases, it's actually
just sitting in office with us too.
And you've been saying that this has scaled to
even today, so how big are you guys at this point?
So we are going on 60 people.
So small for the scale and impact. I was
thinking it'd be a lot larger than that.
Yeah.
And I imagine the largest percent is engineers?
Yeah. To be clear, a big part of the work ahead of
us is building a group of people that is bigger,
and awesome, and can continue to make the
product better, and the service we give to
customers better. And so you don't plan to stay
that small for longer, wouldn't hope so. But
part of the reason that that number is small is,
the percentage of engineering and research and
design is very high within the company, and so
many software companies when they have roughly
40 engineers would be over 100 people, because
there's lots of operational work, and often,
they're very, very sales-led from the get-go,
and that's just quite labor-intensive. And here,
we started from a place of being incredibly
lean in product-led, and we now serve lots
of our market customers, and it built that
out, but there's much more to do there.
A question I wanted to ask you, there's
so much happening in AI, there's things
launching every... There's newsletters, many
newsletters, whose entire function is to
tell you what is happening in AI every single
day. Running a company that's at the center,
the white-hot center of this space, how do
you stay focused, and how do you help your
team stay focused, and heads down, and just build
and not get distracted by all these shiny things?
I think hiring is a big part of it, and
if you get people with the right attitude.
All of this should be asterisked in, I think
we're doing well there, I think that we'd
probably be doing better there too, and it's
something that we should probably talk even
more about as a company. But I think that hiring
people with the right disposition, people who
are less focused on external validation, more
focused on building something really great,
more focused on doing really high quality work,
and people who are just generally level-headed,
and maybe the highs aren't very high, the lows
aren't very low. I think hiring can get you
through a lot here, and I think that's actually
a learning throughout the company, is that for
any... You need process, you need hierarchy,
you need lots of things, but for any kind of
organizational tool that you're introducing into
a company, the result you're looking to get from
that tool also... You can go pretty far on hiring
people with the right behaviors that you want
to resolve from that for organizational thing.
And the specific example that comes to mind is,
we've been able to get away with not a ton
of process yet on the engineering front,
and I think we need a little bit more process,
but for our size, not a ton of process,
by hiring people who I think are really excellent.
One is hiring people that are level-headed. I
think two is just talking about it a lot. I
think three is hopefully leading by example.
And for us personally, we've since 2021, 2022 been
professionally working on this, and been working
on AI, and we've just seen a sea change of the
comings and goings of various technologies and
ideas of... If you're to transport yourself back
to end of 2021, beginning of 2022, this is GPT-3,
Instruct GPT doesn't exist, there's no Dolly,
there's no stable diffusion. And then we've gone
through all of those image technologies existing,
ChatGPT and that rise, and GPT-4, all of these
new models, all these different modalities, all
the video stuff, and only a very small number of
these things really kind of affects the business.
So I think we've kind of just built up a little
bit of an immune system, and know when an event
comes around that actually is really going to
matter for us. This dynamic too of there
being lots, and lots, and lots of chatter,
but then maybe only a few things that really
matter, I think has been mirrored in AI over the
last decade, where there have been so many papers
on deep learning in academia, so many papers on AI
in academia, then the amazing thing is there are
really a lot of... A lot the progress of AI can
be attributed to some very simple elegant ideas
that have stayed around, and the vast majority of
ideas that have been put out there haven't had
staying power, and haven't mattered a ton. And
so the dynamic is a little bit mirrored in the
evolution of deep learning as a field overall.
Last question. What do you think people still
most misunderstand, or maybe don't fully grasp
about where things are heading with AI in
building in the way the world will change?
People are still a little bit occupied too much,
either end of a spectrum of it's all going to
happen very fast, and this is all bluster, and
hype, and snake well, and I think we're in the
middle of a technology shift that's going to be
incredibly consequential. I think it's going to
be more consequential than the internet, I think
it's going to be more consequential than any
shift in tech that we've seen since the advent of
computers. And I think it's going to take a while,
and I think it's going to be a multi-decade
thing, and I think many different groups will
be consequential in pushing it forward.
And to get to a world where computers can
increasingly do more, and more, and more for
us, there's all of these independent problems
that need to be knocked down, and progress needs
to be made on them, and some of those are on the
science side of things of getting these models
to understand different types of data, be faster,
cheaper, smarter, conform to the modalities that
we care about, take actions in the real world.
And then some of it's on how we're going to work
with them, and what's the experience that a human
should actually be seeing and controlling on
a computer, and working with these things.
But I think it's going to take decades. I think
that there's going to be lots of amazing work to
do. I think that also, one of the most...
A pattern of a group that I think will be
especially important here, not to talk our own
book, but I think is the company that works on
automating and augmenting a particular area
of knowledge work, builds both the technology
under the surface for that, integrating the best
parts from providers, sometimes doing it in-house,
and then also builds the product experience for
that. I think people who do that, and... We're
trying to do it in software, people do that in
other areas, I think those folks will be really,
really, really consequential. Not just for
the end value that users see, but then I
think as they get to scale, they'll be really
important for pushing forward the technology,
because I think they'll be able to build... The
most successful of them will be able to build
very, very big businesses. So, excited to see the
rise of other companies like that in other areas.
I know you guys are hiring. For
folks that are interested in, "Hey,
I want to go work here, and build this
sort of stuff." What kind of roles are
you looking for right now? Anyone
specifically you're trying... Any
roles you're most excited about filling ASAP?
What should people know if they're curious?
There are so many things that this group of people
need to do that we are not get equipped to do.
Generic across the board, first of all, and so
if you don't think we have a role for something,
maybe you should reach out, that won't actually
be the case. And maybe we can actually learn from
you, and decide that we need something that we
weren't yet aware of. But by and large, I think
that two of the most important things for us to do
this year are have the best product in the space,
and then grow it. And we're kind of in this land
grab mode, where almost everyone in the world is
either using no tool like ours, or they're using
one that's maybe developing less quickly. So
growing Cursor too is a big goal, and I would say,
especially always on the hunt for folks who...
Excellent engineers, designers, researchers,
but then folks all across the business side too.
I can't help but ask this question
now that you talk about engineers,
there's this question of just, "AI's going
to write all our code." But everyone's
still hiring engineers like crazy. All the
foundational models, so many open roles.
Yeah. We're not out there tooting the
horn of, people can learn to code.
Do you think there's going to be an
inflection point of engineering roles
start to slow down? I know this is a big question,
but just... Do you see engineers being more
and more needed across all these companies,
or do you think at some point there's all
these Cursor agents running building for us?
Again, we have the view that there's this
both long messy middle of it not jumping to a,
just you step back, and you ask for all
your stuff to be done, and you have your
engineering department. And very much, you want
to evolve from programming as it exists today,
we want humans to be in the driver's seat, and we
think even in the end state, that's giving folks
control over everything is really important,
and you will need professionals to do that,
and decide what the software looks like.
So both I think that, yes, engineers are
definitely needed. I think that engineers
will be able to do much more. I think the
demand for software is very lasting, which
is not the most novel thing, but I think it's
kind of crazy to think about how expensive and
labor-intensive it is to build things that are
pretty simple and easy to specify, or it would
look like it to the outside observer, and just
how hard those things are to do right now.
All of the stuff that exists right now that's
justified by the cost and demand that we have
now, if you could bring that down by [inaudible
01:07:56], I think you would have tons, and tons,
and tons of more stuff that we could do in our
computers, tons more tools. And I've felt this,
where... One of my early jobs actually was working
for a biotechnology company, and it was building
internal tools for them, and the off-the-shelf
tools that existed were horrible, and did not
fit their use case at all. And then the internal
tools I was building, there was definitely a ton
of demand there for things that could be built,
and that far outstripped just the things that
I could build in the time that I was with them.
The physics of working on computers are
so great, you should be able to basically
just move everything around, do everything that
you want to do. There's still so much friction,
I think that there's much more demand for
software than what we can build today with
things costing like a blockbuster movie
to make simple productivity software. And
so I think long into the future, yes, there
will actually be more demand for engineers.
Is there anything that we didn't cover that you
wanted to mention? Any last nugget wisdom you
wanted to leave listeners with? You could
also say no, because we've done a lot.
We think a lot about how you set up
a team to be able to make new stuff,
in addition to continuing to improve the stuff
that you have right now. And I think if we were
to be successful, IDE is going to have to change
a ton, [inaudible 01:09:18] looks like is going
to have to change a ton going into the future.
And if you look around, the companies we respect,
there are definitely examples of companies that
have continued to really ride the wave of many
leapfrogs, and continue to actually push the
frontier. But they're kind of rare too, it's
a hard thing to do. So part of that is just kind
of thinking about the thing, and trying to reflect
on it in our good days, and the first principle
side of things, part of it's also trying to get
in and study past examples of greatness here, and
that's something that we think about a lot too.
Yeah. Yeah. Before we started recording, you
had all these books behind you, and I was like,
"What's that over there?" It's the history of
some old computer company that was influential
in a lot of ways that I've never heard of.
And I think that says a lot about you of,
where a lot of this innovation comes from,
is studying the past, and study history,
and what's worked and what hasn't.
Okay. Where can folks find you online
if they want to reach out and maybe apply?
You said that there may be roles they may not
even be aware of, where do they go find that,
and then how can listeners be useful to you?
Yeah. If folks are interested in working on this
stuff, would love to speak, they can find... If
they go to cursor.com, they can kind of both
find the product and find out how to reach us.
Easy. Michael, thank you so much
for being here. This was incredible.
It was wonderful. Thank you.
Bye, everyone.
Thank you so much
for listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating,
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.