A lot of the bets we're making inside the
company are for things that are not three,
four weeks away. We should be cannibalizing
the existing state of our product every six
to 12 months. Every six to 12 months,
it should make our existing product look
silly. It should almost make the form
factor of existing product look dumb.
How do you know when it's time to hire someone?
I want the company to almost be like this
dehydrated entity. Every hire is like a little
bit of water, and we only go back and hire
someone when we're back to being dehydrated.
Any other there skills you think
people should be investing more
in with the rise of AI building
more and more of our products?
The engineers are now able to produce
more technology. The ROI of building
technology has actually gone up. This
actually means you hire more. The best
thing to do is just get your hands dirty
with all of these products. You could be
a force multiplier to your organization in
ways in which they never even anticipated.
Today my guest is Varun Mohan. Varun is the
co-founder and CEO of Windsurf, which has quickly
become one of people's favorite AI coding tools,
and is basically the main competitor to Cursor
with over 1 million users four months in. In our
conversation, Varun shares what makes Windsurf
unique, why they decided to invest heavily in
enterprise sales very early in their history,
why agency is going to be the most important
skill for engineers and product builders to build,
also the story of how they started out as a GPU
infrastructure company and realized there was
a much bigger opportunity up the stack and the
two pivots that got them to where they're today.
He also gives a live demo, advice
for being successful at Windsurf,
and so much more. There's so much to learn about
where things are heading for engineers and product
builders in general in this conversation.
And I'm really excited to bring it to you.
Thank you to everyone on LinkedIn and Twitter
and my newsletter community for suggesting great
questions to dig into with Varun. If you enjoy
this podcast, don't forget to subscribe and follow
it in your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
Also, if you become a yearly subscriber of my
newsletter, you get a year free of Perplexity
Pro, Notion Plus, Linear, Granola, and Superhuman.
Check it out at lennysnewsletter.com.
With that, I bring you Varun Mohan.
This episode is brought to you by Brex, the
financial stack used by one in every three
US venture-backed startups. Brex knows that nearly
40% of startups fail because they run out of cash.
So they built a banking experience that focuses on
helping founders get more from every dollar. It's
a stark difference from traditional banking
options that leave a startup's cash sitting
idle while chipping away at it with fees. To
help founders protect cash and extend runway,
Brex combined the best things about checking,
treasury, and FDIC insurance in one powerhouse
account. You can send and receive money
worldwide at lightning speed. You can get
20X the standard FDIC protection through program
banks. And you can earn industry-leading yield
from your first dollar while still being able
to access your funds anytime. To learn more,
check out Brex at brex.com/banking-solutions.
That's B-R-E-X, .com/banking-solutions.
This episode is brought to you by Productboard,
the leading product management platform for the
enterprise. For over 10 years, Productboard has
helped customer-centric organizations like Zoom,
Salesforce, and Autodesk build the right
products faster. And as an end-end platform,
Productboard seamlessly supports all stages of
the product development lifecycle, from gathering
customer insights to planning a roadmap, to
aligning stakeholders, to earning customer buy-in,
all with a single source of truth. And now,
product leaders can get even more visibility
into customer needs with Productboard Pulse,
a new voice of customer solution. Built-in
intelligence helps you analyze trends across all
of your feedback and then dive deeper by asking
AI your follow-up questions. See how Productboard
can help your team deliver higher-impact products
that solve real customer needs and advance your
business goals. For special offer and free 15-day
trial visit productboard.com/lenny.
That's Productboard.com/L-E-N-N-Y.
Varun, thank you so much for being
here and welcome to the podcast.
Buddy, thanks for having me. A long time listener.
Oh, I really appreciate that. I'm so excited
to have you here. I feel like just you guys
have become this overnight success, which
is definitely not an overnight success,
but I feel like I've been hearing about
Windsurf more and more as people's favorite
AI tool. And I just don't think people know
the story behind Windsurf, behind Codeium,
the company that you built. So I thought it'd
be good to maybe just start there and have you
just briefly share the history of Codeium
and how Windsurf emerged out of Codeium.
Yeah. So the company was actually started
close to four years ago. As you know,
AI coding was not a thing four years ago.
ChatGPT was not out four years ago. At the time,
we actually started out building GPU
virtualization and compiler software.
Before this, I worked in autonomous vehicles. My
co-founder, who I had known since middle school,
worked on AR/VR at Meta. And for us, we believe
deep learning would touch many, many industries.
It wouldn't just touch autonomous vehicles.
It would touch financial services, defense,
healthcare. And we believe these
applications were hard to build,
these deep learning applications. So we made it
possible for you to effectively run these complex
applications on computers without GPUs, and we
would handle all the complexity of being able to
actually run the workload on the GPUs for you. And
we were able to optimize these workloads a ton.
And in the middle of 2022 rolled around and
we had a couple million in revenue and we
were managing upwards of 10,000 sort of GPUs. We
had eight people. At the time, we were free cash
flow positive. But I think what we felt was once
these generative models started to get very good,
we sort of felt a lot of what we built was not as
valuable. And this was a very, very hard moment
for us at the company. We were only eight people
at the time, but we felt, "Hey, would people be
training these very bespoke sentiment classifier
models anymore that were very, very custom models?
Or would they just ask GPT-N, is this a positive
or a negative sentiment?" Probably it's going to
be the latter, right? And in a world in which
everyone was going to run generative AI models,
why would an infrastructure company be a
differentiator? Because everyone is going to
run the same kind of infrastructure down the line.
So instead what we decided to do was we believe
generative AI was almost going to be like
the next internet. And in that case, what
we should go out and do is build the next great
apps like Google, like Amazon. And we vertically
integrated and actually took our infrastructure,
our inference infrastructure to go out and build
Codeium at the time. And at that time, we were
early adopters of GitHub Copilot and we thought
the coding space was going to get tremendously
disrupted in the next coming years. So we actually
took our infrastructure, we ran our own models
in massive scale. We even trained our own models.
In the very beginning it was very, very
simple. It was purely an autocomplete model,
which basically means that as the user was
typing, we'd complete the next one or two or
three or four lines of code. But we provided
the product entirely for free in all the IDEs
that developers coded. That meant to VSCode,
JetBrains, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Vim, Emacs. And
the reason why we were able to build it for free
was because of our infrastructure background. We
were able to optimize these workloads a ton.
I guess very quickly after that, some large
businesses also wanted to work with us. And we
built out this enterprise motion to work with
these large companies like Dell, JPMorgan Chase.
And for them the bigger thing wasn't just, "Hey,
could we autocomplete code or could we chat with
the code base?" It was, "Could you offer us a
secure offering that was also personalized to all
the private data inside the company?" So we took
our infrastructure and made it so that we invested
a ton in making sure that we deeply understood
these large companies code bases. And that's
what we were working on until six months ago.
It's not that we've stopped working on that,
but basically what we realized six months
ago was we were getting limited by the IDEs
that we were already working in. So VSCode,
which is a very popular IDE, had a ceiling
for the AI capabilities, we could showcase
our users. And because of that, we decided to
go out and fork VSCode and build our own IDE
with some of these new agentic capabilities.
And over time in the last couple of years,
the model capabilities have also been growing
exponentially year over year. And that's sort
of where we are right now. I skipped a lot of
pieces there, but that's what we're landed.
There's so many interesting threads there.
One is just, there's always this question
of just where value will accrue in AI. And it's so
interesting, you guys started almost at the bottom
layer of infrastructure GPUs and then you
went to what people call a GPT wrapper,
not actually. So I guess any just
lessons there, just thoughts on
just where you think value will end up in
this world of AI and the stack of AI tools?
Maybe I can start by just saying one thing
about startups that I think are really true,
it's very unlikely the first thing that you
believe you should go work on is going to be
the right thing, which is a very hard thing to
kind of wrangle with being a startup founder,
right? You need to kind of be irrationally
optimistic that what you're going to do is
going to be differentially important. Because
otherwise, why would you go out and do what
you're doing? And if it's obvious, then a
bigger company would've already done it, right?
But then you also need to be really, really
realistic because most ideas that are,
I guess, non-conventional are usually bad ideas,
right? So it's this weird tightrope you need to
kind of balance on top of where you're pushing
for a future that you believe is true, but all
the while you're getting new information. You need
to kill the beliefs that you had. And if I were to
start with the infrastructure piece, we first went
in with the assumption that model architectures
were going to be really, really heterogeneous.
Working from an autonomous vehicle background,
there were many different types of model
architectures out there. There were
convolutional neural networks, graph neural
networks, recurrent neural networks, LSTMs,
sort of lighter neural nets with frustrum
point networks. And there were maybe tens
of architectures we were dealing with. And at that
point we were like, the complexity of this is so
high that it's very clear if someone offloaded
the complexity, there would be a lot of value.
Fast-forward to the middle of 2023,
everything looks like it's going to
be a transformer. So now our hypotheses
are just wrong. So at this point then,
most of the value is probably not going to accrue
at purely the, at least this is our belief,
at the infrastructure layer. It's going to
accrue somewhere else. Where is the layer
that you can actually differentiate on? And
we believe the application layer is a very,
very deep layer to go out and differentiate on,
right? What are the number of ways we can build
better user experiences and better workflows
for developers? We think there's effectively
no ceiling on that, on how much better we
can make the lives of developers basically.
You touched on the second thread that
I thought was really interesting here,
is just how you guys pivoted from ideas that
were working. You were making money, people
loved it. You said you had millions of dollars
of ARR revenue. And then you're just like, "No,
we're going to completely change the business."
So the question there is, just like, what have
you learned about knowing what to follow?
And one thing I heard there that was really
interesting is just once your assumptions
change about that you built your idea on,
it's time to think this idea
and maybe try something else.
I think the way we sort of think about this
is even when we're working right now, we just
accept that we're going to get a lot of things
wrong. We're just going to get a lot of things
wrong. Obviously that's a very big moment because
that was a bet the company moment in the sense
that we basically said, told our investors, "Hey,
we're making money on this." We had already raised
28 million of capital and we were just like,
"Hey, we're just going to pivot entirely from
this." And we did that overnight. This wasn't this
thing where we just said, "Hey, maybe a quarter,
one or two quarters." Because one of the things we
knew that's very important for startups is focus.
If you're trying to do another thing that you
think is big and you're focused on something that
you don't believe is valuable, you're guaranteed
going to fail at the thing you think is going to
be big. So that's a very obvious thing there. But
I think once you go in with the assumption that a
lot of your hypotheses are going to be wrong, but
you will do the most concentrated work possible
to go out and validate these hypotheses
and you won't be in love with your ideas.
I think ideas, it's awesome when you have a great
idea, but you should never be too in love with
your ideas. And you have an organization that
is very truth-seeking. I think a lot of people
at the company have had their ideas tested over
and over again. Even just building Windsurf. That
is not a complete company pivot, but that's a big
decision that we made at the company. You kind of
need to make some bets. And sometimes you're
wrong and sometimes you're right. But if you
have an organization that comes out and you feel
like morale is not going to be low if you made
the wrong decision, that's the best, right? That
means you have optionality for the rest of time.
And Lenny, one thing that I try
to tell the company about this is,
this year the total amount of engineering output
we'll have is much larger than the engineering
output we've had since the beginning of the
company's creation 'till now. So that almost
means every year is a new lease on life for us,
right? It's almost a new way for us to test out
an entirely new set of hypotheses. And maybe
we were wrong about our original hypotheses in
the first place. What makes us more smart than
everyone else to be right more times than that?
That's so empowering. It makes me think
about... Uri Levine was on the podcast,
co-founder of Waze, and he has this
phrase that he wears on his shirt. His
book is called this Fall in Love with the
Problem, Not the Solution. And that feels
like that's exactly what you're describing.
Okay, so let's talk about Windsurf. What's
the simplest way for people to
understand what is Windsurf?
Yeah. So Windsurf is an IDE, right? It's an
application to go out and build software and
build applications. The crazy thing is a
lot of people who use the product don't
even probably know what an IDE is, which is
crazy. And we'll get into that in a second.
But why did we go out and build Windsurf and
what is Windsurf maybe? Why couldn't we have
just done this on top of conventional
IDEs like Visual Studio Code? So maybe
just to get into this a little bit, as we saw
that AI was getting more and more powerful,
the way people go out and build technology,
we thought the interface for that was going
to change remarkably. It was not going to be a
conventional pure text editor where the user is
writing a handful of lines of code or most of
the code and the IDE provides maybe some basic
feedback on what the user is doing right or wrong.
And the basic feedback could be, "Hey, there's a
bug in your software or compiler error in your
software." It could do much more, right? It could
actually go out and modify large chunks of code.
One of the key pieces that we recognized was,
with this new paradigm with AI, AI was probably
going to write well over 90% of the software,
in which case the role of a developer and what
they're doing in the IDE is maybe reviewing code.
Maybe it's actually a little bit different
than what it is in the past. And we'll see
this very soon with Windsurf. Maybe when you're
using the product, actually a good chunk of the
user's time is that you're reviewing what the AI
is outputting. So we needed to build custom-review
flows into the IDE to actually make it so that
it was easier to actually go out and do that,
right? Because the developer is not
spending all their time writing code.
And this is the fundamental premise on why we
built the product. We thought we were going
to get limited a ton if we had very, very
basic UI out there. And I'll give you even
a simple example here. We have this auto-complete
product that completes a handful of lines of code.
Now we've actually launched this offering
called Windsurf Tab that basically shows
you refactors as well. And these refactors
are almost inline refactors. And we were
able to build a custom UI for that in Windsurf.
But in VSCode, because of the access to the APIs,
we needed to dynamically generate images right
alongside the user's cursor because we just
didn't have access to the capabilities
to showcase and edit properly. And what
we realized is immediately by porting over
to Windsurf, our acceptance rate tripled.
Same ML models, it just tripled. So what that, I
guess, gave us confidence in is yeah, you could
argue technology is very important. And I think
technology is very important. But if our users are
getting very little value from the technology
we're sort of building, you need to really
clarify, "Maybe we do need to build a new surface
and interface." And that's what Windsurf is.
So the big bet you took there just to make
this super clear, is you were initially
working within existing IDEs that everyone
was familiar with. And then it was like,
"This isn't going to get us where we need to
go. We're going to try to convince people to
switch to something completely new because it's
going to be so much better. It's our own IDE."
I think maybe people may not
recognize just how risky that is,
convincing engineers to use something
completely new. That's a huge deal.
Yeah, no, of course. And one of the key pieces,
maybe Lenny, that would be important to share
is a lot of our developers do use Visual Studio
Code. But there are lots of people that write in
languages like Java, sort of C++ and so on and so
forth, and they might use the JetBrains family of
IDEs that like IntelliJ. And for us, we are
actually still committed to building on those
platforms, right? We just felt though that one of
the dominant IDEs, which was Visual Studio Code,
was limiting the sort of user interface
that we could give to our actual customers.
What is the current state of traction for
Windsurf? You hear all these crazy numbers
about all the competitors in your space. What
can you share there for folks just to know?
Yeah, so maybe a handful. We launched
the product a bit over four months ago.
And in that period of time, over a
million developers have tried the
product. And obviously we have many hundreds
of thousands of monthly active users right now.
I love how these days like, "oh, a million.
Oh, no big deal." It's just the numbers are
absurd these days. We're just getting used
to just 100 million ARR here, million users
in four months there. It's just like, "Oh, of
course. How could you not have that?" But that's
absurd. It's just like an insane time right now.
You touched on something that I wanted to get to
later, but I may as well bring it up now, the
question of just how engineering will change
in the future. You throw out the stat that 90% of
code is going to be written by AI in the future.
Dario from Anthropic recently said the same
thing. You guys have a really interesting glimpse
into just how things will look in the future.
So I guess the question is just, how do you
think coding specifically will look in the next
few years, how different will it be from today?
I think when we think about what is an engineer
actually doing, it probably falls into three
buckets, right? What should I solve for?
How should I solve it? And then solving it.
I guess everyone who's working in this space is
probably increasingly convinced that solving it,
which is just the pure, "I know how I'm
going to do it" and just going and doing
it. AI is going to handle vast majority, if
not all of it. In fact, it probably actually,
with some of the work that we've done in
terms of deeply understanding code bases,
how should I solve it is also going to get
closer and closer to getting done. If you
deeply understand the environment inside an
organization, if you deeply understand the
code base, how you should solve it, given best
practices when the company also gets solved.
So I think what engineering kind of goes to is
actually what you wanted engineers to do in the
first place, which is, what are the most important
business problems that we do need to solve? What
are the most important capabilities that we need
our application, our product to have? And actually
going and prioritizing those and actually going
and making the right technical decisions to go
out and doing it. And I think that's where
engineering is probably heading towards.
Now, does that mean that no one needs a CS degree?
I think that's maybe a little bit overplayed
a little bit just because maybe here's my argument
for that. A lot of developers nowadays that build
full stack applications, at least until a
handful of years ago, they probably went to
college and took an operating system course. And
in theory, they're not really playing around with
the operating system, like the kernel scheduler
very frequently. But do those principles help
them in understanding why their applications
are slow? Do they help them in understanding
why some design decisions are better than the
other? Yeah, that makes them a much better
engineer than another engineer. And I think
that idea and the understanding of what's going
on at the bottom will make a good engineer even
better. But also at the same time, it empowers a
bunch of people that never understood all of
those things, how to actually build as well,
which is another remarkable sort of thing
that fell out through this whole process.
I don't know if you have kids, but just say
you had kids or you had niece or nephew going
into college, let's say, would you suggest
they do do computer science or would you
suggest you're not going to have a good time
if that's the career you choose right now?
Yeah. Maybe I think back a little bit. So I
went to MIT. A lot of us at the company went
to MIT together on the engineering team. I think
when I think about what we learned the most for
engineering or computer science, it was not
exactly like how do you write code. That is
almost a given that you can write code after going
to college. It's more like the principles of how
you think about a problem and how you break it
down and how you solve it in an interesting way.
So an example of a class that I really enjoyed
was our distributed systems class. And there,
you're kind of reading through literature
and understanding how some design decisions
were kind of made. And I think it's more like a
problem solving kind of course and a major. It's
a major of how you solve problems given some
constraints of how computers today function,
right? Like, here's the speed at which memory
sort of operates. Here's the speed at which...
Here's how much computation you can do in
one cycle or one second. And based on that,
you can make some trade-offs and solve a problem.
So I don't know if I would say that you shouldn't
go get a computer science degree. I think computer
science is almost synonymous with problem solving.
In that case, I think it's pretty valuable. Is
everything you learn in your computer science
degree useful? I'd say a lot of things that
I learned in my computer science degree are
not useful. I'll give you an example. I took a
parallel computing class in Julia. I don't think
Julia is a very popular programming language
anymore. Am I very sad that I took the class?
No. The principles of parallel computing
are still very useful, I would say, today.
So what I'm hearing is, skills
that you still want to build,
whether it's computer science or maybe
some version of computer science, is
kind of building the mental model
of how computers and systems work.
That's right.
Parallel processing, memory, hard drives,
internet, things like that. And then
there's just problem solving skills,
being able to solve interesting problems.
Is there any other skills you think people
should be investing more in with the rise of
AI building more and more of our products?
I think one of the things that's maybe a little
bit undervalued is this kind of agency piece.
And I think about this a lot, which is, you have a
lot of people that could go through college and go
through school and they're basically told exactly
what to do on a P-set. They're given these very,
very, I would say, well-defined paths that they
need to take. I think maybe in society and just
school, we don't prioritize how do you make sure
you get people with real agency that want to build
something, right? Their goal is not just to
maybe graduate from college and then get a
job at a big tech company where they're told
exactly what to do or where to put the pixel
for this one website. I think that's maybe a
skill set that is undervalued just right now,
probably in the last maybe 10 years or so. And I
think that's going to be really, really important.
For a startup, obviously these are skills
that we just look for. We look for people
that are really high agency because
we just recognize that by default,
if we don't innovate and do crazy things,
we're going to die. The company is just going
to die. So we just look for this, right? But I
would say for most software engineering jobs,
that's probably not the case. Just think
about big company X and what they're
hiring for on the average software engineering
interview. It probably doesn't look like that.
I love how you phrased that. If we
don't do crazy things and innovate,
we're going to die. That would be a great
title for this podcast episode. And I think,
I know, it's 100% true. There's just
a lot of crazy things happening and
a lot of innovation happening. And
if you can't keep up, you'll die.
So let's talk about hiring. You have a really
interesting approach to hiring. There's a few
questions I have here. One is just how do you... I
know you try to stay really lean. That's a common
theme across all the AI startups these days.
How do you know when it's time to hire someone?
I love the idea of being a lean company, but I
don't idolize it in the way that, "Hey, it is a
dream to be a 10% or 20% company that's making
50, 100, 200 million in revenue." That's not,
I think, what we idolize inside the company.
I think what we idolize is, be the smallest
company we can be to satisfy our ambitions.
That's what the goal is. And maybe, Lenny,
the way I would sort of put that out there
is, if I told you, "Hey, I'm going to build an
autonomous vehicle," and I said our team is 10
people, you should rightfully say, "Hey Varun,
you're not serious. And you'd be right. I'm not
serious at that point. So I think the answer is,
what is the minimum number of people to go out and
build the crazy ambition project that you have?
And I think the project we are trying to go
out and do, which is completely transform the
way software gets built, we've mentioned
this [inaudible 00:24:11] the company,
our goal is to reduce the time it takes
to build apps and technology by 99%,
right? It is a tremendously sort of ambitious
goal. And it's not possible for us to be a 10,
20, 30, 40 person engineering team in the long
term and actually satisfy that goal. We think
there's a very, very high ceiling. So that's
maybe the first key piece there. It's like,
if we can crack actually being a fairly sizable
company but still operate as if we're a startup,
that's the dream. That's the dream.
In terms of hiring philosophy, the way we sort
of think about things is, we only hire for a role
if we're actually underwater for that function. So
let's say we're going out and building inference
technology. Unless we're underwater there,
we will not go out and hire someone to go out
and work for that. And the reason for that is,
I actually think this is a feature. When
you hire for a role and you already have
enough people there, you get a lot of weird
politics that ultimately ends up happening.
And it's not because people are bad people. I
think most people are really well-intentioned.
But what happens when you have people that join
a company and in reality you didn't really need
them? They will go out and manufacture some
other thing that they should go work on. They
will go out and figure out something else to work
on. And realistically, it's not that important,
but they will go out and try to convince the
rest of the organization that it is important.
I just think as a startup, we don't have the
bandwidth to go out and deal with that, right?
For me, I would like to see everyone just almost
be raising their hands up being like, "I'm dying.
We need one more person." And that's when we go
out and hire someone. And one of the analogies
I like to give is, I want the company to almost
be this dehydrated entity and every hire is like
a little bit of water. And we only go back and
hire someone when we're back to being dehydrated.
I love this metaphor so much. And it sounds
painful. It sounds painful that you need to
be underwater and raising your hand, "I'm
about to die and dehydrated." But I also
know that it's a really exciting way to
work. It sounds hard, but if you're in it,
it's just like... I guess talk about just that
side of it because I think it could sound like,
"This is terrible. I don't want to work this way."
You know what I actually think, Lenny? It's really
good for a handful of reasons, which is that a lot
of the... We respect and trust the people that
work at the company. So this forces ruthless
prioritization. You have a team that's going out
and doing something. They will never ask to work
on something that's not important. In fact, if
there are two things that they're working on,
they're just going to just tell me, "Hey, there
are two things on my plate. I just don't have
the ability to do two. I can only do one." And
they will pick the one that's most important.
And this actually goes back to one thing that I
think is true about startups and just companies
in general. You don't win by doing 10 things
well. You win by doing one thing really well
and maybe you fail nine things. This is
the thing that I've told the company,
"This is very different than school," right?
In school you optimize for your total GPA. But
for companies, I just need to get an A+ on
the one class that matters. And then I can
get an F in all the other classes. And an F in
all the other classes doesn't mean just doing
illegal things. That basically means
you just deprioritize things that don't
matter. That actually forces this organizational
prioritization that is just really, really good.
And Douglas and I, Douglas being my co-founder,
we can tell the company, "These are the two things
that are the most important." But if we go out
and tell these are the two things that are the
most important to the company and then we put
the company has 20% more people than necessary,
what's going to ultimately happen? It's almost
a forcing function for ruthless prioritization
to have fewer people or people that are
just underwater internally at the company.
Everyone listening that works at a big company
knows exactly what you mean when you described
when there's just too many people, they will all
find work to do and they will all be pitching
ideas. They all want to show impact, they want to
do well in their performance reviews. That's just
the nature of too many people at a company.
And so I think this all really resonates.
To even getting even deeper on just what it
looks like when someone's underwater to tell
you it's time to hire, is it just someone
coming to you, "Varun, I need someone on
this team. This is just not possible"? What
does that look like even more practically?
Yeah, I think it's basically along those lines.
It's that, "Hey, there's some pressure to get
something done in a short period of time." By
the way, one of the things that we do believe
though for software, if you want to do great
things, it's not possible to just say, "Hey,
I want to get it done in one month" if it is
like... Because you have to think about it from
this perspective. If a software project could get
built in two to three weeks, what does that really
mean about the true complexity and differentiation
of what you built? It's probably not very high,
unless you believe you are way smarter than
everyone else. But I think that's hubris,
right? I think we actually have a very exceptional
engineering team. But also at the same time,
I don't think our engineering team is so
exceptional that we can do things in three weeks
that the rest of the world can't do in six to nine
months. That's kind of stupid to believe that.
So I think basically it comes down to
that person coming out and being like,
"Hey, look, I don't have enough time to do
X." Us having a conversation to be like,
"Okay, what can you do then?" And if the answer
is, "I can only do less than that," then maybe
we make a decision actually, "Oh wow, that's
great. Maybe we actually should deprioritize
Y." Because this is actually also another thing
that's very hard even for people like me and
my co-founder. It's that we also want to do a
lot of things. There's an urge to do a lot of
things. But if we are forced to make a decision
constantly on like, "We cannot do X," it's very
clarifying. It's very clarifying because our
engineering interview process is also extremely
low acceptance rate. So it's not very easy for
us to very quickly spin up people and have them
join the company really, really quickly either.
So I think it's clarifying for everyone. It's
clarifying for the person that wants more
people. We can just tell them, "Hey look,
we don't believe you should be doing this
other thing." And it's also clarifying
for us because we can also get on the same page
with them. And sometimes we just kind of agree,
"Hey..." Our teams are very flexible that, "Hey,
actually we do need to get something done." And
one of the things that we've kind of tried to
make sure is true on our engineering team is,
people's value to the company does not have
anything to do with the size of their team.
There are projects inside the company, there
are directly responsible individuals for these
projects inside the company. And if we
feel like one project is very important,
then people can move from one project to the next.
There's no notion of someone owning people at the
company. That is a very bad and gnarly idea.
In fact, the person that is the most valuable
at the company is the person that can do
the most crazy sort of project out there
with as few people as possible. And that's
what you should be rewarding internally.
How many people do you have
at coding at this point?
So we have close to 160 people and the
engineering team is over 50 people right now.
Awesome. Oh, what's the other bigger
functions? So [inaudible 00:30:46]-
We have go-to-market. We have a... Yeah.
Oh, right. Okay. I want to talk about that,
the sales learning that you guys had. Okay.
But let's close out this hiring conversation. So
we talked about what you look for... To tell you
it's the time to hire, what do you look for
in the people that you interview and hire?
One of the key pieces that we look for, we have
a very high technical bar. So assuming that
they actually meet the technical bar, I think
we sort of look for people that are really,
really passionate about the mission of what
we're actually trying to solve and people that
are willing to work very hard. I think one of the
things that we don't try to do is convince people,
"Hey look, we are a very chill company
and it's great to work here." I think,
no, this is a very exciting space. It's very
competitive. You should expect us to lose if
the people at the company are not kind of...
They're not working very hard. And I think one
of the biggest dog whistles I hear is, when I
ask people how hard are you willing to work,
some people actually ultimately say, "Hey, I work
very smart." And I basically ask them a question,
"If we have many smart people at our company that
also work hard, what's the differentiator going
to be? Are you just going to pull them down?"
Because I think one of the things that's true
about companies is it's like this massive
group project. And I think the thing about
a person that is not pulling their weight
that's bad. It's not the productivity,
right? At some point when the company becomes
many hundreds of engineers, I'm not going to be
thinking about the one engineer that's not pulling
their weight. It's the team of people they work
with that are almost basically saying, "Is this
the bar internally at the company? Is this the
expectation?" And I guess, Lenny, if I told you
you have a team of five people and the four other
people you're working with just don't care, how
much are you going to feel like you should care?
Not too much.
Exactly. So for us, I think that's what
we more care about. We have a culture
where it's very collaborative.
It's not an individual sport,
but people feel like they can rely on other
people to get complex sort of tasks done.
So the question you asked there just basically is,
how hard are you willing to work? How hard do you
want to work? And I know some people, there's this
whole group of folks that are just like work-life
balance, "How dare you ask me to work crazy
hours?" And I love just the filter upfront of,
"If you work here, you will work really
hard. You'll work a lot of hours. It's
a crazy space to be in. And we will win
by working smart and also really hard."
Yeah.
You said at some point earlier
that your engineering pass rate,
as you said, it was like 0.6% of
candidates, something like that.
Yeah, it's probably post or take home.
It's probably that actually. So the
take home itself filters probably
another 10, 15X on top of that.
Here's a question that I've been hearing more
and more, is just, how do you do interviews
these days with tools like Windsurf
out there that solve all your problems?
We are okay with people using the tools because
I think one of the worst things is like,
if someone comes here and doesn't like using
these tools, we believe there are massive
productivity improvements. We do bring people
into the company on site so we can actually see
how they think through problems on a whiteboard
and all these other pieces. So we do want to see
how they think on their feet and hopefully
they're not just taking what we're saying,
putting it in a voice translator and sticking
it into ChatGPT and getting the answer out.
So there is a way to do this. My viewpoint on
this is the tools are really, really important,
but I do think we still look for some
problem solving ability. If the only
way you can solve a hard problem is put it
into ChatGPT, I think that's a concern to us.
Today's episode is brought to you by Coda.
I personally use Coda every single day to
manage my podcast and also to manage my
community. It's where I put the questions
that I plan to ask every guest that's coming
on the podcast. It's where I put my community
resources, it's how I manage my workflows.
Here's how Coda can help you. Imagine starting
a project at work and your vision is clear,
you know exactly who's doing what and where
to find the data that you need to do your part. In
fact, you don't have to waste time searching for
anything because everything your team needs
from project trackers and OKRs to documents
and spreadsheets lives in one tab all in Coda.
With Coda's collaborative all in one workspace,
you get the flexibility of docs, the structure
of spreadsheets, the power of applications,
and the intelligence of AI all
in one easy to organize tab.
Like I mentioned earlier, I use Coda every single
day. And more than 50,000 teams trust Coda to keep
them more aligned and focused. If you're a startup
team looking to increase alignment and agility,
Coda can help you move from planning to execution
in record time. To try it for yourself, go to
coda.io/lenny today and get six months free of the
team plan for startups. That's C-O-D-A, .io/lenny
to get started for free and get six
months of the team plan. coda.io/lenny.
Okay. Let's talk about this go-to-market sales
experience that you guys had. So you started
obviously like most people, started building
without sales team. And then you realized,
from what I hear, that that was a huge miss and
a big opportunity to talk about there because
that's really unique, I think, that you guys
have a large sales team and go-to-market team.
Yeah, we actually made this decision
pretty early in the company's history,
I would say. We hired our VP of sales over a
year ago actually. And the go-to-market team is
now over 80 people inside the company. So it's
a pretty sizable function inside the company.
Yeah. Maybe a little bit of a backstory here. So
when we started the company, actually we had a
handful of angels that actually were operators,
go-to-market operators. So an example of one was
Carlos Delatorre who used to be the CRO of
MongoDB. And I think for us, we never viewed
enterprise sales and sales as a very negative
thing. I think this is a interesting thing
that technical founders sometimes don't really
like. They think sales is a very negative part
of the process. Everything should be product-led
growth. I think it's not that black and white.
I think enterprise sales is really valuable.
But maybe when we were a GPU virtualization
company and we were an infrastructure company,
the reason why we never hired a salesperson is,
I didn't know how to scale the function.
I was the one who was selling the product.
So ultimately speaking, if it was hard for me to
sell the product incrementally, I didn't know how
we could make that into a process that we could
then go and scale. I didn't know how we could take
the revenue of the business from a couple million
to hundreds of millions and let alone even tenths.
So if I didn't know how to do that, how could I go
out and hire someone and make them scale it out?
On the other hand, for Codeium, very quickly,
a lot of large enterprises reached out to us.
And from that alone in the middle of 2023, we
started, I guess, me and a handful of other
folks at the company started selling the product
and we were doing tens of pilots concurrently with
large enterprises and we were very quickly able
to understand that there was a large enterprise
motion that needed to be built in this space.
So by the end of 2023, we actually hired our
VP of sales. And very quickly after that,
scaled our sales team. Yeah, I mean look,
if you want to sell to the Fortune 500, it is very
hard to do that purely by swiping a credit card.
Let's talk about Cursor. I don't want
to spend too much time with competitors,
but that's what everyone's always thinking about
when they think of you guys. You guys are kind
of the leading players, I think, in the space
also. There's Copilot, but that's different.
So what's the simplest way to
understand how you guys are
different from Cursor and also just how
you think you win in the space long-term?
So I think maybe a handful of things that
I could share. So on the product side,
I think we've invested a lot in making sure
code-based understanding for very large code
bases is really high quality. And that's just
because of where we started. We worked with
some of the worlds are just companies like Dell,
JPMorgan Chase. Companies like Dell have singular
code bases that are over 100 million lines of
code. So being able to understand that really,
really quickly to make large scale changes
is something that we've spent a lot of time
doing. And that requires us actually building
our own models that can consume large chunks
of their code base in parallel across
thousands of GPUs and almost rank them
to be able to find out what the most important
snippets of code are for any question that are
asked about the code base. So we've gone
out and built large distributed systems
based on our infrastructure background to
go ahead and do that. That's maybe one.
Let me actually follow that thread because I
think people may underestimate just how big
of a deal that is. So when we talk about, we had
the founders of Bolt and Lovable on the podcast,
so those products, they build something from
scratch, they built, they write the code for
you. So that versus just loading, say, Windsurf
on your million line code base, say, at Airbnb or
Uber. Like, understanding what the hell you have
and how it works and where to go change things
without breaking it is insanely hard. And so what
I'm hearing is that's kind of a big differentiator
as you guys started there actually. And then
Windsurf is now building up that advantage.
That's right. Yeah. So that's a big thing
that we spent a lot of time on, which is
just understanding what the code base is doing.
And actually one of the other things is, what are
all the user interactions with respect to the code
base? And happy to show that also in a bit here.
Awesome.
The second key piece probably is we're not only
tied to Windsurf actually. This is probably a
weird statement given even we are talking about
Windsurf, which is that actually we're pretty
focused on supporting IDEs like JetBrains.
JetBrains or IntelliJ has over 70 to 80%
of all Java developers coding in JetBrains
based IDEs, right? The reason why we don't
feel as big a need to almost build a competing
product to JetBrains is JetBrains is actually a
very sort of extensible product in a way that
VSCode is not. VSCode is not very extensible.
So I think for us, our goal here is not only
just to satisfy a subset of users that can
actually switch onto our IDE, but we want to give
this agentic sort of experience to every sort of
developer out there. And if that means there are
Java developers that write in JetBrains, that's
fine. We work with a lot of large enterprises that
have 10 plus thousand developers where over 50% of
the developers are on JetBrains. It's a very large
product. And by the way, that company itself is a
privately held company that makes many hundreds
of millions of dollars a year. So it's a very,
very large company. So for us, that's another
key piece. We actually want to meet developers
sort of where they are. And if they use a
different platform, we'll work on that too.
The third key piece, and this probably sounds
another key piece for enterprises, is we work
in a lot of very secure environments. We have
FedRAMP compliance, which means we can sell to
very large government entities. We have a hybrid
mode of actually using the product, which means
that all the code that lives that is indexed,
it actually lives on the tenant of the user,
right? Code is one of the most important pieces
of IP for the company. So I think just if you
were to look at it from a big company perspective,
there are many reasons why over the years of just
building an enterprise product, we've handled
a lot of complexities that large companies want
to see. But that's part of it is because of the
history of how we got here in the first place.
Okay, Varun, enough teasing. Let's do a live
demo of Windsurf so folks can see what it's
like. And then I'm just going to ask you a
bunch of questions as we're going through
it. So I'll let you pull up a little shared
screen where you have Windsurf pulled up.
Great. So some context, this is a very basic
React project. There's nothing in it right
now. So if you were to open any sort of file,
it's the default React app project. I have this
basic image here. You can pass Windsurf images
of what you'd like the project to look like,
of what I would like an Airbnb for
dog's website to kind of look like.
Beautiful. Beautiful mock-up by the way.
I love that this is like all you need.
This is all you need. This is all you
need. So basically what we're going to
do is we're going to say, "Hey..." One
of the cool parts about Windsurf is it
can actually work in an existing project
already. So I can basically say, "Hey,
change this React app to show an Airbnb for dog's
website based on this image and preview it."
So now it'll just go out and start executing
code, reading through the repository. Obviously,
it doesn't know what the current code base
actually looks like. And it'll go out and
analyze the code base to actually find out the set
of changes necessary. So we'll go out and wait and
see what it's going to do. But while we're
doing that, let's continue the conversation.
Awesome. Okay, so first of all, so you open up
Windsurf. You had a boilerplate React project
ready to go. And Windsurf had never really seen
this code before. You ask it to do stuff on your
code base, which is just like, "Change this to
Airbnb for dogs using this design." Amazing.
That's right. That's exactly right.
Yeah. Okay, cool. So we'll let it run and
we'll talk. Let me ask you this question
that I've been asking everyone that comes
on that is building a product that helps
engineers build products and product
managers build products and designers.
Say you could sit next to every single new user
that opens up Windsurf and whisper a couple tips
in their ear to help them be successful with the
product. What would be a couple tips you'd share?
Tip number one is just be a little bit patient
and both patient and explicit. When you ask the
application to go out and make some changes, it
could actually go out and make many irrelevant
changes. One of the things that I think prevents
this the most is just be really, really explicit
or as explicit as possible. And one of the
things I ask people to do is in the beginning,
start by making smaller changes. If there's a very
large directory, don't go out and make it refactor
the entire directory because then if it's wrong,
it's going to basically it destroy 20 files.
And I think from there, one of the key pieces
I think that comes from the users that use the
product is they sort of learn what the hills and
valleys of the product are. The analogy I like to
give are kind of similar to autocomplete. When
you use a product like autocomplete, you would
think a product that is suggesting things but only
getting accepted 30% of the time would be really,
really annoying. But the reason why it's not
very annoying is actually because you've actually
learned that, hey, 70% of the time, I don't
need to accept this. And the times that I do,
I know to get value from it. And you also know
beforehand if a sort of command that you write
is very complex, you just expect, "Hey,
the autocomplete is not going to work for
it." So I think it's almost like a, understand
what the hills and valleys of the product are.
The crazy thing is, every three months
that kind of gets changed and reevaluated.
It almost becomes the case that it becomes
materially better than it was in the past. So I
think maybe patience and being explicit are maybe
the two important key pieces I would tell users.
And I think something that was kind
of between the lines there is get a
gut feeling of what the model is capable of,
like how specific to be versus how abstract
it can be. And there's kind of this gut
feeling you start to build over time.
That's right. Yeah. And with that,
it feels like we have an actual
preview. Guess what? We have a nice-
Cute dogs.
A nice dog app. And one of the cool parts is
that we've also done beyond just modifying
code is actually being able to point to different
pieces. And I guess I could just kind of say... I
could point to different elements and say, "Hey,
make the background..." This is not great design,
but I could basically say, if I took
this element, "Make this background red
and just take a particular element and just
change it and make it red." And it should
go out and be able to go out and do this.
The preview aspect of the product of being
able to showcase the app while it's getting built
helps in that, now actually you can live entirely
in app world. You don't even maybe even need to
look at the code. Granted this looks hideous,
but in some ways if I wanted to,
I could go out and do that, right?
This is what happens when there's no more
designers. Like, [inaudible 00:46:11].
Yeah. When there's no more designers. Sure.
Maybe the answer is like, when you ask me
what should people be doing, they should study
great taste. Having great taste. Because I think
taste is also a very, very hard, right?
But maybe the other key piece, Lenny,
that I wanted to showcase here is obviously you
could keep going here. I could take different
components and kind of change them. We have a lot
of plans here that are beyond just point and click
changing components. But one of the cool pieces
is the AI. There's an AI review flow as well,
which is kind of like what I was saying. The goal
of AI has now changed a lot in that it is now
modifying large chunks of code for you. And the
job of a developer now is to actually review a lot
of the code that the AI has generated. And granted
right now during this podcast, I'm not going to
review all the code that's getting generated.
But let's say I want to go out and modify some
of this code. And this is where if you're an
actual developer that actually wants to go modify,
maybe I don't like my variable name being
called title. I want it to be called Title
String instead, like this. And if I wanted to go
out and make that change and change to go out and
say Title String and that's what I'm going to
do, I'm just going to tell the AI to continue.
The cool part about this is Windsurf not only
knows about what the agent has done. It also
knows everything that the user has done. Our goal
here is to have this almost flow-like state where
everything the user has done, the AI also knows.
And it is able to predict the intent. And as you
can see, it said, "I noticed that the interface
property title was changed to Title String."
And then it now has gone out and modified
all the locations within the app from title
to Title String. And now it no longer says that.
So this is where even if I'm writing software and
I want to go and make point changes, the AI can go
out and quickly make these changes on the user's
path. Imagine doing a refactor or a migration
and you just change one part of the code. You
can just tell the AI to continue the rest. And
because it deeply understands the code base,
it should go out and find all the corresponding
places to go out and make the change. And
obviously now when I reload my app, there's
no bug in the app. It still loads properly.
I could obviously tell it to do even cooler things
like make the app retro. I don't know what that
means, but I guess I could do that. And it should
go out and make the change correspondingly for me.
But yeah, that's maybe the high level parts
there where the AI is not only able to operate
entirely in app space but also on the code
space of the users going out and modifying
code and to bridge the gap between the two. So
it should add leverage not only non-developers
that are just purely building apps, but also
developers that are just hands-on keyboard too.
Amazing. By the way, if you're
not on YouTube, you can't see,
but you can just select any element of the
page and then reference that in your ask of,
"Here's what I want changed." I didn't know
that was a feature. And that is extremely cool.
So interestingly, so having just looked at
Lovable and Bolt and Replit and apps like that,
it's basically doing all the things those
apps do. Oh, wow. There's the retro version.
That's good. I like that it built on your
red and made it really nice actually.
Actually the red looks way better now.
Yeah, a little green button. This is great. Okay.
Cool.
So I don't think people realize this, but
apps like Windsurf, that it could actually
do a lot of agentic work for you where you
just tell it, "Here. I want you to do this"
versus it's auto completing code for you.
The big difference is you need to start it
with some code base so you have this
kind of boilerplate React project.
Is there a reason you guys aren't taking that
step and just doing that automatically for you?
Is it because you're targeting engineers and
they don't need that or is there other reasons?
Lenny, the interesting thing is the base app that
you saw for this was also generated by Windsurf.
The reason why we sort of didn't generate
it is installing all the dependencies takes
like three or four minutes. And for the
demo, I didn't want to wait. But totally,
actually most of the users of the product,
probably zero-to-one build these apps.
And if I can say one interesting thing is, when
we launched Windsurf, actually we tasked everyone
at our company to go out and build an app with
Windsurf. That included our go-to market team
and our sales team. There was a crazy stat that
I think people would find surprising, but we've
saved over half a million dollars of SaaS products
we were going to buy because our go-to-market team
has now built apps instead of buying them.
Our head of partnerships, instead of buying a
partner portal product, has actually built its own
partner portal. He had never built software in the
past. We've actually come up with ways inside
the company to deploy these apps easily in a
secure way. And we're actually now building
very, very custom software for our company
to operate more efficiently, which is, I would
not have expected this probably six months ago.
That is incredibly interesting. You
don't need to name company names,
but I guess what's a space you're least
bullish on that you think is going to
have the most problem here with people building
their own version of these sorts of products?
I think maybe my viewpoint are these very, very
verticalized niche products I think are going
to get... They're going to get competed down a
ton. And I think sales products are an example
of one of these things. And maybe this is a...
I don't want to be very negative, but it's very
hard inside a company like ours to task our best
engineers to build a best in class sales product.
There's not enough interest to do that. Or to
build a best in class legal software product
or finance software product. It's very, very
hard for us to. And actually that's a very big
moat for these companies that built these
products that they were able to come out,
have an opinionated stance on how to do this,
hire good enough engineers to go out and build
the software. Our company is unwilling to do
that. So previously, we would go out and buy the
technology because there would be no alternative.
But now one of the crazy things is that the domain
specialists now have access to build the tools
that they ultimately wanted, which is actually
crazy. If you think about why were these software
companies able to exist these vertical software
companies, the reason is because they had many
features. The kitchen sink of features worked for
a lot of companies, but each individual company
only wanted 10% of the features. But the problem
is, each individual company was not capable of
maintaining a piece of software or building the
custom piece of software for 10% of the features,
but that has now changed entirely. Now they can.
Yeah. There's always been a story of like,
"Why would I spend any time building my
own software if I could just..." But
now it's like five minutes of time.
Five minutes and maybe even more custom to
your system. How many times have you bought
a software and you're almost like, "Why is
there no integration to X? And I actually use
X." How annoying is that? That actually
makes the software less useful to you.
So I think what's cool is when you go back,
if someone zooms back to the beginning of
when you started the demo, it's basically a PM
talking to an engineer, "Hey, build me a Airbnb
for dogs. Here's a stupid mock that I made
with some boxes." That's almost like a bad PM
talking to an engineer and it just actually works.
That's what's insane about this. And so that's why
this example you're sharing of go-to-market folks,
building their own things, it's like they don't
need to know anything about product building.
It's just describe it in some ridiculous way
and draw a couple boxes of what you want it
to look like and it makes something for you.
Which shows that agency is what matters. If
you have a product manager that has an idea,
there's no reason for why that idea
cannot be more well fleshed out.
How many times do you have a product
manager that just continualize ideas,
but it just feels like they are extremely unsure
on how to execute on it? They just want to say
things for sake of saying things? But for the
people that have ideas and a lot of, I guess,
agency, they can go out and prove out what they
want without any sort of external resources.
I think even more acutely for
product folks listening to this,
it's the salesperson coming to you being
like, "Hey, I want this thing. It's going
to help me with my sales team." And you're
like, "I don't have a million things to
build. I don't have time for this." And
so that problem goes away, which I think
will make a lot of product leaders really happy.
The model that this is sitting on, is it Sonnet?
Yeah. So just to break down how it ultimately
works, we have a model that does planning. And
I would say right now Sonnet is a really, really
good planning model. I think OpenAI's GPT-4o is
also good. But the crazy thing is what we try to
do is we try to make the Anthropic based model or
Sonnet model try to do as much of the high level
planning as possible. And then what we try to do
internally is run all the models necessary to
do high quality retrieval for the agent. As you
could see, the agent needed to understand what
the rest of the code base ultimately did. We
actually make sure we run models to actually
chunk up the entire code base and understand
the code base so that obviously it would not be
a good idea if we had a 100 million line code
base to send that entire code base to Anthropic.
First of all, you couldn't do that. That's over
1.5 billion tokens of code. So obviously that
would be three or four orders of my actually
larger than the largest context lens right now.
But you also wouldn't want to do that from a cost
and latency standpoint too. So that's one. And
the second piece that you saw was the model is
able to very quickly make edits to the software
as well. We have custom models that we built that
are post trained on top of popular open source
models that can make these edits really, really
quickly to the code base. And the reason why you
would want to do that is it's A, faster, and B,
also that model can actually have more of the
code base in context too. So it can be better at
applying changes than even Anthropics model too.
So I think the way we like to think about it is,
our only goal is how do we build the best product
possible? How do we build the best product
possible and how do we make the ceiling as high as
possible? And we will go out and build models and
train models wherever necessary. But if we're not
going to be good at a task and we think the open
source is better or Anthropic's better, we'll
go and just use the open source or Anthropic.
And so the models you guys are building,
those are built on open source
models that people are releasing?
Yeah. Interestingly, the one that does retrieval
is actually completely pre-trained in-house that
actually does that. But yeah, for a lot of
different pieces, it's based on open source.
Interestingly for the one that does the edits and
auto-complete, that is also in-house. As you're
typing, we actually do some auto-complete related
stuff. I'm happy to show that, but I think a lot
of users are familiar with that capability. So
I think the way we like to look at it is like,
what could we be best at and we will go out and
trade. But if we're not going to be best at it,
we should not just, for the sake
of ego, go out and trade something.
This may be getting too technical, but just,
is there anything interesting
around what you train on?
Yeah, so one of the interesting things that we
have from our users, and this is where we try
to think like, "Why would we be any better?"
is that, actually every hour, we get probably
tens of millions of pieces of feedback from our
users. We get a lot of feedback on what they like
and what they don't like. For something like
autocomplete, we get a lot of preference data,
a lot of preference data. And the preference data
is weird. It doesn't look like data that you find
on the internet. It's like data as the user
is typing. Imagine you're typing some code in
a code base, the code's going to be incomplete as
you're typing it, right? It's not going to be in a
full-fledged form. It's not like it is on GitHub.
But we have a lot of data that looks like this.
So we are uniquely well-positioned to
actually build a good model that can
complete code even when it's in an incomplete
state when the models that are out there,
the frontier models have consumed very little code
that looks like this. So for that case we're like,
"Hey, we can go out and do a much better
job potentially." And we'll go out and train
models on all the preference data we have.
The same is kind of true on retrieval,
right? There's a way to find out, are we
retrieving the right data? Did the user accept
the code change after that? Was the retrieval
actually a good retrieval a signal that we can
get? So basically the way we like to look at it
is, if something is just purely code planning,
there's not a great reason why we would be the
best at that. I can't come up with a coherent
argument for that. But for something
that looks more along the lines of,
"Hey, here's an intermediate code base
that is very gnarly and here are some
changes that need to get made" and we know
the evolution of the code or we've seen the
evolution of code across millions of users,
we feel like we can do a great job of that.
I think what's interesting about this is another
differentiator/moat for companies
that end up winning in this space,
is you just have more and more of that
data than other companies if you're ahead.
Yeah. This is sort of why maybe at a high level we
like the zero-to-one app building product space. I
think it's really... It's a good product space.
But ultimately I think it needs to boil down to
you understanding the code, because otherwise,
you're living at too high a plane where it's not
clear why you would be able to be the best at that
compared to everyone else. It's not really clear.
As a company, you mean?
As a company.
Versus as a user.
It feels like it might get competitive in
a way that it's not clear where you would
continue to differentiate over and over with time.
I see. Because if they're just sitting on
top of Sonnet and just doing what every
other Sonnet wrapper is doing, there's
not a lot of differentiation or moat.
It depends on how you do it. But maybe if I was
to say this, if the inputs you're consuming are
just web elements, extremely high level web
elements, then the interface might be high
level enough that it's hard to maybe get better
than maybe what the frontier models are doing
just across the board. You are just better
off just plugging in Sonnet for everything.
Got it. Awesome. One thing I wanted to come
back to that I wrote down that I think is
really important for people to understand,
you talked about how with Windsurf it's
not necessarily... There's a boilerplate code
base that you want to start with because it's
actually... Because it's not an abstracted
zero-to-one app builder. It's an actual IDE
you're coding in. And you talked about how
has to install dependencies, which is kind
this painful thing. And the reason it has to do
that is because running locally on your machine
versus in the cloud, like, say, Lovable and
Replit and all these guys, although I think
Bolt runs in your browser in this really cool way.
So that's an important distinction. This is like
you're running this locally in your machine and
has all the libraries you need to actually run it.
No, I think that's important. I think we believe
a lot of people sort of build software in what are
called code spaces and things in a remote machine.
I just think it's that a lot of developers like
building locally for what you said. Like if you're
doing things that are more than just full stack
applications, you might have dependencies on
your machine that are just system dependencies
that are just gnarly to install. Let's imagine
you're building a GPU-based application and the
Nvidia drivers, they're necessary. You just
want to give people the flexibility to build
where they can build. And I think the IDE and
building locally has been a thing that people
have done for decades, so probably it's not
going to go away in the next couple of years.
I love that your sales folks now
are running local host servers.
Well, with the browser previews, it's easier,
right? You kind of just open it up on the side.
Yeah. Yeah. Oh my god. Okay. I have a few more
questions just about how you think and operate at
Codeium. So you guys are kind of at the forefront
of how product teams are going to operate. You're
seeing the future every day. And so I'm curious if
there's ways you guys have structured your teams,
engineers, product design that might be
different from how other companies are doing
it or have tried stuff that has worked really
well or tried stuff that's a huge disaster?
One interesting decision that we kind of have
for core engineering is that we don't have pure
product managers for the core engineering side
of the company. And by the way, that's purely
because we build for developers and our product is
built by developers. So I think the intuition from
our own developers is hopefully valuable. If not,
we might be hiring the wrong type of people. So I
think our developers are, in some sense, flexing
to be more product conventional product managers.
Now on the other hand, if we were building
something that looked more like Uber or the
persona was very different and we didn't
ourselves understand it, I think the
organization wouldn't look the way it looks.
For the enterprise side of the company,
because we do work with a lot of large enterprises
where the requirements are not something that our
engineers would automatically understand, I don't
think our engineers wake up and they're like,
"We need FedRAMP." This is probably something
that a lot of customers come to us with and
tell us. We have people that flex in this
product strategy role that understand
what the customer wants and understands the
technical capabilities that we have to best
build a product that would help them at scale.
So I think we have an interesting organization
in this regard, but mostly I would say
because we are a developer-based product,
I would say that's true.
And then also kind of like what you said for
the engineering team itself, the team structure
is, it's fairly flat. We try to go with two pizza
teams, teams that are fairly small just because
I think the problem is when a team gets too big,
the person leading the team is no longer able to
get in the weeds of the technology itself. And I
think in a space that's moving this quickly,
I think it's dangerous to have leaders that
don't understand the technology deeply and are
not building. It's very, very dangerous because
there's too much armchair quarterbacking. And so
I think that's maybe one other decision we made.
And then teams are very, very flexible. So
if we decide something is a new priority,
we're very quick to change the way a team looks.
And it's very centrally planned in this regard.
The two pizza team concept, I saw a tweet
long ago where someone from India, was like,
there's always talk about two pizza teams, but
pizzas in India are much smaller. And so the
teams end up being smaller and they're like, "Why
can't we build as much of these teams in the US?"
Oh man.
Okay. So how many PMs do you have? So you said
you have 150 employees, something like that?
Yeah. So in terms of the
product strategy function,
we have three people in that role right now.
I see. So it's like product... They're
in their titles is product strategy,
not necessarily product management?
That's right.
Interesting. And then 50 engineers,
you said 80-ish sales folks?
Yes, that's right. And then obviously we
have functions like recruiting parts of G&A,
like finance. We have marketing at the company.
So some other functions internally as well.
It's interesting. And this is something
that you hear all the time with companies
like Dario for example, from Anthropic
talking about how 90% of code is going
to be written by AI. But all at the same time,
all you guys are hiring engineers like crazy.
Yeah. Is that contradictory?
It's that contradictory, will there
be an inflection point of like,
"All right. Now we don't need them anymore."
I think it really comes down to, do you get
incremental value by adding more engineers
internally? I'm going to take... First of all,
maybe just to set the record straight, if AI is
writing over 90% of the code, that doesn't mean
engineers are 10X as productive. Engineers spend
more time than just writing code. The review code,
test code, debug code, design code, deploy code,
right? Navigate code. There's probably a lot of
different things that engineers do. There's this
one famous law in parallel computing, it's called
Amdahl's Law. I don't know if you've heard about
it. But it basically says if you have a graph
of tasks and you have this critical path and
you take any one task and parallelize it a ton,
which is make it almost take zero amount of time,
there's still a limit of the amount of how
much faster it made the whole process go.
So maybe put simply, let's say you have
100 units of time and only 30 units of
time is being spent writing software
and I took the 30 and made it three,
I only took the 100 and made it 73. It's only a
27% improvement in the grand scheme of things.
So I think look, we are definitely seeing over 30,
maybe close to 40% productivity improvements. But
I think for the vision that we're solving for,
even if I were to say the company in the long
tail had 200 engineers, it'd probably be too
low still at that point. So the question is,
how much more productivity do you get per person?
Actually, maybe just to even say one of those
thing for some of these large companies, let's say
you took the CIO of a company like JPMorgan Chase,
right? Her budget on software every year is
$17 billion and there's over 50,000 engineers
inside the company and you told her, "Hey, each
of these engineers are now able to produce more
technology." That's effectively what you've done,
right? The right calculus that JPMorgan Chase or
any of these companies will make is the ROI of
building technology has actually gone up. So the
opportunity cost of not investing more into
technology has gone up, which means that you
should just invest even more. And maybe in the
short term you have even more engineers, right?
Now, that's not true across the board.
There are some companies that are happy
with the amount of technology they're
building and there's a ceiling on the
amount of technology they want to build. But
for companies that actually have a very high
technology ceiling, this doesn't mean you
stop. This actually means you hire more.
This is a great bull case for engineers. I
feel like the canary in the coal mine for
the engineering profession is when companies
like yours slow down on hiring engineers.
Yep.
That's not happening.
[inaudible 01:06:32]. It seems like Anthropic
is also hiring a lot to get it done.
Yeah. Everyone is. So I think that's really
promising. I think if you're in college still,
makes sense to get into engineering at this point.
Okay. Let me ask you this question as kind of
a final question maybe. What's maybe the
most counterintuitive thing you've learned
about building AI products, building
Windsurf and just being in a space?
I think one of the weird things is online,
everyone is very excited about the short-term
wins that we are making, right? Like what
we're putting out maybe weekly. We do these
waves every couple of weeks. But actually a lot
of the bets we're making inside the company are
for things that are not three, four weeks,
maybe three, six months, nine months away.
That's what we're working on internally.
Because I think this is kind of, Lenny,
what I was mentioning to you before. One of the
goals that I tell everyone at our company is we
should be cannibalizing the existing state
of our product every six to 12 months. Every
six to 12 months, it should make our existing
product look silly. It should almost make the
form factor of our existing product look dumb.
So there's this weird tension where you want
to have a product in market and you want to
incrementally iterate and listen to users and
keep making it better and better. But I would
say we were the first identical IDE product out
there. That's what we landed with. And I think the
value of that is going to depreciate very quickly
unless we continue to re-prove ourselves. And we
will need to re-prove ourselves in ways in which
our users are not even asking. So there's this
tension here, where incremental feels very safe,
right? Add this one more button. Users say, "Hey,
I would like to be able to have this drop down
to do X." But that is not the reason why we're
going to win. That's almost table sticks. Yeah,
we'll decide to do some of these. We might
not decide to do a lot of these things. But
it's these longer term efforts inside the company
that almost disrupt the existing product that are
ultimately the reason why we're going to succeed.
It's this weird tension that you need to have in
your head of, you can't also not listen to your
users at all because they're the reason you exist.
This reminds me of a recent podcast guest. We had
Gara from captions on the podcast and he told us
that he has two roadmaps. They have two roadmaps
at the company. They have the real roadmap,
like the typical roadmap based on feature
requests and user feedback and data and
things like that. And then they have the secret
roadmap, which is completely not informed by
users or data/ it's just them making bets
on where they think the world is going.
That's right.
And I love that he calls it the secret
roadmap just to make it very mysterious and-
That's smarts. That's very smart.
Okay. I have one more question. I apologize.
What's one thing that you wish he
had known before starting Codeium?
Honestly, I wish I had... Maybe humility is the
wrong term, but this idea of just being okay with
being wrong faster. I always think about things
on when we make decisions. Me and my co-founder,
we always talk about it. We're almost like,
"Hey, I wish we had made the decision to do this
a couple months earlier." We always talk about
this. And the weird thing is outside looking and
everyone's like, "Wow, actually the decision was
made at the right time." But in my head I'm always
banging my head being like, "What if we had made
it a couple months earlier?" I think part of that
is I waxed poetically about like, "Oh, you need
to be irrationally optimistic and uncompromisingly
realistic." But it's very hard to do this in
practice because you drink your own Kool-Aid too.
Because if you're not drinking your own, you won't
get up out of bed. The answer is already solved.
It's not actually any of these startups. The
answer is Microsoft is going to be the winner in
any software category. Isn't that the answer? Just
because of distribution, resources and capital,
they're going to commoditize every space.
So I think in some ways this amount of
just understanding that, hey, re-evaluate your
hypotheses and get into an uncomfortable space
way more frequently is something I need to remind
myself even to this day. And probably something
that I didn't know coming in and starting
the company. We started the company at peak
zero time. At that time, probably everything
seemed like it was going to moon. And there was
probably a lot of irrational confidence,
I would say, that we shouldn't have had.
Varun, we covered so much ground. What an
incredible conversation. I learned so much
just sitting here listening and asking you
questions. Is there anything else that you
wanted to share I leave listeners with, any last
piece of nuggets or wisdom before I let you go?
To be honest, I could give predictions about
the space. Probably most of them are going to be
wrong. I think the best thing to do is just get
your hands dirty with all of these products. And
I think one of the most obvious things
that's going to happen is, in the next year,
there will be a tremendous amount of alpha for
anyone that is able to take maximum advantage
of these tools. Just imagine how many of your
coworkers just don't even know the existence of
these tools, don't know what they can do and
how much less productive they will be. And
I would just say get your hands as dirty
as possible, as quickly as possible.
And when you say get your hands dirty,
basically it's like download Windsurf,
start coding. Ask it to build things for you.
Yeah, build apps. Build apps. Start using it for
maybe even making mocks, modifying your existing
code base. There's probably ways in which you
could be a force multiplier to your organization
and ways in which they never even anticipated,
right? Imagine if you were a product manager
that could actually very quickly make edits to
the code base and just start pushing changes
yourself. You probably get a tremendous amount of
respect from your own engineering peers. You could
probably get way more done because of that. I feel
like there's no sort of ceiling at that point.
I think this is such an underestimated point
you're making here. There's apps that can
build things from scratch and then there's
apps like this that can edit your existing
code base if you're a PM at... What's the
largest company you work with, people-wise?
Publicly, let's just say JPMorgan Chase.
Okay.
They have over 50,000 developers.
Okay. So you could be a PM at JPMorgan Chase
and be like, "I have a problem I need to solve.
I want to move this metric. I want to change
the step in the signup flow." You just open
up Windsurf and tell it to do the thing you want.
And then can you push straight to GitHub and do a-
Yeah. Actually, you could do that too.
... merge [inaudible 01:12:39]-
Yeah.
Okay. PR?
Yeah, it could make a PR for you.
Oh, my God. This is insane. Folks,
future is out of control. Okay. Man,
that was such an important point at
the end there because I think people
may not realize this. They see all these other
apps, they're like, "Oh, [inaudible 01:12:51],
prototypes," but this is legitimately
something a PM can actually do work with.
Yeah. When you think about the people, at least
that, I don't know, Lenny, who you respect the
most, they're the people that somehow, despite
their title, their level of agency and just
output just all the way down to the weeds to
the highest level strategy is just perfection,
right? They know when to go all the way down.
And I think sometimes you see people that talk
about roles and they irrationally feel like, "Oh,
because I'm this role, I'm not allowed to touch
this." Well now everything's open season, right?
And I think this is an opportunity to almost go
all the way down to the weeds and all the way up
to the top and just be effective on every level.
Unbelievable. All right. Well with that,
we'll leave folks. Varun, thank
you so much for being here.
Awesome. Thanks a lot, Lenny.
What an incredible conversation.
Thanks, Varun. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for listening. If you found
this valuable, you can subscribe to the show
on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.