It seems like there's a playbook for
everything, there is a framework for everything,
but the reality is you have to spend the hours
and the time to really understand your customer.
You were the first marketing hire at OpenAI. I
believe ChatGPT is the fastest-growing product
in history. Let me ask you this. A lot
of people might be hearing like, "Oh,
ChatGPT." It's like, why do you need marketing?
Everyone knew of ChatGPT, but when you clicked one
zoom level further, the thing that came up was,
"I don't know what to use it for." The work of
marketing ended up becoming creating this sort
of use case epiphany where people could say,
"I had no idea ChatGPT can do that." A lot of
marketing metrics tend to be vanity metrics
about the number of clicks that you got,
number of views, number of impressions. I think
those are all bullshit numbers. What is that
experience that you want your customers to come
away with when they interact with your brand?
If your advice is, "Don't just copy what other
companies do," what should people be doing?
Put together a four-step process that has
served me pretty well. The first step here is...
Today my guest is Krithika Shankarraman.
Krithika was the first marketing hire and
VP of marketing at OpenAI, the first marketing
hire at Stripe where she was the only marketing
person for three years. She was also an early
marketing leader at Retool and at Dropbox. She
also did marketing for Android at Google.
Currently, she is executive in residence at
Thrive Capital where she supports their portfolio
and founders on all things marketing and helps
hire early marketing leaders for their startups.
In our conversation, we talk through all of the
biggest lessons that she has learned about how
to market your product from her time at OpenAI,
Stripe, Retool, Dropbox and other places,
including her four-step diagnostic approach
to marketing, her anti-playbook playbook, what
B2B companies can learn from consumer marketing,
career advice for people looking to get into
marketing, and also just what people that
don't want to get into marketing should
know about marketing to be successful.
A big thank you to Kevin Garcia and Kelly
Sims for suggesting questions and stories
to get into. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if
you become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of a bunch of world-class
products, including Superhuman, Notion, Linear,
Perplexity, and Granola and more. Check it out at
lennysnewsletter.com and click Bundle. With that,
I bring you Krithika Shankarraman.
This episode is brought to you by Eppo.
Eppo is a next generation A/B testing and feature
management platform built by alums of Airbnb and
Snowflake for modern growth teams. Companies like
Twitch, Miro, ClickUp and DraftKings rely on Eppo
to power their experiments. Experimentation is
increasingly essential for driving growth and for
understanding the performance of new features, and
Eppo helps you increase experimentation velocity
while unlocking rigorous deep analysis in
a way that no other commercial tool does.
When I was at Airbnb, one of the things that I
loved most was our experimentation platform. I
could set up experiments easily, troubleshoot
issues, and analyze performance all on my own.
Eppo does all that and more with advanced
statistical methods that can help you shave
weeks off experiment time, an accessible UI for
diving deeper into performance, and out of the box
reporting that helps you avoid annoying prolonged
analytic cycles. Eppo also makes it easy for you
to share experiment insights with your team,
sparking new ideas for the A/B testing flywheel.
Eppo powers experimentation across every use
case, including product, growth, machine learning,
monetization, and email marketing. Check
out Eppo at geteppo.com/lenny, and 10 X your
experiment velocity. That's geteppo.com/lenny.
This episode is brought to you by Airtable
ProductCentral, the unified system that brings
your entire product org together in one place. No
more scattered tools. No more misaligned teams. If
you're like most product leaders, you're tired of
constant context switching between tools. That's
why Airtable built ProductCentral after decades of
working with world-class product companies. Think
of it as mission control for your entire product
organization. Unlike rigid point solutions,
ProductCentral powers everything from resourcing
to voice of customer, to road mapping, to launch
execution. And because it's built on Airtable's
no-code platform, you can customize every
workflow to match exactly how your team works.
No limitations. No compromises. Ready to see it in
action? Head to airtable.com/lenny to book a demo.
That's airtable.com/lenny. Krithika, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you so much for having
me. I'm excited to be chatting.
So you were an early and the first
marketing hire at some of the most
iconic companies in the world. What I want to
do with our chat today is basically go through
a lot of these companies that you've worked at and
see what lessons we can extract about your time
leading marketing at these companies. And
I want to start with OpenAI. No big deal.
You were the first marketing hire at OpenAI.
Things seem to have gone really well over there.
I believe ChatGPT is the fastest-growing
product in history. Does that resonate?
It does. Not that I can take credit for it.
Well, we'll talk about that. Either
way, nice job. Let me ask you this.
A lot of people might be hearing
like, "Oh, ChatGPT." It's like,
why do you need marketing? It's like the most
magical thing in the history of the world. How
much value does anything add to making it
as successful? Can you just talk about just
the value that a marketing person adds to a
product like that that's already incredible?
Yeah. When you think about all of the different
stages of the funnel, awareness was clearly not
the problem that ChatGPT or OpenAI had. Everyone
knew of ChatGPT, but when you clicked one zoom
level further, the thing that came up was, "I
don't know what to use it for. I don't know
what it replaces. Should I be using search for
this? Should I be using ChatGPT for this? How
can it even help me?" And so the work of marketing
ended up becoming, creating this sort of use case
epiphany where people could say, "I had no idea
ChatGPT can do that. And yeah, maybe I should be
using it for X, Y, Z reason in my own life." And
so I think you have to be very diagnostic in terms
of what can marketing be doing to help, rather
than just going off of the typical top of funnel,
and then middle of funnel and conversion-oriented
tactics that end up being in a playbook.
So for folks that listen to this
podcast, it's a lot of product managers,
product builders. A lot of them don't have a
lot of experience with marketing. I think it's
an important insight there of just, this is a
thing marketing can help you with is helping
people understand how to use your product,
understand use cases, understand examples,
things like that. So I think as we go through
this, I think this is useful for folks to
understand of, here's what you may not be
good at and may need marketing help with.
Yeah. When done right, product management
and product marketing should be best friends,
right? And you are working together at every stage
of product development. Rather than thinking of it
as a handoff at the end of the conveyor belt when
the product's been built, you sort of hand it off
to marketing to take it out the door. If you can
think of it as sort of a three-legged race from
the very beginning of product development, then
you go to market with the right thing in the first
place. You get these insights from customers,
you hear the language that they're using,
which can be the sort of cheat code for how
to message and position the product in market.
And of course, there's a creativity angle
on how to differentiate your product in the
market, but ideally, you're doing that in
lockstep with the product management side.
The other element of ChatGPT's marketing success,
I know that you spent a lot of time on
the enterprise side, is just consumerish
marketing tactics for enterprisey products.
Can you just talk about that? And it feels
like that's emerging more and more just like
consumer tactics for enterprise products.
In typical organizations that I've been
a part of and leading marketing for,
the enterprise side of the house, the B2B
side of the house usually fits the mold of
demand generation where you're creating demand
for the sales team and you're bringing new
customers and prospects into the fold and
into the orbit of the company. That again,
was not the problem at OpenAI. When we turned on
the contact sales form for ChatGPT Enterprise,
which was one of my first launches at the
company, our lead volume 40 X-ed overnight.
It was unanticipated even beyond our
wildest expectations. And so some of
the things that I had to do are not typical
to marketing at all. I sat down with ChatGPT
and I coded up a Python script that ended up
functioning as our first lead qualification,
lead-scoring model. That was used in production
for way too long, longer than I'd care to admit.
It's so funny. I think about when ChatGPT
first launched and OpenAI just launched,
everyone was just like, "How will you make money?
How do you make money with something like this
chatbot that's pretty smart, but sort of not that
smart?" I remember there's a video of Sam Altman
being asked, "How do you make money with something
like this?" And I don't know if you just saw this,
he just like, "At some point we will
ask ChatGPT, how do we make money?"
Yes. And I think the reality is it's not a
solved problem. And a lot of folks, a lot of
companies in the AI domain are trying to figure
out the right pricing model. And it's something
that you've talked about in your newsletter and so
on, but there is a value creation aspect to using
AI that doesn't kind of neatly fit the mold
of SaaS-based pricing or seed-based pricing,
or even usage-based pricing. So, I think there
are still some frontiers to figuring out where is
the value, how do different types of organizations
and companies and consumers find value? And again,
it's not the typical sort of KPIs that you
would typically try to optimize and maximize.
I will say, though, in terms of pricing, it
feels like ChatGP, it works. It's just like
a monthly fee, talk to it up to a certain limit.
It's wild to think back now, there was a sense,
"We don't have no idea how will this
make money." Now it seems so obvious.
Truly was a research preview.
And I remember Sam Altman just launched,
"Here, check out this chat thing that we
are trying with," and then the fastest
product growth in history. No big deal.
I want to come back to this point you made
about this playbook, anti-playbook kind of a
thinking. You kind of pointed out that with
ChatGPT and OpenAI, there was no playbook,
and you find that often people following
playbooks don't work. Talk about that insight.
In my current role in my career, I've spoken
with a lot of founders, and typically,
the founders reach out because I've worked
at companies that they look up to and they're
looking for that playbook. They're looking for,
"Hey, just tell me how Stripe did it. Tell me
how Retool did it. Tell me how OpenAI did it."
And I really hesitate to share any such detail
because there was a combination of context,
competitive landscape, and the overall sort
of zeitgeist of when the company's operating,
how the company's operating, that really adds
a lot of nuance to what works in the market.
And so doing the same things, like if you're just
kind of copying the outcomes or the outputs of the
strategy and trying to follow in the footsteps of
the tactics, you're not paying enough attention
to the inputs and, what were the variables and
the deciding factors which led to that strategy
in the first place? So what I like to do is try
to unpack more of a framework for how do you get
to become more of a diagnostician to understand
the right strategy or tactic in the first place,
rather than saying, "How do you copy something
that led someone else to success?" Because
those criteria may not apply to you at all.
So let's follow that thread because everyone's
like, "Goddamn, I need a play. Just tell
me how to do this." Okay, so there's no
playbooks that you... If your advice is,
"Don't just copy what other companies do
that have done well," what should people
be doing? How do they approach figuring out how
to market their product and help it grow faster?
Yeah. So I was an engineer before I became a
marketer, and so I have brought a little bit
of an engineer's framework to the marketing side
of the house. And so something that I've tried
to do is put together a four-step process that
has served me pretty well. The first step here
is diagnosing. So, diagnosing the actual problem.
Again, this usually means taking a zoom back when
a founder comes and asks, "Hey, we really need to
hire a demand gen leader. Who do you know in your
network that we should be thinking about?" And I'm
like, "Let's talk about your funnel. Do you have a
lot of people coming in at the top of the funnel?
And when they do come in at the top of the funnel
and you start talking to them and having a sales
conversation, how likely is it that you close
them? How likely is it that you win that deal?"
That usually tells you very astutely, do you have
product market fit? Once you're already in the
room and people are converting, you have found
that problem statement that is critical to them
that is hurting them the most, and your solution
is resonating as a solve to that problem. And
so that means yes, probably throwing in more at
the top of the funnel is a very good move to make
at that time. But on the other hand, if you say,
"Yeah. I mean, we get a lot of interest, but
once they're in the room, they have a bunch
of questions. They're asking about, how do you
compare to X competitor and Y competitor? And why
does it cost so much?" and et cetera, et cetera.
That probably means that there's more to be done
in the product market fit zone rather than
throwing in more at the top of the funnel
because you have a leaky funnel at the
bottom. And so hiring a demand generator
may be the worst thing that you can do versus
thinking about more of a product marketer who's
thinking about the competitive differentiation,
the positioning, the sales enablement that gets
more people through at the bottom. So
that's that diagnostic step at the top.
Second to me is analyzing your
competitors' approaches. So to me,
this is not about being super laser focused
on your competition because that leads to
these local maxima rather than thinking about
face shift changes and breakthroughs that you
can make as a company. But when you analyze your
competitors' approaches, evaluating what others
do in the space can kind of give you a useful
baseline and identify opportunities and gaps
and niches that your company can take in instead.
And then, this is the critical step. The next one
is you have to intentionally take a different path
than what everyone else is doing. And so driving
a strategy that sort of sets the company apart
is really critically important. I think it's so
core to the discipline of marketing, ensuring that
differentiation in the market. And you don't have
to go into a cave to come up with these ideas and
strategies. You can usually go and look at domains
that are far outside of your own rather than your
direct competitors and come up with some great
ideas that you can cross apply and bring in and
steal into your own domain or vertical instead.
And then the final piece is just experiment, test,
validate all of that, and then scale what works
and kind of discard what doesn't. So you really
have to have a lot of that ability to throw away
work when you might have spent a ton of calories
on this wonderful piece of content. But if it's
not working, don't double down on it. That bias
of the sunk cause fallacy really comes into play,
especially when you've poured your heart and
soul into creating artifacts for marketing.
So experiment, test, validate. Give people that
psychological safety to fail, especially your
teams and organizations. And then, yeah, once
you find what works, really double down on it.
Let me summarize what you just shared here.
So essentially if you think you're like,
"I need help with marketing," or, "I have a
problem and I think I need to hire a demand
gen person or a paid growth person or a SEO
person, or I don't know, content writer,"
something like that, before you do that,
first of all, go through these four steps.
So step one is diagnose. Spend time understanding
what's the specific problem you want to solve,
then analyze. This is so interesting, I've never
heard it this way. So then it's analyze what your
competition is doing so that you can then, one,
find inspiration and see where gaps exist. And
then it sounds like the core part of it is just
make sure you differentiate and choose a different
path versus just try to be the better thing or
the cheaper thing. And then the final piece is
just like, "Okay, here's our path. Let's test run
some small scale tests to see if this would work."
Yeah. I'm a marketer through and
through now. So I mean you got
diagnose, D. Analyze, A. Take a different path,
T. And experiment for the E. So it's the
DATE framework. I've just kind of coined it.
Oh, beautiful. Okay. We got a new framework hot
off the presses. I love it. DATE, okay. So with
differentiation, what's your thoughts on saying
you're just a lot better or a lot cheaper?
Being cheaper is a race to the bottom, especially
when you think about sort of scaling laws and how
things are playing out. Every company is sort
of becoming an AI company at this time. And
so as models get cheaper and more capable, being
cheaper is not going to be the thing that really
is a durable approach in the market. And I
think in terms of doing things differently,
it's not just for the sake of it. I think it's
really that novelty and that differentiation is
something that people are craving for. They're
not looking for yet another tool in the market.
They are looking for something that aligns with
their values, aligns with what their goals are.
And so if you can be really crisp on understanding
the user need, understanding what is the problem
space in which they're operating, I think that
one-two punch of a fantastic product experience,
and then the marketing experience to match,
can be a superpower for your company.
Awesome. Okay. So let's go through an
example of a company you did this with,
and then this may take us to another
company you worked at in the stories there.
Yeah. One that comes to mind is definitely Retool.
Retool was very different from both my experiences
at Stripe and at OpenAI because both Stripe and
OpenAI, for better or for worse, were inbound
companies, right? There was so much latent demand
that we were fighting off people breaking down the
door trying to get to our products. With Retool,
marketing was between the company and revenue.
And we had fantastic product market fit with the
enterprise space, with the developer community,
but awareness was a challenge. And so how do
we go out, not just wait inside of our house
waiting for people to knock down the door,
but rather step outside of our house and
start introducing ourselves to the neighborhood?
So, thinking about outbound channels and building
demand engines was the name of the game. And here,
one of the ways to think about that is, "Hey,
should we just scale the paid marketing channels
that we already have working for us?" And that's
when the diagnostic really came into play, which
is, what are the leads that are coming through the
funnel? Are they turning into sales-qualified
opportunities? What kind of pipeline are they
driving? A lot of marketing metrics, again,
tend to be vanity metrics. They tend to be
about the number of clicks that you got, number
of views that a tweet got, number of impressions.
I think those are all bullshit numbers.
Really, what you want to be looking at is your
impact on either signups if you're a self-serve
product, PLG, or in terms of a B2B company,
sales leads and revenue that you're driving,
pipeline and opportunity that you're driving.
So we diagnosed that and we found that for the
most part, our paid social channels were doing
not much for us. And so we had to invest in net
new engines. So that was the diagnostic. When we
looked at some of the competitors, we saw that
they were doing a lot of content marketing. They
were doing a lot of events programming. And we
could've kind of followed in those footsteps, but
there was the ability to take a different path.
And so what we decided to do was double down on
customer marketing and customer storytelling
because the thing that differentiated Retool
from a lot of the copycat competitors in the
market was that we had terrific traction with
true enterprises who were paying for the product,
who believed in the product, who were expanding
within the product. And so having them tell the
stories on our behalf was so much more compelling,
and no other company could replicate the kind
of customers that Retool had in its bench. So,
we wanted to make sure that we were
using those logos, we were using those
companies to the best impact possible, and then we
experimented. We tried to put together webinars,
different types of sales dinners, different
types of event formats to see what actually
worked best for us, and scaled the ones that
worked and discarded the ones that didn't.
Okay, there's so much here. So in the
diagnose step, I think in kind of a
between-the-lines piece of advice here is look
at what's already working. So you looked at,
okay, maybe paid growth, maybe this,
maybe that. And then it's like, "Okay,
what seems to be working is people find us through
maybe another logo, another customer that's fancy,
and they're like, 'Oh, Netflix is using
Retool. Oh, maybe I should check it out.'"
So I think that's a really important
lesson there is don't try to like, "Hey,
we need to start expanding our top of funnel to
all these different channels." There's one more-
And really litigate some of those channels, too,
because on the surface they might be working, but
are they actually driving pipeline and revenue?
Got it. So they may be showing vanity
metrics. Numbers are nice at the top,
but they're not sales qualified potential. They
don't actually stick around. Okay. And then,
the analyze competition is really
interesting. So again, it's just like,
"What are they doing? What can we be
doing differently?" Does it ever make
sense just to do what they're doing but do it
better, or is that rarely a successful path?
You still have to do something a little bit
different. I recall a very specific example at
Stripe where our product, Stripe Connect, which
was made for marketplaces like Uber and Airbnb,
where not only are you accepting money as a
platform, you're also paying out people on the
seller side of the marketplace. The competition
truly was to become a payment facilitator. So
rather than using another off-the-shelf service,
instead of using Stripe Connect, you might go off
and become a PayFac yourself. And a lot of the
services, organizations, the consulting groups
that were helping companies become PayFacs, the
things that they were doing was really leaning
into that old school terminology, the jargon
of the legacy systems and so on and so forth.
And Stripe kind of figured out, "Hey, we
need to rank higher for the SEO terms that
people are searching for. So how do we help
rank for PayFac without actually talking
about ourselves as a PayFac solution?" So we
decided to kind of do a reverse RFP system
where we created a piece of content that said,
"Hey, if you want to be a payment facilitator,
here's the secret playbook. Here's all the
things that you have to do. And by the way,
if this feels onerous or annoying, it is, and you
should use Stripe Connect instead." So there was
still a little bit of a zigging where others were
zagging. Yeah, but I think if we had done the same
thing in terms of becoming a consulting
service to become a payment facilitator,
Connect would be nowhere near the sort of run
rate or revenue that it drives for the company.
Okay. And this is a great segue to Stripe, which,
another company you were the very first marketing
hire at. You were also, I believe, the only
marketing person for three years at Stripe.
I do not recommend that to anybody.
There's a lesson there. Okay, so let's talk about
Stripe. What are some of the biggest things you
learned marketing at Stripe that you think might
be helpful to other marketing people and founders?
Oh, man, there are so many things to choose from
because I was Stripe for almost eight and a half
years. Joining as the company's first marketing
hire, building that marketing function from the
ground up, it really gave me the privilege
of working very closely with our founders,
John and Patrick. I would say actually
I was not the first marketer at Stripe,
John and Patrick were the first marketers at
Stripe because they were developers themselves.
They truly understood the developer community.
And when that audience for Stripe was squarely
developers to begin with, they knew exactly
how to authentically reach that audience.
And so I had to unlearn a lot of the things that
I had learned at Google and Dropbox coming into
Stripe in order to reach developers authentically.
The experience really taught me the importance of
deep product understanding as well. You couldn't
really play act at understanding the product,
especially when developers are trained to
spot bugs, right? So not only do they spot
those bugs in code, they spot those
bugs in marketing and in blog posts.
And so if the marketing pieces are
your first impression of the product,
they're an extension of the product itself, you
have to hold yourself to a very high bar in terms
of how you communicate about the product. And
so we did a lot of investment in design work,
in polish in terms of how the marketing came
together. And yeah, the value of creating
marketing artifacts that were deeply integrated
with the company's mission and the craftsmanship
that went into the product was another
lesson that I learned very deeply at Stripe.
So kind of along those lines, again, people
may look at Stripe and be like, "Okay,
it's the best thing ever for payments. Why do we
need marketing? It's just like, engineers build
it and integrate, it works." What is it that
marketing most adds to a product like Stripe?
Across my time at Stripe, marketings
are very different purposes. And so
I kind of see it in different epochs or
chapters of my time at the company. The
first chapter when I joined, our
head of partnerships at the time,
Cristina Cordova, handed me a Hackpad
at the time, which is like a notion-
I remember Hackpad.
Oh, yeah.
It turned into Dropbox Paper.
That's right. And so she had kept a Hackpad, a
secret Hackpad away from the engineering team,
which was all of the features and products that
we had shipped but had never communicated to our
customers about. And so the launch sort of
ended with shipping the feature rather than
communicating with the user. So the first
chapter at Stripe was really just getting
through that backlog and making sure that
the ethos at the company changed to say,
"Hey, your launch isn't complete if you're
just code complete. You have to actually ship
it to the customer and make them aware
of it." So usage became the north star,
engagement became the north star rather than
just the binary, has it launched or not?
The second chapter at Stripe was really
starting to expand what a launch meant,
right? So, going from just putting out a blog post
for people who were already subscribed to the RSS
feed of the company versus thinking through, "Hey,
how do we reach out to them through an email,
through other channels? How do we really invest
in this fanatical community that is getting so
excited about the product experience?" So
we pulled together developer experience as
a function, built out developer relations to
really have that community feeling and vibe.
And then it was about starting to think through
the multi-product ecosystem. So Stripe went from
a single-threaded payments processing company
to one that had multiple different products and
features for the audience and the user base. So
then the work of marketing became, how do you help
people understand and navigate potentially this
multi-product ecosystem and platform to figure out
what's the right set of features and solutions
that they should be using for their needs?
And so this is, again, a good example
of marketing can do a lot of different
things and depends on the stage,
depends on the needs. It almost
starts again with diagnose. Where do we
have a need for marketing and growth?
And especially in hyper-growth companies, I
think you have to run that diagnostic every
three months, every six months in order to stay
adaptable and flexible because those top level
goals do change. At some point, we really
have to figure out how to scale our sales
function. We have to figure out how to scale
internationally. And so being adaptable to that
meant constant reprioritization and making
sure that you were also hiring people who
weren't super deep in particular disciplines,
but having a team structure that was T-shaped,
people who could be flexible
to those needs of the company.
Coming back to your point
about how there's no playbooks,
is Stripe another example where it's
like, this has never been done before,
we shouldn't copy what other payments
companies have done in the past?
Yeah. If we did, we would still be talking
about PCI compliance and payment gateways.
There's so much of what you share that
reminds me of Raaz from Wiz, who also,
you were an engineer originally, she
was a product person. Yeah, I think.
I don't know if she was an engineer,
but a product person. So it's your-
Her first PM, actually. Yeah, Raaz is great.
Okay. And I think there's a few things
that are so interesting here. One is you
both have non-marketing backgrounds, you
went from another function. And I think,
you tell me, it gives you a whole
new perspective on marketing,
not just the traditional education of
marketing. Is there anything there?
One thing it's definitely made me
is very skeptical of most marketing
channels and strategies and tactics. And so
I would be one of the first people to say,
"Is that really going to work? What developer is
clicking on paid ads? Isn't a better thing that
we could be doing for them telling them to install
ad block?" So I think that skepticism means that
you just have a higher bar for the quality of the
content, the substance of the content. You want
to make sure that the marketing is as substantive
and as crafted as the product experience itself.
The other really interesting corollary here
is she was very big on avoiding the generic
acronyms and classic industry
norms, I forget what they were,
for cloud security. But it's just like, "We're
not this thing. We're Wiz. Here's what we do."
They are definitely a company that zags
when others zig. I still have my Wiz socks,
which have these beautiful 8-bit
characters on them. Their branding
really stands out in the sea of
sameness in SaaS conferences.
Okay. There's something I heard that you
did at Stripe that I wanted to ask you
about that worked really well. When you came
into Stripe, you looked at all of the biggest
customer support issues and you turned those
into docs to help people serve themselves.
Can you just talk about that insight and
the power of doing something like that?
Yeah, and this was a great practice that
existed at Stripe even before I joined,
which is all new hires would do a support rotation
just to build empathy with our customers. So,
users first was a very core operating principle
for the company, and we spent about 20% of our
time collectively talking to customers, talking
to users, talking to non-users to understand
their needs, their gripes about the product.
And that tradition, I think, continues to
today. The support rotation specifically was such
a fantastic fountain of understanding, "Hey, these
are the areas that people are confused about."
Again, I kind of mentioned this sort of cheat
code of talking to your customers and using the
language that they use to describe their problems
as a shortcut to fantastic product marketing and
messaging, because it really tells you what are
their pain points and how can you meet them where
they are. You want them nodding their heads along
as they're reading your landing pages. And so
when I was doing the support rotation, there
were thematic things that kept coming up. People
were asking, "Hey, do you process subscription
payments or recurring payments?" Or, "Can I pay
people out with Stripe?" And I was like, "Of
course you could, but there's no reason you should
know that because we don't tell you anywhere."
And so that ended up being a stacked rank backlog
of landing pages that we produce that just
educated people. And this is really important
when you have strong top of funnel demand,
and potentially not as many people and you're
not trying to scale your teams linearly. Having
those educational resources, especially for
developers, a fantastic marketing funnel
sometimes doesn't look like talking to sales.
It often never looks like talking to sales.
It looks like a self-directed educational
experience. Even the sales process ends up
being very consultative typically with very
technical folks on the other side. So yeah,
that was a great way and a great program to figure
out what content we should focus and prioritize.
These are really cool just little
ways as a new marketing person.
You can add value really quickly
is kind of what I'm taking away.
Talking to customers is at the top of the list.
Today's episode is brought to you by LinkedIn Ads.
One of the hardest and also most important parts
of B2B marketing is reaching the right people.
I'm constantly getting ads for products that I
will never buy, and I almost feel sorry for
the money that these companies are spending
pitching me on their spend management software
or some kind of cybersecurity solution that
my one man business just does not need. When
you're ready to reach the right professionals,
use LinkedIn Ads. LinkedIn has grown to a
network of over 1 billion professionals,
including 130 million decision makers, and that's
where it stands apart from other ad platforms.
You can target your ad buyers by
job title, industry, company, role,
seniority, skills, even company revenue.
All the professionals that you need to
reach in one place. Stop wasting budget on
the wrong audience and start targeting the
right professionals only on LinkedIn Ads.
LinkedIn will even give you $100 credit on
your next campaign so that you can try it for
yourself. Just go to linkedin.com/podlenny.
That's linkedin.com/podlenny. Terms and
conditions apply. Only on LinkedIn Ads.
There's something else that I know that you're a
big advocate of which is internal reviews and just
making sure everyone's aligned, which I think
a lot of people and especially startups try to
avoid. Like, "Let's just move fast. We don't
need to have all these meetings where people
review stuff," but I know you're a big advocate
of that. Talk about why that's so important.
Yeah, this is a hill that I would die on,
which is that good process or sufficient
process is actually something that speeds up
a company rather than slow it down. It stems
from this idea that we talked about a little
bit, which is that marketing is an extension
of your product. It's the first touchpoint your
customers have with your product. And ideally,
you're setting expectations there in terms of
what they should expect once they sign up for the
product or commit to a contract and start using
it within their companies. And when I think about
that, consistency is really, really important.
The other part, the other facet of why process
is important is because especially as you're in
hyper-growth companies, scaling teams is part and
parcel like what you're trying to do. And when
you bring in someone new, you want them to be
just as self-sufficient as somebody who's been at
the company for two years. So in your second week,
can you be as successful as someone who's been
at the company for two years? And the reason
that I have that principle in mind is because
it makes you kind of break out of your shell of,
"I've been at this company for some time now.
I understand the sort of unspoken rules of the
organization. I've built up enough social capital
that I can withdraw from to get something done.
And I know which conference room to stand
outside of to get the founder to review a
piece of content before it goes out the door."
That is not scalable, that is not sustainable.
And so if you want somebody to be successful and
contributing member of the organization very,
very quickly, setting up some of these processes
with the intention of trying to help them navigate
how to go from idea to execution can be very
empowering and powerful. Nobody wants to do
the wrong thing. They want the guardrails to
understand what great looks like at the company.
Can you speak more about what
this looks like? Say a startup
wants to start implementing something like this.
Two simple processes that you
could put into place today is,
one, set up a forum called Marketing Review.
This can be a live meeting that you host for
an hour a week or it can be a Slack channel
where people are posting things async,
or even an email alias where things get sent
to. Have that be transparent to the rest of
the organization so anyone in the marketing
team, anyone in the product organization
can join that forum. What that does is it
creates a fishbowl where you see sort of,
what are the themes that come out when somebody
reviews a piece of content? Are they looking at
the strategy? Are they looking at the audience?
Are they looking at the words? Are they looking at
the sort of design approach? So you learn through
osmosis of looking at some of these discussions.
And then I would say don't overdo it. I would
say there are probably two checkpoints in a
program that are really important to get
aligned at. One is the 20% review. A 20%
review is a strategy review. What are we trying
to accomplish? Who are we trying to do it for,
and what is the rough approach that we're going to
take? If everyone feels comfortable with that, you
come back at the 80% mark where you've done a lot
of the work on the artifacts, the different types
of teams that have to be involved and how do you
take something to market it in the first place.
And the reason that I say 80% is sort of critical
because if you come in at the 99% mark and you're
just looking for a rubber stamp of approval,
and you don't really have the slack in the
system to be able to make any changes, then that
review was worthless. So come in at the 80% mark
where you can still make some substantive
changes before it goes out the door. And
that serves the purpose of consistency so that
your brand is showing up in a consistent way
to the audience. And two, it helps the rest
of the organization learn from each other.
There's almost this unspoken element of what
you're describing that I want to dig into a
little bit, which is the need and value of
having consistent and high quality marketing,
communication. Why is that important?
There's always this talk of just move
fast break things. "We're going to
be scrappy. We're not going to be
obsessed with perfect quality of our, I
don't know, websites and emails." Just,
why is that important? Why do you value that?
Why should companies maybe value that more?
It's funny because with the companies who value
velocity actually do value their brand just as
much, but oftentimes they think of these as two
siloed separate initiatives that they have to
put their headspace and calories towards. And I
actually think they are not mutually exclusive.
They are actually very interconnected. And so
when you understand the consistency of your brand,
it actually empowers the organization to move
faster because you kind of understand how you
want the brand to show up in the world. What is
that experience that you want your customers to
come away with when they interact with your brand?
And the brand is not just marketing artifacts,
it is your product experience. It is how
your customer support team talks to them,
how they resolve tickets. Are you getting passed
between a bunch of different teams or is someone
just resolving your ticket right away? It's
the experience that they have for candidates
when they come to recruit your company. So
all of these variety of touch points that
touch so many different organizations
and teams within your organization,
they are the amalgamation that makes up
your brand. And so if you think of these
two things as separate silos, you are
optimizing for entirely the wrong thing.
I've very viscerally learned the power of
brand doing my newsletter. I so fear doing
something very wrong in my newsletter. It's
like, saying something that's completely off
or having something broken, or sending
an email by accident to everyone that's
not ready. I just feel like once I break that,
just there's so much power and trust that people
have built for what I share and there's
so much power that comes from that trust.
If I launch a new podcast, people will assume
it will be good if they trust what I do and I
maintain high quality. And so it's just like a
constant fear I have now of breaking that trust.
Yeah, I mean whether it's fear that drives you is
questionable because I think it's
also a commitment to your craft.
Yeah, yeah.
But I think that's exactly right. A brand is an
expectation that you create within your audience.
And to what you said, if you have a strong brand
that people trust, everything gets easier. You
pitch them a new product. Like if Stripes
like, "Oh, we have a new billing service."
"Oh. Oh, I bet it'll be awesome because it's
Stripe." Or if OpenAI launches something. So
it just makes life easier if your
brand is strong, if there's trust.
Yeah, and you got to take that responsibility
seriously because even with something like Stripe,
we know that people are going to come try
out things that we put out the door. And
so we wanted to make sure that that met up
to people's expectations. And same thing
with OpenAI. When we launched something, even
though we were trying to be first to market and
that velocity was so important for the company,
oftentimes it also came with sometimes putting
the brakes on to kind of understand, how can
we improve the quality of the experience?
How can we make sure that it is safe? So there
were different criteria at the two companies,
but a similar ethos overall for the brand
experience that we wanted people to experience.
Let's actually come back to OpenAI. How long were
they around before you joined? It
was like many, many years, right?
Many, many years. So OpenAI had
been around for almost a decade
as primarily a research organization. They had
launched ChatGPT about a year before I joined.
And so that was the first foray into
saying, "Hey, our work is not just
announcing research breakthroughs, it is
about putting products into the market."
So there's a few questions I want to ask here.
When is a time to bring in a Krithika? When
is it like, "Okay, we need help here"? Or,
"A bunch of smart people doing great work,
people have the product, but I think we need a
marketing person that knows what they're doing."
I think the first criteria is having tremendous
product market fit, which is really important
because you're throwing fuel on the fire, and you
might be throwing different types of fuel on your
particular fire. So one pillar for marketing that
you have to think about is product marketing. So,
if you have a high velocity engineering
organization and product organization that
is putting out a lot of different features and
your customers aren't able to keep track, maybe
the engagement's not so high for some of the newer
features versus some of the core features that you
had in the past, a product marketer can really
help bring a discipline of launch excellence and
customer engagement, differentiation in the
market. How are you positioning the product?
The second pillar for me is demand generation.
So if you have much more of a sales driven buyer
journey in motion, how are you bringing the demand
engines to bear so that your lead generation,
your pipeline generation is staying really strong
and solid? Or you might want to think about brand,
right? You might want to think about community
development as a big part of what you're doing
as a company. So it really depends, but I think
in all of these, you found a spark of product
market fit before you're really going for it.
The second for me is that you're distinguishing
enough between capital and marketing and
lowercase and marketing. And there's an
important distinction I've learned over
the years, which is capital and marketing,
the marketing team, the marketing function at
the company is responsible for those channels
and artifacts and engines that are driving the
funnel for the company, but they are not the
end all be all of the discipline of marketing.
And that's where the lowercase and marketing
comes in, which is, what do you stand for as a
company? What is the storyline that you're telling
as a founder when you're talking to the press, to
the larger business community? And then it really
is a whole company motion where the product team
is thinking about, "How are we going to market?
What are we going to market with?" The sales
team is figuring out, "What is the right ICP,
the right customer profile that decision makers,
that we need to be reaching?" And then it is
this entire joining of the organizations
to make that happen really effectively.
Yeah. I think along these lines, there's a reason
Brian at Airbnb merged marketing, or product
marketing and product management. However much of
that actually happened or not, but the intention-
I would be so curious to see a follow-up
a few years on on how that's been going.
Yeah. Okay, let's have Brian back to talk
about that. That'd be really interesting. I
wanted to actually ask, an interesting thing is
happening with ChatGPT versus Claude, and it's
so interesting. Claude is arguably better at many
things at code, at least at this point. Things are
always changing. It seems to be a better writer
in a lot of ways. People prefer it for writing,
but it's just like ChatGPT is just dominating.
It's like, that's what people associate with
AI now is just ChatGPT. It's just caught
mindshare globally. What is it, do you think,
that allowed ChatGPT just to be that? Is it
just first mover advantage? Is it some kind
of other element? Has it been better longer?
Something really interesting is going on there.
One of the things that comes to mind is the
orientation when it comes to large language
models, and AI in general, is that we're just
at the very beginning innings of this whole
paradigm shift. And so every single week there is
a new breakthrough in AI that comes out from some
lab or the other. There's this one-upmanship on
point changes and eval numbers and so on and so
forth. But I think to customers, the users of the
product, the things that make it delightful are
the same things that make any product delightful.
And there's a sense of loyalty that builds up over
time when there is a shorter and smaller delta
between your expectations and your reality.
And where those expectations are exceeded, it
is accretive to the brand and your loyalty to
the product. And where there is a negative
delta, that tends to be something that it
really detracts. I guess, long story short, what
I'm trying to say is that all of these companies
have to think in a much more long-term oriented
fashion because it's not about a race of the best
chatbot and the best outputs. It's about, how
does AI become a positive force for humanity?
And so that's going to take a lot of change
management and a lot of collaboration between
a variety of different organizations rather than
just the companies themselves and the product
experience itself, because it's going to permeate
every aspect of our lives. Our personal lives,
our academic lives, our work lives. And
so to make that transformation happen,
my hope is these companies are not super focused
on just their competition and one-upmanship,
but rather thinking about the paradigm changes
that need to happen for our society at large.
It does feel like they are taking
that responsibility really seriously,
but it is a massive responsibility. Before we
leave OpenAI, it feels like it may be the most
impactful, important company in the world
right now just because they seem to be at
the furthest edge of where AI is going. And so
it's just such an interesting place to study.
So let me ask you this. Just as a person
working there, what's something people may
not know that's a wonderful, positive element
of how open AI works that's just like, "Oh,
that's super interesting"? And then, what
was maybe a challenge of working at OpenAI?
A surprising thing that surprised me at the
company was just the warmth and intellectual
curiosity of my peers and leaders at the
company. And truly, the sort of commitment
to the mission of making artificial intelligence
that benefits all of humanity was not just lip
service. It was something that was embodied day
to day. The sort of questioning that happened,
the sort of pressure testing that happened, the
rigor with which products were developed, go-to
market strategies were developed, was bar none.
And so that's something that I really admired,
and it was a privilege to be a part of
that organization. I think challenging,
of course, is just being at the eye of the
storm, right? The eye of the hurricane. So,
all eyes are on OpenAI at all times, and
I think that is a good thing because of
the ramifications of the product. But it
also really raised the stakes in terms
of how we operated and with what scrutiny,
everything that we did was looked at with.
Do you recommend that sort of experience for
people? Because I imagine work-life balance
wasn't great. I imagine there was a
lot of stress and worry constantly.
Who's the right... When in your career is
this a sort of gig to take on versus not?
I'm a big believer of what Claire Hughes Johnson,
who was COO at Stripe, used to share with us,
which is there is a concept of a work-life
blend and sort of making sure that you're
working at a company that has three components.
I think first and foremost is always people. So,
are the people that you're surrounding yourself
with ones that push your thinking, who are kind,
who are genuinely interesting people to
spend your hours with? Because you're
spending a vast majority of your time with them.
The second to me is product, right? Do you go
to sleep thinking about the product, waking up,
wanting to put it into the hands of more people
because you know it is going to be good for them
or useful to them? I'm not one of those marketers
who can pick up any product and market it. I have
to have that conviction behind the product itself.
And then third is sort of potential, right?
Not just potential for the company to do well,
but potential for your discipline to have an
impact on the trajectory of the company. And
so when you have that kind of potent
combination, it can really change your
perspective on what's draining, what's
energizing. But being very self-aware
of what gives you energy is also very helpful
to align with the needs of the company, also.
Let's shift to talking about Thrive, which is
where you work now, and talk about what your
role is. And what's interesting, I think, about
this role is you get to work now with a bunch
of different startups instead of go really deep
with one. So share what you do there. And then,
what are some things you've learned there
so far from a perspective for marketing?
Yeah, surprisingly, more people know about Thrive
these days than used to even just a few years
ago. Thrive's a very unique type of investment
company. And sometimes, when I made the leap,
people used to ask me, "Oh, was this always in
your ambition to make the leap into the investment
side of the house?" And I can honestly say it
wasn't. But I think being at a firm like Thrive
really gives you a very different perspective
and it strengthens your ability to be a stronger
operator, whether that's in marketing or go-to
market or strategic finance, or whatever other
pillar within the company there is.
Yeah, Thrive's mission is to be the
most meaningful partner to founders. And
so there's a lot of high-concentration,
high-conviction investments each year. And Thrive
is also unique in that it's a network of builders,
and so they are really pulling their investment
strategies from having been founders themselves.
So my role at the company is to help our entire
portfolio with all of their marketing needs,
so sometimes it means being interim CMO for
some portion of time until they find a great
leader to fill that seat. Sometimes it
means pressure testing their strategy
and making sure that their growth targets
are ambitious enough. Sometimes it means
looking at a Figma file for a landing
page that's going out the next day and
making sure the words are as good as they can be.
And that variety across a bunch of industries,
a bunch of stages of companies, everything from
a company that hasn't even been incorporated yet,
all the way to Databricks and Stripe and OpenAI
when it comes to the types of organizations that
we work with. And in the end, the variety of
domains can range from consumer to healthcare,
to defense, to B2B SaaS, to AI. So it is
a variety pack in the best way possible.
And so what are some things you've learned
so far? Because I imagine this is a very
different experience. I don't know, especially
things that you've changed your mind on even,
working with a bunch of companies,
early stage versus, what can I say?
It's a really different method of operating.
And so when you're in the leadership role for
marketing within a single organization, you have
at least a medium term north star in terms of what
your teams are trying to drive for the company.
And as much context switching as there might be,
there is still one company, ideally one
product, one buyer journey. That hasn't
always been the case, especially with OpenAI
and Stripe, but it can span B2C, B2B, B2D.
Thrive is very different in that if you want to be
a meaningful partner to the founders, you cannot
just jump from 30-minute call to 30-minute call to
30-minute call. You have to go deep to understand
the context. And if anything, it's really
underscored my ethos that you as a marketer,
the best thing that you can bring to the table is
your adaptability and flexibility. So, to really
diagnose and not just try to spot patterns
and themes and playbooks for these companies,
but rather be very deep in the trenches with them
to understand their unique context, their unique
concerns, their unique characteristics, and their
values and what they want to bring into the world.
The reason that they want to work with
Thrive is not because we are bringing our
past experiences to the table, but rather
because they're trying to do something new
that has never been done in the world. And
so those are engagements that are the most
exciting is that you are building and going into
uncharted territory alongside these founders.
I bet they're all like, "Krithika,
what is the playbook for growing this B2B
SaaS company?" And you're like, "Nope."
And I say, "There is none."
Damn. But we got the framework
that we talked about. Okay,
I want to zoom out a little bit and talk
about just career advice for marketing people,
whether it's early stage or later
stage. You have this concept,
the chameleon CMO. Talk about that and why that's
important for marketing folks to think about.
Yeah. The conventional wisdom for many CMOs is
to be like a T-shaped marketer. And what that
means is go deep in one of these pillars that we
talked about, product marketing, demand marketing,
brand marketing, and that kind of becomes
your calling card in the world. If a company
needs brand expertise, they go for this kind of
flavor of CMO. Or if a company needs to really
grow their pipeline or their demand gen or their
consumer growth, they go for more of a demand and
growth-oriented CMO. And I think this chameleon
CMO concept is a bit of a novel one in that,
again, I think modern marketing leaders have to
be really good at a bunch of different things.
They have to be very analytical. They have
to be best friends with the data science pod
because they need to understand the impact of
their marketing. They, of course, have to bring
creativity, but it is in service to the buyer
journey. It is in service to revenue goals and
goals that they share with the sales team or the
product team and so on, so marketing operating
in a silo is no longer a real possibility. So
the ability to diversify your interest, maybe
going from T-shaped to comb-shaped is probably the
right approach here so that you can go deeper in
different domains when it is useful for the
company through the diagnostic that you do.
That sounds very hard. I love
this beneficial of the comb
shape. It sounds like I have so much to
learn, so many little skills to build.
Before AI can come in handy. Some of the most
brand marketers can become very analytical with
the support of a tool like ChatGPT. If your eyes
glaze over when you look at giant dumps of CSVs,
it's nice to have a partner that is nonjudgmental
to kind of push your thinking and to help you
understand the details of the data behind
the brand work that you might be doing,
or vice versa. If you're a very creative product
marketer, a very analytical growth marketer,
you can work with ChatGPT to be more of a
brainstorm partner and really push your thinking
on the creative side. So I think becoming a non
T-shaped marketer is getting a little bit easier.
That's such a good point. A good segue to
an AI question. Hey, we got to talk about
AI. One of your former colleagues, Kevin
Garcia, wanted me to ask you something.
He suggested I ask you about taste and
creativity in AI. So he said that you're
one of the best writers that he's ever worked
with. You combine technical backgrounds with
creative taste. You do pottery, you should. And
you're a voracious reader. And he wanted just to
poke at what you think about just how taste and
creativity and writing change in the era of AI.
I think it's going to become so much
more important. First of all, I will
say I am not a ChatGPT hyphen person. I was an
em dasher well before it became a ChatGPT thing.
Me too. Me too. I hate that. But just for people
don't know, people are filtering out em dashes,
right? Because they think ChatGPT
is the only thing using em dashes?
Yeah, and I don't know what to do about it because
this is such a core part of my identity, but-
That's a big statement, the em dash.
To take a step back though, I think if anything,
taste is going to become a distinguishing factor
in the age of AI because there's going to
be so much drivel that is generated by AI,
can be generated by AI, that power is at anyone's
fingertips. But truly, the companies that are
going to distinguish themselves are the ones
that show their craft. That they show their
true understanding of the product, the true
understanding of their customer, and connect
the two in meaningful ways. If they can use AI
to augment their efforts to make that happen,
that's better than them subsuming their efforts.
So to build taste, there's plenty of past episodes
that you yourself have recorded that get into
building that work. But to me, that is going to be
a real differentiator for not only great marketers
but great companies to stand out in the field.
There's a concept that I love that recently
I learned from Guillermo at Vercel. He calls
it exposure hours. That's when I asked
him how to build taste, and that's kind
of a value they have at their company is just
increase your exposure hours to great stuff,
because that is how you build taste. I love that.
It's such a simple actionable thing you can do.
Yeah.
And at Thrive, we have this share channel, which
is just sharing things that we're seeing out
into the world. It's not particularly deal flow
news or competitive news or anything like that,
but it is things that we have seen that
resonated with us for whatever reason.
Along these lines of not over-relying on ChatGPT,
AI tools for writing and creativity, it feels like
there's going to be a big issue with people just
starting early in their career where they just
never learn how to do the thing, and they just
rely really heavily on ChatGPT and tools like
that to write, to email, to communicate well.
I guess, do you have any advice for folks that
are early career, just how to find that balance of
not over-relying but still leveraging these tools?
I think there's two schools of thought
here. One is that sort of the domain,
the discipline itself stays static and the
way that you approach it changes over time,
whether you're going at it in a manual way or
an automated way or an AI augmented way. But
I think the other school of thought, which
I more believe in, is that the discipline
itself is changing. And so what it means to
market a product, what it means to show up as
a fantastic operator is in and itself changing.
So if you're not leveraging some of these tools,
you will be putting yourself at a disadvantage.
But understanding the underlying mechanics,
this is why I would still be a very firm
believer in STEM education, is that you
understand the fundamental concepts. And then
you can have a choice and optionality in how you
decide to apply those concepts, but the concepts
themselves have to be there in the foundations.
Yeah. Easier said than done because there's
all these tools now and you're just like,
"Hey, I need to write a report
for school. I guess I could just,
maybe this time I'll just ask
ChatGPT to help me with this one."
Yeah, the mindset of learning
has to be maybe the one that
we have to really imbue as a value.
Because being of that growth mindset,
if you go to school just to earn the grades or
to finish the coursework, it's a very different
mindset than if you go to school to learn those
concepts and to understand how to apply them.
That's something that stuck with me
from my chat with Toby Lutke from
Shopify. We were chatting about just
what is the most important things to
incubate in your child? And his answer
I loved, which is just, "Curiosity."
I love that.
Yeah, and that's what you're kind of speaking
to is just if you're curious about learning,
you'll almost avoid some of these things or you'll
use these tools in a really interesting
way just to learn things more deeply.
And that stays with you into your career,
right? Because you can either go into your
career trying to get to that next ladder in
the promotion rung or you can get there to
bring a genuine curiosity to, what makes us
different? What makes our customers tick? And
how do we find those unique insights that
can unlock something that nobody else has?
That reminds me. To sort of
close out our conversation,
I wanted to come back to pricing strategy. I
have that in my notes here and I haven't gone
back to it. So let's focus on the AI and pricing
strategy. Just say someone is trying to figure
out pricing for their product and they have
some kind of AI product. What are some tips,
some piece of advice to think this
through? Any general frameworks you use?
Again, there's no playbook. I feel like
it's such a non-answer, but I think the
real answer is experimentation. And we found
this firsthand multiple times at Stripe,
but also at Retool. I think there was a very
visceral example where we decided to bring our
free product into the hands of more users and
sort of what was available in the free plan.
And then there was another one that we tested
out as a pricing function where we decided to
do something quite controversial, which is to
take the thing that our sales team was gated on,
a self-hosted version of Retool, and made that
available self-serve to anybody who wanted it.
They didn't have to talk to a salesperson. And
that kind of blew up the funnel, right? Because
the amount of pipeline that the sales team saw
had diminished considerably, but it also helped
them focus up market, on higher ACV deals.
And so that trade-off is really hard to make,
so the only way we could do it was through
experimentation and piloting to build
conviction. So I would say AI is no different in
that you kind of have to test the market to see
what works. Is it a seed-based model? Is that
where people are deriving value? Or is the way
that they speak about the value of the product
something quite different? Is it hours saved?
Is it the amount of things that they could do
now that they couldn't do before? And so there
might be a metric there to go off of, and I don't
think anyone solved it, especially with agents
coming into play. How you pay for AI workers is
going to be very different. What is that unit
of completion for things like code generators?
It's going to be a Wild, Wild West before we come
up with something that is as internalized now
as seed-based pricing or usage-based pricing.
Wild indeed. I want to actually follow
this insight you had around Retool.
That's really interesting. Yeah, so you opened up
self-hosted Retool. What was the insight there,
because this might be useful to
people, that convinced you to play
with that? Seems like a big deal
change to how you price and do trials.
There were two guiding principles here.
One is, do people actually want to talk
to sales before they get a self-hosted
thing? It's sort of like the SSO attacks,
right? Is that really the thing that you want
to gate your value on? So, that was one. And so
we saw a lot of demand from smaller customers that
still wanted self-hosted for a variety of reasons,
because they worked in regulated industries or
they worked with very private data and PII. And
so it wasn't just something that was, "Hey, if you
have 10,000 employees at your company and you're
an enterprise, you want self-hosted." It was that
for a variety of different reasons, regardless of
your company size, you might want self-hosted.
So that insight kind of led us to say, "Hey,
where is the delineation here? Because the sales
team should be talking to larger customers,
landing larger deals." And so to align
those two was one of the driving principles.
Awesome. Okay. Two final questions before we
get to our very exciting lighting around. I'm
going to take you to a couple of recurring
segments on this podcast. The first is AI
Corner. And with AI Corner, what I try to get to
is some way that you have figured out to use an
AI tool in your work to do better work or do
faster work, to be more efficient. Is there
something there that you could share?
And if not, that's also totally cool.
Ooh, it is hard to pick because there's not
many things I don't use AI for these days,
and oftentimes it's a catalyst and an accelerant
to the work that I'm already doing. But I think
I can actually unlock my ability to talk
to dozens of companies across the Thrive
portfolio in any given week, and the ability to
get deep on their context, their environment,
their competitive landscape. We can do that
because of the tools and the products that Thrive
has invested in from an engineering perspective.
So we have internal tools that are driven with
AI that give us a lot of insights and access to
expertise for these companies so we can show up as
more meaningful partners in a day-to-day basis.
So I think the ability to mix AI tooling then
accelerates work that you're already doing, and
then AI-based tools that unlock superpowers that
wouldn't otherwise be available to you unless
you're going deep into Google Groups archives
or talking to people across the organization to
pull out things that are inside of their brain.
That kind of institutional knowledge being made
more accessible by AI is actually more powerful
sometimes than the tools themselves. And in fact,
even at OpenAI, it's one of the things that we
advised most enterprises to invest in first is
their own operational efficiency rather than
just the AI magic dust they could sprinkle on top
of their product experience for their customers.
Awesome. Okay. Final segment of the podcast
we call Fail Corner. And the idea here is we
have all these amazing guests, all these
super successful people on the podcast,
all these stories of epic wins and nothing
but success. And I think in reality,
that's not the case. And it's important for
people to hear that things aren't always up
and to the right and always win, win, win.
Is there a story from your career you can
share where things didn't work out and
what you learned from that experience?
And again, this question's hard because there's so
many things to choose from as potential examples
here. And you're absolutely right, Lenny, in that
most careers are not the sort of linear journeys
that are reflected on somebody's LinkedIn profile.
No, I'll talk about a fantastic success, which is
called Stripe Relay, which you probably... Oh,
I'm just kidding because nobody remembers it.
It was ahead of its market. We launched it back
in 2014. It was supposed to be the platform with
which e-commerce companies would tap into social
commerce. The buy buttons if you remember that.
And it launched to a lot of fanfare, but then
eventually failed. It didn't produce the sort
of revenue or the numbers that we had expected.
And the understanding here was that as much as
one side of the marketplace, or you might have
some conviction that you need to put something
into the market for a particular moment in time,
the timing of the market really matters. And the
timing of multiple parties coming together to
make a platform work really matters. And so
the learning here was we hadn't gone deep enough
into the market dynamics. We hadn't done enough
user research. Did people really want this? And
if they did, what were their alternatives? What
was the stacks that they were operating in? And
would they adopt a net new tool versus one that
integrated into existing systems directly like
their e-commerce inventory management systems
and so on? And so for that reason, I think, again,
it was ahead of its market and ahead of its time,
but a clear flop regardless of the
effort that we put into that launch.
This reminds me of when Kevin Weil was on
the podcast talking about Libra, which was
his cryptocurrency project that Facebook ran, and
he's just like, "Okay, that was a terrible time to
launch something like that where people trusted
Facebook the least in our history." And now may
be a good time to try something like that.
Basically, a cryptocurrency platform to send
money internationally for free. What a dream that
would be. Okay. Krithika, is there anything else
you wanted to share or maybe something you wanted
to remind people of from what we've talked about?
Just to leave folks with a final nugget before
we get to our very exciting lightning round.
If there's one thing that folks take away, I
hope it is that they know that there isn't one
clear answer to any of the marketing problems.
It seems like there's a playbook for everything,
there is a framework for everything, but the
reality is the work is hard. You have to spend
the hours and the time to really understand your
customer, and there is no replacement for that,
and there isn't going to be even with the advent
of AI. And the other part of it is to deeply
understand your product as well. What are you
bringing to the table? And not just your product,
but your company's values, your unique approach
that you're bringing to the table. And really
be intentional and thoughtful about
that because in the absence of that,
nothing is going to be a substitute to bring
that combination of ingredients together.
With that, we've reached our
very exciting lightning round.
We have five questions for you. Are you ready?
Hit me.
Here we go. What are two or three books that you
find yourself recommending most to other people?
On the professional side, one book that I
recommend to most people is April Dunford's
book on positioning called Obviously
Awesome. She does a great job breaking
down how to position a product from scratch if
you've never had to do that, and she's just so
great for her real talk. So, really highly
recommend that. And then I love fiction,
so I would say one of the best reads in the last
couple years has been Madeline Miller's Circe,
which is a retelling of a Greek myth. Lyrical
prose, beautiful writing, highly recommend.
Love the combo. April Dunford, we're
huge fans of her on the podcast. She's
been on twice. I think her book is in my
background. We'll link to her episodes.
And mine.
Oh, wow. Okay. So cool. Yeah, she's
the best. Okay, next question. Do you
have a favorite recent movie or TV
show that you have really enjoyed?
I'm really late to the game, but I'm finally
catching up on Severance. So, no spoilers,
but I'm about halfway through the first season.
Wow, okay. It's hard to weigh the spoilers, but
yeah, keep going. It's amazing. Do you have a
favorite product you've recently
discovered that you really love?
Granola for meeting notes because, all right,
I love taking meeting notes as a way to stay
engaged in the conversation and to pay a lot of
attention, but I also know I'm furiously typing
away. And so the ability to augment my notes
and bullet points has been a game changer.
That's two guests in a row that said
Granola, and I'll give a plug. You get
a year free of Granola if you become an annual
subscriber of my newsletter. For not just you,
but your whole company up to some limit. Check
out lennysnewsletter.com and click Bundle,
and sign up and get Granola. So cool. I love that.
Happy to help, Lenny.
It's helping Granola, and me, I guess.
Yeah, it's great. Okay, thank you. Two
more questions. Do you have a favorite life
motto that you find useful in work or in life?
My teams have now gotten tired of me
saying this, but I say it all the time,
which is the delta between expectations and
reality is the function for unhappiness.
And so it is much easier to change
expectations than it is reality,
so I tend to spend a lot of my energy making sure
that expectations are set. Not just with customers
when it comes to our external marketing, but
internally with stakeholders, project partners,
and even within the team so that they understand
what are some of the trade-offs that we're making,
or why we're making certain decisions. So
I could not espouse that philosophy enough.
I love that this isn't, because I think when
people first hear that it's about your own
happiness, but I love that it's about
other people perceiving how a something
did and setting their expectations
correctly. Final question. Okay,
we've already talked about the em dash, but
I want to ask you again. What I'm finding is,
so the story here is basically people have
discovered ChatGPT's using em dashes a lot,
which are these long dashes that you have to
use special couple letters on the keyboard to
use. I'm a huge... I use these all the time,
and people are starting to filter them out
on Twitter because they're assuming it's
generated by ChatGPT. There's content that
has em dashes they assume isn't real. Will you
continue using em dashes in spite of all this?
I have begrudgingly reduced my usage of em dashes-
Same.
... but you will not pry them out
of my cold dead hands if you tried.
Oh, man, me too. I don't even
know. It's like command, options,
dash or something to even put it in there.
No, it's option, shift, minus.
Option, shift, minus.
Yeah.
I have to type it. I can't conceptualize in
my head. Yeah, and then there's actual rules
for when an em dash is the right
thing versus, there's a middle-
Em dash and the Oxford comma, the
two core tenets of my toolbox.
Is an Oxford comma where you add the comma
at the end or you don't? Is that the-
You keep the comma at the end. You must.
Okay. I'm all for that, too. It looks so
weird without it. But there's also another,
like a shorter not em dash. I guess it's
called something else, right? There's like-
The en dash, yeah.
En dash.
That's for ranges of numbers.
Okay, okay. I love that you know all this. Okay.
Well, with that, Krithika, this has been so
fun and so awesome. Thank you so much for being
here. Two final questions. Where can folks find
you online if they want to reach out, maybe work
with you, and how can listeners be useful to you?
Krithix.com is where you'll find links
to all my online presences. And one of
my personal missions this year is to meet as
many of the up-and-coming marketing talents
in the world. So anyone that you know is
earlier career, ambitious, but really showing
their impact at their organization, please
introduce them to me. I would love to chat.
And then what's the best way for them to
reach out to you? Is it just on your website?
Yes, please.
Amazing. We'll link to that in the show notes.
Krithika, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you for having me.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.