Product leadership is the type
of role where if you are not in
control of the voices in your
head, they will eat you alive.
You spend a lot of time thinking about how
to help your team learn to take a punch.
If they come to me and they're upset, I try
to focus them less around how you litigate
another person's impression of you and more on
what is the action that you can take to counter
program the narrative that you are afraid
that this other person has of you. What are
you going to do next to demonstrate that you
are the person that you know yourself to be?
You have specific tactics that you
teach your team to deal with hardship.
I would really love it if more people were
like, "Screw it. I'm going to do something
that's probably going to fail. It's important and
it's worth doing and I'm going to do it well."
Is there something you've learned about when
your leader tells you to do
something you disagree with?
People think that the game is
all about influencing the CEO,
influencing the people around them. You come
up thinking like you're the protagonist. But
in the story of work, you are probably
not the protagonist. You're not special.
Today my guest is Hilary Gridley. Hilary is
head of core product at Whoop. Previously,
she was a senior director of product at Big
Health and a senior product marketing manager
at Dropbox. Even more importantly, she wrote
what is now the sixth most popular post of
all time in my newsletter, How to Become a
Super Manager with AI. She's also the first
ever cross over guest between this podcast and
our sister podcast, How I AI with Claire Vo.
And not just that, her episode with Claire is
on track to be the most popular episode of the
podcast. So all that to say, Hilary is incredible
and I'm so excited to continue learning from her.
This conversation is packed with advice
that will make you a better product leader,
builder and also just a better human.
If you know what's good for you,
you don't want to miss this episode. A big
thank you to Sam Propis, Danielle Reynold,
and Kelvin Wong for sharing
suggestions for this conversation.
If you enjoy this podcast, don't forget to
subscribe and follow it in your favorite
podcasting app or YouTube. Also, if you
become an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get a year free of a bunch of incredible
products, including Superhuman, Notion, Linear,
Perplexity, and Granola. Check it out at
lennysnewsletter.com and click bundle.
With that, I bring you Hilary Gridley.
This episode is brought to you by WorkOS.
If you're building a SaaS app, at some point
your customers will start asking for enterprise
features like SAML authentication and SCIM
provisioning. That's where WorkOS comes in,
making it fast and painless to add enterprise
features to your app. Their APIs are easy to
understand so that you can ship quickly
and get back to building other features.
Today, hundreds of companies are already powered
by WorkOS, including ones you probably know like
Vercel, Webflow, and Loom. WorkOS also recently
acquired Warrant, the fine-grained authorization
service. Warrant's product is based on
a groundbreaking authorization system
called Zanzibar, which was originally designed
for Google to power Google Docs and YouTube.
This enables fast authorization checks at enormous
scale while maintaining a flexible model that can
be adapted to even the most complex use cases.
If you're currently looking to build role-based
access control or other enterprise features
like single sign-on, SCIM, or user management,
you should consider WorkOS. It's a drop-in
replacement for Auth0 and supports up to 1 million
monthly active users for free. Check it out at
WorkOS.com to learn more. That's WorkOS.com.
This episode is brought to you by Persona, the
adaptable identity platform that helps businesses
fight fraud, meet compliance requirements, and
build trust. While you're listening to this
right now, how do you know that you're really
listening to me, Lenny? These days, it's easier
than ever for fraudsters to steal PII, faces,
and identities. That's where Persona comes in.
Persona helps leading companies like LinkedIn,
Etsy, and Twilio securely verify individuals and
businesses across the world. What sets Persona
apart is its configurability. Every company has
different needs depending on its industry use
cases, risk tolerance, and user demographics.
That's why Persona offers flexible
building blocks that allow you to
build tailored collection and verification flows
that maximize conversion while minimizing risk.
Plus, Persona's orchestration tools automate
your identity process so that you can fight
rapidly shifting fraud and meet new waves of
regulation. Whether you're a startup or an
enterprise business, Persona has a plan for you.
Learn more at withpersona.com/lenny. Again, that's
with-P-E-R-S-O-N-A. com/lenny. Hilary, thank you
so much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thank you, Lenny. I'm so excited to be here.
I talked to a bunch of people that I work
with you about what we should talk about and
what you're amazing at. First of all, every
one of them loves working with you so much.
One of them is like, "I joined Whoop just
to work with Hilary and to report to her."
And of that, there's this theme that emerged
that I think is a good overarching theme for
our conversation, and it's something that
you spend a lot of time thinking about,
and it's how to help your team and how to
help people within your company learn to
take a punch. Essentially, how to help them
deal with hard stuff and do hard stuff and
build hard things. So I guess just broadly,
does that ring a bell? Does that resonate?
Yeah, absolutely. It's something I
care a lot about. I've been, I think,
pretty lucky in my career. I've been very
drawn to working on hard product problems,
regulated areas, really hard business models,
things with pretty high emotional stakes for
the users of the products. You're really likely
to run into a lot of setbacks along the way.
And I think this is really relevant today
because I look out and I talk to a lot of
people and I hear fear and I hear uncertainty,
and I think it comes from a few places.
I think obviously I'm really excited about AI and
how it's transforming the way we work, and I think
a lot of people are, but I think a lot of people
are scared too. And they're embracing these tools,
they're learning these tools, but a lot of them
have a question in the back of their mind, what
does this mean for the future of my job? And in
many cases, what does this mean for my identity?
I think it makes people question even just how
we provide value as humans in society. And I
also think people, especially young people,
today haven't even necessarily been in a
career environment where there wasn't always
a thread of layoffs or things like that. And
I think that's taken a real psychic toll on a
lot of people. And so I think all managers now
really need to be able to lead their teams through
uncertainty, through fear, through hard things.
And I love the concept of taking a punch. I've
got a couple other tools that I like to use,
but I think it can teach people how to thrive
in these environments. And it's really important
to me because I would love if more people took
on hard things. I think there's so many really
hard challenging problems out there to solve.
And the more people are fearful about the future
of their careers or the future of work, I think
the more they gravitate toward things that they
feel like they're likely to succeed at. And
I think that's wonderful. We need that too,
but I would really love it if more people were
like, "Screw it. I'm going to do something that's
probably going to fail and it's important and
it's worth doing and I'm going to do it well."
There's so many Venn diagrams of why this skill
is so important, especially today. One is it
feels like the easy stuff is done. The stuff
left to build is hard. It feels like hardware,
deep tech is where things are heading.
Also, just machine learning, AI skills,
just stuff that's really hard. And then
the other is just AI is just changing so
much. It's just such a stressful time
and hard time for a lot of people.
Let's actually walk through some of the things
that you have learned about how to help people
get good at these things, about how to help
people learn to take a punch, AKA do hard things,
deal with struggle. The first is you actually
actively teach them. You have specific tactics
that you teach your team to deal with hardship
and to take a punch. So what are some of those
things? What are some of the things that you
teach your team and help them develop a skill?
So at its core, when I say take a punch,
what I mean is you're going to run into
situations where something has gone wrong.
Maybe you have misstepped. Maybe you are
just hearing someone speak critically
about your work. Whatever it might be,
you're going to feel like you have taken a punch.
It's a very physical feeling. And I think as
managers, you spend a lot of time teaching
your team how to be successful. You want to
prepare them to maximize the chances of good
outcome. But if you don't also prepare them
for what happens when that outcome isn't as
good, you're going to run into some problems.
And so when I think about how to take a punch,
what I say to my team is if they come to me and
they're upset because something has happened,
maybe they said something in a meeting that
wasn't received well, or again, they're hearing
somebody else talk about them in some way,
whatever it is, I try to focus them
less around whatever happened and how
you litigate another person's impression of you
based on something that has already happened,
and more on what is the action that you can take
next to counter program the narrative that you
are afraid that this other person has of you.
And I think the counter program piece is really
important. Because whenever we feel our
egos injured, I think it's very natural
for all of us to say like, "Well, that's
not fair. I want to correct the record."
When you do that, I think more than often,
more often than not, you come off as just
looking defensive and you start obsessing over
things that you don't actually have control over,
which is what another person thinks of you. You
don't even necessarily have that information.
And so I always ask myself in these moments,
what is one thing that I can do, small,
that will demonstrate the opposite of what
I'm afraid this person thinks of me? And so
I'll give you an example of this. I was in
a meeting a while ago, and we were talking
about different things that we wanted to start
tracking in the Whoop Journal. And our chief
technology officer suggested ketamine tracking.
And I thought she was making a joke and I laughed,
and she looked at me very seriously and was
like, "This isn't funny, Hilary. This is a
serious issue for a lot of people, and it's an
emerging problem in some cases. And I think we
should take it seriously. I think there's a
lot of value we could provide here." And I
was completely humiliated. Humiliated because
I actually take this stuff really seriously. I
take addiction really seriously. I have a ton
of empathy for people who struggle with it.
And I also think of myself as somebody who
embraces new ideas and wants to be on the
forefront and would never laugh off something
that seems like a fringe issue that's I think
becoming actually more and more a big part of
what's happening today. And so I realized that
in that moment I was having that reaction because
of the feeling that it gave me about who I am as
a person, and I became so worried that this
other person had the wrong impression of me.
And I wanted to follow up with her after and
say, "Let me explain myself. Let me explain
why I didn't mean that," or whatever it is. But
as I said, I think usually you're fighting a
losing battle when you're trying to do that,
and it draws attention to the thing that you
did poorly. And you don't really want to draw
more attention to it. You want to move on,
take action, move forward. And so I thought about,
well, what am I afraid that she thinks of me?
I'm afraid that she thinks that maybe I
don't take some of these health issues
seriously. I'm afraid she thinks that maybe
I'm somebody who laughs off emerging trends.
And so I thought about what's something that I
could do to demonstrate the opposite of that?
And I did some research very, very quickly on
what are some emerging public health concerns
that people really aren't talking about that
would be interesting to track? And I found
some interesting research about sports betting,
and especially young people in sports betting,
and it's becoming this thing that a lot of
public health experts are very worried about.
And so I very quickly just sent her a note
that said, "Wanted to build on this idea you
had today. I really liked that idea, by the way.
I saw this article, I saw this research about
this other emerging thing, sports betting,
and I think it'd be really interesting for
us to start tracking that because we could maybe
draw some correlations between people stress. We
have a stress monitor in Whoop. We can track their
stress. We could draw interesting correlations
between betting behaviors and stress levels."
And so that's all I did. It took me five,
10 minutes total. But I think it's a great example
of showing this idea of counter-program that
narrative, don't fight about the narrative. And so
when I teach this to my team, I'm always doing the
same thing. They come to me. They seem agitated
about something and I say to them, "It seems like
this is really bothering you. What's going on in
your head? What are you afraid of? What are you
worried about?" And often it will emerge, "I'm
worried that this other person thinks I'm bad at
my job. I'm worried that this person thinks I'm
an idiot," whatever it is. And I challenge that.
I think this is really important for managers
too to challenge this negative thinking when
you see it happen and not just validate it and
allow them to go down these negative spirals.
I challenge it and I say, "First of all,
I don't think there's evidence for that.
Is there evidence for that? And even if there
is, it doesn't really matter. What's something
that you could do to show them that it's
not true because you know it's not true?"
And I think giving people that power to
focus on the next step they can take and
the action that they can take that helps them
feel more secure in their identity in who they
are because their action demonstrates that, it
just gets them out of that negative thinking
and it gets them through that trough of despair
that comes after you feel like you took a punch.
So the idea here is when you're afraid somebody
that matters in your career thinks ill of you,
of something that you did, of you're not
good at something or you think something
that they're not happy about, this is a
version of getting punched basically is
you just feeling like someone thinks you're
not doing a great job. And so the tactic here
is how to change their mind almost about
you and give you something tangible to do.
Exactly.
Okay. And so the question to ask, and
I wrote this down as you were talking,
is, and this is what you ask of your
reports, what is the one thing that
you can do that demonstrates the opposite of
what you think this person thinks about you?
Exactly. This comes up all the time.
There will be narratives that emerge,
some are good, some are bad, about you and
your career. And I think especially when
people get to a place where they're putting
themselves out there more, they're talking
in more presentations, they're talking in more
meetings, it's very natural for them to become
concerned with the perception themselves.
And it is scary because it feels like something,
as I said, you don't have control
over. And so exactly. If instead of
focusing people around what do these people
think of me, you focus them around, well,
what are you going to do next to demonstrate that
you are the person that you know yourself to be,
I think that can just be incredibly effective
at giving people more of a sense of agency.
I guess talk about the balance of I'm just
going to prove everyone wrong against what
they think versus here's who I am and
I know this is me and this person is
mistaken. And instead of debating them,
I'm going to show them who I am. Just not
overstressing about everyone thinking
things about you in different ways.
There is some value I think in having a little bit
of a chip on your shoulder. You see that people
who are really successful, they do have a little
bit of like, "I'm going to prove them wrong." And
so I don't want to say that you shouldn't think
about it at all or you shouldn't care. Of course,
it's natural to care, and of course, it's fine
to care, but I do want to just help my team
build this habit of doing the things that you
know to be right and having conviction in that.
Being open to learning along the way and
calibrating as you go, but not becoming
overly concerned with your fears of what other
people are going to think of you. Because I think
especially for otherwise really thoughtful,
really the people who are hard on themselves,
I think that that just holds them back
from being the person that they can be.
So a key part of this is, this is going to
help you stop just spiraling on thinking
about what they think about you and gives
you something to do that will change that.
And then the other key point here is don't
try to convince them otherwise. You're not
going to go to your manager like, "Oh, I
really think ketamine therapy and addiction
is really important, and I didn't mean to
say it this way," and that kind of thing.
I'm not interested in litigating the things that
happened already when we can move forward. And
I'm certainly not interested in litigating what
another person thinks about a thing that happened.
I feel like I've spent so much time talking
to people in meetings, whatever it is,
where it's just this ruminating on something
that has already happened. It's very anxious
thinking pattern, I think, and people can
just get stuck in it. And so let them do it.
It's like when you get bad feedback or critical
feedback and you naturally have this reaction of,
"Oh, well, that's not fair because they
don't understand. I actually have numbers
I have to deliver on, or I only had 10 minutes
to do this, so of course, it wasn't perfect."
You naturally come up with these reasons why you
are actually not wrong, and that's fine. I don't
want to say you should feel bad for doing that.
Let yourself have the pity party, let yourself
feel those things, but then you got to move on
as quickly as possible because those feelings,
they actually do tend to spiral and get worse
if you're not actively working against them.
Oftentimes these sorts of lessons come from
the person experiencing this themselves. Is
this something that you dealt with when
you're starting your career or even now?
Oh, absolutely, 100%. And I think it is more
than just my career, but just my general
mental health and my life. A lot of where this
comes from is a concept in cognitive behavioral
therapy called behavioral activation.
And in my former job, I was working for
a company called Big Health and we make digital
therapeutics. So those are mobile apps that have
been clinically validated to treat behavioral
conditions like insomnia, depression, anxiety.
And I was working on a new depression
therapeutic, and so went very deep on this
and was working with a really wonderful clinical
team full of clinical psychologists who helped me
understand the techniques that therapists
use when they are working with people who
have depression. And so much of depression
is characterized by these negative thinking
patterns and this feeling that I feel bad and I
just need to wait until I feel better, and then
I'll start doing the things that are good for me.
I don't feel like responding to this text,
so I'm just not going to do it, but I'll respond
when I feel better. I don't feel like working out,
so I'm not going to do it, but I'll do it when I
feel better. And the truth is that doesn't go away
on its own, especially if you have depression.
Again, the idea of behavioral activation is
you have to identify these actions that
you can take that will reverse that
negative spiral and will improve your mood.
And so the misconception is I'll feel better
and then I'll act. And the thing that therapists
try to teach people, they're working with them in
therapy is I will act and then I will feel better.
But acting is hard if you are in the furrows of
depression. And so easier said than done. And
a lot of the work is in how you help people
identify specific actions that they can
take that will reliably lift their mood.
I mean, I have a list of myself. I've got a
list on my phone of my behavioral activations,
and it's things that I know I can do if I start
feeling like the walls are closing around me,
if I feel myself getting sucked into
very low mood or negative thinking,
or whatever it is. You can see how effective
that is at just getting you out of there versus
the instinct to just go and lay in bed and feel
bad for yourself, which I understand very well.
And so understanding that concept, which is
at its core a therapeutic concept used in
cognitive behavioral therapy, but it changed
how I see the entire world and how I see,
especially as a manager, the ways that people
on my team think and behave and how easy it is
to get stuck in some of these downward spirals
that you really need to actively push back on.
And as a manager, I want to help them do that.
I want to help them, A, see that, see the ways
they are in some ways sabotaging themselves,
getting in their own ways with whatever is
going on in their head. And then I want to help
them counter-program it in themselves. And also,
as I said, counter-program the things that
you are worried about out there as well.
So interesting. So the core of
this technique is what's an action,
and you said this, it could be very small.
Very small.
That you can take that in this case
shows someone else you're not who
they think you are. You're worried
they think about you in a certain
way and you want to take an action
that helps them see you're not that.
So yes, that's the taking the punch concept. The
behavioral activation could be anything. It can be
picking up a piece of laundry off of the chair and
putting it away, and that's just enough to get you
out of the downward thing you're in. So behavioral
activation just conceptually is, how are you
taking action to reverse the downward feeling
or the negative feeling that you're feeling?
And then the take a punch concept is that applied
in the context of I'm in a working environment.
I am very conscious of how I'm being perceived by
other people. That's causing me a great deal of
stress. I think especially for product people who
are... So much of their self identity is wrapped
up in having the answers, being competent,
getting things done. And so many of them
have been people who have been really good at
that for most of their careers, which is how
they got into these jobs in the first place.
I think that can be an extremely stressful
thing for them. That in many cases can be the
driver of burnout and the driver of I can't
really handle the stress of this job anymore.
And so I think the take a punch concept is more
just applied to that specific problem of I'm
struggling at work and I'm struggling largely
because of my perceptions of other people and
I want to feel more agency in that situation.
This is so cool. On the idea of the specific take
a punch concept, what kind of impact have you seen
this have on people's mood and careers?
How big a deal is this specific tactic?
Well, I think it's a big deal on two levels.
One, it's a big deal because it can help you
in a crisis or a minor crisis. But I actually
think it's a bigger deal because I see so many
people who don't put themselves out there because
they're afraid of how it's going to go. And so I
think of the classic example of I'm often trying
to encourage people to speak up in meetings more,
to practice the skill of how you move a
conversation forward in a way that can contribute
value, both because doing so I think is important
because nobody wants to be in bad meetings,
but also because it will help with your career.
This is how you get on people's radar as somebody
who's like, "Oh, that person's got great ideas,
thinks about things the right way," whatever it
is. I think it's one of these things that I talk
to people about it and they are interested in
coming to the meeting and hearing about
these big decisions are getting made,
but they just want to sit there and observe.
And I'm like, first of all, every additional
person in a meeting has a cost, because every
additional person in a meeting makes the people
in that meeting less candid than they would have
been if there were fewer people in that meeting.
And so one key piece of a meeting is you usually
have a problem you're trying to solve collectively
as a group. And it's really hard to do that
if people are being overly cautious about what
they're saying because there's too many people
in there. So when I tell people this, I'm like,
"It's really important that you earn your place
in this meeting and let's work on how to do that."
And the core piece of that is you've got
to say stuff that's valuable. And people
always come up with all these excuses for why
they can't do it. And one thing I've learned
is that I think people are really good at coming
up with very rational sounding reasons to not do
things that just make them uncomfortable. But in
their head they're like, "Oh no, I'm too junior.
Nobody wants to hear what I have to say.
Or everyone was already thinking it. Or
I like to process things internally. And by
the time I say them, the conversation moved
on," whatever it is. So much of that skill,
it's like a communication skill at its core,
it's just how to express yourself verbally,
but so much of the blocker of that is I think
fear. Fear of saying the wrong thing.
Fear of looking stupid. Fear of just the
discomfort of everyone in a room turning
and looking at you as you're trying to
formulate a half-baked thought. And so if
you can help people be less afraid of that,
that's 90% of the challenge of actually
improving some of these skills. And so I
think when you give people the skills of taking
a punch, you are helping them feel less afraid
of getting the punch in the first place.
And that's why I think it's so important.
That's profound, the second order effect of
the skill. There's something you mentioned
when we were chatting earlier that
stuck with me with this idea that too
many PMs and too many people are playing
on easy mode and not trying hard things.
Uh-oh. Maybe we'll get ourselves in trouble here.
Okay, let's do it. Say more.
Oh, I think this is my hot take. You hear
people talking about craft and taste and product
management, and it's all very wonderful. And I'm
totally on board. I love it. I'm a sucker for
that kind of thing, but I'm like, well, if you are
really in it just for pure love of the game, you
just love product management, why are you building
products for people exactly like you who have all
your exact same at a company that sells to other
companies that doesn't worry about pricing?
There's no real... I mean, I don't
want to act like I think this is easy,
to be clear. But in the grand scheme of things,
I wish that the people who have this pure love
of product management and have this pure love
of building things that you would see more of
that applied to building for low income people,
building for social services, things like that,
that really, really need that kind of work.
And I think there's a level of prestige
obviously associated with working in certain
companies, and you get less of that in other
industries. And so people would naturally
gravitate toward that. I totally get it. I
totally get it. You get paid better. No real
judgment from me. I wish I saw more, but I
wish that you would see more people. And I'll
say this, I know there's a lot of you out there.
I know there's a ton of people out there
doing really, really important work in really,
really hard spaces, and I see you and
I appreciate it and shout out to you.
Awesome. Okay, I'm glad you shared that.
Thank you. I think this will resonate with
a lot of people. I want to move on to another
trait/habits/skill that you are good at and help
people learn, which is being very transparent
in what's happening within the organization,
within your thinking. You almost help
people think the way you think and see
the way you think so that they can operate
at a higher level. Just talk about that,
what that looks like and why that's important.
It's interesting, I think another thing I hear a
lot of people complain about in organizations is
the why do 10 people have to sign off on this
email before I send it kind of problem. And
I think the answer to that is because those 10
people all have different information, different
context, and in many cases, completely different
working models for how the CEO of the company and
other strategic leaders in the company think.
And it makes things super inefficient. I think
people will often say like, "Oh, it's
a process problem." It's not a process
problem. It's not approval problem. I think it's
a transparency and it's communication problem,
like downward communication, outward
communication. And what I mean by that is
when I think about artifact-based communication,
so reading a strategy document for...
About artifact-based communication. So reading
a strategy document, for example. Everyone at
the company reads the strategy document. Great.
Everyone is working from the same idea of what
the strategy is. But then things change, right?
Especially if you're working in a really dynamic
space, new competitive threats emerge, new
opportunities emerge all the time. This is
especially true now with AI. Obviously everyone
is lighting their strategies on fire and trying
to figure out the best way to sort of transform
their organization. And so if the way that you
understand what's going on at the company is from
reading a document that was written six months
ago, you're going to be working from outdated
information and you're not going to be able to
think and respond to new things that happen.
And so what is much more helpful than
understanding what your CEO thinks is, I think
understanding how your CEO thinks. And that goes
for all sorts of levels of the company. I want
to understand how all the strategic leaders at
my company think, and I want my team to understand
how I think. And when I feel confident that people
on my team understand how I think, I don't need to
read their emails, I don't need to approve things.
The times where I feel like I need to do that is
because I'm working with people where I'm like, I
don't have confidence that these people understand
how I think, or I don't have confidence that they
understand how this email or whatever it is, is
going to be received by this important person.
And so I try to teach that to my team. And
the way that I do that is a few ways. First,
I'm in meetings with people, important people
at the company. So I'm constantly hearing the
things that they're saying and paying attention
to sort of the note behind the note. Why do I
think they're saying this? What insight do they
have that they're bringing to this conversation
that might not be obvious? And I try to make an
effort every week. I don't always do it, but I
try to send my team just a quick rundown in Slack
of, "Here are the most important conversations or
the most interesting conversations I had this
week. Here's what that person said verbatim."
Again, I write a lot of notes so I've
got it. If you've got a transcriber,
maybe that'll help you. "And here's what I
interpret that as. Here's why I think they
say that. Here's where I think that's coming from
and here's what I'm going to do differently as a
result." And these aren't long. And sometimes if
I don't have time, I'll just, in a team meeting,
I'll literally just go through my notes
from the week and sort of voiceover stuff
and editorialize it as I go. And over time, I
think my team has a pretty good sense of what
people are saying and how to think about the
thinking behind it and how this person thinks,
how this person thinks and how I think. And
I think when you get an entire organization
working that way where everyone's working from
the same models of what the CEO thinks matters,
what level of risk tolerance the company has,
things like that, then you can actually start
to move much, much faster and communication
becomes much, much, much less painful.
So the tactic here is to help your teams
kind of build a mental model of everyone
in the company that matters so that it's...
The way you put it almost is when they're
emailing them or asking for something, they
already know how they're going to respond. Is
they're an example you could share of something
like this, of just something a person at Whoop
of how they think? I don't know, maybe you
could keep it anonymous just to make this a
little reel of the kind of mental model
you might want to build around someone.
So our CEO, Will, is somebody who obsesses
over pixels in a way that is challenging to
get things through design review, but I think
results in a product that is a thousand times
better than it would be if he were accepting of
small excuses here and there for, "Oh, well this,
we had to cut scope here. We couldn't quite
do what they wanted here." He sets a high bar
and he holds it and he doesn't compromise. And I
think this can sometimes get misconstrued, and I
think a lot of people might think that he just
wants maximal scope on everything. And I think
that is a misunderstanding of what he cares about.
We often get feedback from him that's like, "This
doesn't feel like the future and everything that
we're building needs to feel like the future."
A lot of people hear that and they're kind of
like, "Oh gosh, we're never going to get this
thing done on time. We can't make any sort of
sacrifices to scope or anything like that." But
when I hear that, what I hear is more that we have
this AI coach in the product, we have all this
amazing data in the product. We're tracking every
single one of your heartbeats and we're pulling at
all this other data and we have every screen is a
moment to show that to people in a way that feels
like something that has never existed before.
And there are small ways to do that,
right? It's like how you pull in. If you're
explaining a concept like VO2 Max, which is a
measure of your cardiovascular health, you can
explain that to people with static content or
you can explain that to people by bringing their
data into the method of explanation that you're
using. You can make it really conversational
because you're using this AI coach. You can
make it feel more like you're talking to a
person and a person who by the way has all
the data about you, which doesn't exist today.
Your doctor doesn't have that, your coach doesn't
have that. And that's not like, "Oh gosh, we've
got to blow up the scope on this thing and make
it a hundred X as big." But it's finding these
little touches to say, "Wow, that was really
magical, that was really thoughtful and this
feels like the future. This feels like I'm very
conscious of the fact that this product knows so
much about me and is able to sort out the signal
from the noise on that in these really small and
elegant ways." And so for something like that,
I would get that feedback in design review or
I'd hear that in a design review and maybe one
of my PMs would be in that design review.
And so I bring that to the team. And I
hear of things like that in a few different
design reviews. So I bring those back to the
team and I'm like, "I've noticed that recently we
are consistently getting this type of feedback.
Here's why I think it's really important to
Will, because I think he's really focused on
building the health company of the future. And I
don't want you all to think that this just means
we have to just throw AI at everything and we
have to just throw maximum scope at everything.
I think the key is understanding on the matrix of
cost and effort for impact, what are those high
impact but low cost ways that we can just find
and sprinkle through the experience and really
try to make that magical?" So I'm connecting the
dots for my team. Right? I'm saying, "You weren't
in all these meetings, but I saw it. Here's what
I heard. Here's my interpretation of what I heard,
and here's how I'm thinking about how this other
person thinks about it. And so as a result,
here are some things that I think we can
do across our product going forward."
Essentially these are principles, values, or
tenets per person of what matters to them.
Exactly.
So for Nick it's, "This needs to feel
like we're living in the future." It
can't just be like another heartbeat dragging out.
Yeah. Yeah.
This is so cool. And there's so many
trickle-down benefit to this. One is
people feel like they're aware of what's
happening. That's one of the most common,
I think, piece of feedback people
have with big companies. Like,
"I don't know what's happening." So there's
so much visibility to all the secretive stuff
happening in the meetings. "I don't know what
people are deciding my fates and all these
discussions." So I think just even knowing
that you're sharing all this is so powerful.
Well, and on that note, when I approach these
conversations, I always try to think of them as,
even if I don't agree with the feedback,
if I don't agree with the decision,
what is the insight that I'm missing?
How am I wrong about this? In ways like,
what would be true for this other person to
be right? And I'll go through that thought
exercise and I might not get to the other side
and agree with it. I might still think I'm right
or whatever. But oftentimes it forcing myself to
think that way forces me to think about how this
other person thinks it. And if I do that enough,
I will be like, "Oh, this makes sense. I think
this makes sense if. I think this makes sense
if, and oh, maybe this other thing is true."
And I think when I hear the people, the people who
are like, "I don't know what's going on with this
company," I think they do the opposite. I think
they look for reasons to disagree and they look
for holes to poke in, "Well, this decision
doesn't make any sense because I came up
with something that might be wrong about it."
And I think that's another thing, by the way,
in terms of just sort of helping your team have
the emotional maturity to exist and thrive in
an organization is helping them think that way,
helping them understand you have a point of view.
Your point of view is important, but on some
level, you do kind of have to have respect for
these other points of view and have the humility
to think that maybe they're onto something that
you're not onto. And it's amazing how much you
can learn into it without having to have all the
facts just by doing that. If you're like, "Well,
this person's behavior makes sense in a situation
where X, Y, and Z is happening," oftentimes
you'll find that X, Y and Z is happening.
I'm glad you went there. I wanted to
actually follow this thread, which is
kind of a different direction, but I think a
lot of people are always struggling with this
as a leader. When your leader disagree, it does
say something that you completely disagree with,
but you still need to represent that as,
"Here's the thing we're doing." But you
don't want to be like, "Oh, just because Nick
said so." Because you lose power as a leader.
Is there something you've learned about
how to do that well when your leader tells
you to do something you disagree with and
you still need to get your team to do it.
First, I do try to go through the what if
I'm wrong exercise. I think a lot of people
just sort of expect that if you ask somebody a
open-ended question like, "Why are we doing this?"
You're going to get a straightforward answer. And
oftentimes the answer is not straightforward for
various reasons. Maybe there's confidentiality
reasons, maybe there's just somebody is acting
on a hunch, but that hunch is informed by years
or decades of reps of developing judgment, and
they're probably really onto something. And it's
not just this kind of arbitrary gut feeling. But
whatever it is, I really try to get to the bottom
of, let me really make sure that I have done my
best to understand this person's point of view.
And I have some sort of tools for doing that,
which I can also talk about. But if I've done
that, and I still disagree, I'm relatively candid
about that, but candid in a way where it's still
respectful. I think what you want to avoid is a
situation where as a manager you're like, "Ah, I
have no control. This sucks. This decision is so
stupid, but that's a job, so we have to do it."
Obviously that's not going to set your team up
for success or make anybody happy about it, but
you do hear that, you do see that happening. And
so I think what I try to do in those situations is
separate out my opinion from it, from the, " Well,
what is the insight that makes it make sense
to this person" and explain their rationale.
Even if I'm comfortable saying, "I don't
necessarily think this isn't how I would
do it," or "I don't even really agree with
how they're thinking about it, but from
their point of view, from their perspective,
their professional experience, whatever it is,
I could see how this makes sense. And they
might be right. I don't think they're right,
but they might be. Let's find out. We're not going
to find out if we are all squabbling about whether
this is a good idea the whole time. The only way
we're going to find out is if we give it the best
shot that we have and try to do it. And if we're
wrong, that happens sometimes and we try again."
I like that this comes back to your mental model
orientation of, "Here's their mental model,
here's what their experience has been like,
here's how they see the world, the trends,
and then this is why they think the way they
think." And so instead of encouraging your team
or yourself even to be like, "No, no, you're wrong
here." It's more, "Okay, here's their data set,
let's try this, and this will inform that
data set and maybe change their mind."
Yeah. Because I think in product, I like
to joke, there's no right answers. Right?
There's only wrong answers, and you're just
trying to execute well on the least wrong
answer that's available to you. And so I think
it is the sort of reasonable people can disagree
about this stuff at all of this is what I
think, and this is how I would approach it.
I think this is what they think and I think
this is why they would approach it this way.
And again, the only chance we have of succeeding
is not being torn apart on that. And so at the
end of the day, if it's not a obviously terrible
answer, and sometimes even if it isn't obviously
terrible answer, you're still more likely to
succeed if you just sort of reorient yourself
around a world where it's not a terrible answer
and then just try to will that into existence.
You said that you have some tools to
help you understand someone's point
of view. I can't help but ask more about that.
I talk about what I like to call the magic
questions, but the thing about magic questions is
they're not actually questions, they're statements
and they end with, "Do you agree?" Or "Is that
right?" And so I have found this, the most helpful
way for kind of trying to understand a person's
mental model is to just put facts in front
of them and see what they say no to and what
they say yes to. And then if you can get them to
explain, great. And if they're good communicators,
they often can, but if they're not, you don't have
to let that stop you view. And so I mean, I'll do
this even just as an example in a non-leadership
context with if I'm working with legal teams or
compliance teams or things like that, they're
often working from a literal set of rules. Right?
There are laws, there are regulations, and you are
trying to understand if we were to take this path,
would that be okay? Would that not be okay?
And sometimes that's not straightforward.
Sometimes there's regulatory areas that are up
to interpretation. And so when I first started
working in a regulated space, I would find this
kind of frustrating and confusing because I would
say, "Can you just give me the rule so I can
understand what's right and what's left of it?"
And they'd be like, "Oh, well, it depends.
It depends, it depends." And so I learned
that if I kind of flip that and approached
that, "Well, what if we did X, Y, and Z?
What if this is what it looked like? What if this
is what the copy said? Would that be okay?" No,
yes. If no, why? If yes, why? And so I'm sort
of teasing out the mental model rather than
asking them to explain it to me. And this is
what I tell my team all the time to do this
to me. When they come to me and they say,
"Well, what do you think I should do?" Or
"What could I have done differently?" I'll
say, "Rephrase that as 'Tell me what you
think you could have done differently.' And
then ask me if I agree." And when I do this,
I think it has a few benefits. One, it helps
them kind of calibrate their judgment over time.
So they're actually forcing themselves to
make this assertion. And then they're kind
of calibrating how close that was to how I would
think about it, which will get you much faster,
much further than just asking open-ended questions
and getting the answer. And then the second part
of it is they don't become reliant on me for
answering these questions. I think that's kind of
a trap that a lot of managers fall into is people
come to you with questions, you want to help them,
you answer the question, and then you find that
they come to you with all their questions and
you're kind of like, "Yeah, you got to solve some
of these on your own." So again, I think the magic
questions to me, is that right? Do you agree?
And anytime you find yourself tempted to ask an
open-ended question to somebody whose brain you're
trying to understand, stop yourself and say,
"Let me just say that. Let me say as a statement
what I think," and then try to calibrate based on
their reaction. And I think that's the fastest
way to understand how another person thinks.
It makes me think about a lot of people, it could
come across as it's a weird manipulative way of
asking someone stuff, but it turns out that
we're not good at really knowing what we think
or know a lot of times. And you need someone
almost to interview you in a really effective
way to get out all this knowledge. And this is
just a really simple way of getting that idea.
It's funny because when I talk about this, I get
that reaction a lot where people are like, "Well,
doesn't it feel coercive?" And I'm like, "Well,
you got to go in pure of heart." You've got to
go in open to being wrong and even expected to
be wrong. And you have to make that clear to
them. Right? If you're coming in and you're
like, "Here's what I think. You agree? You
agree?" Of course you're not getting the answer
you want. Or you might get the answer you want,
I might get a yes. If your goal is to get
to yes, that's not what I'm talking about.
If your goal is to understand and you are coming
from a, "Help me understand how I'm wrong,
help me understand what I'm getting wrong here"
and approach it with that sort of curiosity and
humility and make sure that you're caring yourself
and presenting yourself to this person in a way
that shows that, that you're not coming in hostile
or forceful or something. Yeah. Because there are
absolutely circumstances where you're doing that
and you're going to get bad intel because you're
making the person uncomfortable, so they're
going to lie to you. But that's I think,
a whole set of interpersonal skill that we
probably don't have time to talk about today.
I wanted to come back to, you said this
interesting insight about your CO that
he wanted to build something that felt
like the future. I just wanted to share,
there's a story that has always stuck with me
at Airbnb. There was a big launch coming up and
there was a designer sitting late in the office
trying to update the website to include this new
product. It was a launch of Airbnb Neighborhoods,
I don't know, 10 years ago. And she was just like,
"Hey, Joe." And this is Joe Gebbia was walking
around the office. And she's like, "Hey Joe,
what do you want the website to be?
What do you want it to look like?
What should we try to..." And it was
going to launch in two days. He's like,
"Build something the internet has never
seen before." And now this makes... It's
interesting because when I always think about
that story and tell that story, it's like,
this is a crazy ask. And now as you share an
approach for how to handle something like that,
it really changes my perspective to like, "Okay,
what's Joe's worldview? Why is that the way he
saw the world and why we needed to build a site
like that,?" Which I could start thinking about,
but that's a really interesting way to just handle
things that sound absurd and out of nowhere.
I agree so much. I proud former English major,
and so I'm a huge proponent of reading fiction
and reading in general. And I feel like that's
where so much of this comes from for me. It is
just a curiosity for in what world does this make
sense for this person? And it's so easy to look
at another person's behaviors, another person's
actions and what they say and just be like, "That
doesn't make any sense." And I find that, I don't
know, your relationships become so much richer,
even just in a work context, when you approach
it with that, "What is the world of this person
where the thing that they're saying makes sense?"
And I feel like in my life, honestly, a lot of my
frustration has come from being frustrated
with other people. And so this is something
that I've had to learn over time. Because when
I come home from work and I'm just like, "Oh,
this person said this and it didn't make any
sense, and this person's totally out to lunch
and leadership doesn't know what's going on."
All I was doing was making myself miserable.
And actually worse than that, I was making myself
miserable and I was making myself pretty useless
to the company. And so I would get frustrated
because I was like, " No, nobody appreciates my
perfect, unique, beautiful insight and all these
other people have no unique, beautiful, perfect,
concise, just wrong opinions." And so I feel
like that's been a big area of growth for me,
honestly, is learning to approach
people that way. It's not just like,
"Oh, this is a nice thing to do," but I think it
genuinely makes me a happier person. And yeah,
I think a lot of it comes from reading fiction.
I love that we're just unpacking the onion
of the power of this very specific habit
of just helping you learn the mental
model of the people around you. And-
I feel like this is just making
me sound like a crazy force.
No, there's so much power to this. As you talk,
I'm like, "Wow, there's so much value here."
Because not only is it, you talk about how this
is the source of a lot of burnout for a lot of
people where they're just so frustrated, the CEO
or the chief product officer, designers just like,
"I hate this." Why are they just asking all
these ridiculous things, keeping the bar way
too high? It's just nothing's ever good enough."
But not only does it help you feel better about
their asks, because you can understand where
they're coming from, it also helps you be more
effective and helping them change their mind
potentially and see a different perspective
because now you see the data that informs their
perspective and you could help adjust that or kind
of poke at it like, "Hey, are you sure this
is true? Are you sure I don't know, they're
a competitor and this is how they see it. Maybe
it's not. Let's look into that a little deeper."
Yeah, it's really interesting. At my last
company when I started reporting to the CEO,
they found various coaches for me to work with,
and one of them was the former chief product
officer at Coinbase who's gone to found Bridge,
which is just that apart by Stripe for a ton of
money. One thing that he said to me that really
stuck with me is when you're reporting to the CEO
and as a chief product officer, the big mistake
that people make is they think that the game is
all about getting what is inside their head and
influencing the CEO, influencing the people around
them to make it so, and if you go into the role
trying to do that, you're going to fail because
actually what your job is to do is to understand
what the CEO's vision is and what they care about,
again, sort of how they think about things
and figure out how to operationalize that
in a way that results in the best possible
manifestation of it in the form of product.
And that was just such a radically different way
from what I ever thought my job was. Again, to
go back to sort of the fiction example, you kind
of come up thinking you're the protagonist. And
you can be the protagonist in your life. You can
be the protagonist in the story of your family,
but in the story of your work of a company,
you are probably not the protagonist. And as
much as it can feel kind of weird to say that
I genuinely think some of the best advice I've
got in my life in terms of things that have just
not only transformed how I see the world and how
I act in it, but just my own sense of happiness
is you're not special. And I used to spend so
much time and energy just being like, "Oh, people
don't see it my way and I have to convince them.
And when you're in an organization, it's an
ecosystem. Right? It's an organization full
of people who are all trying to work together
to get a thing done. And if every single one
of those people is operating from their
own protagonist viewpoint of "This is how
I actually see the world, this is what I think
we're here to do and I need to convince everyone
around me at all times," it becomes extremely
inefficient. It becomes extremely painful,
because everyone's just fighting all the
time. And so in some ways it feels like
you're kind of, it sounds almost defeatist.
I'm always worried about the sounding. I'm just
like, "Yeah, just do whatever the boss says."
And that's not how I feel at all. I think it's
incredibly important to bring your skills and
your talents and your perspective to the job
you have and really your taste and your craft and
all of these things. But I do think this idea of
understanding how to build a shared mental model
of everyone together that definitionally cannot be
defined by your own narrow perspective, actually
just makes work a lot better for everybody.
So then a lot of people, like you said, I love
that you went there, is just like if you're,
because it could sound like, okay, your job is
just to execute what the CO tells you. There's
no value to your insights and perspectives, and
you're just get out of the way. You're just get
everyone to do the thing the CO wants. Where
do you... I guess, in your experience or just
advice on where's the fulfillment for you
then as a CPO or example or a director of
product where it's not that fun just to be there
executing a CO's vision and not have any input?
Well, and I think there's so many decisions
all the way down and there's so many micro
places where you can zig where others
would've zagged. And I think I personally,
a lot of where my fulfillment comes from is from
feeling like if somebody else were in this job,
it would be done differently. And something about
the product is different because I was the one who
worked on it because I was in the job. And that
comes from my unique perspective, my unique point
of view, the experiences I've had in the past,
my various influences. And I think it's trying
to figure out the right level for it so that
you're not pushing against an immovable force.
It's almost like if you're playing Jenga and
you're sort of trying to feel around to find,
okay, well, where are the pieces that can move?
And when you know how somebody else thinks A,
you can find that there are immovable forces.
Those are not the battles worth fighting. But
there are also areas where maybe they don't
know as much, and there's also areas where
maybe they're actually kind of scared because they
don't know as much. And maybe that's an area where
you have an interesting point of view. And so
you can step into that role and be tremendously
valuable and being tremendously influential.
But you can only do that if you have a good
frame for kind of what the model is and
where are the things where it's like, okay,
we are operating on a person's insight here that
is itself extremely unique and extremely valuable,
and it is the reason this company even
exists in the first place. But that, I mean,
there's millions of decisions have to get made,
you know what I mean? And there's millions of
different places that you can put yourself. And
so I think it's just kind of constantly feeling
out for where are the places that I'm really
spiky? Where are the things that I think I do
really well? Where are the gaps? And again,
you can only find those if you're engaging
really good faith and engaging earnestly and
really understanding how other people think.
There's two really interesting thoughts
that I have as you're talking that I think
will even further crystallize what you're
saying. One is that you're just saying,
this is the way the world works. It
makes me think about Jeffrey Pfeffer,
he was a guest on this podcast. He teaches
this class at Stanford Business School about
how to gain power in the world. It's like
the rules of power. And he talks about,
and it's all these ways to influence and win and
achieve and gain status and all these things.
And he's like, this part doesn't sound fun and
great, but I talk about here's the way the world
works and is not the way you wish it would be. And
what you're describing is the way a company works
is the CO in charge and your job is to, they're
the boss. And the sooner you understand their
vision trumps your vision, the easier everything
gets. You're not there to tell the CO, "Here's
what we should be building." Right? Their job is
to own the vision of the business and the company.
Yeah, I think that's true.
And if you disagree with it,
you probably shouldn't be working at that company.
Yeah. The other piece is, it's just the
vision. Here's the vision of the future
of where we're heading. If we win, here's
what will be true and the world will look
like. But there's so much more that you need
to figure out that is to achieve that vision.
And that's basically the role of the CPO and
director of products, all those sorts of folks-
And of everyone at that level.
Everyone at the company.
And I think how you said it there is so right on,
because it is like, the vision is in many ways,
I mean, in some ways it's execution base, but
in many ways it's a vision of what the world is
going to look like in five years, in 10 years.
And so in some ways, I would say your job is,
if you can understand that and you can understand
here's what this person thinks the world is going
to look like, assuming all that is true, what are
the things that I can do to maximize the chances
of that and becoming the actual future?
And then also, what does that mean for a
product? What does that mean for if it has
to be true? That take Whoop, for example,
if there's a vision of the future where you have
all of your health data in one place and we're
able to detect health issues before you even
know you have them and we're able to do really
hyper-personalized coaching to help you understand
how your behaviors today are impacting how healthy
you're going to be in decades, what does that
mean for what Whoop needs to be today and what
does that mean for how it needs to evolve in the
next couple of years in order to both make that a
reality but also win in that world. And I do think
that's exactly where the people in the right.
And I do think that's exactly where
the people in the rank and file can
be tremendously influential. It's that level
of, "I'm going to fight with you about how the
world's going to work in five years," where
I think you're just fighting a losing battle.
And if you don't like the vision,
you could leave, right? It's like,
or try to change it. Those are two options.
And I think, to your point about pushing
back, because you asked about this. Again,
I never want it to sound like I'm just defeatist,
"just accept it." I'm a very opinionated person.
I go to the mat for things that I think are
true, and so, I teach my team, "You have
to be really good at forming arguments,
and that can show up in different ways."
Some people are really good at doing that with
data. Some people are really good at doing that
with the qual and the quant, and moving it
together. But you have to be able to advocate
for what you think is true in the most compelling
way possible. And you have an obligation to do it.
And if you have done it, and you've done it well,
and it didn't work, that's when it's time to say,
"Well, maybe there's something here that I
wasn't seeing previously." And that's where I
think it's time to have some humility around it.
But it's a journey. You don't start from, "Well,
I got nothing to say here." So I think knowing
where you are on that journey is important, too.
This reminds me, there's a PM leader at
Airbnb, who ended up leading a new initiative,
and they ended up doing a bunch
of stupid stuff. And he's like,
"I'm realizing that it's me that
needs to be pushing back on stuff,
now that I'm in charge of this product team.
I'm the person that needs to convince the CEO
this is a bad idea." And I am just realizing, that
after doing a bunch of stuff, that it was stupid.
You will see that idea is that you do have an
obligation to try to convince them that it's a
bad idea. And you're going to be right sometimes,
and you're not going to be right every time.
I think that that's why it's so hard to
talk about these things in absolutes,
because sometimes you're right, and sometimes
you're not right. And it is important to get
really good at knowing the difference,
and knowing where you go from there.
This episode is brought to you by
Attio, the AI native CRM. Attio is
built to scale with your business from day one.
Connect your e-mail and calendar, and Attio
instantly builds a CRM that matches your business
model, with all of your company's contacts and
interactions, enriched with actionable insights.
Sync in your product's usage, billing info,
or any other data sources and Attio's flexible
data model will handle it all, without any rigid
templates or workarounds. With Attio, AI
isn't just a feature, it's the foundation.
You can do things like instantly prospect and
route leads with research agents, get real-time
insights from AI, using customer conversations,
and build powerful AI automations for your most
complex workflows. Industry leaders like flatfile,
Replicate, and Modal are already experiencing
what's next for CRM. Go to attio.com/lenny to
get 15% off your year. That's attio.com/lenny.
I want to move on to another skill you really
get at, but first of all, something I noted,
that I wanted to touch on real quick. You
mentioned that WHOOP now does VO2 Max, and this
is not a promotion for WHOOP, but that's so cool.
That's a huge thing to track, that this is the
thing that Peter Thiel and all these guys are
always saying, "This is the thing you want to
track, to understand your health and progress
as your VO2 Max. It's like your blood oxygen
level." I don't know exactly what it's, but
that's cool. The new WHOOP lets you do that.
There's so much cool stuff
we're doing right now. I'm like,
I don't know if I want to get
into it all right now, but I can.
We'll get back to it. We'll get back to it.
All right. Let's get back to it.
Okay, cool. Yeah. Okay. So another habit/skill
that you are really good at, that I've heard
from folks is, and you've mentioned this
a couple times, is just building habits,
helping your team build good habits.
And coming back to the CBT stuff,
just like behavior loops and things
like that. Talk about just what that is,
why that's important, what you
help your team learn there.
Yeah, I'm obsessed with habit formation,
and reward loops and behavior change,
and all of these things. And when I think
about trying to change behavior on your team,
or just trying to encourage your team to do more
of the behaviors that you believe are associated
with success, I think a lot of people think about
it more of an education model, where it's like,
you teach the thing, you assess the thing, and
then there's some accountability around the thing.
And I think, if you think about it more
in the context of behavioral psychology,
it actually works a lot better. So I'll give
you an example. Many leaders have been trying to
think about how to drive AI adoption, AI
upscaling on my team, and what that can look like.
And when I talk to people about this outside
of the company, I'm always surprised like,
"Well, how do you measure it, and how do
you enforce it?" And I don't really think
about any of that stuff. I'm thinking about,
"How am I creating habits around using this?"
And for me, there's a couple of things there.
So it's consistency. How are you getting someone
doing something every single day? And to
do that, it has to start small. It has to
start super easy. You have to give them things
that take no more than a minute or two to do.
And actually, I have a 30 days of GPT, I call
it, of a list of 30 things to do, one every
single day, that I don't know anyone who has gone
through this, and not come out the other side,
feeling a hundred times more confident in
their skills, and actually using it every
day as a habit, because it's built as a habit
formation tool, and not an education tool.
And this is using a specific GPT build, or
building their own GPT, or what's the habit there?
The habit is using ChatGPT, or
Claude, or any of these tools-
Oh, okay. Okay, got it. I got it.
... [inaudible 01:03:50] tools, to get their
work done, in just a generic and get work done
way. And so, I have this little tool, if you
sign up for my newsletter, I'll send it to you.
What's the URL of the
newsletter, as you mention that?
Thanks for asking. It is
hils.substack.com, H-I-L-S, substack.com.
Sweet.
But basically, it's one little thing you can
do every single day. And the key with this is,
again, consistency. So you need to get people
doing this thing every day, reducing friction.
I think a mistake a lot of people make when they
start thinking about how to drive adoption is,
they're like, "Oh, we have to show people
how to do their work with these tools."
But I'm like, "Well, work is hard." And if you
are on a deadline for something, you've got to get
something done, the last thing that you ever want
is more friction associated with getting it done.
It is so annoying when you're trying to get a
thing done, and your tools are being changed
on you, and you don't know how the thing works,
and the hot keys are all different, or whatever.
So I actually think, using it in situations that
have nothing to do with your work are way easier,
because you're removing all of that friction of,
"Oh wait, I got to go think about, 'All right,
what's a project that I'm working
on? Oh, I put this into ChatGPT,
and I didn't really get a good answer.'"
Or, "Now I'm frustrated, because this
thing's taking longer than I need it to take, or
whatever." I start with things that are just fun,
simple use cases. It might be coming up with times
to take a vacation, or places to go on vacation.
Or it might be uploading your calendar
into ChatGPT, and asking it for ideas,
for talking points for the meetings, or
things where the person doesn't have to think,
because it's all just spelled out.
And things where there's no external
work pressure, that you have to apply this
to, that's going to make it an unpleasant
experience. So consistency, reduce friction. And
then, most importantly, designing reward loops.
And this is something, that when I'm talking
to people about designing for behavior change,
the number one thing I always tell them is, "You
are not thinking enough about the reward loop."
The reward loop needs to be powerful, it needs
to be immediate, and it needs to be emotional,
so that when this person does the thing that you
want them to do, they feel like a million bucks.
When I think about any kind of habit I'm trying
to build on my team, that's something that I'm
always thinking about, is how can I make sure that
when a person does this, they feel really great?
And part of why I like Custom GPTs as a
tool for helping people learn to use LLMs,
and I talk about this on the podcast I did
with Claire, on how I AI, is because if you
put in the prompt, you as the person building the
custom GPT, you write the prompt, you put it in,
you design it such that somebody can upload
a specific document. And then, they can get a
specific output, like feedback on that document,
or maybe something more fun than feedback,
an improved written version of that document.
They get the joy of like, "Oh, this helps me.
This was cool," without any of the despair of,
"Oh, I'm not very good at prompting, and this
didn't really work, and I'm frustrated." And so,
I just always think about that in general. If I'm
trying to build any kind of habit on my team, it's
less about the accountability of how I'm enforcing
this, and more about how I make it so rewarding
for people to do it, that they do it naturally.
I wrote down notes as you were talking, so kind
of, the four parts of habits, and I'm going to
ask you for an example, to help people see how
this actually works in real life. But basically,
to help people build an actual habit, the three
steps are the three things you want to focus on,
consistency, friction, and reward
loop. And within reward loop,
you want it to be powerful, immediate,
and emotional. What is an example of this?
Yeah, I can give some,
actually, examples of how we do this in
product, if that would be interesting.
Absolutely.
Because I think there's something WHOOP is really
good at. So I think one of the most interesting
kind of anti-reward loops on WHOOP is around
alcohol. WHOOP has this recovery system. You get
a recovery score every morning. It's red, yellow,
green, and it's basically how recovered you are,
and how ready you are to take on the day.
And if you drink, and you're on WHOOP,
you will very quickly learn that any time
you drink, you get a red recovery. It's so
interesting, because it's not like people who
were drinking weren't getting hangovers before,
or they knew that it was disrupting their
sleep. None of this is news for people,
but there's something about seeing that red score
that just feels like, it just feels bad. It has
this really profound emotional impact on people.
And when you see the green score,
it feels great. It's like, "Ooh, I'm doing
something well, I'm taking care of myself.
I'm a healthy person." And I hear this when I talk
to members all the time, and I hear people say,
"I've had problems with my drinking for years. And
it wasn't until I got on WHOOP, that I was really
able to get a handle on my drinking."
I'm always, again, amazed by this,
because I'm like, "You had all the information you
needed before," but there's something about the,
you wake up, and you get that red score,
that's just, it manages to override whatever
was driving people to do it in the first place.
And then, I think, continuing to have that data,
where you can look back at your data
and see, "Oh, that was the red day,
that was the day that I did this thing." And
it's something that we've actually been trying to
find ways to do this in a longer term way.
Because when you have these short reward loops,
it's easier, where it's like, "I did a thing."
And then, I immediately either got a reward, Green
Recovery, or got an anti-reward, Red Recovery,
and that is changing my behavior as a result.
And we have this new feature, Healthspan,
that we just launched with our new hardware.
And basically, what it's trying to
do is help you have this reward loop,
between your behaviors and activities that
you're doing today, and what means for how
healthy you're going to be in 20, 30, 40 years.
And so, we have something similar where we have
this, we call it the Amoeba. It has your WHOOP
age in it. It has colors, and moves around,
and that changes, based on how your behaviors
and your activities change, every single day.
And the colors change when you're doing better,
and when you're doing worse. And you can kind
of see it all broken down, how you sleep,
your VO2 Max, the consistency of your sleep,
how much time you're spending
in different heart rate zones,
how much time you're spending in
strength training, things like that.
And we found that, again, it's just this
incredibly powerful reward loop, because
we're taking something that historically
has been really, really hard, which is,
"When I make healthy changes today, not only
do I not see the results of those for decades,
but the short term reward loop of those often
feels pretty bad, because change is hard,
and it feels bad before it feels good."
And trying to build that reward loop that
is more rewarding for people to see those numbers
change, and to see those colors change, so that
they're actually able to make those changes, and
see that progress, and feel really good about it.
I love that you're using all these habit building
tactics that folks have been using historically,
to get you to check your Instagram likes, and your
Facebook posts for actual good, for helping people
live longer and happier. That makes me very happy.
Is there an example of doing this sort of thing
with your team, of helping them build, and you
talk about AI learning to use Claude, ChatGPT?
Yeah, I think with AI, I think a lot of
it's just shouting people out, right?
When somebody is using AI to solve a problem that
they wouldn't have used AI before, give them a
shout-out in the team meeting, let them demo that.
Again, make them feel like a million bucks for
doing the thing. And people respond to that,
people will see, I mean, maybe it's because I
work at WHOOP, and we're all obsessed with
reward loops, so we're all choosing them.
Or reward looping each
other. "Here's your reward."
No, exactly. But no, people see that, and
people respond to it. I think another example
is something that I think about a lot,
and is relevant to our conversation about,
just how you build teams that can do hard things,
is how you encourage people to take care of
themselves outside of work. And it's something
that I'm always trying to model for my team,
and make it really visible the ways that
I'm doing this, and sort of having my
hobbies, and my other various things.
And as a result, I also try to reward,
have these reward loops, when I see people on my
team doing the same thing. Because I think people,
bosses often inadvertently create reward loops
for, "Oh, this person, they had to stay up till
two o'clock to get it done, but they got it
done." When you create those reward loops,
that's the behavior that people start mimicking.
And so, I try to do the opposite. I try to
find ways that I really am impressed with
my team, and the ways that they take care
of themselves outside of work, because I think
that makes them better at their jobs, frankly,
and just happier humans. So there's a PM on
my team, Emily, who teaches at Handlebar.
She's a fitness instructor in her spare time.
And so, whenever we have a long meeting, I'll be
like, "Oh, Emily, why don't you lead stretches, to
get the energy level in the room up? Just nothing
serious, just for a minute, before we start the
meeting." And it's kind of fun. Everyone has a
laugh about it, "Emily's doing her thing," and
I'll be like, "Everyone, come check out Emily at
Handlebar in Charlestown this Saturday, 10 a.m."
And by the way, you all out there in the podcast
world should do that if you're in the Boston
area, she's great. Shout-out to Emily. But it's
things like that. It's just finding these small
ways to, because people are already laughing,
people are already smiling, we're doing this silly
thing, everyone's in a good mood, and I'm like,
"Boom, perfect time to give someone a shout-out,
and make them feel like a million bucks for doing
something, that in many cases, they might
think, 'Oh, am I allowed to have this other
job outside work? Is this okay?'" And so yeah,
you got to proactively build those reward loops.
I love the reward loop of Emily getting
this shout-out right now. This is so meta.
Ultimate reward.
You have a full class coming up in Boston.
Is there anything else along those lines?
Because that was really interesting?
And also, people, I know managers
already kind of do this, just promoting.
But so, I think the core lesson here is,
focus on things you want to encourage more. Less
so, "Hey, they worked the weekend, they got it
done, so awesome. Thank you for doing that."
You're saying that's almost an anti-pattern,
because you don't necessarily want that
as a habit. So it's more like, shift your
reward announcements to things you actually,
intentionally want to create, in a new team.
Yeah, and just be really,
really thoughtful about it.
Yeah, okay. So let's come back to the taking
care of yourself, because that's something
else that came up, almost everyone mentioned
this. So you're doing a good job with this,
of finding time to take care of yourself,
and modeling that for other people.
Specifically, a lot of people commented on how
you create space for creativity. And I think,
to a lot of people, a lot of PMs, especially, is
just, "I have no time for anything. I just have
meetings, back to back, all day. I barely
have time to go to the bathroom or eat."
And I'm curious to hear just how you do
this. How do you create space in your
day for creative work, and deep work,
and thinking outside of the meeting?
Yeah, it's funny. I'm glad to hear
people think I'm good at this,
because I'm terrible at organizing events.
My team's always, "Oh, we should do a fun
event." I'm like, "Yeah, that's a great idea."
And then I don't organize it. So I like to think,
I do this in other ways. And I do think one
of them is just in modeling, how to carve out
space for things, and a couple of things. I think
there's the creativity, which for me is probably
more outside of work. For me, it's creativity.
But again, it's a big part of me as a manager,
what I think I can help people with is,
back to the point of behavioral activation,
understanding what the things are that a person
needs to be happy, to be their best self,
to be a high functioning person. That depends
on their values, it depends on a lot of things
about them. So for Emily, it's fitness, it's
teaching, it's these things. For me, it's having
my crafts that I do, my illustration, my writing,
my reading, all of these sorts of things.
I think that that's the first step is just, as a
leader, understanding what those are for people
on your team. And then, as I said, modeling it.
I try to always tell people, "Here's how I'm doing
these things." I talk about them, so it's really
normalized, because I think a lot of PMs are like,
"Oh my gosh, I'm so busy. I have no time.
I'm in meetings all day." But that's a
little bit self-inflicted, I think.
At some point, you have to be the one
responsible for getting yourself out of the weeds,
and it's hard to do, but it is doable. So I think,
just showing people that it's possible, showing
people that you can do these things. And I talk
about them, I bring them to lessons.
I have a book club that I sometimes
require at work, and then I say, "Maybe I don't
need to require this anymore," but ways to just
make it really visible, make sure people know
that I'm doing it, and then ask them about it.
If I, in my one on one lens, and I'm
checking in with people, I'm asking them,
"What do you do for joy? Are you doing something
every single day that's bringing you joy in your
life?" And if they say no, I'm like, "That's
a problem. What are we going to do about that?
And do you even know what those things are?"
Because I think a lot of people don't, and a
lot of people, it's great. They're like, "Oh, I
need to be getting X number of hours of exercise,
X hours of sleep. I know I need to eat lunch
right at 12:00, or else I turn into a pumpkin."
If it's somebody who knows what all those things
are, and you're just there to kind of help them
carve out time, that's one thing. But I think, and
a lot of times, people don't even know. Then you
kind of behavioral activation them, where you're
like, "All right, well, why don't you try some
things, and get back to me, and let me know what
seemed to work, what seemed to make a difference?"
But I do think so much of it is like
a permission structure, because people
feel the pressure to be like, "Oh, I'm so
busy, I'm so busy, I'm in meetings all day.
I can't decline these meetings. I can't not
do these things." So in many ways, I think
just modeling, it gives them the permission
structure to start to take back their life.
I could see why people love working for
you. Being asked in your one on one,
"Have you done anything today that brings you
joy? And if you haven't, that's a problem." Wow.
It's important. It's what life's all out. Why are
we here, if it's just to toil, and be miserable?
And also, they will be better people at work,
and they'll do better work. I think that's,
tell me, correct me if I'm wrong, but
it feels like that's an element of this.
Well, and it is so funny, because so much of
this stuff, it's obvious when you apply it to
an athletic context. And obviously,
I talked about the recovery score.
This concept of athletes need to recover is very
obvious. No one, I think, would argue with that.
If you're just pushing yourself at 100% of your
physical capacity all the time, not only are you
going to burn out, but you're literally going to
suffer performance decline. And in the same way,
I think in the athletic world, there's so much
more, just acceptance of, I don't even want to
say limits, but just like, you have to take the
time to do the things you need to be your best.
And that's not just running into the wall all day.
And I think we forget that at work, but I think
the analog is 100% there. I also think about this
with, in terms of being able to have creative
breakthroughs of any kind, it's just so important
to have active rest. It's so important to have
heads downtime. This stuff is all very well
documented. We know it all, but we just come up
with excuses to not give it to ourselves. I think
it's kind of self-sabotage, at a certain point.
I definitely come up with excuses not to do that,
and work all the time. So I
could use this advice myself.
And that's why, here's the thing, here's the
thing. The Reason I'm so regimented about this
is because, if I'm not, I will fall apart. There's
this quote, I can't remember where I saw this,
but I love it. It's like, "I have
exercised the demons from my head,
but they are outside and they are doing pushups."
The threat of the demons coming back is always
there. And so, I take this stuff really seriously,
because I know, if I let myself start to slide
into, I'm not doing the things I need to do to
take care of myself, I'm going to have a bad time.
The walls are going to start closing in around me.
And I'm not shy about that. To me, there's no
point in torturing myself, and just working so
hard, and having no room for joy, and having no
room for creativity. Even just from a practical
standpoint, I'm just not going to succeed.
This comes back to your point about, I
think it was called behavioral activation,
doing the thing. Instead of waiting
for you to feel a certain feeling,
do the thing that will make you feel that way.
Yeah.
Okay. As maybe a final area, but I
have a few more questions after this,
so maybe not. The final area is AI. I am happy
that we waited this long to get deep into AI.
We're not going to spend a lot of time here.
You wrote a whole guest post about this. You
did How I AI to talk through some of this stuff.
But when we were talking earlier, you said that
you think people still are completely undervaluing
the power AI could have on their ability to learn,
and improve themselves. And I know you spent a lot
of time on this, with all these GPTs you've built.
Just talk about the sense of how much
you think people still under-appreciate
how much power there is in AI,
and helping them become better.
Yeah. I think we are not being nearly
creative enough, when it comes to how
to think about learning with AI. And I think,
you hear people worry about entry level jobs,
and when you think about an entry level
job, it is sort of inefficient by design,
because you have taken analyst,
sort of a classic entry level role.
They're doing grunt work, they're doing really
tedious work, but they're getting a lot of reps
in, because that's exactly how you learn the
judgment to do higher level jobs well. And
I hear this in creative fields too. I hear
this from every, I certainly feel this way.
The work that I did in the beginning of my career,
it didn't feel like it was all that important,
in terms of the impact it was having, but it did
feel like it was transformative, in terms of my
own judgment and my own taste, and how I think
about just making very quick judgment calls.
Now, I just wouldn't have been able to do that,
if I didn't spend years learning. I used to do
social media, the skill of having to condense
something that I want to say into 120 characters,
or whatever it used to be on old
Twitter, 240, I can't remember.
I forget, actually, isn't
that crazy? I forget what
the original was. I think it was
140. Okay, 140 characters, yeah.
140, I think. It was short. And if you had
to get a link in there, good luck to you.
But oh my gosh, my ability to just look at
something written today, and just cut it,
that text in half, third, whatever it needs to
fill the space, I can do that in my sleep, because
I got all these reps very early in my career.
I think people see the way that there's a threat
of companies not wanting to hire as much
entry-level talent, because it's like, "Oh,
this is the kind of work that AI can do."
The fear that I hear, at least, is
if you're not getting those reps early in
your career, maybe it's not contributing
so much value to the company at that moment,
but it's how you learn to be great later on.
And so, there's a fear that in five, 10 years,
we're just not going to have that class of people,
who have learned to do the jobs well,
and who have built judgment in that way.
But what I think that misses is, it assumes that
you go and you do this analyst job for two years,
and at the end of it you have a person
who knows how to make models really well,
knows how to do a few things really well. But
why does that have to take two years? Why does
that model of you grind over this thing?
You wait for feedback. Eventually, you get
that feedback. Maybe that feedback's good, maybe
it's not. You go back, you try again. It actually
is really inefficient, when you think about it.
And the sort of learning applicAttions around AI
that I get really excited about are, how do you
shrink that loop? So in my podcast with Claire,
I showed her how I build these GPTs, that kind
of think like me. And the purpose of that is so
that my team can get feedback that is at least 80%
close to the feedback that I would be giving them.
But instead of having to wait until I get
to their message, or until our one on one,
they can get that on demand as many times as they
want forever. And I think there's a lot of things
like this, of ways that things that require
other people, just naturally slow things down,
require getting feedback from other
people, just naturally slow things down.
We can build AI tools that, in my view,
there's no reason why the amount of reps
that you get at whatever task you're doing,
you can be a film editor, just sitting there,
poring over the film, deciding what to edit,
what to cut, what to put into the trailer,
or whatever it's making. That's an
incredibly tedious job that takes forever.
And I think there's no reason we can't make that
way more efficient with AI, that make the learning
more fun. And so, I think that that's sort of my
hot take is yes, there is this threat of, a lot
of these jobs that are things that seem like you
can just automate them away, that might happen.
But we absolutely still need to be investing
in people's skills. I just don't think we need
to be investing in them historically in the way
that we always have. And I think in the future,
we'll find that those ways actually seem quite
inefficient, compared to what's possible today.
That's such a powerful point. And we're already
seeing this. I imagine you've seen these studies,
I think it's in Nigeria, where they give students
AI tutors, and they just zoom to the next,
they accelerate so quickly in their
progression of just reading and math.
I think we're already seeing it. And it's
harder to measure in PM and product, and all
these things, but in school, it's a lot easier to
measure, and we're already seeing results there.
Yeah, 100%.
And to make this very real for
people, you have this specific GPT,
I think it's called Socrates, or what is called?
Oh, Aristotle, yeah.
Aristotle? Okay. No, we're going
to edit that out. Aristotle,
where it gives you scenarios
in a product scenario.
Yeah.
Give an example, just to give
people a sense of what this can do.
Yeah, so this came from, I was talking earlier
about learning how to make a really strong,
logical argument, or just a strong
argument for your point of view,
in general. And the sort of fundamental skill
for that, in my view, is logical thinking,
logical reasoning. And when I think about the
best way, we have to test that today, at least ...
Think about the best way we have to test that
today, at least the best is maybe not the right
word, but the standard way we have to test that,
the LSAT, the test that you take to get into law
school, that is what that tests. And it sort
of gives you these different scenarios and
we'll try to say if a is true, then which of the
following is true, is not true? Sort of testing
some of these different logical relationships.
And so what I did was I made a GPT that I
basically told it, "Create LSAT style questions
to test logical reasoning, but put them in the
scenarios of things that a PM would encounter."
And I have a version of this that's very specific
to WHOOP and working in consumer health,
but you could do it for anything or you
can just do generic, however you want to do it.
And actually it's kind of fun because it gives
you the scenario and it's like, "The sales team
is telling you that we need to invest in feature
A and the, I don't know, the engineering team
is telling you that we only have time to do
feature B and the metrics are telling you that
people who get this feature retain better." It
just sort of gives you these little things
and it's like, follow that logic, which is
the logically best path from this? And it gives
you a little multiple choice answer, you select
one and it explains why you're right or wrong.
And so I think that's just another example of,
you can't create those hyper personalized
learnings, where I can make one that is
literally so specific to you and your life,
but is testing and training you on this broader
skill set. And I think you can make things more
fun that way, even in just the school context,
in terms of doing that in a way that's just
relevant to a person's interest, relevant to
the things they care about. I think there's a
ton of really interesting potential there too.
So we're going to link to this
GPT that you're talking about
that people can try it out. And once
you see it you're like, "Holy shit,
I should just be doing this all the time," because
you just get so many reps as a product builder.
And we were talking about a similar one with
understanding engineering benchmarks. I don't have
an engineering background, so this was really
hard for me when I was moving into product,
is just getting an instinct for what types
of things tend to be easier or harder for
engineering teams. And so we can have one similar
that's saying, " Here's the scope that's being
proposed. If you had to t-shirt size this, which
one would you choose and why?" And you can say,
"Oh, this sounds, small or whatever." And it'll
say, "Oh actually these types of integrations
tend to be complex for these reasons. So it's
probably going to end up being more like a large."
And it doesn't have enough context to really
inform you in the way that your tech stack at
your company is. Although I guess could build it
and give it that information and then it would,
that would be cool. You should do that. But again,
it's like you do that as a PM, you might get a
chance to do that, I don't know, a couple times a
week, maybe, maybe less often than that. And when
you have this little tool, you can do it infinity
times. You can spend an afternoon doing it. And
so again, both the speed of those loops and the
number of those loops that you're able to get
is just radically different with AI compared to
just when they come up in the course of your job.
I think this is extremely cool. We're going
to link to it. People should definitely play
with this. Okay, I'm going to take us
to two corners, recurring segments,
of the podcast and then I want to
talk about WHOOP before we get to
a very exciting lightning round. So this is
a new segment I'm trying out, I'm going to
call it Pivotal Corner. And here's the question,
what's the most pivotal moment in your career?
I mean I think it was at my former company, at
Big Health, when my former boss left the company
and I started reporting to the CEO. And again, I
think it was my first time working with a CEO so
closely, and it just, definitely trial by fire.
But it made me understand so many things that
seemed like they didn't make sense to me before,
when I was just in the rank and file of a big tech
company earlier in my career. You get in the room
and you talk to these people and you're like, "Oh,
this actually makes sense. I understand why
this person has come to these conclusions."
And some of it's understanding the pressure
they're under. Some of it's understanding,
again, the way they view the world. But
I think that was, to get to our earlier
point around the humility of understanding that
maybe this person is right about something that
I don't see and maybe I can start by... If I
start by giving them the benefit of the doubt,
it is not only a nice thing to do, but
it is also, it will help me understand
why they're doing the things that they
are. And I think I would've been so much
less frustrated earlier in my career if I
understood that instead of just being like,
"Oh, this doesn't make any sense from where I'm
sitting, so therefore it must not make any sense."
It's so cool that this connects
back to your habit of doing this,
having seen it, and being like,
"Oh, I see, this is why..."
Yeah, I guess I hadn't realized.
Maybe I'm wrong, maybe I could be wrong.
Well, I mean that's what it is. I feel like I've
had so many of those times where I don't know,
when I was growing up, I felt so confident
in how I felt about everything. And then you
get out there and you're just like, "Oh,
I was missing some things." And after a
while you're kind of like, "Okay, maybe I
should approach these situations a little
differently with the possibility
that maybe I'm missing something."
So I actually asked your boss Kelvin, which
is an awesome name by the way, Kelvin,
about this moment. When I asked him what to
ask you, and he brought this up actually,
and here's the way, described it, "She may
describe it as being thrown into the deep
end or baptism by fire, but the reality is that
she had the core skills and this was simply an
opportunity for her to let those shine even more.
She was an incredible first principles thinker,
quick to tune the framing of problems
as she learned more context. It's a
great example of luck is what happens
when preparation meets opportunity."
Thanks Kelvin. That's really nice.
He also said, "I wonder if she
remembers how terrified she was now,
because she absolutely knocked
it out of the park and it felt
like it was an inflection point that
grew her confidence significantly."
Oh, I was terrified. Yeah. Big time terrified. And
then, I mean this is also what I was saying about
why it's so important to be regimented about
having these things outside of work that allow
you to continue to thrive, even in the
face of just utter feelings of failure,
of, "I am not doing a good job, this is not
going well. I don't know what I'm doing."
A lot of it was that time. Kelvin actually gave
me some great advice that, this is maybe kind
of scary advice, but when I asked him what his
advice for me with the time was, and he said,
"Product leadership is the type of role where
if you are not in control of the voices in
your head, they will eat you alive."
And I think it's right. As I said,
it is so often this feeling like there is not
a clear right answer and not even necessarily
a good answer. And everyone is looking to you for
clarity and everyone is looking to you to make the
right decisions and everyone sees the errors, or
at least everyone can spot the flaws in whatever
decision you make or whatever recommendation you
make. And as I said, every path forward has flaws
that can be poked in it. And so understanding
that the existence of potential ways to be
criticized about something does not warrant
criticism in a way that can, I think often
result in a lot of negative self-talk for people.
So yeah, I mean it had a tremendous impact on me.
It's interesting you have so much of these
habits and skills you've built seem to,
it's clear where they come from, from
all these experiences that you had.
Well, and to the point of when you start
talking to people and you start trying to
build this mental model of how they think,
that's exactly what you learn, is well,
I can see how this person worked at this company
at this time and I can see how this person had
this kind of relationship with this other
person. And all of these things shape the
way that we approach problems and the way that
we try to just move through the world. And it
is understanding those types of things that
allow you to understand how a person thinks.
I wonder if you could ask ChatGPT to build,
or Claude to build, these mental models. Like,
"Here's their LinkedIn, here's their bio,
here's a few things, how do they see the world?"
I will admit that I have tried this. And I think
it's a great idea. I think it does help. I have
not gotten to a point where I'm comfortable
sharing it with other people, nor have I told
anyone that I have tried to do this for them, but
I've certainly done it for myself. And I think it
would be helpful. Because you could say things,
you could upload a doc or whatever and be like,
"What are the three questions that this
person's going to ask me about it?" And
then you could be prepared for the questions
that person's going to ask you and that's great.
In this hypothetical example, what context do
you share with this model to help it be good?
Great question. Hypothetically, I told
you that I take all these notes on,
here's what this person said and here's how
I interpret it, and LLMs are really good at
pattern matching and sort of spotting the...
You could feed all of those in and just say,
"Come up with the 10 criteria that
this person is most likely to use to
assess a possible recommendation or path forward,"
or, "Give me the top 10 ways that this person is
likely to pick apart an argument or object to
something," and you're going to get a good answer.
More reason to build this habit of taking notes
and sharing with your team. On the other hand,
this might also be a good use case
for Granola or something like that
where you have all these meeting
notes and you could just feed it,
"Here's all the things Hilary said," and, "Oh,
what is she probably going to say about this?"
Totally.
Wow, so cool. Okay, next corner, I'm going to
take us to Fail Corner. And in Fail Corner,
the idea here is people come on this podcast,
they share all these wins and success,
everything's up and to the right and amazing,
but in reality things don't always go that
smoothly. So the question is, is there a story
you could share of failure in your career where
things didn't go the way you hoped and
what you learned from that experience?
I mean I think the one that probably looms
largest in my mind is, I mentioned this
depression therapeutic that I spent about a year
working on, and ultimately the company ended up
acquiring a different depression therapeutic. And
we kind of ended up merging the two of them. And
a lot of the stuff that we had initially built
that I had really loved about this product we
were working on didn't really ever end up seeing
the light of day beyond the kind of testing that
we had done around it. And it was heartbreaking
because I wish this product existed. I look at
it and I'm like, "This was a great product
and we put so much heart and soul into it."
And I think the lesson that
I learned from that is,
I think there's always a shot clock. When you're
working, especially on a zero to one product,
I think it can be very easy to feel like
you have the luxury of time, of just like,
we got to take the time to figure this out and
get it right and that's what's most important. But
the sort of build versus buy question is always
live and it's always fair. And whether you want
to admit it, if you're the one working on it, and
you probably don't, I didn't want to admit this,
there is a point at which it makes more sense for
the company. If it is taking too long to develop
something and there is a solution out there that
works, it is the right decision to acquire that.
I mean I worked at Dropbox where I saw this
happen all the time where we would acquire
products that other teams internally
had been working on and it's just like,
it's heartbreaking when it happens. But I think
there's an urgency that that has instilled in me
that I think is actually really good and healthy,
especially again working in this era where there
is kind of this AI arms race and everyone's trying
to move really quickly of, yeah, there's always
a shot clock. And you might not be aware of it,
but it's there, and you got to build your heart
out and you got to ship and you got to get things
out because at any time, that clock might run out.
Speaking of shot clock, not necessarily,
but I want to spend a little time on WHOOP,
you guys just launched something that feels
like a really big deal. I'm excited. That's
the reason I got it. There's all these really
cool new features. I think you call it WHOOP 5.0.
What should people know? What's the newest,
coolest thing that's happening with WHOOP?
Yeah, I'm really excited you got it.
I know you tried it before and...
That's right. That's right.
People who have tried WHOOP in the past maybe felt
like it was very focused on
elite athletes and that is...
Yeah, that's exactly what I felt.
Sort of the lifeblood of the company. And I
think what we've done with our new experience is
we've really built something that can help
everyone be healthier and live better. I would
say we're no longer just for elite athletes. We're
really now a health and performance companion
for anybody who wants to feel their best.
For the first time in our company's history,
we've updated our mission, so we're now saying
that WHOOP exists to unlock human performance
and health span. And health span I think is,
and I mentioned earlier this feature I'm really
excited about, because I do think it is kind of
the most powerful version of a longevity-type
feature I have seen because it is so focused
on your behaviors and your habits today.
And we built it to be super, super actionable. So
rather than just giving you a score that you're
kind of like, "Okay, that's nice," if you start
sleeping even 20 minutes more, 30 minutes more
tonight, you're going to see how that changes
your case of aging. You're going to see how
that changes your WHOOP age. And I think that, as
I mentioned earlier, I think is really rewarding.
We also have a lot of personalized coaching
through our AI in terms of actions that you
can take to improve your WHOOP age,
to improve your sleep, to feel better,
and it's all part of our broader aim to make
health more actionable and accessible. I think
one thing I'm really excited about is we have
a bunch of new women's health features, so we
have hormonal insights with improved menstrual
cycle tracking. I'm actually pregnant and I-
What? I didn't know that.
That's a big announcement.
Wow. Congratulations Hilary. That's so exciting.
But actually part of how I found out I
was pregnant was in seeing my WHOOP data.
What? What? That's insane.
In my WHOOP data, which is pretty remarkable.
Wow.
And the way that we have this cycle tracking
now, you can see the way that your different,
your HRV, your resting heart rate, things
like that, that's your heart rate variability
and your resting heart rate, fluctuates
throughout different times of your cycle.
And even in the time leading up to that, I
had a not straightforward pregnancy journey,
and having these tools to really understand
what was going on in my body was tremendously
helpful and tremendously empowering for
me and honestly really has changed my
life. So I'm really excited about that.
We have a lot of great new heart health
features. We have a heart health screener with
blood pressure insights and ECG. That's really
cool. We got a lot of great stuff cooking.
So even if you tried WHOOP in the past and
thought it wasn't for you, I think the
new experience is a real upgrade and it's
something that I'm deeply proud of having worked
on and really excited to have out in the world.
I am genuinely very excited about this. You
could do, you said blood pressure and VO2 max?
Mm-hmm.
And I know the battery is even longer
too. There's just so much stuff.
Oh, we have a 14 day battery life. I didn't
even say. We have these beautiful
new leather bands which I love.
Oh wow.
Okay. 14 day battery's life is
insane. I'm going on vacation
tomorrow and I don't even need to
bring a charger. This is fantastic.
Oh man. This sounds like a WHOOP
ad, but I'm very excited about this.
I'll say one more thing, which is we've opened
a wait list for Advanced Labs and so pretty soon
you're going to be able to have comprehensive
lab work in the app, and I think we talk about
the future of health, of having control
of all of your health data in one place,
and then being able to not just sort of find
the signal in it and understand how your sleep
is impacting your metabolic health or things like
that. But again, get really actionable coaching
on actions that you can take to feel better and
be your healthiest and just pushing the limits of
all the data that we're pulling into the WHOOP
ecosystem. So really excited about that too.
I'm hoping the WHOOP can actually
take my blood and labs. Is that where
this is going? Because that'd be so convenient.
No comment.
Okay. It'd be weird but also awesome. I
don't have to go anywhere to do that. Hilary,
we covered so much ground. Before we
get to a very exciting lightning round,
is there anything else that you wanted to
touch on? Anything else that we haven't
covered that you think, or last nugget
you wanted to leave listeners with?
I don't think so. I feel
like we covered everything
We did. We covered so much. In
the best way possible. With that,
we've reached our very exciting
lightning round. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
What are two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
Buddy, you can't call something
a lightning round and then ask
me about books. We could go for a
whole other podcast where I'm like...
Let's recreate a time box for it.
Yeah, exactly.
Lightning round.
Okay, I'm going to, hearing what I'm going to
say, I'm going to go full fiction on this. I'm
going to say if you're going to read a book, don't
bother reading a business book. Even the business
books I love the most that shaped how I think
I'm like, "I kind of got the gist of them part
way through," but fiction, I'm like, everybody
should read East of Eden by John Steinbeck and
everybody should read The Sun Also Rises by
Ernest Hemingway, which is my comfort book.
I think what I love about fiction is it teaches
you how to sit inside tension. I think so much of
working in product is, as I said, you're in this
fog and you just have to provide clarity and you
have to be really good at providing structure to
ambiguous things and finding the way forward and
to succeed at the job, you have to be able to do
that. But I also think to succeed as a human in
the job, you have to be able to sit in the mess
and sit in the ambiguity. John Keats, the poet,
talks about this concept of negative capability,
which is the ability to remain in uncertainties,
mysteries, doubts without any irritable
reaching after fact and reason. And I love that.
That sounds like a perfect quote for all PMs to...
Exactly. And you got to be both, right. Again,
fiction, I love dualities. There's a lot of
dualities in fiction, a lot of warring forces
within people that can be so driving for people
but can also be the source of so much anguish.
I think it is important to live in both. In the,
"I'm going to break down this problem, I'm
going to structure it, I'm going to get out,
but also I'm going to sit here and I'm going
to accept that there is no right answer and
there is no perfect answer." And that's life. You
don't learn that from... To the extent that you
learn that from a book at all, which maybe you
don't, but I think you can learn it in fiction.
I don't know how you feel about this book. I
think you'll be proud of me. I'm
reading Anna Karenina right now.
Oh, literally that's the book that I'm
bringing on vacation with me tomorrow.
Wow. You've never read it?
I've never read it.
Cool. Me neither. Okay, we'll exchange some notes.
It's very long I'm realizing. Because I'm
reading on the Kindle, and only 12%. Okay.
Now I really have to read it. I was kind of
wavering. I was like, "Is this really what I'm
going to want to read when I'm sitting
by the pool?" But no, I've committed.
You got to do it. Another guest recommended it
and I saw it on some lists recently and then like,
"Oh, I should read that." So yeah.
Okay, great. Next question. Do you
have a favorite recent movie or TV
show that you've really enjoyed?
I've been watching The Rehearsal with
Nathan Fielder. Have you seen this show?
I saw the first season. I've been a huge fan
of Nathan Fielder for so long. I don't know
if you saw his previous thing that
he did, I forget what it's called.
Oh yeah.
Okay. He's so hilarious and such a genius.
Nathan for You.
Nathan for You? Oh my God. I
haven't seen the new season, no.
The man is a freaking genius. Just when I thought
that I had a good sense of all the
human emotions that exist out there,
I watch the show and I feel things that
I'm like, I feel like 10 different things.
Duality.
And I'm like, "I have no words
for any of the things that I'm
feeling right now." It's weird. It's
weird stuff, but I'm enjoying it.
I got to watch it. Do you have a favorite product
you've recently discovered that you
really enjoyed? Other than the WHOOP.
I love my Zwift. It's like a program
that you can hook up a smart trainer
to for an indoor cycling situation. And
you kind of bike around like you're in
Mario Kart and you're sort of in these
virtual worlds biking with other people.
It's I think for very serious cyclists,
I'm not a very serious cyclist. For me,
it's been amazing as somebody who actually
really struggles to find time to exercise.
They have, speak of reward loops, they
have one of the most amazing reward loops,
which is you're biking along and you get into
this track and a ghost of your previous self
breaks out from you and starts racing alongside
you at your personal best for that track. And
you have to beat your personal self, or
you have to beat this ghost version of
yourself. And nothing has ever motivated me
more in my life than past Hilary being like,
"I'm coming for you." And I'm like... I don't
get that competitive with other people, but past
Hilary comes for me and I'm like, "This, I can't
let happen." So I think it's a great product.
I'm thinking about how to use that, I
don't know, mode for other use cases,
like the ghost version of something to
motivate you essentially. Interesting.
I've been in so many product
meetings where I'm like,
"Can we make a ghost version of
yourself?" [inaudible 01:49:21]
Yeah. They're like, "Shut up about the ghost."
Okay, amazing. Okay, two more questions. Do
you have a life motto that you often come
back to, find useful in work or in life?
I'll say one that's been top of mind for
me recently, because I was talking about
the high brow fiction. I also have to go low
brow. I saw this clip of Beavis and Butthead
online recently where they were watching a
music video for Creep by Radiohead. And it
starts off really slow and one of them,
I think maybe Butthead, is like, "Oh,
this sucks." And then the chorus comes and it
starts getting all hyped and they're like, "Oh,
this rocks, this rocks." And then, I'm not going
to do my Beavis and Butthead impression. So then
it gets back to the slow part and they're
like, "Oh wait, this sucks again." And then
Butthead is like, "Why don't they just play the
cool part the entire time?" And Beavis is like,
"Because if they didn't have the part of the song
that sucked, the cool part wouldn't be as cool."
And I was like, "That is so profound." That
is what life is all about, is just if it
didn't have the parts that sucked, the cool parts
wouldn't be as cool. And we're always chasing the
cool parts. We want it all to be the cool parts,
but it can't. So thank you Beavis and Butthead.
Thank you Beavis and Butthead. Okay, final
question. I love that you're talking about
fiction books. This is where my question was
going to go. What's a fiction book that most
impacted your product building approach or
career or the way you think about product?
Can I give a poem?
Absolutely. Even better. Poem, extra credit.
There's a poem by Derek Walcott about, it's
called Sea Grapes, and it's about Odysseus,
and he talks about Odysseus being driven
by the ancient war between obsession and
responsibility. And I read that line when I was
18 years old and it has always stuck with me.
And I sort of mentioned earlier, I think
about these dualities that drive us. And
I think as a product person, I always feel like
I'm living between these two, the obsession and
the responsibility. I want to go so deep on
this and I want to spend as much time as I
possibly can just sorting every little piece out.
But we live in a society, we exist in a business.
I am trying to create value for shareholders and
trying to bring these two things together, I feel
like a, has been the kind of defining struggle
of my career, I think of many people's careers,
is how you have something that you feel like you
can really obsess over and have that flow over,
or have that flow when you're working on. But
then it's got to kind of work in this broader
system as well. And I think that's sort of been
the thing that I think of as the guiding post
for what I want to do with my career and with my
life. So I think it's got to be Derek Walcott.
What a beautiful way to end it. Hilary,
two final questions. Where can folks find
you online if they want to reach out,
maybe follow up on stuff that you talked
about? And how can listeners be useful to you?
Great, thank you. So as I mentioned, I have
a newsletter, it's hils.substack.com. That's
hils.substack.com. I'm also teaching
a Maven class on being a super manager
with AI. So if you were listening to all this and
you were like, "Oh Hilary, that sounds so great,
but I don't have time for any of that. How
do you have time for all that?" Honestly,
hyper-leveraging myself with AI has been a big
part of how I find time to do any of this stuff.
And so I share a bunch about how I do that,
how I use AI as a manager, building on a lot
of the stuff that I shared on Claire's podcast
as well, How I AI. So you can find me on Maven
there. We've got a couple of cohorts coming up.
And then, yeah, I encourage everyone to try out
WHOOP, you can get a free month
on me at join.whoop.com/hilary,
that's Hilary with one L. And you can post at
me or tweet at me on X and let me know what
you think of it. And I would love everyone's
feedback because we're really excited about it.
As you were talking, I looked up your course
just for make sure people can find it. So
you go to maven.com, you just search
for Hilary Gridley and you'll find it.
Yep. And you can also, I realize that if
you Google super manager, you will find me.
Whoa.
So that is my new claim to fame.
Oh my God, that's so great. 4.9 stars.
Holy moly. There we go. Okay, Hilary,
thank you so much. This was incredible.
Covered everything I was hoping to,
this was everything I wanted it to
be. Thank you so much for being here.
Thank you. Thank you for
having me. This was so fun.
So fun. Bye everyone.
Thank you so much for
listening. If you found this valuable, you
can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps other
listeners find the podcast. You can find all
past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.