You are a product manager shipping product
without knowing how to write code,
barely knowing how to review code.
I have zero technical background, did
music in high school ... when Sonnet
3.5 came out. I remember watching a YouTube
video building apps using Bolt or Lovable.
It basically felt like someone came up to
me and said, "You have superpowers now."
These days, you're using Cursor with Claude Code.
If you're non-technical like me, code
is terrifying, but AI just makes it so
much possible. In the next coming years, I
think everyone's going to become a builder.
Titles are going to collapse and
responsibilities are going to collapse.
The main challenge people have is
reviewing the code that AI has written.
It's very difficult for me to catch
mistakes. What I'll do is basically
/review. This tells Claude to start reviewing
its own code, but what's even cooler is I have
Codex as well as Cursor open. I will
have each of them review the code.
This comes back to this quote. I think
everyone's always hearing. It's not that
you will be replaced by AI. You'll be replaced
by someone who's better at using AI than you.
It's the best time to be a junior, contrary
to what a lot of people are saying,
how there's no more junior roles
out there. Yeah, that's true,
but also when else in history could you get out
of school and just build a startup on your own?
Today, my guest is Zevi Arnovitz. Zevi is a
PM at Meta. Prior to that, he was a PM at Wix,
and this is a truly remarkable conversation that
every non-technical product person needs to hear.
Zevi is super young and has no technical
background, but as a smart, young,
ambitious person, has learned how to use
Cursor and Claude Code to build significant
and real products completely on his own, and he's
created his own very clever and effective workflow
that everyone listening can copy.
To make that copying even easier,
at the top of the show notes of this episode, you
can download all of the prompts and /commands and
start doing all of this yourself. Zevi shows you
how to work with cursor to quickly add your ideas
to Linear to explore your idea with AI, how to
develop your plan, how to then build the thing,
and then have different LLMs review
your code and update your documentation,
and then use all of this as a learning opportunity
to develop your own sense of how things work.
I haven't stopped thinking about
this conversation since we had it,
and everyone needs to pay attention to what
AI is unlocking for non-technical people.
A huge thank you to Tal Raviv for encouraging
me to meet Zevi. If you enjoy this podcast,
don't forget to subscribe and follow it in
your favorite podcasting app or YouTube.
It helps tremendously. And if you become
an annual subscriber of my newsletter,
you get 19 premium products for free for
an entire year including Lovable, Replit,
Bolt, Gamma, n8n, Linear, Devin, PostHog,
Superhuman, Descript, Wispr Flow, Perplexity,
Warp, Granola, Magic Patterns, Raycast,
ChatPRD, Mobbin, and Stripe Atlas. Head
on over to lennysnewsletter.com and click
product pass. With that, I bring you Zevi
Arnovitz after a short word from our sponsors.
This episode is brought to you by 10Web,
the company that pioneered AI website building
before ChatGPT. In the last three years, over two
million websites have been generated with 10Web's
vibe coding platform. 10Web's vibe coding platform
is a powerful way to build websites. Think of it
as lovable for WordPress, front end and backend.
Users can build any website at any complexity,
e-commerce, portfolios, information websites,
blogs, and it comes with the WordPress admin
panel and thousands of ready to use plugins.
10Web also offers website generation as an API
as a service for SaaS companies, marketplaces,
hosting providers, MSPs and agencies. SaaS
companies can embed it via API so that users
can launch AI generated sites directly inside
of their platform, connected to their own data.
Agencies and MSPs can get a white label
dashboard to manage clients and resell under
their brand. Hosting providers can self-host
the API builder on their own infrastructure.
Check it out at 10web.io/lenny and use code
Lenny for exclusive free credits and 30% off
API or white labeled solutions. That's the number
10web.io/lenny, vibe coding platform as an API.
Today's episode is brought to you by DX, the
developer intelligence platform designed by
leading researchers. To thrive in the AI era,
organizations need to adapt quickly, but many
organization leaders struggle to answer pressing
questions like, which tools are working? How are
they being used? What's actually driving value?
DX provides the data and insights that leaders
need to navigate this shift. With DX, companies
like Dropbox, Booking.com, Adyen, and Intercom
get a deep understanding of how AI is providing
value to their developers and what impact AI is
having on engineering productivity. To learn
more, visit DX's website at getdx.com/lenny,
that's getdx.com/lenny. Zevi, thank you so
much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
Thanks for having me, Lenny.
I'm a huge fan of the show and
tons of people that I've admired most and
learned the most from. I've been on here,
so it's a crazy moment for me.
I'm really excited for this.
I really appreciate that. I want
to start by reading actually a note
I got about you from Tal Raviv,
who is a previous podcast guest,
many times newsletter collaborator. One of
the most AI forward product managers that
I know I've learned a ton from him. So here's
what he said about you when he introduced us.
Zevi is the most hands-on vibe coding PM I know,
and I've personally learned so much from him. His
engineers at Meta ask him to teach them how
to do what he does. Every time we get coffee,
I repeatedly get this feeling of
everyone needs to be hearing this.
That's so nice.
And so that's the goal. That's the goal of this
conversation is to help more people hear what you
figured out. We're going to get very hands-on.
We're going to do a lot of show versus tell,
showing people what you've figured out about how
to be a PM, a non-technical PM building stuff. I
want to give people a little bit of background
on you because I think this is going to inspire
a lot of listeners to feel like they can also
do what we're about to show you. This is going
to look very advanced, but just give people a
little bit of sense of just your background.
I'm very non-technical. I have zero technical
background. Did music in high school. A lot of
Israelis do technology units in the Army. I was
not in a tech unit. And basically a year ago,
I was traveling with my wife for three
months in Asia and we were in Japan and
that was around when Sonnet 3.5 came out.
And I remember watching a YouTube video.
I think it was either Greg Isenberg or Riley
Brown and they were basically building apps using,
it was either Bolt or Lovable, just using AI.
And it was like a crazy moment for me because
I was watching this and it basically felt like
someone came up to me and said, "Hey Zevi, there's
this cool new technology you should check out. You
should really give it a try. Oh, and by the way,
you have superpowers now." And the second I got
home from Japan, I didn't even unpack my bags,
ran to my computer, opened Bolt, opened an
account, and for the past year I've been building.
And the last thing I'll say on that is we talked
about this a bit before we started recording,
but I was prepping with Claude for the episode
and I was trying to clarify what my goal is for
this episode. And Claude said, "If people
walk away thinking how amazing you are,
you failed. And if people walk away and
open their computer and start building,
you've succeeded." So I really hope that
we can inspire some people to do the same.
I love that so much. I feel like that should
be the goal for my podcast. If you're like,
"I love that guest." It's less of a win.
If it's just like, "Oh, I'm so inspired
to do the thing that they figured out, that
is the real win." I love, Claude is the best.
I agree.
Okay. So let's dive in and give people, let's
start with kind of a high level overview of
how you operate and you use AI in your job. What
are the core tools and just what's kind of like
the frame of reference for the workflow
that you figured out and how you operate?
This all started where I was a project's
power user. I love projects, GPT projects.
ChatGPT projects?
Yeah, exactly. GPT projects and Claude projects,
which are basically a shared folder of chats which
share both custom instructions and shared
knowledge base. And I think it was around
when GPT started using memory where I thought
it was interesting, but it really annoyed me
because I do a bunch of different things. I'm
a terrible runner, I'm a PM, I was a student,
psychology student, so I had all these
different facets of life. And what happened was
the memory feature was mixing stuff up.
So like I talked to GPT about running
and it would say, "Oh yeah, after this 5K, you're
going to crush all your next product reviews." And
it's like, okay, I understand that you have that
in your memory, but it's just not relevant. And
projects basically allows you to compartmentalize
and have things within the right context. So
tracking back to the story I told when we came
back from Japan, I started building this app.
The first thing I noticed was that these products
were built in a way where, and when I say these
products, I mean Bolt and Lovable, were built in
a way where they were super eager to write code.
So their system prompt was you're a coding
agent. So when you'd write something, they'd
straight away start coding. So at the beginning
of a project, this was super fun and exciting
because they just go and start building your app.
But later on when things got more complex, this
created much more problems because planning
is really important when you're implementing
something technical and let's say you're
implementing payments or something that's
going to be a change to your database. If
the coding agent is just like, "All right,
I got it." And just starts writing code,
this always results in terrible things,
some really gnarly bugs that I had.
And to mitigate this, what I did was I created
sort of a CTO. So again, I'm not technical. I
have been in product for a while, but I know
zero stuff about code. So basically what I did was
I created a CTO with the custom prompt of it being
the complete technical owner of the project. So I
told it, "I own the problem. I own how we want the
users to feel. You're the complete owner of how
this is going to be built. I want you to challenge
me. I don't want you to be a people pleaser."
All these things that kind of mitigate the
regular ChatGPT-isms. I always think about this
where for some reason, the easiest way for me to
think about AI is to imagine it as people. And
I think ChatGPT would probably be the worst CTO
because it's such a people pleaser and it's so
sycophantic where ... Just a short story I had
a few weeks ago, I was trying to learn about
Bun JavaScript, which was acquired by Anthropic
and I was trying to understand what they do.
So I was talking to GPT and this wasn't within my
co-founder CTO project and I asked it if it's
similar to a different framework that I have
in my app called Zustand, which nothing
to do at all with what Bun JavaScript
does. And basically GPT goes, "Oh yeah, it's
exactly the same." And then it started talking
about what it meant and I was like, "Wait,
no, these are not the same at all." And it
said the most terrifying and hilarious thing.
He goes, "Oh, I'm sorry. I thought you were
just making this up and I was riffing
with you." And I was like, "Oh no, no,
no, this is terrible." So basically if regular
ChatGPT was a CTO, that would be the CTO who goes
along with your dumbest ideas. So creating
the project allowed me to mitigate that.
So this is, just to be super clear, you have
a ChatGPT project that you've given a prompt
to be your CTO of your product
and being a non-technical person,
this is kind of like the thing you talk to
when, and we'll get to what you're actually
using to build when you have questions about
architecture and decisions that are technical.
Yeah. So now I'll show my full workflow
and I don't involve GPT anymore,
but I definitely would recommend, even though the
technology has gone ... So when I started this,
there was no plan mode or ask mode. It was just
build on these products on Lovable and Bolt,
and they've progressed a ton. A lot of what
I had as workflows have become ingrained
in these products, which is really interesting.
I would still recommend start with a project for,
first of all, the reason that I said, and also
it kind of puts you in a place where you're in
a chatbot and not writing code. So you take the
time to converse and to learn, which I think is
critical. And the second thing is if you're
non-technical like me, code is terrifying.
It's the scariest thing in the world to look at,
and I look at it as kind of like exposure therapy.
I think if you see this where I'm working like
in Claude or in Cursor, you might be excited to
start using those, but I would really recommend
starting slow with a GPT project, beautiful UI,
super simple, then maybe graduate to like a Bolt
or a Lovable, and then go to Cursor in light mode,
slowly, slowly, gradually ease
in until you open a terminal,
go full dark mode, go full dev. So I would
really recommend doing this gradually.
That is awesome advice. And so just to be clear,
these days you're using Cursor with Claude Code
powering it. And what I love about that is that
you've never written code. The way you put
it, you're afraid of even looking at code.
Yeah, 100%.
You can do exposure therapy, and I love
that Cursor is useful to you. And what
you're telling us is that graduating
from a ChatGPT project that is kind of
your technical co-founder kind of taught you
enough to feel more comfortable going straight
to cursor. You said that you actually went
to Bolt and Lovable kind of in the interim
and then you went just straight to Cursor. What's
the reason to just go straight to Cursor? Is it
just Cursor can do everything and once you get the
hang of it, it's actually the most powerful tool?
Yeah, I think I graduated from each tool when I
kind of outgrew it. So Bolt was awesome until I
was trying to connect payments to my app
and I kind of started losing it and then
I graduated to Cursor and I've actually fallen
in love with Claude. So I'm using Claude Code,
but that also runs within Cursor, and
I think this is Tal who told me this.
I'm not sure who he's quoting, but code is
just words at the end of the day. So it's
just files on your computer. So basically you
can be working on the same project and carry
it from app to app. And especially now,
I can work with multiple models and apps
on my project. So start slow, but definitely
there's a lot of places you can graduate to.
Awesome. Okay. Should we dive into
screen share showing how you operate?
Awesome. I pulled up cursor. Can you see it?
Mm-hmm.
Perfect. So within my code base, what you can see
here on the left, these are all my code files.
Here on the right is Cursor. So this is
basically like having AI, which has access
to all the code. And here in the middle, I have
Claude Code running. And what you can see here,
I'm going to close cursor for a second.
What you can see here are all my /commands.
Basically what /commands are, they are reusable
prompts that I save within the code base that
I can run by writing / and then the name of
the file. So here you can see Create Issue,
which is the first command that I'm going to
use. And basically what this tells Claude,
it says the user is meant development and
thought of a bug or a feature and improvement,
capture it fast so they can keep working.
And then it basically says, this is the
format that I want you to capture the linear
issue in, and it explains a bunch of things
what exactly Claude needs to do to get there.
So the way I invoke this is basically I'll do
/create issue and this injects this prompt
into Claude. So it says, "I'm ready to help
you to capture this issue, what's on your mind."
So basically when I'll do this is if I'm working
on a big project and I suddenly come across
a bug or have an idea that I don't want to
work on right now, but I want to work on later,
I'll do this really quick and Claude's main goal
is to quickly capture what I'm thinking about.
So quickly to run through my full workflow. So
basically it starts with creating an issue.
So this is the create issue /command, which
basically tells Claude that I'm mid-development
and it should quickly capture what I'm thinking
about and create an issue within linear.
Then later on, when I want to pick this up,
I have the exploration phase. Exploration
phase is basically telling Claude,
we're going to only explore what we want to
solve here. It could either pull from linear
or I can just speak freely to it. And what it
will do is it will analyze and understand the
issue and just ask clarifying questions.
The next phase after we've done finished
exploration phase is we're going to create a plan.
So you can see create plan. This basically has
a template that I love for creating plans, and
the output of this at the end of the day will be
a markdown file with our plan that we can end up
building along with code. After creating the plan,
we have execute plan. After execution, we
have review and then we have peer review,
which is really cool and we'll get into
later on, and at the end, we update the docs.
So this is updating documentation and everything
so that agents can write better code later on. So
I think what we'll do is we're going to build a
feature live for my app, which I think is really
cool. But first what I'd like to do is show
you the app so you have some context. So this
is StudyMate. It's a platform for students, which
allows them to upload study materials and create
interactive tests based on their own materials.
So here we can go to the top. Let's upload a PDF.
We can decide what pages we want to be quizzed
on. We can decide the number of questions,
the difficulty level. And basically what happens
behind the scenes is we send the information the
user uploaded along with the system prompt and
any other augmentations the users decided to
Gemini and we create a quiz. These are challenging
questions that are meant to assess comprehension.
You even have some hints and once we do a few
of these, we can submit ... I got them right?
Terrible results.
Yeah, lucky.
And so just to be really clear about this, this
is like a side business that you have, an app that
you built that's making money. That's like a thing
you vibe coded having no technical experience.
Yeah, this is my weekend
project. Yeah. This is what I do.
Amazing.
On weekends. Yeah. So you get basically
deep explanations into why each
question was wrong or each question was
right. And at the moment, StudyMate only
has multiple choice questions. And I was doing
some competitor research over the last weekend
and I saw competitors who had true or false
questions and also fill in the blank questions,
which I loved. So I think that'd be really cool
if we could build that live. How's that sound?
I love it. Crossing your fingers, this all
work. I just want to highlight the stuff
you shared right before this in cursor. So this
is a huge deal, what you describe here. This is
essentially what you've figured out is a way as
a person that has no idea how to write any code,
how to build a product in Cursor as a product
manager using this series of /commands that
you've concocted that you're going to be sharing
with listeners. They can download all these and
just use them directly. They don't have to figure
out all these prompts that you've figured out.
Yeah, 100%. Basically what happened
was I formulated the backbone of this
with the CTO, and it was basically
within the system prompt of the CTO
project that I had within GPT. So it
said, step one, we do this. Step two,
we do this. And now I'll keep building. And if I
see something that happens over and over again,
I'll just create a /command and then it
will be automated within the workflow.
Amazing. So just to summarize the /command.
So one is create an issue in Linear, which
I love. Linear is awesome. Shout out Linear.
That's also from the product pass.
From the product pass. Oh my God, what a value?
Okay. So step one is create the issue in linear.
So it's a command. So this prompt /command you've
created, just create issue. Then it's explore,
which is explore the idea, help me ideate on
what this could be. And this is Claude helping
you think through the feature and product.
And then it's actually create the plan.
And so it's like the AI helping you build the plan
to build the product. Then it's actually execute,
which is just build the thing.
And then there's this review,
peer review step, which is awesome that
you'll share. And then there's document,
update documentation based on the
new feature that we're adding. Sweet.
Yeah. Cool. So let's go ahead and start
building. So I'm going to use Wispr Flow
to dictate and basically this starts with /create
issue. So this basically sends that prompt. And I
love this because I usually do this during when
I'm building something else. So basically it
tells Claude that I'm mid building something and
I don't have a lot of time to waste time on this.
So just ask some brief questions so that
you have enough to capture within linear.
So I want to add fill in the blank questions to
StudyMate. I want this to be 30% of tests to be
generated as fill in the blank questions.
I want there to be six potential answers
for two blank spots, and of course there's only
going to be two correct answers. So one correct
answer and two incorrect answers for each spot
and I want the interface to be drag and drop.
So that's just basically a quick
think of how I want this to work.
So it's going to ask me a few questions. Quizzes
are 100% multiple choice, question structure,
single sentence passage to blanks and priority.
So one and two are correct, and this is
not high priority. It's a nice to have feature.
So now basically what Claude is going to do is
it's going to use MCP, which is basically
a technology that was created by Anthropic,
which gives AI the ability to use tools. So
this is connected to my linear. So what it's
going to do now is it's going to use everything
we've said and create an issue within Linear.
And by the way, as this is loading, I just
love the way, the way you described this,
especially doing voice mode, it's like exactly
how you would talk to an engineer describing a
feature, "Here's what I want." And then they
ask you questions, here's the clarification.
Yeah. So at first when I was doing this with
the CTO, I would do it with ChatGPT voice mode,
and that was crazy. That literally felt like
ideating with a person. It would push back,
ask questions, and maybe one day the coding tools
will get there too, but that was exactly ... It
really felt like sitting with my CTO. Great. So
created STU88. So if we open up Linear now, we
should be able to see ... Let's see where STU88.
There it is. Fill in the blank questions with drag
and drop interface. So it has a TLDR, it has the
current state. It did a little bit of research on
the code base, I think, expected outcomes, some
context. So yeah, so this is basically ready for
me to pick up when I'm interested in building.
So now let's say a few days go by, I finished the
current project I'm working on, I can pick it up.
So when I pick it up, I do /exploration phase,
which is what we said. And then instead of
pressing enter, I'll press tab and I'll show
you this. So basically, exploration phase, what
it does is it will take an argument. This is
basically a placeholder within the prompt,
which allows me to enter something that is
extra context for the AI. So I can say here,
Linear STU88, which is referencing the ticket.
And now what it's going to do is it's going
to go, it's going to fetch the Linear ticket.
And what's the idea? What's
the goal of the exploration
phase? This ideate on the idea. Is that the-
Exactly.
Okay.
So it's both for the CTO to deeply
understand the problem that we're
trying to solve and also understand
the current state of the code base,
what files need to be affected, and how is
the best way to implement this technically.
And usually what happens is right now, Claude
is just basically reading a bunch of files,
understanding the basic structure of the
code, and then it's going to come back with
a bunch of clarifying questions that will
decide how we end up implementing this.
So it feels like it's talking
to your engineering manager.
Exactly, exactly. 100% this
is how I think about it.
And you said that you're a CTO,
so you used to use ChatGPT prompt
to have a CTO in there. Now the
CTO's living inside here in Cursor?
Yeah, because of the way the tools have developed
and they've become so good at both exploration and
code execution. So now it's just a habit that
I call it a CTO, but it's basically all in one.
The same agent will both do the exploration and
write the plan and end up executing the code.
Got it. So it's basically it's
Claude Code. Is there a prompt
you gave it to act like that? To
act like the right kind of CTO?
Yeah, so within the Claude.md, which is
basically the system prompt that's loaded
within Claude's context in every conversation, I
have some basic stuff like this is our workflow,
this is how we work. Within exploration
phase, I want you to challenge my thinking,
all kinds of stuff like that that can
be loaded within the Claude.md file.
Cool. One last question before we move on here,
just because I'm thinking about it as this
happens, the Linear issue that you generated,
how often is it actually great and ready? How
often do you have to edit it? What's the quality
of the Linear ticket that it generates? Because
a lot of people are probably wondering just like
all these terrible linear issues are being
created by AI. Are they actually any good?
It's completely different because I'm a company
of one. So a lot of the context is within here
and there's no need for me to talk to other teams
and understand. It's basically very accessible,
and also I can easily see when
Claude understood something wrong.
I don't want to say that I would create Linear
issues at work like this, but definitely if you're
building your own side project, they're pretty
quality. And also, it just kicks off when I want
to start working on it. I wouldn't say it's ready
to be built. It's ready to start being explored.
Got it. So it's just the beginning of an idea.
Actually, let's come back after we go through this
flow of how you would approach this if you were
at say Meta or another, maybe a smaller company,
how this workflow might work at a larger
company that isn't just your own startup.
Yeah. Interesting.
Let's come back to that.
Cool. All right. So this is Claude coming back.
I have a comprehensive understanding of the code
base. I thoroughly analyzed StudyMate live
codebase and understand the current system,
feature quest and key areas that it's identified.
Usually I'd spend a lot of time going over this
because this is super, super important, but
just for the sake of development right now,
we're going to brush through this.
Now Claude basically comes back after it's
gone through the code base and understood the
way it currently works. It's basically telling
me what the current understanding is. So it's
talking about how the app is set up at the moment,
how the data is structured, what it understood
from the feature quest, and what it has identified
as key areas, and then it asks me some questions.
So it's asking about the scope, it's asking about
the data model, the UX/UI of the feature, how
it should be validated, how it should be graded,
what changes need to be happened to the AI
system prompt and all kinds of questions
about the app. I've prepared answers to all these
questions beforehand because I don't think we all
want to sit through this. So I'm just going to
paste that in and we'll see what Claude says.
Awesome. I love it. And I love just scanning those
questions I was asking. It's like such smart,
sophisticated, important questions instead of
just, "Cool, here I go, I'm going to build it."
Yeah, and I think this is the big difference
between just vibe coding and going along with the
vibes and really building serious apps. I spend
a lot, a lot of time going back and forth and
understanding. Also, a very cool /command that I
haven't showed yet is learning opportunity, which
basically when something is really difficult for
me to understand, I'll do /learning opportunity
and then talk about what I want to learn.
And this basically primes Claude and says,
"I am a technical PM in the making. I
have mid-level engineering knowledge.
I understand architecture and basically I want
you to explain what we're currently working on
using the 80/20 rule." So this is a great way to
learn. I would definitely take this and every time
you kind of see something that you don't fully
understand, I would definitely use this to learn.
Great. So Claude basically comes back and says how
it understands the current data model and how it's
going to implement. Yeah, so it's ready to create
the plan. So basically what I'm going to do now
is I'm going to go and do /create plan and while
Claude is doing this, I'm going to show really
quick what this looks like. So basically, these
plans are from a template that I found on Twitter.
I forgot who it was, but it was just a
template that really resonated with me. And
it's basically saying, based on our exchange,
create a markdown file that will be the plan,
include clear, minimal, concise steps, track the
status. So this basically has like status trackers
on each task that Claude updates as it's going
through and it will have a TLDR, some critical
decisions that we've made and the plan itself.
So Claude has finished writing the plan,
so we'll be able to look and see exactly what the
plan is. So it has a TLDR, it has the critical
decisions we've made and the tasks broken down.
And this is a perfect plan and it's also a really
good way to write this because a lot of times,
I'll use different models to execute certain
stuff. So Cursor has an amazing model called
Composer, which is superfast. So a lot of things
that are not that complex, I'll use Composer.
Gemini 3 that just came out is unbelievable
at UI. So a lot of times, I'll split
the plan into backend and front end,
and then I'll have Gemini just read the plan and
do the front end. So having this as a markdown
file is really good. And also going forward,
it's really good to have within the app so that
later on, if an agent is writing code in a certain
area, I can see what's already been done there.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to
execute the plan. So now I think we're going to
do this with Cursor just because Composer is so
freaking fast. So what we can do is basically
just say execute and then we can tag the file. And
Composer is ridiculously fast. So that's it. It's
off. It basically understands what the plan is and
it's going to go ahead and start writing the code.
Let me ask you a question while this is happening.
Awesome.
I have many questions, so this is
a good time to ask a few of them.
You said that Lovable and Bolt and other
apps in that space are just not enough to
build really serious apps and you have to move
to Cursor to do that. Tell us more about that.
Just what's the limitation you ran into with
those products and why you switched to Cursor?
I started using Cursor and Claude Code a few
months ago and I haven't looked back, but at that
time, these teams have been moving like crazy.
So I don't want to say I wouldn't trust them. I
don't know what the current state is. But for me,
it was basically the issue of I felt that Bolt was
being very opinionated on how I should do things.
And I felt like my knowledge has gotten to a point
where I can graduate and be more in control.
By the way, I think that the main difference
between all these tools is basically the harness.
So the models are all the same models. I'll run
Claude within Cursor, I'll run it within Claude
Code, and it's also the models that Claude is also
the model that is underlying Bolt and Lovable,
but basically, Bolt and Lovable will add a bunch
of levels in the middle that will take all kind
of guesswork and hard decisions out for the user.
So the user doesn't have to make these hard
decisions. So it's also very easy to build,
but the flip side of that is that you have
less control. And basically Claude Code is
just taking Claude and shoving it straight in
your code system and giving it full tools and
to do whatever it wants, but also with that comes
a lot of decisions that you need to make. So I
don't know if you can't build really amazing
production apps using Bolt or Lovable now,
but I think basically if you want the most cutting
edge abilities of the models and you want to
be able to make all the decisions on your own,
it's probably best to be on one of these tools.
What I'm feeling and hearing is
that planning work that you did,
that's the stuff that Lovable, Bolt, and
would you put Replit in that bucket too?
Yeah, for sure. Lovable, Bolt, Replit, Base44.
v0.
Yeah, v0, all same bucket.
So essentially, they're doing that
planning for you. And as you said,
they're very opinionated. They try
to make it easy. So it's just like,
"Here's how to do it. Here's the way we think
is best for people." And what you're saying is
once you're trying to get a little more serious
about it or want to go in a different direction,
you don't have the power to change how
they plan. So Cursor lets you do that.
Yeah, I don't want this to come out like
I'm badmouthing them. Base44, let's say.
No, absolutely.
Yeah. Base44 does an amazing job at basically
taking all the complex guesswork out of
building product and just allows you
to just go with the vibes and build,
but it will do sign in with Google
for you and it will do a database,
but then you don't have decisions on what database
am I using. Do I need sign in with Google this way
or another way? It would just do it out of the
box. So that's basically the trade-off there.
Awesome. Shout out Maor, the founder of Base44.
Yeah. Maor Shlomo. Yeah. He's amazing.
Okay. I just love how this is like the way you're
like flinging, what's the word? Slinging models
like Gemini 3 for frontend. I love that you've
never written any code and you're just like,
"Cool, use Gemini for this and Claude
for this. And I'm just working on Cursor,
talking to this CTO, helping you build
stuff and build significant product."
Yeah. We just live in the craziest of times where
basically the world changes once a week, it feels
like. And there is just no boundaries. You can
use all of these just on your regular MacBook
or regular laptop. And I have these moments,
I call them time machine moments, which is
basically this week, for instance, I was prepping
for the podcast using Claude with a project.
I was building, I was fully localizing StudyMate
from Hebrew to English, which I did in two days,
which would probably take a dev team weeks. And
I was building a personal site, which went from
no domain, no nothing, to live on a domain within
an hour and a half. And I was doing all three of
these in parallel. And there was a point where
basically all three of the agents were running,
so I didn't have anything to do.
I just had to let them think,
and these are the time machine moments where I
feel like I was in the future and I just stick
my head out of the time machine and whoever's
next to me, at the moment it was my wife,
I'll just say, "We live in the future." And she'll
be like, "Huh, what?" And I'll be like, "No, no,
don't worry about it." But it's just basically so
crazy that all these things are just an API away.
You can use anything. So I think it's an awesome
time to be curious and optimistic and hardworking.
These are my favorite kinds of podcast guests.
People that are living in the future, figuring
out all these things and then are just kind of
come back, as you said, poke your head out of the
rocket ship and just like, "Hey, here's this thing
that I figured out. Here's where we're going."
Yeah, best time to be alive. So
awesome. So it looks like it's finished.
So now what we're going to do is we're going
to run the app locally and we'll be able to see
what Composer ended up building and we're
going to see if anything else is needed
on our end to maybe do some manual
review. Does that sound good?
Sounds great. And I love, that was
like, I don't know, a few minutes
where if it was a human engineer, it'd
be like days, maybe a week for work.
For sure. Yeah, for sure. No, Composer
like the one thing is it's just so,
so blazing fast, keeps you in flow.
So yeah, full features take minutes.
And it probably costs a
couple bucks in AI credits.
I don't even look. I used to be so stingy about
paying for products and now I'm just basically,
I look at it all as tuition,
as stuff that I'm paying for
learning. So I don't know how much it
costs, but it's definitely worth it.
That explains why they're the
fastest growing products in history.
100%.
Your marketing website sets the tone for
your brand and is the one touchpoint that
every single one of your customers sees.
In today's age, if you're still having
a hard time making small changes and simple
updates to it, you are doing something wrong.
That is why so many companies from
early stage startups to Fortune 500s,
including companies like DoorDash, Zapier,
Perplexity, and ElevenLabs turn to Framer,
the website builder that turns your .com from a
formality into a tool for growth. Framer works
like your team's favorite design tool and comes
with real-time collaboration, a robust CMS with
everything you need for great SEO and advanced
analytics that includes integrated AB testing.
Changes to your Framer site go live to the web
in seconds with a single click and without any
help from engineering. Whether you want to
launch a new site, test a few landing pages
or migrate your full.com, Framer has programs for
startups, scale-ups, and large enterprises to make
going from idea to live site as easy and fast as
possible. Learn how to turn your website into a
growth engine from a framer expert or get started
building for free today at framer.com/lenny,
that's framer.com/lenny. Rules
and restrictions may apply.
So now we have this feature, which basically
we built and I can ask it to make some changes
because it's running locally and once
it's ready, I'll be able to ship it to
users. So now the next phase after I've
QA'd it and basically tested it manually,
I'll have Claude review its own work. So
what I'll do is I'll reopen Claude Code.
I love this because this is one of the things
that comes up a lot in this podcast is writing
code is now so easy. The main challenge people
have is reviewing the code that AI has written.
100%.
And what you're doing here is you're
having Claude review its own code.
Yeah, so this is another thing where it's
very difficult for me to catch mistakes.
So my review process has gone through a bunch
of iterations to really be as good as possible
and to catch as many things as possible. So
I'll always manually QA at first to make sure
if I can see any mistakes that Claude made.
And then what I'll do is basically /review.
And this tells Claude to start reviewing its own
code. But what's even cooler and something that
I'm really proud of is I will usually do multiple
reviews and I'll have Codex, which is ChatGPT's
competitor to Claude Code, as well as cursor open,
and I will have each of them review the code. And
then what I do is I have a /command called peer
review, which is really interesting. And basically
what it does is it's going to take Claude,
which is usually the agent who I'm working with.
And just to put this in a mental model, this
is basically my dev lead that I'm working with.
The /command is basically saying, "You're the dead
lead on this project. Other team leads within the
company have looked at your code and reviewed
it and found these issues." Don't take what
they said at face value. The reason is you have
more context than them and you led this project.
You need to either explain why the stuff they
found are not real issues and wrong or fix them
yourself. And it's really cool because the way
I look at these things is I look at the models,
I try to imagine them as people and I
can really tell you how each one of these
would be as a real human because they have-
Each model.
Yeah. Each model has such distinct
characteristics. So let's say Claude, she would
be the perfect CTO. She's very communicative.
She's very smart. She doesn't just go with the
flow and do whatever you tell her. She's very
opinionated, but also super collaborative, which
is I think why I'm always drawn to Claude because
I need to do so much learning and it's your dream,
a very communicative, but very opinionated
dev lead, but then there's also Codex.
So I use Codex 5.1 Max, whatever. I don't
know, they're not the best at naming models,
but GPT's model. I always imagine it as like
the best coder within the company who comes
to the office with a hoodie and sandals and
sits in a dark room. And you basically only
bother him when you have the worst bugs and you
say, "Listen, we have this bug and it will just
close the door for two hours and come out and say,
I fixed it." And you're like, "Wait, what? Are you
going to tell us what happened or whatever?"
And he's like, "Don't worry about it. I fixed
it." It's like really not communicative, but
it solves all the worst problems. And let's
say Gemini is like a crazy scientist who's
super artsy, super talented at designing,
but if you sit next to it and watch it work,
it's terrifying. You would fire that person
instantly. This might be just my experience,
but when I'm using Gemini within antigravity,
which is Google's new competitor to
Cursor, when it's writing code, you can
see the steps it's taking and it's terrifying.
You'll say, "I want you to redesign the top of
the dashboard." And you're looking at its thought
process and it will say, "Oh, first things first,
I'll delete the dashboard." And then it'll be
like, "Nope, that was a mistake. I'll bring
it back." And then it will say, "Oh, can I
edit the database?" And you're like, "No,
do not edit the database. You're just doing a
redesign." And then it will end up designing
something beautiful. So the way there is a
rollercoaster and very scary, but at the end
of the day, Gemini is very good at design.
So I think that using all these models
and basically playing to their strengths
and mitigating their weaknesses by using
other models is a game changer for me. So I'll
do peer review a bunch of times and I'll have
other models review other models code and kind
of have them fight it out basically. Sometimes
Claude Code will get really sassy and be like,
"This has been raised for the third time. And
for the third time I'm telling you, this is
not an issue. This is by design." So it's
just a really cool thing that I've added
and I haven't seen many people doing it.
That is such an incredible rant/way
to understand what's going on. Okay,
awesome. So we just ran the review.
So show us what we saw there and let's
actually try this peer review. I'm really
excited to see what you learned there.
Yeah. So basically Claude has reviewed its code
and it's found a bunch of bugs, a critical bug
it found in the prompt, some high bugs, some
medium bugs, and now what I'll do is I'll do
the same thing with the other models. So Codex has
a built-in code review that you can do, or I just
like to say review all the code in this branch.
Of course, branch is referring to the GitHub
branch that we're working on. We're not working
on the live code base. And then I'll do this with
Composer say with, let's do it with Composer One.
So I'll do /review here as well. And basically
these are both going to run and do a in-depth
review similar to what Claude does. But again,
because of the differences between the models,
they're all going to catch different things and
they're all going to look differently,
and this is a really cool way to work.
It's basically if you had other team leads
within the company review the code. Here,
you can see how fast Composer is. I think GPT
probably will take a bunch of time. Like I said,
it's in its own dark room right now reviewing
code and we'll come back in a few minutes.
Okay, cool. So we can let these
run in. We don't actually have to
go through the whole process, but is
the idea once you get these results,
you run peer review and you copy and paste
kind of these results. Is that the idea?
Exactly. I'll copy and paste the results. I'll
do peer review and then I'll say dev lead one
and then paste from one of the models. And then
I'll say dev lead two and paste from the other
model and basically have them fight it out
until I feel like we have no more issues.
Incredible.
For me, this is super important
because I'm not technical and
I'm not a developer. And I'll also
use /learning opportunity a bunch
during this to learn about stuff that I
don't understand or don't fully grasp.
Incredible. What a clever solution to solving
this code review problem where it's like,
I don't know what you ... I don't know how to
recode, so what am I going to even ... Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay. Incredible. Let's wrap up this
workflow. Is there anything else that's
important in this workflow? And again,
all this stuff is going to be available
where people can just plug this stuff into
their Cursor account and use it themselves.
100%. The one thing I'll say is that I think just
like working in general with AI and even just like
working on any product, doing constant
postmortems is critical. So a lot of
times we'll find all these kind of bugs or
maybe Claude will fail to execute something
correctly. And at the beginning when I
started vibe coding, I would basically
just keep running at it like running at the
wall and until it worked. And once it worked,
I was like, "All right, awesome. This works.
Let's keep going." But I've learned over time
that updating documentation and tooling is
one of the biggest hacks for productivity.
So when Claude will fail to do something or I'll
see this really bad bug that shows that Claude
really didn't understand something, I'll ask it,
"What in your system prompt or tooling made you
make this mistake?" And Claude will kind of like
go introspective and think of what made it create
that mistake. And then I'll say, "Okay, great.
Let's update your tooling and documentation so
that this mistake never occurs again." And
I do this every time I'm either building
an internal tool or anything. And
I think this is just like working.
If you end up doing a bunch of mistakes and
then end up releasing the feature to users,
so you're like, "All right, it's a big success."
But going back and even when you've succeeded,
looking and understanding what you did and
what you could have done better is critical.
And also using AI, this is probably one of the
biggest unlocks. Going back to your prompts,
understanding what was not good enough, iterating
on them and then seeing how AI's responses get
better, I think that's probably one of the most
important things and one of the things that
divides between people who are okay with using AI
and the people who actually know how to use it.
That is such good advice. So what
I'm hearing is when the models do
something dumb, make a mistake, you ask it
to reflect on what the mistake it made was,
and then you update the /command prompts
with that knowledge so that in the future,
it's not making that same mistake,
and it just keeps getting better.
Exactly.
These things just keep getting smarter
and smarter. So you're building up this
really incredible prompt that
just gets better and better.
Exactly. Not always the /commands.
It will sometimes update
different documentation or its tooling,
but basically it's understanding what
the root cause of the mistake
that the AI made and fixing it.
Awesome. So the models are getting smarter
and then there's also the other parts of
your workflow can get smarter as you
find flaws in the way it does stuff.
100%. Yep.
Amazing. Okay. Is there anything else there
before I move in a couple other directions?
I think that's it. I think we covered pretty
much everything. Basically, just to wrap this up,
what I do is I do a bunch of code review and
then update the documentation so that everything
is documented. So the next time I try to build a
feature in this area, there won't be any mistakes.
And then I'll do a bunch of testing. I'll do some
user testing as well before I release this to
general availability. Obviously we're not going to
release this. This was just a show, but hopefully
maybe by the time the podcast comes out, I'll
have done this correctly and release the feature.
It's incredible that this was not possible, I
don't know, two years ago, maybe a year ago,
you are a product manager shipping a
product without knowing how to write code,
barely knowing how to review code. You said you're
afraid of looking at code. As a product manager,
you're building a product in Cursor using
all of these different AI models. You're
making money with this product. We're so used to
this now, but it's insane what is now possible.
It's the best time to be live. 100%.
I think that I understand the fear,
but AI just makes it so much possible. Just
a quick side note here, my brother, who I'm
building one of the apps with is an entrepreneur.
He has a beautiful business that helps old people
and seniors understand to use technology and
AI better. And he's basically doing the same
kind of learning as me, and he's replaced
all of the tools he was paying for. I think
he was paying for Zapier and Airtable, and he's
basically built a full-fledged CRM system and
automation system for his business completely
alone. So for the people who are curious,
optimistic, hardworking, this is
the best time to be a builder.
And what I love about this conversation
we're having here is it feels like the
biggest barrier for a lot of people is like,
how do I get started? What exactly do I do?
I open up cursor. It looks very intimidating.
I don't know how to write code. I don't know
how to build stuff. I don't know about
databases. And so you're going to be
sharing all these /commands and basically
this whole workflow with the audience.
Yeah.
Okay.
And like I said, just start at GPT.
Start on GPT, tell it what your idea is,
tell it to explain to you what are
even the first steps of thinking,
what are the decisions you need to
make? And just be inquisitive, learn.
Don't rush things. It's very important to just
dive in and really spend the time to learn.
And you share this. One of your /commands is
learning opportunity, and it's how you learn
a lot of these things. Just teach me this
thing and how this database issue works.
Exactly.
Okay. There's a couple directions I want to
make sure we touch on. One is coming back to
a question I asked earlier about how this might
work at a larger company. Say it's not like Meta,
but just like, I don't know, a thousand person
company, 500 people. How much of this can you
plug and play into a workflow as a PM at a
larger company? What would be your advice for
someone that may want to start trying to ship
code, at least showing people what's possible?
I think that first making your code base AI native
is a really important step, and I think this needs
to be done by technical people. So basically my
codebase has a ton of just plain text in it. So it
will have a bunch of markdown files that explain
to agents how to work in certain areas of the code
base and high level structure so that the
agents navigate through the code base easier.
And I think that if this is set up in
a really good way, I still don't think
PMs should be shipping heavy database
chain migrations or any big project,
but contained UI projects, especially if
you just build it, create the PR and send
it to a dev to do the final finishes. I
think that's definitely something that's
possible. And I think we're going to see
that a lot in the next coming years. I
think basically everyone's going to become a
builder, so it should be really interesting.
Okay. So your advice here is as a PM, maybe don't
go right to Cursor, start building, shipping,
trying to ship features to production, especially
complicated features. Do you think we'll get
there? Do you think in a couple years, PMs will
be doing this and it'll feel less scary and crazy?
If there are PMs. Yeah, I think titles are
going to collapse and responsibilities are
going to collapse and everyone's just going to
be building. I definitely think that the models,
the context window is getting bigger, the models
are getting smarter and I definitely see how PMs
or any other background can be writing. At the
moment, I wouldn't wait for that. I would use this
as a collaborative learning opportunity to work
with your dev team. It's going to be difficult.
A lot of developers are very, very
skeptic about the current state,
and I think that it's going to be a lot
of sales work on your end to convince,
but if you're able to convince, and I think
teams that are really sold on this and want
to take the time to work on their workflow
about how can our team become more AI native,
I think that these teams are going to probably
be a few years in the future and they're going
to look back at the few weeks they spent
setting this up as the best time they spent.
Let me ask you another question around just the
job of a PM. One of the biggest fears people have
with these AI tools for PMs for every function I
imagine is just you start to rely on these things,
your skills start to atrophy, you're
producing all this slop that looks great,
cool, amazing strategy doc. No, it's
actually not at all good. Are these Linear
tickets or just products that are half-baked?
What's your take on these two parts of just like,
how has this impacted your craft as a PM?
Do you feel like this is weakening your
skills because you're so reliant on these
tools and just how do you keep the quality
of this stuff up and not just like, "Eh,
it's just a bunch of AI generated slop."
I have a very strong disagree to this and I've
heard it a bunch. I remember when I started using
Tal Raviv has this whole course on building a PM
Copilot using projects, which is probably one of
the best courses that you can take. And when I
started working with my own Copilot, I remember
people at work looking and saying like, "Oh, so
you're basically outsourcing your thinking." And
to me, that's just the worst way to look at it.
And I think for some reason, these people usually
have a high correlation with the kind of person
who doesn't like to show their presentation when
it's only 10% done or doesn't want to ask for help
a lot. I think that there's a misconception with a
lot of PMs that the job is always having the right
answers and being the smartest person in the room.
And at least how I was trained and how I believe
the role of the PM is, it's the exact opposite.
It's basically harnessing anything that can get
us as quick as possible to delivering the right
solution to users. And I just think this is
like that really smart person that has context
or your mentor or whatever, but is just always
available and doesn't judge you and can really
help you. So if you're using it to just create
your outputs and then putting them out there,
yeah, that's AI slot, but it's also human error.
I think it's really important that you own your
own outputs. If you put anything out there or show
something in a product review and you say, "Oh,
sorry, that was built by AI." That's your mistake.
I think if you use these intentionally and really
take the time to understand how to use AI in
the correct way, it's one of the biggest game
changers that will make you much better as a PM.
And another thing here is that, especially for
more junior PMs, it allows you to play at such
a higher level than you would normally. I think
that at Wix, I wasn't thinking of what's the
marketing strategy of the company and how will
the onboarding be completely revamped within
the whole product. But on my side product,
I can just do whatever decisions I want and think
of the strategy and marketing and the messaging.
And this is basically just getting me reps,
which is one of the most important things
at the beginning of your career. So I understand
the fear that how do you outsource certain stuff
and you're not owning 100% of everything, but I
think the upside is so much more valuable. And I
think the only way that AI makes you worse
at your job is if you're using it wrong.
Is there anything that you've learned about
reducing the sloppiness of the output,
just like a tip for keeping the quality
high of the stuff that it produces?
Similar to people, setting up AI for success,
for the task at hand. So if I just brought in
a junior to write a deck or something and I
didn't give it any guideline, I just said, "Give
a strategy deck." He would probably just go online
and find top strategy deck and just reproduce
that, which is basically what AI is doing.
It's basically just fed all of the internet.
So instead of that, guiding it and giving it
context on what your style of writing is and
what you're trying to solve and all these
different things, I think that's probably
one of the biggest unlocks. So that's just a quick
tip. And also Cursor has a /command called deslop,
which is basically going back over the code.
I don't know if this is integrated into the
product yet, but it's on Twitter. Their
founders have been talking about this,
so that's definitely something I would run after
just to make sure that no slop is left behind.
That is so funny, deslop. Okay. One more question,
which may lead to something else, but kind
of going in a whole different direction.
You used AI to help you actually interview for
the job that you got at Meta. Talk about how
you did that, because a lot of people right now
are struggling to find a job reading about all
these people using AI to help them interview. You
actually did it. What did you use? What worked?
I feel like the analogy here is I have 12 nieces
and nephews and you can see how people who have
grown up in a different world, how their mind is
formed differently. So if you ask me, how do you
answer a phone, I'll do this. But a child now,
when you say, "How do you answer the phone?"
They'll do this. They'll do the iPhone answer. And
I feel like people who are growing up now in their
professional lives were the same just with AI.
So every time I'm faced with a new challenge
or problem, I think AI first how to solve
it. So Meta reached out and said they'd
like me to interview. Straight away, I opened
up a project within Claude. I started looking
online for all the best information out there,
things that I resonated with. I took a ton of
frameworks and stuff from Ben Erez who has
written a guest post for you, who I think
is one of the best minds out there right now.
And basically I created a project which was my
coach, which I would come and consult what to
do at each phase. I would mock interview with,
and this was amazing. Also, I created
a game in Base44, which helped me ... I
was really struggling with segmentation
within the product questions, so thinking
of the correct segments. So I basically just
created a quiz game, which creates questions
and different segmentations and I have to choose.
So this was like, I spun this up. It's a web app
that I would play sometimes when I was on the
bus to work. So basically, I think Ben talks
about this a bunch, so I don't just go read Ben's
stuff, but just creating a project and feeding it
with all the best information on the internet and
then mocking a bunch. I will say that the biggest
game changer for me was doing human mocks.
So cold outreaching to people on LinkedIn and
having them do actual mocks for me, I think that
at the end of the day, especially for the Meta PM
prep, which is super competitive and difficult,
I think there's no way to get around that.
That is so cool they use that post. I wasn't
aware. We're going to link to it. And in that
post, Ben shares all these prompts you can feed
ChatGPT to help you prepare for interviews,
do mocks online. It's a really important point
to say that those take you to a point, but it's
actually better to use humans. I actually have a
post coming out soon in collaboration with Noam
Segal about how everyone is using AI to interview.
And one of the most interesting ways I've heard
people and that we've found in this research was
that people use it to get feedback. They record
the interview and then it gives them feedback.
Here's where you could have done better.
Here's what you missed because the feedback
loop is so missing. No one ever tells you,
here's what you did badly in this interview.
No one tells you that, and AI can do that.
So I'll add two things to that. One, which
is exactly this. So I'll mock with AI. Also,
I did something really cool where there's
a question bank online free by Louis Lynn,
which basically is an always updating bank
of questions that people are asked in real
interviews. And I basically used Comet, which
is the Perplexity's browser. And I had the
agent run all kinds of analyses on what the most
asked questions are. And that's how I knew how
to prioritize what questions I would mock.
And then at the end of these mocks, I would
tell Claude within the project, "You're my coach
and I don't want you to make me feel good. I want
you to make me as ready as possible for these
interviews. So give me feedback, like you said."
And the other thing that I did was really cool
was some questions where I didn't have time to
mock. I would ask Claude to play the candidate,
and then it would just give me a really good
answer. And I could also learn from that, like
learning from someone who does a perfect answer.
Oh, man. I really love the way you phrased
it, that people kind of in your generation,
the default is, "I have something I need
to do. Let's go to AI immediately and help
me prepare for this thing, help me figure it out."
Yeah.
And this comes back to this quote that I always
think about, which I think everyone is always
hearing, but it's such an important quote that
it's not that you will be replaced by AI at
least for a long time. It's you'll be replaced
by someone who's better at using AI than you.
I agree.
And that's what these conversations are for
to help people keep up with all that and to
learn some of these skills. And again, see
where the future is going and start to learn
how to get there yourself. Okay. Zevi, before
we get to our very exciting lightning round,
I'm going to take us to a recurring segment
on this podcast I call Failure Corner.
And why I love this segment is people
come on this, just even this conversation,
it's like all these amazing things
you figured out, everything is going
so well. People rarely hear the things that
don't go well, and those are often the most
interesting and impactful stories. So
the question is just, what's the story
of a time you failed in your career and
what did you learn from that experience?
Yeah, I love this. I love this. I love Failure
Corner, big fan. So I'll tell a story about
when I started at Wix. So basically I started
within Wix as a student program and straight
out of the student program, you get put into a
certain team. So I was in the editor, which is
the core product of Wix. And the other
PMs were just the best PMs almost at Wix.
There's four other people had much more experience
than me and they were ridiculously good. And I
remember coming in and thinking like, my first
product review, I'm going to blow these people's
socks off. They're not going to believe how
good of a PM I am. And I basically didn't
really share what I was thinking. I would
work tons of hours alone and I was like,
"I'm going to kill this product review. They're
going to be so impressed." And I ended up failing
miserably. My product review was not good.
It wasn't the format they expected. They
had a ton of questions that I missed and
I felt awful when it was over. I was like,
"Ah, you're such an idiot." And I saw that
everyone was like, "All right, cool. Yeah,
just come back in two weeks and we'll keep getting
at this." And I understood in that moment that
they had zero expectation of me being a 10X PM,
but the expectation of me was being a 10X learner.
And the second I understood that, my whole mindset
shifted. And I think this is probably the best tip
that I give now to junior PMs is basically be the
best learner you can be at the beginning. No one
expects you to know all the answers and no one
expects you to be good. So basically what I did
was I took each person on the PM team, there
was four other PMs and I assessed what their
strength is and used them as a mentor for that.
So Neri who's still my mentor till today,
he has the best product sense of
anyone I've met. Oya is super,
she's like a methodology expert. She just thinks
in frameworks. Yahra, who is the head of product,
basically can look at a product and then instantly
understand the third and fourth order effects
of them, the system thinking. So every time I
had an issue with one of these areas, I would
come to one of them and consult them, and this
does two things. First of all, I learned a ton.
And the second thing is that when the
next time, the next product review,
my success felt to them like their success
because it wasn't this kid who's trying
to show us up how cool he is. It was like our
mentee kind of making us all proud. And it was
such a great shift for me. And basically at the
end of the day, I really excelled through this.
That is an awesome story. And this idea of
learning is such a good thread throughout
this whole conversation that AI is good at
getting stuff done, but it's also really
good at helping you learn how to do the thing
and to be this partner, this thought partner,
the way you talked about the interview process
you went through and this learning opportunity
/command. So awesome. Great story. Zevi, okay.
Before we get to our very exciting lightning
round, is there anything else that you wanted to
share? Anything you want to leave listeners with?
Yeah. So kind of to tie back into the first
thing I said where if people walk away thinking,
"Zevi's so cool." Then I've failed here. I
think that it's just the best time to be alive,
I think. It's the best time to be a junior
contrary to what a lot of people are saying how
there's no more junior roles out there and people
get out of school and you can't find a role.
Yeah, that's true. But also when else in
history could you get out of school and
just build a startup on your own with a couple
of friends completely bootstrapped. And I see
more and more people towards the end of my
time at Wix, I was interviewing and I saw
more and more people building their own stuff
with AI. And I think contrary to what a lot of
people think, it's the best time to be a junior.
It's the best time to be a learner. And I think
if any listener is listening to this and you're
a curious person, you're a hardworking person,
I want to say kind, I'm not sure, but if you're a
kind person and a good communicator, you have such
an unfair advantage and you can give more value
to companies than most people who have 20 years of
experience. So I really hope people get inspired
by this and start killing it with their projects.
Amazing. So many ways to be inspired
from this conversation. Zevi, with that,
we've reached our very exciting lightning round.
I've got five questions for you. Are you ready?
Yep, let's do it.
What are two or three books that you find
yourself recommending most to other people?
So I'll take one from each kind of genre. So in
fiction, I love The Fountainhead by Ayn Rand,
one of my favorite books. Really makes you
think, really makes you feel. Business books,
I'm a big fan of Shoe Dog, the Nike
story, one of my favorite books.
I just finished reading that. So funny.
Amazing.
This is great. It was great.
Yeah. I love Shoe Dog. And then more on
the psychology side Mindset by Carol Dweck,
who coined the term growth mindset.
It's just such an amazing book. It
kind of sounds like a self-help book, but
then you understand that it's completely
psychological and is based on research
and that book completely changed my life.
Really, I was always with a fixed mindset, and
then after reading that, I kind of understood
that it was something holding me back.
And since then, I've been really,
really trying to cultivate a growth mindset.
So I really recommend everyone reading that.
Again, connects to that thread of the way you
described it, being a 10X learner versus a 10X
doer. Okay. Next question. Favorite recent
movie or TV show you have really enjoyed?
Yeah, actually, my wife is really into film, so
we watch a lot of TV. It's probably our favorite
together time. I just finished watching The Pitt,
which was amazing. It was really good.
And my first recommendation to everyone
is if you haven't seen Severance run to
see Severance, one of my favorite shows.
Is there a favorite product that you have
recently discovered that you really love?
This is a good question. I'm always trying new
products. I'll always have three or four browsers
installed on my computer and all this different
kind of stuff, and I recently discovered a Loom
alternative. I was kind of disappointed with Loom.
They were taking so much money and the product,
I don't know, I just didn't love it. And
there's an open source alternative called Cap,
which is just really well-crafted. You can
see that the person was really sweating the
details and it's just a really, really great
alternative. So I've been using that recently.
There's also a product called Supercut
that I love that's also a Loom alternative.
Shout out. Okay. Two more questions. Do
you have a favorite life motto that you
find yourself coming back to in work or in life?
Yeah. I'm kind of between two right now. One,
which has become a Twitter meme basically,
which is you can just do things. I feel
like that is basically going always in my
head every time I do something that I'm
just shocked at the speed and ability to
do things now so you can just do things, and
the second one I stole from my brother. His
motto is nobody knows what the fuck they're
doing. And I just love that. And I think it
kind of makes you take life more lightly. So
yeah, nobody knows what the they're doing.
I think people see these companies on the outside
and it feels like everything they've got all
figured out. And if you're ever on the inside of
a company that's doing really well, you're like,
how is this staying on the rails? How is this
still a thing that is working? Doesn't make any
sense. It's all about to fall apart. Yeah. Okay.
Last question. You've had a long entrepreneurial
thread throughout your career. There's a
couple other real world businesses you've
started in the past. You did a thermal
clothing business and then like a hummus
delivery thing. So maybe pick one of those
and just tell the story of what that's about.
Yeah, I'd love to. Really fun that you asked about
this. So I'll tell the thermal clothing because
I think it's really cool. So in high school,
I was selling thermal clothes in 10th grade
for one of my sister's friends or something,
and basically it was just packs of thermal
clothing, shirt and pants. I grew up in
Jerusalem, so it's a bit chillier there.
So it was perfect for the weather. And in 10th
grade, when I was selling them, they were like 20,
$25 a piece and I was making like $4 a sale,
and if you look in the food chain, I was like
sixth or seventh down the line. So this was like
crazy margins. So during the summer I thought
about it like I should just go straight to the
importer. So throughout the summer I called the
importer and at first he was really, really mad.
He was like, no, you have to work for me for years
to get to this state. And I said, listen, man,
I'm finishing school soon. This is not going to be
my career. Either do it or not. And we basically
negotiated throughout the whole summer. And this
was also like how I did things before ChatGPT.
So he would throw out something, he'd say, "Oh,
the import tax has gone up." And I'll just search
Google, like Import Tax Israel and start reading.
And I'll be on the phone with him and I'll be
like, "Hey, I would just basically stall." And
then I'd somehow come back with a challenge.
And I ended up getting a really great price,
like 12 and a half dollars a piece. So I was
making 100% profit and I spread throughout a
bunch of different schools. Each school, I had the
coolest people in school selling for me. And then
a really fun thing that I did was we had a really
awesome basketball team and our basketball team
would basically be 30 points up within the first
half and it kind of got boring for the crowd.
So I wrote a song, like a basketball
chant about Thermal Clothes that
basically has my number within it. And
the end of it was if you join in now,
we'll give you a discount. And it was with drums
and everything. And still when I go to Jerusalem,
I know some people who I don't even know
my number by heart because they know it
by the tune. And sometimes when I walk in
Jerusalem, people stop me and say like,
"Hey, it's Thermal Zevi." So that was
just a really cool experience as a kid.
This explains so much just the marketing
genius of that move. Oh man. Okay. Zevi,
this was incredible. Two final questions.
Where can folks find you if they want to reach
out and maybe follow up on some of the stuff?
We'll link to the scripts and prompts and all
that in the show notes so you don't have to read
that, and then how can listeners be useful to you?
Awesome. So I've been helped throughout my
whole career a ton, so I love helping any
way I can. So reach out on LinkedIn or on X.
I'd really love to help whoever I can. How can
listeners be useful to me? So if you're a student,
try StudyMate, tell me what you think. If you're
in Israel and you are not using dictation
yet, try Dibur2text. Tell me what you think.
Amazing. I just love how much you're giving
away and how useful that's going to be to so
many people. So again, we'll link to that in
the show notes. Zevi, you're awesome. Thank
you so much for being here. Thank you so much for
sharing so much. This is going to help, I think,
a lot of people and I think it's going to
help people get over the hump on. Okay,
I see all these people doing cool stuff.
Here's how I can actually do this stuff. So
thank you so much for being
here and for sharing so much.
Thank you for having me. And
if you build something cool
with some stuff that I learned here,
hit me up, send me. I'd love to see.
Amazing. Zevi, thank you so much for being here.
Thank you.
Bye everyone. Thank you so much for listening. If
you found this valuable, you can subscribe to the
show on Apple Podcast, Spotify, or your favorite
podcast app. Also, please consider giving us a
rating or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You can find
all past episodes or learn more about the show at
lennyspodcast.com. See you in the next episode.